<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/atharsefid/Desktop/grobid-0.5.3/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.3" ident="GROBID" when="2020-09-29T01:53+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">CAFTL: A Content-Aware Flash Translation Layer Enhancing the Lifespan of Flash Memory based Solid State Drives</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Feng</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
							<email>fchen@cse.ohio-state.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Dept. of Computer Science &amp; Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The Ohio State University Columbus</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>43210</postCode>
									<region>OH</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tian</forename><surname>Luo</surname></persName>
							<email>luot@cse.ohio-state.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Dept. of Computer Science &amp; Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The Ohio State University Columbus</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>43210</postCode>
									<region>OH</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaodong</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
							<email>zhang@cse.ohio-state.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Dept. of Computer Science &amp; Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The Ohio State University Columbus</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>43210</postCode>
									<region>OH</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">CAFTL: A Content-Aware Flash Translation Layer Enhancing the Lifespan of Flash Memory based Solid State Drives</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Although Flash Memory based Solid State Drive (SSD) exhibits high performance and low power consumption, a critical concern is its limited lifespan along with the associated reliability issues. In this paper, we propose to build a Content-Aware Flash Translation Layer (CAFTL) to enhance the endurance of SSDs at the device level. With no need of any semantic information from the host, CAFTL can effectively reduce write traffic to flash memory by removing unnecessary duplicate writes and can also substantially extend available free flash memory space by coalescing redundant data in SSDs, which further improves the efficiency of garbage collection and wear-leveling. In order to retain high data access performance , we have also designed a set of acceleration techniques to reduce the runtime overhead and minimize the performance impact caused by extra computational cost. Our experimental results show that our solution can effectively identify up to 86.2% of the duplicate writes, which translates to a write traffic reduction of up to 24.2% and extends the flash space by a factor of up to 31.2%. Meanwhile, CAFTL only incurs a minimized performance overhead by a factor of up to 0.5%.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The limited lifespan is the Achilles' heel of Flash Memory based Solid State Drives (SSDs). On one hand, SSDs built on semiconductor chips without any moving parts have exhibited many unique technical merits compared with hard disk drives (HDDs), particularly high random access performance and low power consumption. On the other hand, the limited lifespan of SSDs, which are built on flash memories with limited erase/program cycles, is still one of the most critical concerns that seriously hinder a wide deployment of SSDs in reliability-sensitive environments, such as data centers <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[10]</ref>. Although SSD manufacturers often claim that SSDs can sustain routine usage for years, the technical concerns about the endurance issues of SSDs still remain high. This is mainly * Currently working at the Intel Labs in Hillsboro, OR. due to three not-so-well-known reasons. First, as bit density increases, flash memory chips become more affordable but, at the same time, less reliable and less durable. In the last two years, for high-density flash devices, we have seen a sharp drop of erase/program cycle ratings from ten thousand to five thousand cycles <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[7]</ref>. As technology scaling continues, this situation could become even worse. Second, traditional redundancy solutions such as RAID, which have been widely used for battling disk failures, are considered less effective for SSDs, because of the high probability of correlated device failures in SSD-based RAID <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[9]</ref>. Finally, although some prior research work <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[13,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">22,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">33]</ref> has presented empirical and modeling-based studies on the lifespan of flash memories and USB flash drives, both positive and negative results have been reported. In fact, as a recent report from Google ® points out, "endurance and retention (of SSDs) not yet proven in the field" <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[10]</ref>.</p><p>All these aforesaid issues explain why commercial users hesitate to perform a large-scale deployment of SSDs in production systems and why integrating SSDs into commercial systems is proceeding such "painfully slowly" <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[10]</ref>. In order to integrate such a "frustrating technology", which comes with equally outstanding merits and limits, into the existing storage hierarchy timely and reliably, solutions for effectively improving the lifespan of SSDs are highly desirable. In this paper, we propose such a solution from a unique and viable angle.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1">Background of SSDs</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1.1">Flash memory and SSD internals</head><p>NAND flash memory is the basic building block of most SSDs on the market. A flash memory package is usually composed of one or multiple dies (chips). Each die is segmented into multiple planes, and a plane is further divided into thousands (e.g. 2048) of erase blocks. An erase block usually consists of 64-128 pages. Each page has a data area (e.g. 4KB) and a spare area (a.k.a. metadata area). Flash memories support three major operations. Read and write (a.k.a. program) are performed in units of pages, and erase, which clears all the pages in an erase block, must be conducted in erase blocks.</p><p>Flash memory has three critical technical constraints: (1) No in-place overwrite -the whole erase block must be erased before writing (programming) any page in this block. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(2)</ref> No random writes -the pages in an erase block must be written sequentially. (3) Limited erase/program cycles -an erase block can wear out after a certain number of erase/program cycles (typically 10,000-100,000).</p><p>As a critical component in the SSD design, the Flash Translation Layer (FTL) is implemented in the SSD controller to emulate a hard disk drive by exposing an array of logical block addresses (LBAs) to the host. In order to address the aforesaid three constraints, the FTL designers have developed several sophisticated techniques: (1) Indirect mapping -A mapping table is maintained to track the dynamic mapping between logical block addresses (LBAs) and physical block addresses (PBAs). (2) Log-like write mechanism -Each write to a logical page only invalidates the previously occupied physical page, and the new content data is appended sequentially in a clean erase block, like a log, which is similar to the log-structured file system <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[41]</ref>. <ref type="formula">(3)</ref> Garbage collection -A garbage collector (GC) is launched periodically to recycle invalidated physical pages, consolidate the valid pages into a new erase block, and clean the old erase block. (4) Wear-leveling -Since writes are often concentrated on a subset of data, which may cause some blocks to wear out earlier than the others, a wear-leveling mechanism tracks and shuffles hot/cold data to even out writes in flash memory. (5) Over-provisioning -In order to assist garbage collection and wear-leveling, SSD manufacturers usually include a certain amount of overprovisioned spare flash memory space in addition to the host-usable SSD capacity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1.2">The lifespan of SSDs</head><p>As flash memory has a limited number of erase/program cycles, the lifespan of SSDs is naturally constrained. In essence, the lifespan of SSDs is a function of three factors: (1) The amount of incoming write traffic -The less data written into an SSD, the longer the lifespan would be. In fact, the SSD manufacturers often advise commercial users, whose systems undergo intensive write traffic (e.g. an email server), to purchase more expensive highend SSDs. (2) The size of over-provisioned flash space -A larger over-provisioned flash space provides more available clean flash pages in the allocation pool that can be used without triggering a garbage collection. Aggressive over-provisioning can effectively reduce the average number of writes over all flash pages, which in turn improves the endurance of SSDs. For example, the highend Intel ® X25-E SSD is aggressively over-provisioned with about 8GB flash space, which is 25% of the labeled SSD capacity (32GB) <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[25]</ref>. <ref type="formula">(3)</ref> The efficiency of garbage collection and wear-leveling mechanisms -Having been extensively researched, the garbage collection and wearleveling policies can significantly impact the lifespan of SSDs. For example, static wear-leveling, which swaps active blocks with randomly chosen inactive blocks, performs better in endurance than dynamic wear-leveling, which only swaps active blocks <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[13]</ref>.</p><p>Most previous research work <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[21]</ref> focuses on the third factor, garbage collection and wear-leveling policies. A survey <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[21]</ref> summarizes these techniques. In contrast, little study has been conducted on the other two aspects. This may be because incoming write traffic is normally believed to be workload dependent, which cannot be changed at the device level, and the over-provisioning of flash space is designated at the manufacturing process and cannot be excessively large (due to the production cost). In this paper we will show that even at the SSD device level, we can still effectively extend the SSD lifespan by reducing the amount of incoming write traffic and squeezing available flash memory space during runtime, which has not been considered before. This goal can be achieved based on our observation of a widely existing phenomenon -data duplication.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.2">Data Duplication is Common</head><p>In file systems data duplication is very common. For example, kernel developers can have multiple versions of Linux source code for different projects. Users can create/delete the same files multiple times. Another example is word editing tools, which often automatically save a copy of documents every few minutes, and the content of these copies can be almost identical.  To make a case here, we have studied 15 disks installed on 5 machines in the Department of Computer Science and Engineering at the Ohio State University. Three file systems can be found in these disks, namely Ext2, Ext3, and NTFS. The disks are used in different environments, 4 disks from Database/Web Servers, 7 disks from Experimental Systems for kernel development, and the other 4 disks from Office Systems. We slice the disk space into 4KB blocks and use the SHA-1 hash function <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref> to calculate a 160-bit hash value for each block. We can identify duplicate blocks by comparing the hash values. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1</ref> shows the duplication rates (i.e. the percentage of duplicate blocks in total blocks).</p><p>In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1</ref>, we find that the duplication rate ranges from 7.9% to 85.9% across the 15 disks. We also find that in only one disk with NTFS, the duplicate blocks are dominated by 'zero' blocks. The duplicate blocks on the other disks are mostly non-zero blocks, which means that these duplicate blocks contain 'meaningful' data. Considering the fact that a typical SSD has an overprovisioned space of only 1-20% of the flash memory space, removing the duplicate data, which accounts for 7.9-85.9% of the SSD capacity, can substantially extend the available flash space that can be used for garbage collection and wear-leveling. If this effort is successful, we can raise the performance comparable to that of high-end SSDs with no need of extra flash space.  Besides the static analysis of the data redundancy in storage, we have also collected I/O traces and analyzed the data accesses of 11 workloads from three categories (see more details in Section 4). For each workload, we modified the Linux kernel by intercepting each I/O request and calculating a hash value for each requested block. We analyzed the I/O traces off-line. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 2</ref> shows the percentage of the duplicate writes in each workload. We can find that 5.8-28.1% of the writes are duplicated. This finding suggests that if we remove these duplicate writes, we can effectively reduce the write traffic into flash medium, which directly improves the endurance accordingly, not to mention the indirect effect of reducing the number of extra writes caused by less frequently triggered garbage collections.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.3">Making FTL Content Aware</head><p>Based on the above observations and analysis, we propose a Content-Aware Flash Translation Layer (CAFTL) to integrate the functionality of eliminating duplicate writes and redundant data into SSDs to enhance the lifespan at the device level.</p><p>CAFTL intercepts incoming write requests at the SSD device level and uses a collision-free cryptographic hash function to generate fingerprints summarizing the content of updated data. By querying a fingerprint store, which maintains the fingerprints of resident data in the SSD, CAFTL can accurately and safely eliminate duplicate writes to flash medium. CAFTL also uses a twolevel mapping mechanism to coalesce redundant data, which effectively extends available flash space and improves GC efficiency. In order to minimize the performance impact caused by computing hash values, we have also designed a set of acceleration methods to speed up fingerprinting. With these techniques, CAFTL can effectively reduce write traffic to flash, extend available flash space, while retaining high data access performance.</p><p>CAFTL is an augmentation, rather than a complete replacement, to the existing FTL designs. Being contentaware, CAFTL is orthogonal to the other FTL policies, such as the well researched garbage collection and wearleveling policies. In fact, the existing mechanisms in the SSDs provide much needed facilities for CAFTL and make it a perfect fit in the existing SSD architecture. For example, the indirect mapping mechanism naturally makes associating multiple logical pages to one physical page easy to implement; the periodic scanning process for garbage collection and wear-leveling can also carry out an out-of-line deduplication asynchronously; the loglike write mechanism makes it possible to re-validate the 'deleted' data without re-writing the same content; and finally, the semiconductor nature of flash memory makes reading randomly remapped data free of high latencies.</p><p>CAFTL is also backward compatible and portable. Running at the device level as a part of SSD firmware, CAFTL does not need to change the standard host/device interface for passing any extra information from the upper-level components (e.g. file system) to the device. All of the design of CAFTL is isolated at the device level and hidden from users. This guarantees CAFTL as a drop-in solution, which is highly desirable in practice.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.4">Our Contributions</head><p>We have made the following contributions in this paper: (1) We have studied data duplications in file systems and various workloads, and assessed the viability of improving endurance of SSDs through deduplication. (2) We have carefully designed a content-aware FTL to extend the SSD lifespan by removing duplicate writes (up to 24.2%) and redundant data (up to 31.2%) with minimal overhead. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first study using effective deduplication in SSDs. (3) We have also designed a set of techniques to accelerate the in-line deduplication in SSD devices, which are particularly effective with small on-device buffer spaces (e.g. 2MB) and make performance overhead nearly negligible. (4) We have implemented CAFTL in the DiskSim simulator and comprehensively evaluated its performance and shown the effectiveness of improving the SSD lifespan through extensive trace-driven simulations.</p><p>The rest of this paper is organized as follows. In Section 2, we discuss the unique challenges in the design of CAFTL. Section 3 introduces the design of CAFTL and our acceleration methods. We present our performance evaluation in Section 4. Section 5 gives the related work. The last section discusses and concludes this paper.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Technical Challenges</head><p>CAFTL shares the same principle of removing data redundancy with Content-Addressable Storage (CAS), e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">24,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">30,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">45,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">47]</ref>, which is designed for backup/archival systems. However, we cannot simply borrow CAS policies in our design due to four unique and unaddressed challenges: (1) Limited resources -CAFTL is designed for running in an SSD device with limited memory space and computing power, rather than running on a dedicated powerful enterprise server. (2) Relatively lower redundancy -CAFTL mostly handles regular file system workloads, which have an impressive but much lower duplication rate than that of backup streams with high redundancy (often 10 times or even higher). (3) Lack of semantic hints -CAFTL works at the device level and only sees a sequence of logical blocks without any semantic hints from host file systems. (4) Low overhead requirement -CAFTL must retain high data access performance for regular workloads, while this is a less stringent requirement in backup systems that can run during out-of-office hours.</p><p>All of these unique requirements make deduplication particularly challenging in SSDs and it requires nontrivial efforts to address them in the CAFTL design.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">The Design of CAFTL</head><p>The design of CAFTL aims to reach the following three critical objectives.</p><p>• Reducing unnecessary write traffic -By examining the data of incoming write requests, we can detect and remove duplicate writes in-line, so that we can effectively filter unnecessary writes into flash memory and directly improve the lifespan of SSDs.</p><p>• Extending available flash space -By leveraging the indirect mapping framework in SSDs, we can map logical pages sharing the same content to the same physical page. The saved space can be used for GC and wear-leveling, which indirectly improves the lifespan.</p><p>• Retaining access performance -A critical requirement to make CAFTL truly effective in practice is to avoid significant negative performance impacts. We must minimize runtime overhead and retain high data access performance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Overview of CAFTL</head><p>CAFTL eliminates duplicate writes and redundant data through a combination of both in-line and out-of-line (a.k.a post-processing or out-of-band) deduplication. Inline deduplication refers to the case where CAFTL proactively examines the incoming data and cancels duplicate writes before committing a write request to flash. As a 'best-effort' solution, CAFTL does not guarantee that all duplicate writes can be examined and removed immediately (e.g. it can be disabled for performance purposes). Thus CAFTL also periodically scans the flash memory and coalesces redundant data out of line. Figure 3 illustrates the process of handling a write request in CAFTL -When a write request is received at the SSD, (1) the incoming data is first temporarily maintained in the on-device buffer; (2) each updated page in the buffer is later computed a hash value, also called fingerprint, by a hash engine, which can be a dedicated processor or simply a part of the controller logic; (3) each fingerprint is looked up against a fingerprint store, which maintains the fingerprints of data already stored in the flash memory; (4) if a match is found, which means that a residing data unit holds the same content, the mapping tables, which translate the host-viewable logical addresses to the physical flash addresses, are updated by mapping it to the physical location of the residing data, and correspondingly the write to flash is canceled; (5) if no match is found, the write is performed to the flash memory as a regular write.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Hashing and Fingerprint Store</head><p>CAFTL attempts to identify and remove duplicate writes and redundant data. A byte-by-byte comparison is excessively slow. A common practice is to use a cryptographic hash function, e.g. SHA-1 <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref> or MD5 <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[40]</ref>, to compute a collision-free hash value as a fingerprint. Duplicate data can be determined by comparing fingerprints. Here we explain how we produce and manage fingerprints.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.1">Choosing hashing units</head><p>CAFTL uses a chunk-based deduplication approach. Unlike most CAS systems, which often use more complicated variable-sized chunking, CAFTL adopts a fixedsized chunking approach for two reasons. First, the variable-sized chunking is designed for segmenting a long I/O stream. In CAFTL, we handle a sequence of individual requests, whose size can be very small (a few kilobytes) and vary significantly. Thus variable-sized chunking is inappropriate for CAFTL. Second, the basic operation unit in flash is a page (e.g. 4KB), and the internal management policies in SSDs, such as the mapping policy, are also designed in units of pages. Thus, using pages as the fixed-sized chunks for hashing is a natural choice and also avoids unnecessary complexity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.2">Hash function and fingerprints</head><p>In order to identify duplicate data, a collision-free hash function is used for summarizing the content of pages. We use the SHA-1 <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>, a widely used cryptographic hash function, and rely on its collision-resistant properties to index and compare pages. For each page, we calculate a 160-bit hash value as its fingerprint and store it as the page's metadata in flash. The SHA-1 hash function has been proven computationally infeasible to find two distinct inputs hashing to the same value <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[32]</ref>. We can safely determine if two pages are identical using fingerprints. In order to locate quickly the physical page with a specific fingerprint, CAFTL manages an in-memory structure, called Fingerprint Store. Apparently, keeping all fingerprints and related information (25 bytes each) in memory is too costly and unnecessary. We have studied the distribution of fingerprints in the 15 disks and we plot a Cumulative Distribution Function (CDF) figure in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 4</ref>. We can see that the distribution of duplicated fingerprints is skewed -only 10-20% of the fingerprints are highly duplicated (more than 2). This finding provides two implications. First, most fingerprints are unique and never have a chance to match any queried fingerprint. Second, a complete search in the fingerprint store would incur high lookup latencies, and even worse, most lookups eventually turn out to be useless (no match found). Thus, we should only store and search in the most likely-to-be-duplicated fingerprints in memory.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.3">The fingerprint store</head><p>We first logically partition the hash value space into N segments. For a given fingerprint, f , we can map it to segment ( f mod N), and the random nature of the hash function guarantees an even distribution of fingerprints among the segments. Each segment contains a list of buckets. Each bucket is a 4KB page in memory and consists of multiple entries, each of which is a key-value pair, {fingerprint, (location, reference)}. The 160-bit fingerprint indexes the entry; the 32-bit location denotes where we can find the data, either the PBA of a physical flash page or the VBA of a secondary mapping entry (see Section 3.3); the 8-bit reference denotes the hotness of this fingerprint (i.e. the number of referencing logical pages). The entries in each bucket are sorted in the ascending order of their fingerprint values to facilitate a fast in-bucket binary search. The total numbers of buckets and segments are designated by the SSD manufacturers.</p><p>The fingerprint store maintains the most highly referenced fingerprints in memory. During the SSD startup time, after the mapping tables are built up (to be discussed in Section 3.3), the fingerprint store is also reconstructed by scanning the mapping tables and the metadata in flash to load the key value pairs of {fingerprint, (location, reference)} into memory. Initially no bucket is allocated in the fingerprint store. Upon inserting a fingerprint, an empty bucket is allocated and linked into a bucket list of the corresponding segment. This bucket holds the fingerprints inserted into the corresponding segment until the bucket is filled up, then we allocate another bucket. We continue to allocate buckets in this way until there are no more free buckets available. If that happens, the newly inserted fingerprint will replace the fingerprint with the smallest reference counter (i.e. the coldest one) in the bucket, unless its reference counter is smaller than any of the resident fingerprints. Note that we choose the inserting bucket in a round-robin manner to ensure a relatively even distribution of hot/cold fingerprints across the buckets in a segment. It is also worth mentioning here that a 8-bit reference counter is sufficiently large for distinguishing the hot fingerprints, because most fingerprints have a reference counter smaller than 255 (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 4)</ref>. We consider fingerprints with a reference counter larger than 255 as highly referenced and do not further distinguish their difference in hotness. In this way, we can include the most highly referenced fingerprints in memory. Although we may miss some opportunities of identifying the duplicates whose fingerprints are not resident in memory, this probability is considered low (as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 4</ref>), and we are not pursuing a perfect in-line deduplication. Our out-of-line scanning can still identify these duplicates later.</p><p>Searching a fingerprint can be very simple. We compute the mapping segment number and scan the corresponding list of buckets one by one. In each bucket, we use binary search to speed up the in-bucket lookup. However, for a segment with a large set of buckets, this method is still improvable. We have designed three optimization techniques to further accelerate fingerprint lookups. (1) Range Check -before performing the binary search in a bucket, we first compare the fingerprint with the smallest and the largest fingerprints in the buckets. If the fingerprint is out of the range, we quickly skip over this bucket. <ref type="formula">(2)</ref> Hotness-based Reorganization -the fingerprints in the linked buckets can be reorganized in the descending order of their reference counters. This moves the hot fingerprints closer to the list head and potentially reduces the number of the scanned buckets. (3) Bucketlevel Binary Search -the fingerprints across the buckets can be reorganized in the ascending order of the fingerprint values by using a merge sort. For each segment we maintain an array of pointers to the buckets in the list. We can perform a binary search at the bucket level by recursively selecting the bucket in the middle to do a Range Check. In this way we can quickly locate the target bucket and skip over most buckets. Although reorganizing the fingerprints requires performing an additional merge sort, our experiments show that these optimizations can significantly reduce the number of comparisons of fingerprint values. In Section 4.3.3 we will show and compare the effectiveness of the three techniques.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Indirect Mapping</head><p>Indirect mapping is a core mechanism in the SSD architecture. SSDs expose an array of logical block addresses (LBAs) to the host, and internally, a mapping table is maintained to track the physical block address (PBA) to which each LBA is mapped. For CAFTL, the existing indirect mapping mechanism in SSDs provides a basic framework for deduplication and avoids rebuilding the whole infrastructure from scratch.</p><p>On the other hand, the existing 1-to-1 mapping mechanism in SSDs cannot be directly used for CAFTL, which is essentially N-to-1 mapping, because of two new challenges. (1) When a physical page is relocated to another place (e.g. in garbage collection), we must be able to identify quickly all the logical pages mapped to this physical page and update their mapping entries to point to the new location. (2) Since a physical page could be shared by multiple logical pages, it cannot be recycled by the garbage collector until all the referencing logical pages are demapped from it, which means that we must track the number of referencing logical pages. In this two-level indirect mapping structure, we can locate the physical page for a logical page either through LBA→PBA or LBA→VBA→PBA.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.1">Two-level indirect mapping</head><p>We maintain a primary mapping table and a secondary mapping table in memory. The primary mapping table maps a LBA to either a PBA, if the logical page is unique, or a VBA, if it is a duplicate page. We differentiate PBAs and VBAs by using the most significant bit in the 32-bit page address. For a page size of 4KB, using the remaining 31 bits can address 8,192 GB storage space, which is sufficiently large for an SSD. The secondary mapping table maps a VBA to a PBA. Each entry is indexed by the VBA and has two fields, {PBA, reference}. The 32-bit PBA denotes the physical flash page, and the 32-bit reference tracks the exact number of logical pages mapped to the physical page. Only physical pages without any reference can be recycled for garbage collection.</p><p>This two-level indirect mapping mechanism has several merits. First, it significantly simplifies the reverse updates to the mapping of duplicate logical pages. When relocating a physical page during GC, we can use its associated VBA to quickly locate and update the secondary mapping table by mapping the VBA to the new location (PBA), which avoids exhaustively searching for all the referencing LBAs in the huge primary mapping table. Second, the secondary mapping table can be very small. Since CAFTL handles regular file system workloads, most logical pages are unique and directly mapped through the primary table. We can also apply an approach similar to DFTL <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[23]</ref> to further reduce the memory demand by selectively maintaining the most frequently accessed entries of the mapping tables in memory. Finally, this incurs minimal additional lookup overhead. For unique pages, it performs identically to conventional FTLs; for duplicate pages, only one extra memory access is needed for the lookup operation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.2">The mapping tables in flash</head><p>The mapping relationship is also maintained in flash memory. We keep an in-flash copy of the primary and secondary mapping tables along with a journal in dedicated flash space in SSD. Both in-flash structures are organized as a list of linked physical flash pages. When updating the in-memory tables (e.g. remapping a LBA to a new location), the update record is logged into a small in-memory buffer. When the buffer is filled, the log records are appended to the in-flash journal. If power failure happens, a capacitor (e.g. a SuperCap <ref type="bibr">[46]</ref>) can provide sufficient current to flush the unwritten logs into the journal and secure the critical mapping structures in persistent storage. Periodically the in-memory tables are synced into flash and the journal is reinitialized. During the startup time, the in-flash tables are first loaded into memory and the logged updates in the journal are applied to reconstruct the mapping tables.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.3">The metadata pages in flash</head><p>Unlike much prior work, which writes the metadata (e.g. LBA and fingerprint) in the spare area of physical flash pages, we reserve a dedicated number of flash pages, also called metadata pages, to store the metadata, and keep a metadata page array for tracking PBAs of the metadata pages. The spare area of a physical page is only used for storing the Error Correction Code (ECC) checksum. If each physical page is associated with 24 bytes of metadata (a 160-bit fingerprint and a 32-bit LBA/VBA), for a 32GB SSD with 4KB flash pages, we need about 0.6% of the flash space for storing metadata and a 192KB metadata page array. In this way, we can detach the data pages and the metadata pages, which allows us to manage flexibly the metadata for physical flash pages.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Acceleration Methods</head><p>Fingerprinting is the key bottleneck of the in-line deduplication in CAFTL, especially when the on-device buffer size is limited. Here we present three effective techniques to reduce its negative performance impact.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4.1">Sampling for hashing</head><p>In file system workloads, as we discussed previously, duplicate writes are not a 'common case' as in backup systems. This means that most time we spend on fingerprinting is not useful at all. Thus, we selectively pick only one page as a sample page for fingerprinting, and we use this sample fingerprint to query the fingerprint store to see if we can find a match there. If this is true, the whole write request is very likely to be a duplicate, and we can further compute fingerprints for the other pages to confirm that.</p><p>Otherwise, we assume the whole request would not be a duplicate and abort fingerprinting at the earliest time. In this way, we can significantly reduce the hashing cost.</p><p>The key issue here is which page should be chosen as the sample page. It is particularly challenging in CAFTL, since CAFTL only sees a sequence of blocks and cannot leverage any file-level semantic hints (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[11]</ref>). We propose to use Content-based Sampling -We select the first four bytes, called sample bytes, from each page in a request, and we concatenate the four bytes into a 32-bit numeric value. We compare these values and the page with the largest value is the sample page. The rationale behind this is that if two requests carry similar content, the pages with the largest sample bytes in two requests would be very likely to be the same, too. We deliberately avoid selecting the sample pages based on hash values (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">30]</ref>), because in CAFTL, hashing itself incurs high latency. Thus relying on hash values for sampling is undesirable, so we directly pick sample pages based on their unprocessed content data. We have also examined choosing other bytes ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 6</ref>) as the sample bytes and found that using the first four bytes performs constantly well across different workloads. In our implementation of sampling, we divide the sequence of pages in a write request into several sampling units (e.g. 32 pages), and we pick one sample page from each unit. We also note that sampling could affect deduplication -the larger a sampling unit is, the better performance but the lower deduplication rate would be. We will study the effect of unit sizes in Section 4.4.1. Figure 7: Condense rates vs. hash bits. Computing a light-weight hash function often incurs lower computational cost. For example, producing a 32-bit CRC32 hash value is over 10 times faster than computing a 160-bit SHA-1 hash value. More importantly, our study shows that reducing the hash strength would not incur a significant increase of false positives for a typical SSD capacity. We can see in <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref> that using only 32 bits can achieve nearly the same condense rate as using 160 bits. Plus, many SSDs integrate a dedicated ECC engine to compute checksum and detect errors, which can also be leveraged to speed up hashing.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4.2">Light-weight pre-hashing</head><p>We propose a technique, called light-weight prehashing. We maintain an extra 32-bit CRC32 hash value for each fingerprint in the fingerprint store. For a page, we first compute a CRC32 hash value and query the fingerprint store. If a match is found, which means the page is very likely to be a duplicate, then we use the SHA-1 hash function to generate a fingerprint and confirm it in the fingerprint store; otherwise, we abort the highcost SHA-1 fingerprinting immediately and perform the write to flash. Although maintaining CRC32 hash values demands more fingerprint store space, the significant performance benefit well justifies it, as shown in Section 4.4.2. We have also considered using a Bloom filter <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[12]</ref> for pre-screening, like in the DataDomain ® file system <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[47]</ref>, but found it inapplicable to CAFTL, because it requires multiple hashings and the summary vector cannot be updated when a fingerprint is removed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4.3">Dynamic switches</head><p>In some extreme cases, incoming requests may wait for available buffer space to be released by previous requests. CAFTL provides dynamic switch as the last line of defense for performance protection in such cases.</p><p>We set a high watermark and a low watermark to turn the in-line deduplication off and on, respectively. If the percentage of the occupied cache space hits a high watermark (95%), we disable the in-line deduplication to flush writes quickly to flash and release buffer space. Once the low watermark (50%) is hit, we re-enable the in-line deduplication. Although this remedy solution would reduce the deduplication rate, we still can perform out-ofline deduplication at a later time, so it is an acceptable tradeoff for retaining high performance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.5">Out-of-line Deduplication</head><p>As mentioned previously, CAFTL does not pursue a perfect in-line deduplication, and an internal routine is periodically launched to perform out-of-line fingerprinting and out-of-line deduplication during the device idle time.</p><p>Out-of-line fingerprinting is simple. We scan the metadata page array (Section 3.3.3) to find physical pages not yet fingerprinted. If one such a page is found, we read the page out, compute the fingerprint, and update its metadata. To avoid unnecessarily scanning the metadata of pages already fingerprinted, we use one bit in an entry of the metadata page array to denote if all of the fingerprints in the corresponding metadata page have already been computed, and we skip over such pages.</p><p>Out-of-line deduplication is more complicated due to the memory space constraint. We adopt a solution similar to the widely used external merge sort <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[39]</ref> in database systems. Supposing we have M fingerprints in total and the available memory space can accommodate N fingerprints, where M &gt; N. We scan the metadata page array from the beginning, each time N fingerprints are loaded and sorted in memory, and temporarily stored in flash, then we load and sort the next N fingerprints, and so on. This process is repeated for K times (K = M N ) until all the fingerprints are processed. Then we can merge sort these K blocks of fingerprints in memory and identify the duplicate fingerprints.</p><p>Out-of-line fingerprinting and deduplication can be performed together with the GC process or independently. Since there is no harm in leaving duplicate or unfingerprinted pages in flash, these operations can be performed during idle period and immediately aborted upon incoming requests, and the perceivable performance impact to foreground jobs is minimal.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Performance Evaluation 4.1 Experimental Systems</head><p>We have implemented and evaluated our design of CAFTL based on a comprehensive trace-driven simulation. In this section we will introduce our simulator, trace collection, and system configurations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.1">SSD Simulator</head><p>CAFTL is a device-level design running in the SSD controller. We have implemented it in a sophisticated SSD simulator based on the Microsoft ® Research SSD extension <ref type="bibr">[5]</ref> for the DiskSim simulation environment <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[14]</ref>. This extension was also used in prior work <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[6]</ref>.</p><p>The Microsoft extension is well modularized and implements the major components of FTL, such as the indirect mapping, garbage collection and wear-leveling policies, and others. Since the current version lacks an ondevice buffer, which is becoming a standard component in recent generations of SSDs, we augmented the current implementation and included a shared buffer for handling incoming read and write requests. When a write request is received at the SSD, it is first buffered in the cache, and the SSD immediately reports completion to the host. Data processing and flash operations are conducted asynchronously in the background <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[16]</ref>. A read request returns back to the host once the data is loaded from flash into the buffer. We should note that this simulator follows a general FTL design <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[6]</ref>, and the actual implementations of the SSD on the market can have other specific features. In our experiments, we use the default configurations from the SSD extension, unless denoted otherwise. <ref type="table">Table  1</ref> gives a list of the major config parameters.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.2">SSD Configurations</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Description</head><p>Description Latency Flash Read/Write/Erase 25 µs/200µs/1.5ms SHA-1 hashing (4KB) 47,548 cycles CRC32 hashing (4KB) 4,120 cycles <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Latencies configured in the SSD simulator. <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> gives the parameters of latencies used in our experiments. For the flash memory, we use the default latencies in our experiments. For the hashing latencies, we first cross compile the hash function code to the ARM ® platform and run it on the SimpleScalar-ARM simulator <ref type="bibr">[4]</ref> to extract the total number of cycles for executing a hash function. We assume a processor similar to ARM ® Cortex R4 <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[8]</ref> on the device, which is specifically designed for high-performance embedded devices, including storage. Based on its datasheet, the ARM processor has a frequency from 304MHz to 934MHz <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[8]</ref>, and we can estimate the latency for hashing a 4KB page by dividing the number of cycles by the processor frequency. It is also worth mentioning here that according to our communications with SSD manufacturer <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>, high-frequency (600+ MHz) processors, such as the Cortex processor, are becoming increasingly normal in high-speed storage devices. Leveraging such abundant computing power on storage devices can be a research topic for further investigation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.3">Workloads and trace collection</head><p>We have selected 11 workloads from three representative categories and collected their data access traces.</p><p>• Desktop (d1,d2) -Typical office workloads, e.g. Internet surfing, emailing, word editing, etc. The workloads run for 12 and 19 hours, respectively, and feature irregular idle intervals and small reads and writes.</p><p>• Hadoop (h1-h7)-We execute seven TPC-H data warehouse queries <ref type="bibr">(Query 1,6,11,14,15,16,20)</ref> with scale factor of 1 on a Hadoop distributed system platform <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. These workloads run for 2-40 minutes and generate intensive large writes of temp data.</p><p>• Transaction (t1,t2) -We execute TPC-C workloads (1-3 warehouses, 10 terminals) for transaction processing on PostgreSQL 8.4.3 database system. The two workloads run for 30 minutes and 4 hours, respectively, and feature intensive write operations.</p><p>The traces are collected on a DELL ® Dimension 3100 workstation with an Intel ® Pentium™4 3.0GHz processor, a 3GB main memory, and a 160GB 7,200 RPM Seagate ® hard disk drive. We use Ubuntu 9.10 with the Ext3 file system. We modified the Linux kernel 2.6.32 source code to intercept each I/O request and compute a SHA-1 hash value as a fingerprint for each 4KB page of the request. These fingerprints, together with other request information (e.g. offset, type), are transferred to another machine via netconsole <ref type="bibr">[35]</ref>. This avoids the possible interference caused by tracing. The collected trace files are analyzed offline and used to drive the simulator for our experimental evaluation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Effectiveness of Deduplication</head><p>CAFTL intends to remove duplicate writes and extend flash space. In this section, we perform two sets of experiments to show the effectiveness of deduplication in CAFTL. In both experiments, we use an SSD with a 934MHz processor and a 16MB buffer.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.1">Removing duplicate writes</head><p>CAFTL identifies and removes duplicate writes via inline deduplication. Denoting the total number of pages requested to be written as n, and the total number of pages being actually written into flash medium as m, the deduplication rate is defined as n−m n . <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">Figure 8</ref> shows the deduplication rate of the 11 workloads running on CAFTL. In this figure, offline refers to the optimal case, where the traces are examined and deduplicated offline. We also show CAFTL without sampling and with a sampling unit size of 128KB (32 pages), denoted as nosampling and 128KB, respectively.  As we see in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">Figure 8</ref>, duplication is highly workload dependent. Across the 11 workloads, the rate of duplicate writes in the workloads ranges from 5.8% (t1) to 28.1% (h6). CAFTL can achieve deduplication rates from 4.6% (t1) to 24.2% (h6) with no sampling. Compared with the optimal case (offline), CAFTL identifies up to 86.2% of the duplicate writes in offline. We also can see that with a larger sampling unit (128KB), CAFTL achieves a lower but reasonable deduplication rate. In Section 4.4.1, we will give more detailed analysis on the effect of sampling unit sizes. Besides directly removing duplicate writes to the flash memory, CAFTL also reduces the amount of occupied flash memory space and increases the number of available clean erase blocks for garbage collection and wearleveling. <ref type="figure">Figure 9</ref> shows the percentage of extended flash space in units of erase blocks, compared to the baseline case (without CAFTL). We show CAFTL without sampling (no-sampling) and with sampling (128KB).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.2">Extending flash space</head><p>As shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 9</ref>, CAFTL can save up to 31.2% (h1) of the occupied flash blocks for the 11 workloads. The worst cases are h2 and h5, in which no space saving is observed. This is because the two workloads are relatively smaller, the total number of occupied erase blocks is only 176. Although the number of pages being written is reduced by 16.6% (h2) and 15% (h5), the saved space in units of erase blocks is very small.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Performance Impact</head><p>To make CAFTL truly effective in practice, we must retain high performance and minimize negative impact. Here we study three key factors affecting performance, cache size, hashing speed, and fingerprint searching. The acceleration methods are not applied in experiments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.1">Cache size</head><p>In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 10</ref>, we show the percentage of the increase of average read/write latencies with various cache sizes (2MB to 16MB). We compare CAFTL with the baseline case (without CAFTL). In the experiments, we configure an SSD with a 934MHz processor. We can see that with a small cache space (2MB), the read and write latencies can increase by a factor of up to 34% (t1). With a moderate cache size (8MB), the latency increases are reduced to less than 4.5%. With a 16MB cache, a rather standard size, the latency increases become negligible (less than 0.5%). For some workloads (d2, h3, h5, h7, t1, t2), we can even see a slight performance improvement (0.2-0.5%), because CAFTL removes unnecessary writes, which reduces the probability of being blocked by an in-progress flash write operation. In this case we see a negative performance impact with a small cache space, and we will show how to mitigate such a problem through our acceleration methods in Section 4.4.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.2">Hashing speed</head><p>Computing fingerprints is time consuming and affects access performance. The hashing speed depends on the capability of processors. Using a more powerful processor can effectively reduce the latency for digesting pages and generating fingerprints. To study the performance impact caused by hashing speed, we vary the processor frequency from 304MHz to 934MHz, based on the Cortex datasheet <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[8]</ref>. We configure an SSD with a 16MB cache space and show the increase of read latencies compared to the baseline case (without CAFTL) in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 11</ref>. We did not observe an increase of write latencies, since most writes are absorbed in the buffer. In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 11</ref>, we can see that most workloads are insensitive to hashing speed. With a 304MHz processor, the performance overhead is less than 8.5% (t2), which has more intensive larger writes. At 934MHz, the performance overhead is merely observable (up to 0.5%). There are two reasons. First, the 16MB on-device buffer absorbs most incoming writes and provides a sufficient space for accommodating incoming reads. Second, the incoming read requests are given a higher priority than writes, which reduces noticeable delays in the critical path. These optimizations make reads insensitive to hashing speed and reduces noticeable latencies. Also note that if a dedicated hashing engine is used on the device, the hashing latency could be further reduced. We have proposed three techniques to accelerate fingerprint searching. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 12</ref> shows the percentage of reduced fingerprint comparisons compared with the baseline case. We configure the fingerprint store with 256 segments to hold the fingerprints for each workload. We can see that using Range Check can effectively reduce the comparisons of fingerprints by up to 23.7% (t2). However, Hotness-based Reorganization can provide little further improvement (less than 1%), because it essentially accelerates lookups for fingerprints that are duplicated, which is relatively an uncommon case. As expected, Bucket-level Binary Search can significantly reduce the average number of comparisons for each lookup. In d2, for example, Bucket-level Binary Search can effectively reduce the average number of comparisons by a factor of 85.5%. Thus we would suggest applying Bucket-level Binary Search and Range Check to speed up fingerprint lookups.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.3">Fingerprint searching</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Acceleration Methods</head><p>With a small on-device buffer, the high computational latency caused by hashing could be significant and perceived by the users. We have developed three techniques to accelerate fingerprinting. In this section, we will show the effectiveness of each individual technique and then show the effects in aggregate. We configure an SSD with a 934MHz processor and a small 2MB buffer.  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 13</ref> and <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 14</ref>, sampling can significantly improve performance. With the increase of sampling unit size, fewer fingerprints need to be calculated, which translates into a manifold reduction of observed read and write latencies. For example, h7 achieves a speedup by a factor of 94.1 times for reads and 3.5 times for writes, because of the significantly reduced waiting time for the buffer. Meanwhile, the deduplication rate is only reduced from 18% to 15.4%. Considering such a significant speedup, the minor loss of deduplication rate is acceptable. The maximum speedup, 110.6 times (read), is observed in t1, and its deduplication rate drops from 4.6% to 1.3%. This is mostly because for workloads with low duplication rate, the probability of sampling right pages is also relatively low.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4.1">Sampling</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4.2">Light-weight pre-hashing</head><p>Light-weight pre-hashing uses a fast CRC32 hash function to filter most unlikely-to-be-duplicated pages before performing high-cost fingerprinting. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 15</ref> shows the speedup of reads and writes by using CRC32 for prehashing, compared with CAFTL without pre-hashing. Only pre-hashing is enabled here. We can see that in the best case (t1), pre-hashing can reduce the latencies by a factor of up to 148.3 times for reads and 3.9 times for writes. This is because, as mentioned previously, this workload is write intensive and has a long waiting queue, which makes the queuing effect particularly significant. Similar to sampling, writes receive relatively smaller benefit, because the buffer absorbs the writes with low latency and diminishes the effect of speeding up writes. Meanwhile, we also found negligible difference in deduplication rates, which is consistent with our analysis shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref>. CAFTL also provides dynamic switch to dynamically turn on/off the in-line deduplication, depending on the usage of the on-device buffer. We configure the high watermark as 95% (off) and the low watermark as 50% (on). <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 16</ref> shows the speedup of reads and writes in the workloads. Again, t1 receives the most significant performance speedup by a factor of 200.6 times. Some workloads (h1-h5) receive no benefits, because they are less I/O intensive. For the other workloads, we can observe a speedup of 2.1 times to 94.6 times.  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 17</ref>, we enable all the three acceleration techniques and show the increase of read and write latencies, compared with the baseline case (without CAFTL), and the corresponding deduplication rate. We can see that by combining all the three techniques, we can almost completely remove the performance overhead with only a 2MB on-device buffer. In the meantime, we can achieve a deduplication rate of up to 19.9%.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4.3">Dynamic switch</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4.4">Putting it all together</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Other Related Work</head><p>Flash memory based SSDs have received a lot of interest in both academia and industry. There is a large body of research work on flash memory and SSDs (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[6,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">9,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">13,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[15]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[16]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[17]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[18]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">20,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">23,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[26]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[27]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[28]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[29]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">31,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">34,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">37,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">38,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">42,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">44]</ref> ). Concerning lifespan issues, most early work focuses on designing garbage collection and wear-leveling policies. A survey <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[21]</ref> summarizes these techniques. Here we only present the papers most related to this work.</p><p>Recently Grupp et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[22]</ref> have presented an empirical study on the performance, power, and reliability of flash memories. Their results show that flash memories, particularly MLC devices, exhibit significant error rates after or even before reaching the rated lifetime, which makes using high density SSDs in commercial systems a difficult choice. Another report <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[13]</ref> has studied the write endurance of USB flash drives with a more optimistic conclusion that the endurance of flash memory chips is better than expected, but whole-device endurance is closely related to the FTL designs. A modeling based study on the endurance issues has also been presented in <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[33]</ref>. These studies provide much needed information about the lifespan of flash memory and small-size flash devices. However, so far the endurance of state-of-theart SSDs has not yet been proven in the field <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[10]</ref>.</p><p>Early studies on SSDs mainly focus on performance. Some recent studies have begun to look at reliability issues. Differential RAID <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[9]</ref> tries to improve reliability of an SSD-based RAID storage by distributing parity unevenly across SSDs to reduce the probability of correlated multi-device failure. Griffin <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[42]</ref> extends SSD lifetime by maintaining a log-structured HDD cache and migrating cached data periodically. A recent work <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[36]</ref> considers write cycles in addition to storage space as a constrained resource in depletable storage systems and suggests attribute depletion to users in systems like cloud computing. ChunkStash <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[19]</ref> uses flash memory to speed up index lookups for inline storage deduplication. Another work <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[43]</ref> proposes to integrate phase change memory into SSDs to improve the performance, energy consumption, and also lifetime. Our study has made its unique contributions to enhancing the lifespan of SSDs by removing duplicate writes and coalescing redundant data at the device level, as a more general solution.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion and Discussions</head><p>Enhancing the SSD lifespan is crucial to a wide deployment of SSDs in commercial systems. In this paper, we have proposed a solution, called CAFTL, and shown that by removing duplicate writes and coalescing redundant data, we can effectively enhance the lifespan of SSDs while retaining high data access performance.</p><p>A potential concern about CAFTL is the volatility of the on-device RAM buffer -the buffered data could be lost upon power failure. However, this concern is not new to SSDs. A hard disk drive also has an on-device buffer, but it provides users an option (e.g. using sdparm tool) to flexibly enable/disable the buffer on their needs. Similarly, if needed, the users can choose to disable the in-line deduplication and the buffer in an SSD, and the out-of-line deduplication can still be effective.</p><p>Although we have striven to minimize memory usage, CAFTL demands more space for storing fingerprints and the secondary mapping table, compared with traditional FTLs. According to our communications with SSD manufacturer <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>, memory actually only accounts for a small percentage of the total production cost, and the most expensive component is flash memory. Thus we consider this tradeoff is worthwhile to extend available flash space, and SSD lifespan. If budget allows, we would suggest maintaining the fingerprint store fully in memory, which not only improves deduplication rate but also simplifies designs.</p><p>Further improvements are also possible. One is to relax the stringent "one-time programming" requirement. According to the specification, each flash page in a clean erase block should be programmed (written) only once. In practice, flash chips can allow multiple programs to a page and the risk of "program disturb" is fairly low <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[7]</ref>. We can leverage this feature to simplify many designs. For example, we can write multiple versions of LBA/VBA and fingerprints into the spare area of a physical page, which can largely remove the need for metadata pages. Another consideration is to integrate a byteaddressable persistent memory (e.g. PCM) into the SSDs to maintain the metadata, which can remove much design complexity. We are also considering the addition of on-line compression into SSDs to better utilize the highspeed processor on the device. This can further extend available flash space but may require more changes to the FTL design, which will be our future work.</p><p>As SSD technology becomes increasingly mature and delivers satisfactory performance, we believe, the endurance issue of SSDs, particularly high-density MLC SSDs, opens many new research opportunities and should receive more attention from researchers.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: The percentage of redundant data in disks. To make a case here, we have studied 15 disks installed on 5 machines in the Department of Computer Science and Engineering at the Ohio State University. Three file systems can be found in these disks, namely Ext2, Ext3, and NTFS. The disks are used in different environments, 4 disks from Database/Web Servers, 7 disks from Experimental Systems for kernel development, and the other 4 disks from Office Systems. We slice the disk space into 4KB blocks and use the SHA-1 hash function [1] to calculate a 160-bit hash value for each block. We can identify duplicate blocks by comparing the hash</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>d2 h1 h2 h3 h4 h5 h6 h7 t1 t2 Percentage of Duplicate Writes (%) d − desktop; h − hadoop; t − transaction</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: The perc. of duplicate writes in workloads. Besides the static analysis of the data redundancy in storage, we have also collected I/O traces and analyzed the data accesses of 11 workloads from three categories (see more details in Section 4). For each workload, we modified the Linux kernel by intercepting each I/O request and calculating a hash value for each requested block. We analyzed the I/O traces off-line. Figure 2 shows the percentage of the duplicate writes in each workload. We can find that 5.8-28.1% of the writes are duplicated. This finding suggests that if we remove these duplicate writes, we can effectively reduce the write traffic into flash medium, which directly improves the endurance accordingly, not to mention the indirect effect of reducing the number of extra writes caused by less frequently triggered garbage collections.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: An illustration of CAFTL architecture.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: The CDF figure of duplicate fingerprints. In order to locate quickly the physical page with a specific fingerprint, CAFTL manages an in-memory structure, called Fingerprint Store. Apparently, keeping all fingerprints and related information (25 bytes each) in memory is too costly and unnecessary. We have studied the distribution of fingerprints in the 15 disks and we plot a Cumulative Distribution Function (CDF) figure in Figure 4. We can see that the distribution of duplicated fingerprints is skewed -only 10-20% of the fingerprints are highly duplicated (more than 2). This finding provides two implications. First, most fingerprints are unique and never have a chance to match any queried</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5: An illustration of the indirect mapping. We have designed a new indirect mapping mechanism to address these aforementioned issues. As shown in Figure 5, a conventional FTL uses a one-level indirect mapping, from LBAs to PBAs. In CAFTL, we create another indirect mapping level, called Virtual Block Addresses (VBAs). A VBA is essentially a pseudo address name to represent a set of LBAs mapped to the same PBA. In this two-level indirect mapping structure, we can locate the physical page for a logical page either through LBA→PBA or LBA→VBA→PBA. We maintain a primary mapping table and a secondary mapping table in memory. The primary mapping table maps a LBA to either a PBA, if the logical page is unique, or a VBA, if it is a duplicate page. We differentiate PBAs and VBAs by using the most significant bit in the 32-bit page address. For a page size of 4KB, using the remaining 31 bits can address 8,192 GB storage space, which is sufficiently large for an SSD. The secondary mapping table maps a VBA to a PBA. Each entry is indexed by the VBA and has two fields, {PBA, reference}. The 32-bit PBA denotes the physical flash page, and the 32-bit reference tracks the exact number of logical pages mapped to the physical page. Only physical pages without any reference can be recycled for garbage collection. This two-level indirect mapping mechanism has several merits. First, it significantly simplifies the reverse updates to the mapping of duplicate logical pages. When relocating a physical page during GC, we can use its associated VBA to quickly locate and update the secondary mapping table by mapping the VBA to the new location (PBA), which avoids exhaustively searching for all the referencing LBAs in the huge primary mapping table. Second, the secondary mapping table can be very small. Since CAFTL handles regular file system workloads, most logical pages are unique and directly mapped through the primary table. We can also apply an approach similar to DFTL [23] to further reduce the memory demand by selectively maintaining the most frequently accessed entries of the mapping tables in memory. Finally, this incurs minimal additional lookup</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Figure 6: An illustration of four choices of sample bytes.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>d2 h1 h2 h3 h4 h5 h6 h7 t1 t2 Perc. of Removed Writes (%) d − desktop; h − hadoop; t − transaction offline no−sampling 128KB</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Figure 8 :</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Figure 8: Perc. of removed duplicate writes.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 9: Perc. of extended flash space. Besides directly removing duplicate writes to the flash memory, CAFTL also reduces the amount of occupied flash memory space and increases the number of available clean erase blocks for garbage collection and wearleveling. Figure 9 shows the percentage of extended flash space in units of erase blocks, compared to the baseline case (without CAFTL). We show CAFTL without sampling (no-sampling) and with sampling (128KB). As shown in Figure 9, CAFTL can save up to 31.2% (h1) of the occupied flash blocks for the 11 workloads. The worst cases are h2 and h5, in which no space saving is observed. This is because the two workloads are relatively smaller, the total number of occupied erase blocks is only 176. Although the number of pages being written is reduced by 16.6% (h2) and 15% (h5), the saved space in units of erase blocks is very small.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head>Figure 11 :</head><label>11</label><figDesc>Figure 11: Perf. impact of hashing Speeds.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head>Figure 10 :</head><label>10</label><figDesc>Figure 10: Performance impact of cache sizes (2-16MB). note that if a dedicated hashing engine is used on the device, the hashing latency could be further reduced.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 12: Optimizations on fingerprint searching. We have proposed three techniques to accelerate fingerprint searching. Figure 12 shows the percentage of reduced fingerprint comparisons compared with the baseline case. We configure the fingerprint store with 256 segments to hold the fingerprints for each workload. We can see that using Range Check can effectively reduce the comparisons of fingerprints by up to 23.7% (t2). However, Hotness-based Reorganization can provide little further improvement (less than 1%), because it essentially accelerates lookups for fingerprints that are duplicated, which is relatively an uncommon case. As expected, Bucket-level Binary Search can significantly reduce the average number of comparisons for each lookup. In d2, for example, Bucket-level Binary Search can effectively reduce the average number of comparisons by a factor of 85.5%. Thus we would suggest applying Bucket-level Binary Search and Range Check to speed up fingerprint lookups.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_14"><head>Figure 14 :</head><label>14</label><figDesc>Figure 14: Dedup. with Sampling As shown in Figure 13 and Figure 14, sampling can significantly improve performance. With the increase of sampling unit size, fewer fingerprints need to be calculated, which translates into a manifold reduction of observed read and write latencies. For example, h7 achieves a speedup by a factor of 94.1 times for reads and 3.5 times for writes, because of the significantly reduced waiting time for the buffer. Meanwhile, the deduplication rate is only reduced from 18% to 15.4%. Considering such a significant speedup, the minor loss of deduplication rate is acceptable. The maximum speedup, 110.6 times (read), is observed in t1, and its deduplication rate drops from 4.6% to 1.3%. This is mostly because for workloads with low duplication rate, the probability of sampling right pages is also relatively low.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_15"><head>Figure 13 :</head><label>13</label><figDesc>Figure 13: Performance speedup with Sampling (unit size: 8-128KB).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_16"><head>Figure 16 :</head><label>16</label><figDesc>Figure 16: Speedup with dynamic switch. CAFTL also provides dynamic switch to dynamically turn on/off the in-line deduplication, depending on the usage of the on-device buffer. We configure the high watermark as 95% (off) and the low watermark as 50% (on). Figure 16 shows the speedup of reads and writes in the workloads. Again, t1 receives the most significant performance speedup by a factor of 200.6 times. Some</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_17"><head>Figure 17 :</head><label>17</label><figDesc>Figure 17: Three acceleration tech. combined In Figure 17, we enable all the three acceleration techniques and show the increase of read and write latencies, compared with the baseline case (without CAFTL), and the corresponding deduplication rate. We can see that by combining all the three techniques, we can almost completely remove the performance overhead with only a 2MB on-device buffer. In the meantime, we can achieve a deduplication rate of up to 19.9%.</figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We are grateful to our shepherd Dr. Christos Karamanolis from VMware ® and the anonymous reviewers for their constructive comments. We also thank our colleague Bill Bynum for reading this paper and his suggestions. This research was partially supported by the NSF under grants CCF-0620152, CCF-072380, and CCF-0913150.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">FIPS 180-1, Secure Hash Standard</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995-04" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Hadoop</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://hadoop.apache.org/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Personal communications with an SSD architect</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Design tradeoffs for SSD performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Agrawal</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Prabhakaran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Wobber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Davis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manasse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Panigrahy</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of USENIX&apos;08</title>
		<meeting>USENIX&apos;08<address><addrLine>Boston, MA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rethinking flash in the data center</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andersen</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Swanson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IEEE Micro</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010-08" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Arm</forename><surname>Cortex</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.arm.com/products/processors/cortex-r/cortex-r4.php" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Differential RAID: Rethinking RAID for SSD Reliability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Balakrishnan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kadav</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Prabhakaran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Malkhi</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EuroSys&apos;10</title>
		<meeting>EuroSys&apos;10<address><addrLine>Paris, France</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010-04" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Warehouse-scale computing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Barroso</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Keynote in the SIGMOD&apos;10 conference</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Indianapolis, IN</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extreme binning: Scalable, parallel deduplication for chunk-based file backup</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bhagwat</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Eshghi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Long</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">D E</forename><surname>And Lillib-Ridge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of MASCOTS&apos;09</title>
		<meeting>MASCOTS&apos;09<address><addrLine>London, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009-09" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Space/time trade-offs in hash coding with allowable errors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Bloom</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Communications of the ACM (1970)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="422" to="426" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Write endurance in flash drives: Measurements and analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Boboila</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Desnoyers</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of FAST&apos;10</title>
		<meeting>FAST&apos;10<address><addrLine>San Jose, CA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bucy</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Schindler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Schlosser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ganger</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.pdl.cmu.edu/DiskSim" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>DiskSim 4.0.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Turning flash drive into a disk energy saver for mobile computers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chen</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhang</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Smartsaver</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ISLPED&apos;06</title>
		<meeting>ISLPED&apos;06<address><addrLine>Tegernsee, Germany</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006-10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding intrinsic characteristics and system implications of flash memory based solid state drives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chen</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Koufaty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhang</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of SIGMET-RICS/Performance&apos;09</title>
		<meeting>SIGMET-RICS/Performance&apos;09<address><addrLine>Seattle, WA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Essential roles of exploiting internal parallelism of flash memory based solid state drives in high-speed data processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chen</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhang</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of HPCA&apos;11</title>
		<meeting>HPCA&apos;11<address><addrLine>San Antonio, TX</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exploiting flash devices for synchronous logging performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chen</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Flashlogging</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of SIGMOD&apos;09</title>
		<meeting>SIGMOD&apos;09<address><addrLine>Providence, RI</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">ChunkStash: Speeding up inline storage deduplication using flash memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Debnath</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Sengupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of USENIX&apos;10</title>
		<meeting>USENIX&apos;10<address><addrLine>Boston, MA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The performance of PC solid-state disks (SSDs) as a function of bandwidth, concurrency, device, architecture, and system organization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dirik</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jacob</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ISCA&apos;09</title>
		<meeting>ISCA&apos;09<address><addrLine>Austin, TX</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Algorithms and data structures for flash memories</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gal</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Toledo</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACM Computing Survey&apos;05</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="138" to="163" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Characterizing flash memory: Anomalies, observations, and applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Grupp</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Caulfield</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Coburn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Swanson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Yaakobi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Siegel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wolf</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of MICRO&apos;09</title>
		<meeting>MICRO&apos;09<address><addrLine>New York, NY</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009-12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">DFTL: a flash translation layer employing demand-based selective caching of page-level address mappings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gupta</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Urgaonkar</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ASPLOS&apos;09</title>
		<meeting>ASPLOS&apos;09<address><addrLine>Washington, D.C.</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009-03" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Difference Engine: Harnessing memory redundancy in virtual machines</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gupta</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Vrable</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Savage</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Snoeren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Varghese</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Voelker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vahdat</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of OSDI&apos;08</title>
		<meeting>OSDI&apos;08<address><addrLine>San Diego, CA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Intel X25-E extreme SATA solid-state drive</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Intel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">DFS: A file system for virtualized flash storage</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Josephson</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Bongo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Flynn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of FAST&apos;10</title>
		<meeting>FAST&apos;10<address><addrLine>San Jose, CA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A flashmemory based file system</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kawaguchi</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Nishioka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Motoda</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of USENIX Winter</title>
		<meeting>USENIX Winter<address><addrLine>New Orleans, LA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995-01" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="155" to="164" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">BPLRU: A buffer management scheme for improving random writes in flash storage</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kim</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ahn</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of FAST&apos;08</title>
		<meeting>FAST&apos;08<address><addrLine>San Jose, CA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Design of flash-based DBMS: An inpage logging approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lee</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Moon</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of SIGMOD&apos;07</title>
		<meeting>SIGMOD&apos;07<address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sparse indexing: Large scale, inline deduplication using sampling and locality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lillibridge</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Eshghi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Bhagwat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Deolalikar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Trezise</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Camble</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of FAST&apos;09</title>
		<meeting>FAST&apos;09<address><addrLine>San Jose, CA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using transparent compression to improve SSD-based I/O caches</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Makatos</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Klonatos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Marazakis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Flouris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bilas</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EuroSys&apos;10</title>
		<meeting>EuroSys&apos;10<address><addrLine>Paris, France</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010-04" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Handbook of applied cryptography</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Menezes</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Oorschot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vanstone</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<publisher>CRC Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How I learned to stop worrying and love flash endurance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mohan</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Siddiqua</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Gurumurthi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stan</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of HotStorage&apos;10</title>
		<meeting>HotStorage&apos;10<address><addrLine>Boston, MA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Migrating enterprise storage to SSDs: analysis of tradeoffs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Narayanan</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Thereska</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Donnelly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Elnikety</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rowstron</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EuroSys&apos;09</title>
		<meeting>EuroSys&apos;09<address><addrLine>Nuremberg, Germany</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009-03" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Depletable storage systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prabhakaran</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Balakrishnan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Davis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wobber</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of HotStorage&apos;10</title>
		<meeting>HotStorage&apos;10<address><addrLine>Boston, MA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prabhakaran</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Rodeheffeer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhou</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Flash</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of OSDI&apos;08</title>
		<meeting>OSDI&apos;08<address><addrLine>San Diego, CA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008-12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">SieveStore: A highlyselective, ensemble-level disk cache for cost-performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pritchett</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thottethodi</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ISCA&apos;10</title>
		<meeting>ISCA&apos;10<address><addrLine>Saint-Malo, France</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Database managment systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ramakrishnan</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gehrke</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2030" />
			<publisher>McGraw-Hill</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The MD5 message-digest algorithm</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rivest</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The design and implementation of a log-structured file system</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rosenblum</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ousterhout</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACM Transactions on Computer Systems (1992)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="26" to="52" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extending SSD lifetimes with disk-based write caches</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Soundararajan</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Prabhakaran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Balakrishnan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wobber</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of FAST&apos;10</title>
		<meeting>FAST&apos;10<address><addrLine>San Jose, CA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A hybrid solid-state storage architecture for the performance, energy consumption, and lifetime improvement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sun</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Joo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Niu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Xie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of HPCA&apos;10</title>
		<meeting>HPCA&apos;10<address><addrLine>Bangalore, India</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010-01" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Query processing techniques for solid state drives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tsirogiannis</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Harizopoulos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shah</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of SIGMOD&apos;09</title>
		<meeting>SIGMOD&apos;09<address><addrLine>Providence, RI</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">HydraFS: A high-throughput file system for the HYDRAstor content-addressable storage system</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ungureanu</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Atkin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Aranya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gokhale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Rago</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Calkowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Dubnicki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bohra</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of FAST&apos;10</title>
		<meeting>FAST&apos;10<address><addrLine>San Jose, CA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Avoiding the disk bottleneck in the data domain deduplication file system</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhu</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patterson</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of FAST&apos;08</title>
		<meeting>FAST&apos;08<address><addrLine>San Jose, CA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
