<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/atharsefid/Desktop/grobid-0.5.3/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.3" ident="GROBID" when="2020-09-29T01:56+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">FATE and DESTINI: A Framework for Cloud Recovery Testing</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haryadi</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Gunawi</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thanh</forename><surname>Do</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Wisconsin</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Madison * Facebook</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pallavi</forename><surname>Joshi</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Alvaro</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joseph</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hellerstein</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrea</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Arpaci-Dusseau</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Wisconsin</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Madison * Facebook</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Remzi</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Arpaci-Dusseau</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Koushik</forename><surname>Sen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Wisconsin</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Madison * Facebook</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dhruba</forename><surname>Borthakur</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berkeley</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">FATE and DESTINI: A Framework for Cloud Recovery Testing</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>As the cloud era begins and failures become commonplace , failure recovery becomes a critical factor in the availability, reliability and performance of cloud services. Unfortunately, recovery problems still take place, causing downtimes, data loss, and many other problems. We propose a new testing framework for cloud recovery: FATE (Failure Testing Service) and DESTINI (Declara-tive Testing Specifications). With FATE, recovery is systematically tested in the face of multiple failures. With DESTINI, correct recovery is specified clearly, concisely, and precisely. We have integrated our framework to several cloud systems (e.g., HDFS [33]), explored over 40,000 failure scenarios, wrote 74 specifications, found 16 new bugs, and reproduced 51 old bugs.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Large-scale computing and data storage systems, including clusters within Google <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref>, Amazon EC2 <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>, and elsewhere, are becoming a dominant platform for an increasing variety of applications and services. These "cloud" systems comprise thousands of commodity machines (to take advantage of economies of scale <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16]</ref>) and thus require sophisticated and often complex distributed software to mask the (perhaps increasingly) poor reliability of commodity PCs, disks, and memories <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">9,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">17,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">18]</ref>.</p><p>A critical factor in the availability, reliability, and performance of cloud services is thus how they react to failure. Unfortunately, failure recovery has proven to be challenging in these systems. For example, in 2009, a large telecommunications provider reported a serious data-loss incident <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[27]</ref>, and a similar incident occurred within a popular social-networking site <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[29]</ref>. Bug repositories of open-source cloud software hint at similar recovery problems <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>.</p><p>Practitioners continue to bemoan their inability to adequately address these recovery problems. For example, engineers at Google consider the current state of recovery testing to be behind the times <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref>, while others believe that large-scale recovery remains underspecified <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. These deficiencies leave us with an important question: How can we test the correctness of cloud systems in how they deal with the wide variety of possible failure modes?</p><p>To address this question, we present two advancements in the current state-of-the-art of testing. First, we introduce FATE (Failure Testing Service). Unlike existing frameworks where multiple failures are only exercised randomly <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">35,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">38]</ref>, FATE is designed to systematically push cloud systems into many possible failure scenarios. FATE achieves this by employing failure IDs as a new abstraction for exploring failures. Using failure IDs, FATE has exercised over 40,000 unique failure scenarios, and uncovers a new challenge: the exponential explosion of multiple failures. To the best of our knowledge, we are the first to address this in a more systematic way than random approaches. We do so by introducing novel prioritization strategies that explore non-similar failure scenarios first. This approach allows developers to explore distinct recovery behaviors an order of magnitude faster compared to a brute-force approach.</p><p>Second, we introduce DESTINI (Declarative Testing Specifications), which addresses the second half of the challenge in recovery testing: specification of expected behavior, to support proper testing of the recovery code that is exercised by FATE. With existing approaches, specifications are cumbersome and difficult to write, and thus present a barrier to usage in practice <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">25,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">32,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">39]</ref>. To address this, DESTINI employs a relational logic language that enables developers to write clear, concise, and precise recovery specifications; we have written 74 checks, each of which is typically about 5 lines of code. In addition, we present several design patterns to help developers specify recovery. For example, developers can easily capture facts and build expectations, write specifications from different views (e.g., global, client, data servers) and thus catch bugs closer to the source, express different types of violations (e.g., data-loss, availability), and incorporate different types of failures (e.g., crashes, network partitions).</p><p>The rest of the paper is organized as follows. First, we dissect recovery problems in more detail ( §2). Next, we define our concrete goals ( §3), and present the design and implementation of FATE ( §4) and DESTINI ( §5). We then close with evaluations ( §6) and conclusion ( §7).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Lens #2: Study of Bug/Issue Reports</head><p>These anecdotes hint at the importance and complexity of failure handling, but offer few specifics on how to address the problem. Fortunately, many open-source cloud projects (e.g., <ref type="bibr">ZooKeeper [19]</ref>, Cassandra <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[23]</ref>, HDFS <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[33]</ref>) publicly share in great detail real issues encountered in the field. Therefore, we performed an indepth study of HDFS bug/issue reports <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. There are more than 1300 issues spanning 4 years of operation <ref type="bibr">(April 2006</ref> to July 2010). We scan all issues and study the ones that pertain to recovery problems due to hardware failures. In total, there are 91 recovery issues with severe implications such as data loss, unavailability, corruption, and reduced performance (a more detailed description can be found in our technical report <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref>).</p><p>Based on this study, we made several observations. First, most of the internal protocols already anticipate failures. However, they do not cover all possible failures, and thus exhibit problems in practice. Second, the number of reported issues due to multiple failures is still small. In this regard, excluding our 5 submissions, the developers only had reported 3 issues, which mostly arose in live deployments rather than systematic testing. Finally, recovery issues appeared not only in the early years of the development but also recently, suggesting the lack of adoptable tools that can exercise failures automatically. Reports from other cloud systems such as Cassandra and ZooKeeper also raise similar issues.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Lens #3: Write Recovery Protocol</head><p>Given so many recovery issues, one might wonder what the inherent complexities are. To answer this, we dissect the anatomy of HDFS write recovery. As a background, HDFS provides two write interfaces: write and append. There is no overwrite. The write protocol essentially looks simple, but when different failures come into the picture, recovery complexity becomes evident. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig- ure 1</ref> shows the write recovery protocol with three different failure scenarios. Throughout the paper, we will use HDFS terminology (blocks, datanodes/nodes, and namenode) <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[33]</ref> instead of GoogleFS terminology (chunks, chunk servers, and master) <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref>.</p><p>• Data-Transfer Recovery: <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1a</ref> shows a client contacting the namenode to get a list of datanodes to store three replicas of a block (s0). The client then initiates the setup stage by creating a pipeline (s1) and continues with the data transfer stage (s2). However, during the transfer stage, the third node crashes (s2a). What <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1a</ref> shows is the correct behavior of data-transfer recovery. That is, the client recreates the pipeline by excluding the dead node and continues transferring the bytes from the last good offset (s2b); a background replication monitor will regenerate the third replica.</p><p>• Data-Transfer Recovery Bug: <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1b</ref> shows a bug in the data-transfer recovery protocol; there is one specific code segment that performs a bad error handling of failed data transfer (s2a). This bug makes the client wrongly exclude the good node (Node2) and include the dead node (Node3) in the next pipeline creation (s2b). Since Node3 is dead, the client recreates the pipeline only with the first node (s2c). If the first node also crashes at this point (a multiple-failure scenario), no valid blocks are stored. This implementation bug reduces availability (i.e., due to unmasked failures). We also found data-loss bugs in the append protocol due to multiple failures ( §6.2.1).</p><p>• Setup-Stage Recovery: Finally, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1c</ref> shows how the setup-stage recovery is different than the datatransfer recovery. Here, the client first creates a pipeline N , C , R1/2 , and numeric letters represent the namenode, client, rack number, and datanodes respectively. The client always starts the activity to the namenode first before to the datanodes. from two nodes in Rack1 and one in Rack2 (s0a). However, due to the rack partitioning (s1), the client asks the namenode again for a new fresh pipeline (s0b); the client has not transferred any bytes, and thus could start streaming from the beginning. After asking the namenode in several retries (not shown), the pipeline contains only nodes in Rack1 (s0b). At the end, all replicas only reside in one rack, which is correct because only one rack is reachable during write <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[33]</ref>.</p><p>• Replication Monitor Bug: Although the previous case is correct, it reveals a crucial design bug in the background replication monitor. This monitor unfortunately only checks the number of replicas but not the locations. Thus, even after the partitioning is lifted, the replicas are not migrated to multiple racks. This design bug greatly reduces the block availability if Rack1 is completely unreachable (more in §5.2.3).</p><p>To sum up, we have illustrated the complexity of recovery by showing how different failure scenarios lead to different recovery behaviors. There are more problems within this protocol and other protocols. Without an appropriate testing framework, it is hard to ensure recovery correctness; in one discussion of a newly proposed recovery design, a developer raised a comment: "I don't see any proof of correctness. How do we know this will not lead to the same or other problems? <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>"</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Current State of the Art: Does It Help?</head><p>In the last three sections, we presented our motivation for powerful testing frameworks for cloud systems. A natural question to ask is whether existing frameworks can help. We answer this question in two parts: failure exploration and system specifications.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4.1">Failure Exploration</head><p>Developers are accustomed to easy-to-use unit-testing frameworks. For fault-injection purposes, unit tests are severely limited; a unit test often simulates a limited number of failure scenarios, and when it comes to injecting multiple variety of failures, one common practice is to inject a sequence of random failures as part of the unit test <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">35]</ref>.</p><p>To improve common practices, recent work has proposed more exhaustive fault-injection frameworks. For example, the authors of AFEX and LFI observe that the number of possible failure scenarios is "infinite" <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">28]</ref>. Thus, AFEX and LFI automatically prioritize "highimpact targets" (e.g., unchecked system calls, tests likely to fail). So far, they target non-distributed systems and do not address multiple failures in detail.</p><p>Recent system model-checkers have also proposed the addition of failures as part of the state exploration strategies <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[21,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">37,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">38,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">39]</ref>. MODIST, for example, is capable of exercising different combinations of failures (e.g., crashes, network failures) <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[38]</ref>. As we discuss later, exploring multiple failures creates a combinatorial explosion problem. This problem has not been addressed by the MODIST authors, and thus they provide a random mode for exploring multiple failures. Overall, we found no work that attempts to systematically explore multiple-failure scenarios, something that cloud systems face more often than other distributed systems in the past <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">9,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">17,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">18]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4.2">System Specifications</head><p>Failure injection addresses only half of the challenge in recovery testing: exercising recovery code. In addition, proper tests require specifications of expected behavior from those code paths. In the absence of such specifications, the only behaviors that can be automatically detected are those that interrupt testing (e.g. system failures). One easy way is to write extra checks as part of a unit test. Developers often take this approach, but the problem is there are many specifications to write, and if they are written in imperative languages (e.g., Java) the code is bloated.</p><p>Some model checkers use existing consistency checks such as fsck <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[39]</ref>, a powerful tool that contains hundreds of consistency checks. However, it has some drawbacks. First, fsck is only powerful if the system is mature enough; developers add more checks across years of development. Second, fsck is also often written in imperative languages, and thus its implementations are complex and unsurprisingly buggy <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref>. Finally, fsck can express only "invariant-like" specifications (i.e., it only checks the state of the file system, but not the events that lead to the state). As we will see later, specifying recovery requires "behavioral" specifications.</p><p>Another advanced checking approach is WiDS <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[24,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">25,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">38]</ref>. As the target system runs, WiDS interposes and checks the system's internal states. However, it employs a scripting language that still requires a check to be written in tens of lines of code <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[24,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">25]</ref>. Furthermore, its interposition mechanism might introduce another issue: the checks are built by interposing specific implementation functions, and if these functions evolve, the checks must be modified. The authors have acknowledged but not addressed this issue <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[24]</ref>.</p><p>Frameworks for declarative specifications exist (e.g., Pip <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[32]</ref>, P2 Monitor <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">[34]</ref>). P2 Monitor only works if the target system is written in the same language <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">[34]</ref>. Pip facilitates declarative checks, but a check is still written in over 40 lines on average <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[32]</ref>. Also, these systems are not integrated with a failure service, and thus cannot thoroughly test recovery.</p><p>Overall, most existing work use approaches that could result in big implementations of the specifications. Managing hundreds of them becomes complicated, and they must also evolve as the system evolves. In practice, developers are reluctant to invest in writing detailed specifications <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>, and hence the number of written specifications is typically small.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Goals</head><p>To address the aforementioned challenges, we present a new testing framework for cloud systems: FATE and DESTINI. We first present our concrete goals here.</p><p>• Target systems and users: We primarily target cloud systems as they experience a wide variety of failures at a higher rate than any other systems in the past <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref>. However, our framework is generic and applies to other distributed systems. Our targets so far are HDFS <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[33]</ref>, <ref type="bibr">ZooKeeper [19]</ref> and Cassandra <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[23]</ref>. We mainly use HDFS as our example in the paper. In terms of users, we target experienced system developers, with the goal of improving their ability to efficiently generate tests and specifications.</p><p>• Seamless integration: Our approach requires source code availability. However, for adoptability, our framework should not modify the code base significantly. This is accomplished by leveraging mature interposition technology (e.g., AspectJ). Currently our framework can be integrated to any distributed systems written in Java.</p><p>• Rapid and systematic exploration of failures: Our framework should help cloud system developers explore multiple-failure scenarios automatically and more systematically than random approaches. However, a complete systematic exploration brings a new challenge: a massive combinatorial explosion of failures, which takes tens of hours to explore. Thus, our testing framework must also be equipped with smart exploration strategies (e.g., prioritizing non-similar failure scenarios first).</p><p>• Numerous detailed recovery specifications: Ideally, developers should be able to write as many detailed specifications as possible. The more specifications written, the finer bug reports produced, the less time needed for debugging. To realize this, our framework must meet two requirements. First, the specifications must be developerfriendly (i.e., concise, fast to write, yet easy to understand). Otherwise, developers will be reluctant to invest in writing specifications. Second, our framework must facilitate "behavioral" specifications. We note that existing work often focuses on "invariant-like" specifications. This is not adequate because recovery behaves differently under different failure scenarios, and while recovery is still ongoing, the system is likely to go through transient states where some invariants are not satisfied.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">FATE: Failure Testing Service</head><p>Within a distributed execution, there are many points in place and time where system components could fail. Thus, our goal is to exercise failures more methodically than random approaches. To achieve this, we present three contributions: a failure abstraction for expressing failure scenarios ( §4.1), a ready-to-use failure service which can be integrated seamlessly to cloud systems ( §4.2), and novel failure prioritization strategies that speed up testing time by an order of magnitude ( §4.3).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Failure IDs: Abstraction For Failures</head><p>FATE's ultimate goal is to exercise as many combinations of failures as possible. In a sense, this is similar to model checking which explores different sequences of states.</p><p>One key technique employed in system model checkers is to record the hashes of the explored states. Similarly in our case, we introduce the concept of failure IDs, an abstraction for failure scenarios which can be hashed and recorded in history. A failure ID is composed of an I/O ID and the injected failure <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">(Table 1)</ref>. Below we describe these subcomponents in more detail.</p><p>• I/O points: To construct a failure ID, we choose I/O points (i.e., system/library calls that perform disk or network I/Os) as failure points, mainly for three reasons. First, hardware failures manifest into failed I/Os. Second, from the perspective of a node in distributed systems, I/O points are critical points that either change its internal states or make a change to its outside world (e.g., disks, other nodes). Finally, I/O points are basic operations in distributed systems, and hence an abstraction built on these points can be used for broader purposes.</p><p>• Static and dynamic information: For each I/O point, an I/O ID is generated from the static (e.g., system call, source file) and dynamic information (e.g., stack trace, node ID) available at the point. Dynamic information  is useful to increase failure coverage. For example, recovery might behave differently if a failure happens in different nodes (e.g., first vs. last node in the pipeline).</p><p>• Domain-specific information: To increase failure coverage further, an I/O ID carries domain-specific information; a common I/O point could write to different file types or send messages to different nodes. FATE's interposition mechanism provides runtime information available at an I/O point such as the target I/O (e.g., file names, IP addresses) and the I/O buffer (e.g., network packet, file buffer). To convert these raw information into a more meaningful context (e.g., "Setup Ack" in Table 1), FATE provides an interface that developers can implement. For example, given an I/O buffer of a network message, a developer can implement the code that reverse-engineers the byte content of the message into a more meaningful message type (e.g., "Setup Ack"). If the interface is empty, FATE can still run (the interface returns an empty domain-specific string), but failure coverage could be sacrificed.</p><p>• Possible failure modes: Given an I/O ID, FATE generates a list of possible failures that could happen on the I/O. For example, FATE could inject a disk failure on a disk write, or a network failure before a node sends a message. Currently, we support six failure types: crash, permanent disk failure, disk corruption, node-level and rack-level network partitioning, and transient failure. To create a failure ID, one failure type appropriate to the I/O is selected one at a time (and hence, given an I/O ID, FATE could produce multiple failure IDs).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Architecture</head><p>We built FATE with a goal of quick and seamless integration into our target systems. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> depicts the four components of FATE: workload driver, failure surface, failure server, and filters.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.1">Workload Driver, Failure Surface, and Server</head><p>We first instrument the target system (e.g., HDFS) by inserting a "failure surface". There are many possible lay- ers to insert a failure surface (e.g., inside a system library or at the VMM layer). We do this between the target system and the OS library (e.g., Java SDK), for two reasons. First, at this layer, rich domain-specific information is available. Second, by leveraging mature instrumentation technology (e.g., AspectJ), adding the surface requires no modification to the code base.</p><p>The failure surface has two important jobs. First, at each I/O point, it builds the I/O ID. Second, it needs to check if a persistent failure injected in the past affects this I/O point (e.g., network partitioning). If so, the surface returns an error to emulate the failure without the need to talk to the server. Otherwise, it sends the I/O ID to the server and receives a failure decision.</p><p>The workload driver is where the developer attaches the workload to be tested (e.g., write, append, or some sequence of operations, including the pre-and post-setups) and specifies the maximum number of failures injected per run. As the workload runs, the failure server receives I/O IDs from the failure surface, combines the I/O IDs with possible failures into failure IDs, and makes failure decisions based on the failure history. The workload driver terminates when the server does not inject a new failure scenario. The failure server, workload driver, and target system are run as separate processes, and they can be run on single or multiple machines.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.2">Brute-Force Failure Exploration</head><p>By default, FATE runs in brute-force mode. That is, FATE systematically explores all possible combinations of observed failure IDs. (The algorithm can be found in our technical report <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref>). With this brute-force mode, FATE has exercised over 40,000 unique combinations of one, two and three failure IDs. We address this combinatorial explosion challenge in the next section ( §4.3).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.3">Filters</head><p>FATE uses information carried in I/O and failure IDs to implement filters at the server side. A filter can be used to regenerate a particular failure scenario. For example, to regenerate the failure described in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 1</ref>, a developer could specify a filter that will only exercise the corresponding failure ID. A filter could also be used to reduce the failure space. For example, a developer could insert a filter that allows crash-only failures, failures only on some specific I/Os, or any failures only at datanodes. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Failure Exploration Strategy</head><p>Running FATE in brute-force mode is impractical and time consuming. As an example, we have run the append protocol with a filter that allows crash-only failures on disk I/Os in datanodes. With this filter, injecting two failures per run gives 45 failure IDs to exercise, which leads us to 1199 combinations that take more than 2 hours to run. Without the filter (i.e., including network I/Os and other types of failures) the number will further increase. This introduces the problem of exponential explosion of multiple failures, which has to be addressed given the fact that we are dealing with large code base where an experiment could take more than 5 seconds per run (e.g., due to pre-and post-setup overheads). Among the 1199 experiments, 116 failed; if recovery is perfect, all experiments should be successful. Debugging all of them led us to 3 bugs as the root causes. Now, we can concretely define the challenge: Can FATE exercise a much smaller number of combinations and find distinct bugs faster? This section provides some solutions to this challenge. To the best of our knowledge, we are the first to address this issue in the context of distributed systems. Thus, we also hope that this challenge attracts system researches to present other alternatives.</p><p>To address this challenge, we have studied the properties of multiple failures (for simplicity, we begin with two-failure scenarios). A pair of two failures can be categorized into two types: pairwise dependent and pairwise independent failures. Below, we describe each category along with the prioritization strategies. Due to space constraints, we could not show the detailed pseudo-code, and thus we only present the algorithms at a high-level. We will evaluate the algorithms in Section 6.3. We also emphasize that our proposed strategies are built on top of the information carried in failure IDs, and hence display the power of failure IDs abstraction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.1">Pairwise Dependent Failures</head><p>A pair of failure IDs is dependent if the second ID is observed only if the failure on the first ID is injected; observing the occurrence of a failure ID does not necessarily mean that the failure must be injected. The key here is to use observed I/Os to capture path coverage information (this is an acceptable assumption since we are dealing with distributed systems where recovery essentially manifests into I/Os). <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3a</ref> illustrates some combinations of dependent failure IDs. For example, F is dependent on C or D (i.e., F will never be observed unless C or D is injected). The brute-force algorithm will inefficiently exercise all six possible combinations: AE, BE, CE, DE, CF, and DF.</p><p>To prioritize dependent failure IDs, we introduce a strategy that we call recovery-behavior clustering. The goal is to prioritize "non-similar" failure scenarios first. The intuition is that non-similar failure scenarios typically lead to different recovery behaviors, and recovery behaviors can be represented as a sequence of failure IDs. Thus, to perform the clustering, we first run a complete set of experiments with only one failure per run, and in each run we record the subsequent failure IDs.</p><p>We formally define subsequent failure IDs as all observed IDs after the injected failure up to the point where the system enters the stable state. That is, recording recovery only up to the end of the protocol (e.g., write) is not enough. This is because a failed I/O could leave some "garbage" that is only cleaned up by some background protocols. For example, a failed I/O could leave a block with an old generation timestamp that should be cleaned up by the background replication monitor (outside the scope of the write protocol). Moreover, different failures could leave different types of garbage, and thus lead to different recovery behaviors of the background protocols. By capturing subsequent failure IDs until the stable state, we ensure more fine-grained clustering.</p><p>The exact definition of stable state might be different across different systems. For HDFS, our definition of stable state is: FATE reboots dead nodes if any, removes transient failures (e.g., network partitioning), sends commands to the datanodes to report their blocks to the namenode, and waits until all datanodes receive a null command (i.e., no background jobs to run).</p><p>Going back to <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3a</ref>, the created mappings between the first failures and their subsequent failure IDs are: {A→ E}, {B→ E}, {C→ E, F}, and {D→ E, F}. The recovery behaviors then are clustered into two: {E}, and {E, F}. Finally, for each recovery cluster, we pick only one failure ID on which the cluster is dependent. The final prioritized combinations are marked with bold edges in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3a</ref>. That is, FATE only exercises: AE, CE, and CF. Note that E is exercised as a second failure twice because it appears in different recovery clusters.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.2">Pairwise Independent Failures</head><p>A pair of failure IDs is independent if the second ID is observed even if the first ID is not injected. This case is often observed when the same piece of code runs in parallel, which is a common characteristic found in distributed systems (e.g., two phase commit, leader election, HDFS write and append). <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3b</ref> illustrates a scenario where the same I/O points A and B are executed concurrently in three nodes (i.e., A1, A2, A3, B1, B2, B3). Let's name these two I/O points A and B as static failure points, or SF P in short (as they exclude node ID). With bruteforce exploration, FATE produces 24 combinations (the 12 bi-directional edges in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3b</ref>). In more general, there are SF P 2 * N (N − 1) combinations, where N and SF P are the number of nodes and static failure points respectively. To reduce this quadratic growth, we introduce two levels of prioritization: one for reducing N (N − 1) and the other for SF P 2 .</p><p>To reduce N (N − 1), we leverage the property of symmetric code (i.e., the same code that runs concurrently in different nodes). Because of this property, if a pair of failures has been exercised at two static failure points of two specific nodes, it is not necessary to exercise the same pair for other pairs of nodes. For example, if A1B2 has been exercised, it is not necessary to run A1B3, A2B1, A2B3, and so on. As a result, we have reduced N (N − 1) (i.e., any combinations of two nodes) to just one (i.e., a pair of two nodes); the N does not matter anymore.</p><p>Although the first level of reduction is significant, FATE still hits the SF P 2 bottleneck as illustrated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig- ure 3c</ref>. Here, instead of having two static failure points, there are four, which leads to 16 combinations. To reduce SF P 2 , we utilize the behavior clustering algorithm used in the dependent case. That is, if injecting failure ID A1 results in the same recovery behavior as in injecting B1, then we cluster them together (i.e., only one of them needs to be exercised). Put simply, the goal is to reduce SF P to SF P clustered , which will reduce the input to the quadratic explosion (e.g., from 4 to 2 resulting in 4 uni-directional edges as depicted in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3d</ref>). In practice, we have seen a reduction from fifteen SF P to eight SF P clustered .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Summary</head><p>We have introduced FATE, a failure testing service capable of exploring multiple, diverse failures in systematic fashion. FATE employs failure IDs as a new abstraction for exploring failures. FATE is also equipped with prioritization strategies that prioritize failure scenarios that result in distinct recovery actions. Our approaches are not sound; however by experience, all bugs found with brute-force are also found with prioritization (more in §6.3). If developers have the time and resources, they could fall back to brute-force mode for more confidence. So far, we have only explained our algorithms for twofailure scenarios. We have generalized them to threefailure, but cannot present them due to space constraints. One fundamental limitation of FATE is the absence of I/O reordering <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[38]</ref>, and thus it is possible that some orderings of failures are not exercised. Adopting related techniques from existing work <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[38]</ref> will be be beneficial in our case.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">DESTINI: Declarative Testing Specifications</head><p>After failures are injected, developers still need to check for system correctness. As described in the motivation ( §2.4), DESTINI attempts to improve the state-of-theart of writing system specifications. In the following sections, we first describe the architecture ( §5.1), then present some examples ( §5.2), and finally summarize the advantages ( §5.3). Currently, we target recovery bugs that reduce availability (e.g., unmasked failures, failstop) and reliability (e.g., data-loss, inconsistency). We leave performance and scalability bugs for future work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Architecture</head><p>At the heart of DESTINI is Datalog, a declarative relational logic language. We chose the Datalog style as it has been successfully used for building distributed systems <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">26]</ref> and for verifying some aspects of system correctness (e.g., security <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">31]</ref>). Unlike much of that work, we are not using Datalog to implement system internals, but only to write correctness specifications that are checked relatively rarely. Hence we are less dependent on the efficiency of current Datalog engines, which are still evolving <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. In terms of the architecture, DESTINI is designed such that developers can build specifications from minimal information. To support this, DESTINI comprises three features as depicted in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4</ref>. First, it interposes network and disk protocols and translates the available information into Datalog events (e.g., cnpEv ). Second, it records failure scenarios by having FATE inform DESTINI about failure events (e.g., fateEv ). This highlights that FATE and DESTINI must work hand in hand, a valuable property that is apparent throughout our examples. Finally, based only on events, it records facts, deduces expectations of how the system should behave in the future, and compares the two.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.1">Rule Syntax</head><p>In DESTINI, specifications are formally written as Datalog rules. A rule is essentially a logical relation:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">errX(P1,P2,P3) :-cnpEv (P1), NOT-IN stateY(P1,P2,_), P2 == img, P3 := Util.strLib(P2);</formula><p>This Datalog rule consists of a head table (errX) and predicate tables in the body (cnpEv and stateY). The head is evaluated when the body is true. Tuple variables begin with an upper-case letter (P1). A don't care variable is represented with an underscore ( ). A comma between predicates represents conjunction. ":=" is for assignments. We also provide some helper libraries (Util.strLib() to manipulate strings). Lower case variables (img) represent integer or string constants. All upper case letters (NOT-IN) are Datalog keywords. Events are in italic. To help readers track where events originate from, an event name begins with one of these labels: cnp , dnp , cdp , ddp , fs , which stand for client-namenode, datanode-namenode, clientdatanode, datanode-datanode, and file system protocols respectively <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">(Figure 4</ref>). Non-event (non-italic) heads and predicates are essentially database tables with primary keys defined in some schemas (not shown). A table that starts with err represents an error (i.e., if a specification is broken, the error table is non-empty, implying the existence of one or more bugs).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">DESTINI Examples</head><p>This section presents the powerful features of DESTINI via four examples of HDFS recovery specifications. In the first example, we present five important components of recovery specifications ( §5.2.1). To help simplify the complex debugging process, the second example shows how developers can incrementally add tighter specifications ( §5.2.2). The third example presents specifications that incorporate a different type of failure than the first two examples ( §5.2.3). Finally, we illustrate how developers can refine existing specifications ( §5.2.4).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.1">Specifying Data-Transfer Recovery</head><p>DESTINI facilitates five important elements of recovery specifications: checks, expectations, facts, precise failure events, and check timings. Here, we present these elements by specifying the data-transfer recovery protocol ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1a)</ref>; this recovery is correct if valid replicas are stored in the surviving nodes of the pipeline.</p><p>• Checks: To catch violations of data-transfer recovery, we start with a simple high-level check (a1), which says "upon block completion, throw an error if there is a node that is expected to store a valid replica, but actually does not." This rule shows how a check is composed of three elements: the expectation (expectedNodes), fact (actualNodes), and check timing (cnpComplete ).</p><p>• Expectations: The expectation (expectedNodes) is deduced from protocol events (a2-a8). First, without any failure, the expectation is to have the replicas in all the nodes in the pipeline (a3); information about pipeline nodes are accessible from the setup reply from the namenode to the client (a2). However, if there is a crash, the expectation changes: the crashed node should be removed from the expected nodes (a4). This implies that an expectation is also based on failure events.</p><p>• Failure events: Failures in different stages result in different recovery behaviors. Thus, we must know precisely when failures occur. For data-transfer recovery, we need to capture the current stage of the write process and only change the expectation if a crash occurs within the data-transfer stage (fateCrashNode happens at Stg==2 in rule a4). The data transfer stage is deduced in rules a5-a8: the second stage begins after all acks from the setup phase have been received.</p><p>Before moving on, we emphasize two important observations here. First, this example shows how FATE and DESTINI must work hand in hand. That is, recovery specifications require a failure service to exercise them, and a failure service requires specifications of expected failure handling. Second, with logic programming, developers can easily build expectations only from events.</p><p>• Facts: The fact (actualNodes) is also built from events (a9-a16); specifically, by tracking the locations of valid replicas. A valid replica can be tracked with two pieces of information: the block's latest generation time stamp, which DESTINI tracks by interposing two interfaces (a9 and a10), and meta/checksum files with the latest generation timestamp, which are obtainable from file operations (a11-a15). With this information, we can build the runtime fact: the nodes that store the valid replicas of the block (a16).</p><p>• Check timings: The final step is to compare the expectation and the fact. We underline that the timing of the check is important because we are specifying recovery behaviors, unlike invariants which must be true at  all time. Not paying attention to this will result in false warnings (i.e., there is a period of time when recovery is ongoing and specifications are not met). Thus, we need precise events to signal check times. In this example, the check time is at block completion (cnpComplete in a1).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.2">Debugging with Tighter Specifications</head><p>The rules in the previous section capture the high-level objective of HDFS data-transfer recovery. After we ran FATE to cover the first crash scenario in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1b</ref> (for simplicity of explanation, we exclude the second crash), rule a1 throws an error due to a bug that wrongly excludes the good second node <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 1b in  §2.</ref>3). Although the check unearths the bug, it does not pinpoint the bug (i.e., answer why the violation is thrown).</p><p>To improve this debugging process, we added more detailed specifications. In particular, from the events that DESTINI logs, we observed that the client excludes the second node in the next pipeline, which is possible if the client receives a bad ack. Thus, we wrote another check (b1) which says "throw an error if the client receives a bad ack for a live node" (b1's predicates are specified in b2 and b3). Note that this check is written from the client's view, while rule a1 from the global view.</p><p>The new check catches the bug closer to the source, but also raises a new question: Why does the client receive a bad ack for the second node? One logical explanation is because the first node cannot communicate to the second node. Thus, we easily added many checks that catch unexpected bad connections such as b4, which finally pinpoints the bug: the second node, upon seeing a failed connection to the crashed third node, incorrectly closes the streams connected to the first node; note that this check is written from the datanode's view.</p><p>In summary, more detailed specifications prove to be valuable for assisting developers with the complex debugging process. This is unlikely to happen if a check implementation is long. But with DESTINI, a check can be expressed naturally in a small number of logical relations. Moreover, checks can be written from different views (e.g., global, client and datanode as shown in a1, b1, b4 respectively). <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 3</ref> shows a timeline of when these various checks are violated. As shown, tighter specifications essentially fill the "explanation gaps" between the injected failure and the wrong final state of the system.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.3">Specifying Rack-Aware Replication Policy</head><p>In this example, we write specifications for the HDFS rack-aware replication policy, an important policy for high availability <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">33]</ref>. Unlike previous examples, this example incorporates network partitioning failure mode.</p><p>According to the HDFS architects <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[33]</ref>, the write protocol should ensure that block replicas are spread across Time, Events, and Errors t1: Client asks the namenode for a block ID and the nodes.</p><p>cnpGetBlkPipe (usrFile, blk x, gs1, 1, N1); cnpGetBlkPipe (usrFile, blk x, gs1, 2, N2); cnpGetBlkPipe (usrFile, blk x, gs1, 3, N3); t2: Setup stage begins (pipeline nodes setup the files). * fsCreate (N1, tmp/blk x gs1.meta); fsCreate (N2, tmp/blk x gs1.meta); fsCreate (N3, tmp/blk x gs1.meta); t3: Client receives setup acks. Data transfer begins.  a minimum of two available racks. But, if only one rack is reachable, it is acceptable to use one rack temporarily. To express this, rule c1 throws a warning if a block's rack could reach another rack, but the block's rack count is one (rules c2-c4 provide topology information, which is initialized when the cluster starts and updated when FATE creates a rack partition). This warning becomes a hard error only if it is true upon block completion (c5) or stable state (c6). Note again how these timings are important to prevent false errors; while recovery is ongoing, replicas are still being re-shuffled into multiple racks.</p><p>With these checks, DESTINI found the bug in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig- ure 1c ( §2.3)</ref>, a critical bug that could greatly reduce availability: all replicas of a block are stored in a single rack. Note that the bug does not violate the completion rule (because the racks are still partitioned). But, it does violate the stable state rule because even after the network partitioning is removed, the replication monitor does not re-shuffle the replicas.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.4">Refining Specifications</head><p>In the second example ( §5.2.2), we demonstrated how developers can incrementally add detailed specifications. In this section, we briefly show how developers can refine existing specifications (an extensive description can be found in our short paper <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref>).</p><p>Here, we specify the HDFS log-recovery process in order to catch data-loss bugs in this protocol. The highlevel check (d1) is fairly simple: "a user file is lost if it does not exist at the namenode." To capture the facts, we wrote rule d2 which says "at any time, user files should exist in the union of all the three namenode files used in log recovery." With these rules, we found a data-loss bug that accidentally deletes the metadata of user files. But, the error is only thrown at the end of the log recovery process (i.e., the rules are not detailed enough to pinpoint the bug). We then refined rule d2 to reflect in detail the four stages of the process (d3 to d5). That is, depending on the stage, user files are expected to be in a different subset of the three files. With these refined specifications, the data-loss bug was captured in between stage 3 and 4.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Summary of Advantages</head><p>Throughout the examples, we have shown the advantages of DESTINI: it facilitates checks, expectations, facts, failure events, and precise timings; specifications can be written from different views (e.g., global, client, datanode); different types of violations can be specified (e.g., availability, data-loss); different types of failures can be incorporated (e.g., crashes, partitioning); and specifications can be incrementally added or refined. Overall, the resulting specifications are clear, concise, and precise, which potentially attracts developers to write many specifications to ease complex debugging process. All of these are feasible due to three important properties of DESTINI: the interposition mechanism that translates disk and network events; the use of relational logic language which enables us to deduce complex states only from events; and the inclusion of failure events from the collaboration with FATE.</p><p>Besides these advantages, adopting DESTINI requires one major effort: developers need to reverse-engineer raw I/O information (e.g., I/O buffer, stack trace) collected from the Java-based interposition mechanism into semantically-richer Datalog events (e.g., cnpComplete ). However, we hope that this effort will also be useful for other debugging techniques that need detailed I/O information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Evaluation</head><p>We evaluate FATE and DESTINI in several aspects: the general usability for cloud systems ( §6.1), the ability to catch multiple-failure bugs ( §6.2), the efficiency of our prioritization strategies ( §6.3), the number of specifications we have written and their reusability ( §6.4), the number of new bugs we have found and old bugs reproduced ( §6.5), and the implementation complexity ( §6.6).</p><p>Since we currently only test reliability (but not performance), it is sufficient to run FATE, DESTINI, and the target systems as separate processes on a single machine; network and disk failures are emulated (manifested as Java I/O exceptions), and crashes are emulated with process crashes. Nevertheless, FATE and DESTINI can run on separate machines.  <ref type="bibr">Apr. 2010)</ref>. We have run our framework on four HDFS workloads (log recovery, write, append, and replication monitor), one ZooKeeper workload (leader election), and one Cassandra workload (keyvalue insert).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">Target Systems and Protocols</head><p>In this paper, we only present extensive evaluation numbers for HDFS. For Cassandra and ZooKeeper, we only present partial results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Multiple-Failure Bugs</head><p>The uniqueness of our framework is the ability to explore multiple failures systematically, and thus catch cornercase multiple-failure bugs. Here, we describe two out of five multiple-failure bugs that we found.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2.1">Append Bugs</head><p>We begin with a multiple-failure bug in the HDFS append protocol. Unlike write, append is more complex because it must atomically mutate block replicas <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[36]</ref>. HDFS developers implement append with a custom protocol; their latest append design was written in a 19-page document of prose specifications <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22]</ref>. Append was finally supported after being a top user demand for three years <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[36]</ref>. As a note, Google FS also supports append, but its authors did not share their internal design <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref>.</p><p>In the experiment setup, a block has three replicas in three nodes, and thus should survive two failures. On append, the three nodes form a pipeline. N1 starts a thread that streams the new bytes to N2 and then N1 appends the bytes to its block. N2 crashes at this point, and N1 sends a bad ack to the client, but does not stop the thread. Before the client continues streaming via a new pipeline, all surviving nodes (N1 and N3) must agree on the same block offset (the syncOffset process). In this process, each node stops the writing thread, verifies that the block's in-memory and on-disk lengths are the same, broadcasts the offset, and picks the smallest offset. However, N1 might have not updated the block's in-memory length, and thus throws an exception resulting in the new pipeline containing only N3. Then, N3 crashes, and the pipeline is empty. The append fails, but worse, the block in N1 (still alive) becomes "trapped" (i.e., inaccessible). After FATE ran all the background protocols (e.g., lease recovery), the block is still trapped and permanently inaccessible. We have submitted a fix for this bug <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2.2">Combinations of Different Failures</head><p>We have also found a new data-loss bug due to a sequence of different failure modes, more specifically, transient disk failure (#1), crash (#2), and disk corruption (#3) at the namenode. The experiment setup was that the namenode has three replicas of metadata files on three disks, and one disk is flaky (exhibits transient failures and corruptions). When users store new files, the namenode logs them to all the disks. If a disk (e.g., Disk1) returns a transient write error (#1), the namenode will exclude this disk; future writes will be logged to the other two disks (i.e., Disk1 will contain stale data). Then, the namenode crashes after several updates (#2). When the namenode reboots, it will load metadata from the disk that has the latest update time. Unfortunately, the file that carries this information is not protected by a checksum. Thus, if this file is corrupted (#3) such that the update time of Disk1 becomes more recent than the other two, then the namenode will load stale data, and flush the stale data to the other two disks, wiping out all recent updates. One could argue that this case is rare, but cloud-scale deployments cause rare bugs to surface; a similar case of corruption did occur in practice <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. Moreover, data-loss bugs are serious ones <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[27,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">29,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">30]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3">Prioritization Efficiency</head><p>When FATE was first deployed without prioritization, we exercised over 40,000 unique combinations of failures, which combine into 80-hour of testing time. Thousands of experiments failed (probably only due to tens of bugs). Although 80 hours seems a reasonable testing time to unearth crucial reliability bugs, this long testing time only covers several workloads; in reality, there are more workloads to test. In addition, as developers modify their code, they likely to prefer faster turn-around time to find new bugs from their new changes. Overall, this long testing is an overwhelming situation, but which fortunately unfolds into a good outcome: new strategies for multiplefailure prioritization.</p><p>To evaluate our strategies, we first focused only on two protocols (write and append) because we need to compare the brute-force with the prioritization results. More specifically, for each method, we count the number of combinations and the number of distinct bugs. Our hope is that the latter is the same for brute-force and prioritization. <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 4</ref> shows the result of running the two workloads with two and three failures per run, and with a lightweight filter (crash-only failures on disk I/Os in datanodes); without this filter, the number of brute-force experiments is too large to debug. In short, the table shows that our prioritization strategies reduce the total number of experiments by an order of magnitude (the testing time for the workloads in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 4</ref> is reduced from 26 hours to 2.5 hours). In addition, from our experience no bugs are missing. Again, we cannot prove that our approach is sound; developers could fall back to bruteforce for more confidence. <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 4</ref> also highlights the exponential explosion of combinations of multiple failures; the numbers for three failures are much higher than those for two failures (e.g., 7720 vs. 1119). So far, we only cover up to 3 failures, and our techniques still scale reasonably well (i.e., they still give an order of magnitude improvement).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.4">Specifications</head><p>In the last six months, we have written 74 checks on top of 174 rules for a total of 351 lines (65 checks for HDFS, 2 for ZooKeeper, and 7 for Cassandra). We want to emphasize that rules checks ratio displays how DESTINI empowers specification reuse (i.e., building more checks on top of existing rules). As a comparison, the ratio for our first check ( §5.2.1 in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref>) is 16:1, but the ratio now is 3:1.  simplicity offered by DESTINI will open the possibility of having hundreds of specifications along with more recovery specification patterns.</p><p>To show how our style of writing specifications is applicable to other systems, we present in more detail some specifications we wrote for ZooKeeper and Cassandra.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.4.1">ZooKeeper</head><p>We have integrated our framework to ZooKeeper <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19]</ref>. We picked two reported bugs in the version we analyzed. Let's say three nodes N1, N2, and N3, participate in a leader election, and id(N 1) &lt; id(N 2) &lt; id(N 3). If N3 crashes at any point in this process, the expected behavior is to have N1 and N2 form a 2-quorum. However, there is a bug that does not anticipate N3 crashing at a particular point, which causes N1 and N2 to continue nominating N3 in ever-increasing rounds. As a result, the election process never terminates and the cluster never becomes available. To catch this bug, we wrote an invariant violation "a node chooses a winner of a round without ensuring that the chosen leader has in itself voted in the round." The other bug involves multiple failures and can be caught with an addition of just one check; we reuse rules from the first bug. So far, we have written 12 rules for ZooKeeper.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.4.2">Cassandra</head><p>We have also done the same for Cassandra <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[23]</ref>, and picked three reported bugs in the version we analyzed. In Cassandra, the key-value insert protocol allows users to specify a consistency level such as one, quorum, or all, which ensures that the client waits until the key-value has been flushed on at least one, N/2 + 1, or all N nodes respectively. These are simple specifications, but again, due to complex implementation, bugs exist and break the rules. For example, at level all, Cassandra could incorrectly return a success even when only one replica has been completed. FATE is able to reproduce the failure scenarios and DESTINI is equipped with 7 checks (in 12 rules) to catch consistency-level related bugs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.5">New Bugs and Old Bugs Reproduced</head><p>We have tested HDFS for over eight months and submitted 16 new bugs, out of which 7 uncovered design bugs (i.e., require protocol modifications) and 9 uncovered implementation bugs. All have been confirmed by the developers. For Cassandra and ZooKeeper, we observed some failed experiments, but since we do not have the chance to debug all of them, we have no new bugs to report.</p><p>To further show the power of our framework, we address two challenges: Can FATE reproduce all the failure scenarios of old bugs? Can DESTINI facilitate specifications that catch the bugs? Before proposing our framework for catching unknown bugs, we wanted to feel confident that it is expressive enough to capture known bugs. We went through the 91 HDFS recovery issues ( §2.2) and selected 74 that relate to our target workloads ( §6.1). FATE is able to reproduce all of them; as a proof, we have created 22 filters (155 lines in Java) to reproduce all the scenarios. Furthermore, we have written checks that could catch 46 old bugs; since some of the old bugs have been fixed in the version we analyzed, we introduced artificial bugs to test our specifications. For ZooKeeper and Cassandra, we have reproduced a total of five bugs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.6">FATE and DESTINI Complexity</head><p>FATE comprises generic (workload driver, failure server, failure surface) and domain-specific parts (workload driver, I/O IDs). The generic part is written in 3166 lines in Java. The domain-specific parts are 422, 253, and 357 lines for HDFS, ZooKeeper and Cassandra respectively; the part for HDFS is bigger because HDFS was our first target. DESTINI's implementation cost comes from the translation mechanism ( §5.1). The generic part is 506 lines. The domain-specific parts are 732 (more complete), 23, and 35 lines for HDFS, ZooKeeper, and Cassandra respectively. FATE and DESTINI interpose the target systems with AspectJ (no modification to the code base). However, it was necessary to slightly modify the systems (less than 100 lines) for two purposes: deferring background tasks while the workload is running and sending stable-state commands.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusion and Future Work</head><p>The scale of cloud systems -in terms of both infrastructure and workload -makes failure handling an urgent challenge for system developers. To assist developers in addressing this challenge, we have presented FATE and DESTINI as a new framework for cloud recovery testing. We believe that developers need both FATE and DESTINI as a unified framework: recovery specifications require a failure service to exercise them, and a failure service requires specifications of expected failure handling.</p><p>Beyond finding problems in existing systems, we believe such testing is also useful in helping to generate new ideas on how to build robust, recoverable systems. For example, one new approach we are currently investigating is the increased use of pessimism to avoid problems during recovery. For example, HDFS lease recovery would have been more robust had it not trusted aspects of the append protocol to function correctly ( §6.2). Many other examples exist; only through further careful testing and analysis will the next generation of cloud systems meet their demands.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: HDFS Write Recovery Protocol.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: FATE Architecture.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Prioritization of Pairwise Dependent and Independent Failures.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: DESTINI Architecture.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>cdpSetupAck</head><label></label><figDesc>(blk x, 1, OK); cdpSetupAck (blk x, 2, OK); cdpSetupAck (blk x, 3, OK); t4: FATE crashes N3. Got error (b4). fateCrashNode (N3); errBadConnect (N1, N2); // should be good t5: Client receives an errorneous ack. Got error (b1). cdpDataAck (2, Error); errBadAck (2, N2); // should be good t6: Recovery begins. Get new generation time stamp. dnpNextGenStamp (blk x, gs2); t7: Only N1 continues and finalizes the files. fsCreate (N1, tmp/blk x gs2.meta); fsRename (N1, tmp/blk x gs2.meta, current/blk x gs2.meta); t8: Client marks completion. Got error (a1). cnpComplete (blk x); errDataRec (blk x, N2); // should exist</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>We have integrated FATE and DESTINI to three cloud systems: HDFS [33] v0.20.0 and v0.20.2+320 (the latter is released in Feb. 2010 and used by Cloudera and Face- book), ZooKeeper [19] v3.2.2 (Dec. 2009), and Cassan- dra [23] v0.6.1 (</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>I /O ID Fields</head><label>I</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Values 
Static 
Func. call 
: OutputStream.flush() 
Source File : BlockRecv.java (line 45) 
Dynamic Stack trace 
: (the stack trace) 
Node Id 
: Node2 
Domain 
Source 
: Node2 
specific 
Dest. 
: Node1 
Net. Mesg. : Setup Ack 
Failure ID = hash ( I/O ID + Crash ) = 2849067135 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>A Failure ID. A failure ID comprises an I/O ID 

plus the injected failure (e.g., crash). Hash is used to record a 
failure ID. For space, some fields are not shown. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 2 : Sample Specifications. The table lists all the rules we wrote to specify the problems in Section 5.2; Rules aX, bX, cX, and dXerr. Tuple variables B, Gs, N, Pos, R, Stg, NnFile, and UFile are abbreviations for block, generation timestamp, node, position, rack, stage, namenode file, and user file respectively; others should be self-explanatory. Each table has primary keys defined in a schema (not shown). ( * * ) Rule d2 is refined in d3 to d5; these rules are described more in our short paper [14].</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>are for Sections 5.2.1, 5.2.2, 5.2.3, and 5.2.4 respectively. All logical relations are built only from events (in italic). The 
shaded rows indicate checks that catch violations. A check always starts with </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 3 : A Timeline of DESTINI Execution.</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>The 
</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Prioritization Efficiency. The columns from left 

to right are the number of injected failures per run (F), explo-
ration strategy (STR), combinations/experiments (EXP), failed 
experiments (FAIL), and bugs found (BUGS). BF and PR stands 
for brute-force and prioritization respectively. Note that the 
bug counts are only due to two and three failures and depend 
on the filter (i.e., there are more bugs than shown). (  *  ) Bugs in 
three-failure experiments are the same as in two-failure ones. 
(  *  *  ) This high number is due to a design bug; we used triaging 
to help us classify the bugs (not shown). 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>Table 5 compares</head><label>5</label><figDesc>DESTINI with other related work. The table highlights that DESTINI allows a large number of checks to be written in fewer lines of code. We want to note that the number of specifications we have written so far only represents six recovery protocols; there are more that can be specified. As time progresses, we believe the</figDesc><table>Type Framework 

#Chks Lines/Chk 
S/I 
D3S [24] 
10 
53 
D/I 
Pip [32] 
44 
43 
S/I 
WiDS [25] 
15 
22 
D/D P2 Monitor [34] 
11 
12 
D/I 
DESTINI 
74 
5 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" validated="false"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>DESTINI vs. Related Work. The table com-

pares DESTINI with related work. D, S, and I represent declar-
ative, scripting, and imperative languages respectively. X/Y im-
plies specifications in X language for systems in Y language. 
We divide existing work into three classes (S/I, D/D, D/I). 

</table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8">Acknowledgments</head><p>We thank the anonymous reviewers and Rodrigo Fonseca (our shepherd) for their tremendous feedback and comments, which have substantially improved the content and presentation of this paper. This material is based upon work supported by Computing Innovation Fellowship, the NSF under grant Nos. CCF-1016924, CCF-1017073, CCF-1018729, CCF-0747390, CNS-0722077, IIS-0713661, IIS-0803690, and IIS-0722077, the MURI program under AFOSR grant No. FA9550-08-1-0352, and gifts from Google, IBM, Microsoft, NetApp, and Yahoo!. Any opinions, findings, and conclusions or recommendations expressed in this material are those of the authors and do not necessarily reflect the views of NSF or other institutions.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Workload #F STR #EXP FAIL BUGS</head></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ec2</forename><surname>Amazon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://aws.amazon.com/ec2" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hdfs</forename><surname>Jira</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HDFS" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">BOOM Analytics: Exploring Data-Centric, Declarative Programming for the Cloud</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Alvaro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tyson</forename><surname>Condie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Neil</forename><surname>Conway</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Khaled</forename><surname>Elmeleegy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joseph</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hellerstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Russell C</forename><surname>Sears</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EuroSys &apos;10</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards a Cloud Computing Research Agenda</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ken</forename><surname>Birman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gregory</forename><surname>Chockler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robbert</forename><surname>Van Renesse</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM SIGACT News</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="68" to="80" />
			<date type="published" when="2009-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Chubby lock service for loosely-coupled distributed systems Export</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mike</forename><surname>Burrows</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">OSDI &apos;06</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Paxos Made Live -An Engineering Perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tushar</forename><surname>Chandra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Griesemer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joshua</forename><surname>Redstone</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">PODC &apos;07</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bigtable: A Distributed Storage System for Structured Data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fay</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Dean</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sanjay</forename><surname>Ghemawat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wilson</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Hsieh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Deborah</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Wallach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Burrows</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tushar</forename><surname>Chandra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Fikes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Gruber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">OSDI &apos;06</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="205" to="218" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Benchmarking Cloud Serving Systems with YCSB</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brian</forename><surname>Cooper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adam</forename><surname>Silberstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Erwin</forename><surname>Tam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Raghu</forename><surname>Ramakrishnan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Russell</forename><surname>Sears</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">SoCC &apos;10</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Underneath the Covers at Google: Current Systems and Future Directions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Dean</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Google I/O &apos;08</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Google File System</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sanjay</forename><surname>Ghemawat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Howard</forename><surname>Gobioff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shun-Tak</forename><surname>Leung</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">SOSP &apos;03</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="29" to="43" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reliability/Resilience Panel</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Garth</forename><surname>Gibson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">HEC-FSIO &apos;10</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gatekeeper: Mostly Static Enforcement of Security and Reliability Policies for JavaScript Code</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Salvatore</forename><surname>Guarnieri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benjamin</forename><surname>Livshits</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Usenix Security &apos;09</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">FATE and DESTINI: A Framework for Cloud Recovery Testing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Haryadi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thanh</forename><surname>Gunawi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pallavi</forename><surname>Do</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Joshi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joseph</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Alvaro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrea</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Hellerstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Arpaci-Dusseau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Remzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Koushik</forename><surname>Arpaci-Dusseau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Sen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>UCB/EECS-2010-127</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010-09" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">UC Berkeley Technical Report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards Automatically Checking Thousands of Failures with Micro-specifications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Haryadi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thanh</forename><surname>Gunawi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pallavi</forename><surname>Do</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joseph</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Joshi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrea</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Hellerstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Arpaci-Dusseau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Remzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Koushik</forename><surname>Arpaci-Dusseau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Sen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">HotDep &apos;10</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">SQCK: A Declarative File System Checker</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Haryadi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Abhishek</forename><surname>Gunawi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrea</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Rajimwale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Remzi</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Arpacidusseau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Arpaci-Dusseau</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">OSDI &apos;08</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cloud Computing Economies of Scale</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Hamilton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">MIX &apos;10</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On Designing and Deploying Internet-Scale Services</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Hamilton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">LISA &apos;07</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cloud Storage FUD: Failure and Uncertainty and Durability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alyssa</forename><surname>Henry</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">FAST &apos;09</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">ZooKeeper: Wait-free coordination for Internet-scale systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Hunt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mahadev</forename><surname>Konar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Flavio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benjamin</forename><surname>Junqueira</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Reed</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">USENIX ATC &apos;10</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">AFEX: An Automated Fault Explorer for Faster System Testing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lorenzo</forename><surname>Keller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Marinescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">George</forename><surname>Candea</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Life, Death, and the Critical Transition: Finding Liveness Bugs in Systems Code</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Charles</forename><surname>Killian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ranjit</forename><surname>Jhala</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amin</forename><surname>Vahdat</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NSDI &apos;07</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hairong</forename><surname>Kuang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Konstantin</forename><surname>Shvachko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nicholas</forename><surname>Sze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sanjay</forename><surname>Radia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Chansler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/attachment/12445209/appendDesign3.pdf" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cassandra -a decentralized structured storage system</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Avinash</forename><surname>Lakshman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prashant</forename><surname>Malik</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">LADIS &apos;09</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">D3S: Debugging Deployed Distributed Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xuezheng</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhenyu</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xi</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Feibo</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaochen</forename><surname>Lian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jian</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ming</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">Frans</forename><surname>Kaashoek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zheng</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NSDI &apos;08</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">WiDS Checker: Combating Bugs in Distributed Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xuezheng</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aimin</forename><surname>Pan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zheng</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NSDI &apos;07</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Implementing Declarative Overlays</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Boon Thau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tyson</forename><surname>Loo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joseph</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Condie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Hellerstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">SOSP &apos;05</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Petros Maniatis, Timothy Roscoe, and Ion Stoica</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Om</forename><surname>Malik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://gigaom.com" />
		<title level="m">When the Cloud Fails: T-Mobile, Microsoft Lose Sidekick Customer Data</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An Extensible Technique for High-Precision Testing of Recovery Code</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Marinescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Radu</forename><surname>Banabic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">George</forename><surname>Candea</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">USENIX ATC &apos;10</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Facebook temporarily loses more than 10% of photos in hard drive failure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lucas</forename><surname>Mearian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="www.computerworld.com" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Bank fined 3 millions pound sterling for data loss, still not taking it seriously</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Oates</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="www.theregister.co.uk" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">MulVAL: A logic-based network security analyzer</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xinming</forename><surname>Ou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sudhakar</forename><surname>Govindavajhala</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Appel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Usenix Security &apos;05</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pip: Detecting the unexpected in distrubted systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Reynolds</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Janet</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Wiener</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Mogul</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mehul</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Shah</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Charles</forename><surname>Killian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amin</forename><surname>Vahdat</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NSDI &apos;06</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Hadoop Distributed File System</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Konstantin</forename><surname>Shvachko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hairong</forename><surname>Kuang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sanjay</forename><surname>Radia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Chansler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">MSST &apos;10</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using Queries for Distributed Monitoring and Forensics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Atul</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Petros</forename><surname>Maniatis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Timothy</forename><surname>Roscoe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Druschel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EuroSys &apos;06</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Fault Injection framework: How to use it, test using artificial faults, and develop new faults</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hadoop</forename><surname>Team</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://issues.apache.org" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tom</forename><surname>White</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.cloudera.com/blog/2009/07/file-appends-in-hdfs" />
		<title level="m">File Appends in HDFS</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">CrystalBall: Predicting and Preventing Inconsistencies in Deployed. Distributed Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maysam</forename><surname>Yabandeh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nikola</forename><surname>Knezevic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dejan</forename><surname>Kostic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Viktor</forename><surname>Kuncak</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NSDI &apos;09</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">MODIST: Transparent Model Checking of Unmodified Distributed Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Junfeng</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tisheng</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ming</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhilei</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xuezheng</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haoxiang</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mao</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fan</forename><surname>Long</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lintao</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lidong</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NSDI &apos;09</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">EXPLODE: A Lightweight, General System for Finding Serious Storage System Errors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Junfeng</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Can</forename><surname>Sar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dawson</forename><surname>Engler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">OSDI &apos;06</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
