<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/atharsefid/Desktop/grobid-0.5.3/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.3" ident="GROBID" when="2020-09-29T01:58+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The HybrEx Model for Confidentiality and Privacy in Cloud Computing</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Ko</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kyungho</forename><surname>Jeon</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ramsés</forename><surname>Morales</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Xerox Research Center Webster</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">† University at Buffalo</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">The State University of New York</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The HybrEx Model for Confidentiality and Privacy in Cloud Computing</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>This paper proposes a new execution model for confidentiality and privacy in cloud computing, called the HybrEx (Hybrid Execution) model. The HybrEx model provides a seamless way for an organization to utilize their own infrastructure for sensitive, private data and computation, while integrating public clouds for non-sensitive, public data and computation. We outline how to realize this model in one specific execution environment , MapReduce over Bigtable.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Cloud computing allows large organizations to tap into a virtually infinite pool of resources with the ability to control cost. Cloud providers give this power to their customers by offering a pay-as-you-go pricing model as well as elasticity and availability of computing and storage resources. Due to this benefit, cloud computing has quickly gained popularity in recent years.</p><p>Yet many organizations have not widely adapted the use of clouds due to the concerns of confidentiality and privacy. For example, a recent survey collected responses from more than 500 IT executives from around the world, and reports that IT executives prefer their existing internal infrastructure (i.e., their private cloud) over a third-party cloud (i.e., a public cloud) due to security threats and lack of control over their data and systems that handle it <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref>. For industries such as finance and healthcare, explicit regulations regarding data protection -Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS) <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref> and Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA) <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref> -severely limit the potential use of public clouds.</p><p>These concerns are well-founded. Researchers have shown that an outside attacker can extract unauthorized information in Amazon EC2 <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref>. Other researchers discovered a vulnerability that allows user impersonation in Google Apps <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. Encryption can only provide a limited guarantee, since any computation on encrypted data either involves decrypting the data or has yet to be practical even with fully homomorphic encryption <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>.</p><p>One line of research to resolve these issues is to make public clouds more secure <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">20]</ref>. However, a public cloud is a shared platform managed by a third-party with potential security risks such as insider attacks and software vulnerabilities. These risks are difficult to eliminate as evidenced by the examples mentioned above as well as the history of security breaches and patches in general -after all, this is precisely the reason why organizations are hesitant to adapt the use of public clouds.</p><p>Recognizing this difficulty, we argue for an alternative that treats public clouds as an inherently insecure environment instead of trying to make them more secure; we propose an execution model that utilizes public clouds only for safe operations while integrating an organization's private cloud. We refer to this as the HybrEx (Hybrid Execution) model. More specifically, our HybrEx model utilizes public clouds only for an organization's non-sensitive data and computation classified as public, i.e., when the organization declares that there is no privacy and confidentiality risk in exporting the data and performing computation on it using public clouds. For the organization's sensitive, private data and computation, the HybrEx model utilizes their private cloud. Moreover, when an application requires access to both the private and public data, the application itself also gets partitioned and runs in both the private and public clouds. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> depicts the architecture with a HybrEx execution framework that partitions and runs applications, as well as a HybrEx storage that manages private and public data separately.</p><p>The main benefit of the HybrEx model is integration with safety, i.e., the ability to add more computing and storage resources from public clouds to a private cloud without the concerns for confidentiality and privacy. By partitioning data and computation, the HybrEx model side-steps the question of trustworthiness of pub- lic clouds and provides the same level of confidentiality and privacy guarantees as the traditional local computing provides. Businesses are already looking into the integration of private and public clouds mainly for capacity and performance, i.e., to elastically scale out from their private cloud to public clouds <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref>; the HybrEx model can give an additional benefit of confidentiality and privacy to these businesses.</p><p>In order to concretely explore this general direction, we first focus our effort on how to realize the HybrEx model in one specific execution environment, MapReduce over Bigtable, using Hadoop MapReduce and HBase. We have chosen this execution environment for two reasons. First, MapReduce <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref> is arguably the most popular execution environment in cloud computing. Second, MapReduce's massively parallel nature of execution, combined with the semi-structured data management of Bigtable <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>, allows clean and well-defined partitioning between private and public clouds.</p><p>Using partitioning for secure computing is not a new idea <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">21,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">22]</ref>. However, realizing it in the HybrEx model and MapReduce brings its own set of challenges. First, we need to be able to partition data and computation. Second, utilizing both private and public clouds for a single (partitioned) MapReduce job means running the job over the wide-area Internet. Due to the all-toall communication pattern in MapReduce as well as its master-slave architecture, providing reasonable performance over the wide-area can be challenging. Finally, while partitioning provides confidentiality and privacy for private data and computation, it does not ensure integrity of public data and computation. Section 3 outlines these challenges and our research directions.</p><p>The HybrEx model enables new kinds of applications utilizing both private and public clouds. We discuss this in the context of MapReduce in the next section.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Execution Categories</head><p>MapReduce presents a unique opportunity to realize the HybrEx model since a MapReduce job is sub-divided into tasks that run massively in parallel. We present four categories ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>) showing how HybrEx MapReduce enables new kinds of applications that utilize both private and public clouds. These categories highlight both the integration and safety aspects of the HybrEx model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Map Hybrid</head><p>Many MapReduce applications analyze private and public data sets; a number of public data sets are available for domains such as forensic analysis, spam detection, and genome analysis, via well-known repositories, e.g., Amazon AWS Public Data Sets and CDC WONDER. Using these data sets, organizations can analyze both their own data sets and public data sets together for comparison or accuracy improvements. Since these applications process both private and public data sets, it is difficult to execute them in a public cloud without compromising on confidentiality and privacy.</p><p>HybrEx MapReduce enables this type of applications to safely utilize a public cloud by executing the Map phase in both private and public clouds while executing the Reduce phase in only one of the clouds. We refer to this category as Map hybrid, depicted in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>(a).</p><p>We illustrate this with an example called CloudBurst <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[18]</ref>, a bioinformatics MapReduce application. Simply put, it implements an algorithm that compares genome sequences, which serves as a basis for other biological analyses such as comparing a patient's genome to a reference human genome for medical purposes. CloudBurst's input consists of (potentially) private data called target genomes (e.g., patients' genomes) and public data called reference genomes (e.g., human reference genomes available from a public repository).</p><p>CloudBurst uses the same algorithm to process both the reference genomes and the target genomes in the Map phase. Thus, HybrEx MapReduce can safely utilize the public cloud for the reference genomes while utilizing the private cloud for the target genomes during the Map phase. On the other hand, the Reduce phase of CloudBurst produces (potentially) private outputs, e.g., a genome comparison result for a patient. Thus, we can utilize only the private cloud for the Reduce phase.</p><p>Horizontal Partitioning There are two popular usage cases for the current public clouds. The first case is long-term archiving of an organization's data, where the organization encrypts their private data before storing it on a public cloud. The second case is exporting and importing data for running periodic MapReduce jobs in a public cloud. This is in fact a common usage case in Amazon Elastic MapReduce <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19]</ref>; an organization first exports its data to a public cloud, runs a MapReduce job in the public cloud, and (optionally) imports the result back to its own private storage.</p><p>Since HybrEx MapReduce seamlessly integrates private and public clouds, it can automate these usage cases by utilizing different clouds for different phases. We refer to this category as horizontal partitioning, depicted in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2(b)</ref>. For example, in the long-term archiving case, HybrEx MapReduce can run Map tasks that encrypt private data in the private cloud, transfer encrypted data to the public cloud via the Shuffle phase, and run Reduce tasks that store the data in the public cloud.</p><p>Vertical Partitioning In 2007, the New York Times transformed its scanned images of the public domain articles to PDF files using MapReduce running in Amazon EC2. <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">1</ref> Each original article comprised of many small TIFF images, and a MapReduce job "glued" these images together to produce one PDF file per article. However, they only transformed public domain articles; if an organization wants to process private and public documents at the same time, it becomes difficult to do so in a public cloud due to confidentiality and privacy.</p><p>HybrEx MapReduce enables this type of applications to safely utilize a public cloud by executing a MapReduce job in both private and public clouds while avoiding any inter-cloud shuffling of intermediate data.</p><p>Although this type of partitioning is technically akin to running two separate jobs in private and public clouds, HybeEx MapReduce supports this naturally without the overhead of separate management of jobs and data. We refer to this category as vertical partitioning. Hybrid Many organizations are looking into ways to integrate public clouds for performance reasons or due to resource limitations in their private cloud <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref>. These organizations mainly utilize their private cloud even for storing and processing public data, but occasionally want to scale out to a public cloud. HybrEx MapReduce can achieve this by utilizing both private and public clouds in all three phases of MapReduce as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2(d)</ref>. We refer to this simply as hybrid.</p><p>Beyond Pure MapReduce For general applications, the pure MapReduce programming paradigm is limiting as there are only two primitives to play with. Thus, we are exploring ways to overcome this limitation. The first is an optional phase in between Map and Shuffle called the Sanitize phase. Using this phase, HybrEx MapReduce could allow programmers to explicitly sanitize intermediate data for more flexible utilization of private and public clouds.</p><p>We are also exploring the applicability of HybrEx in Pig 2 and Hive 3 . Both systems are based on MapReduce, but allow more flexbility and generality in programming. We believe that supporting these systems will likely result in wider applicability of HybrEx.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Research Challenges and Directions</head><p>We need to overcome three main challenges to implement the HybrEx model -data partitioning, system partitioning, and integrity -and achieve integration with safety. The following outlines these challenges and our research directions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Data Partitioning</head><p>Since the HybrEx model proposes the use of partitioning for confidentiality and privacy, it raises an immediate question of how to partition data. We address this question by using two labels, the private label and the public label. HybrEx Bigtable and HybrEx MapReduce recognize these labels and determine data and computation placement accordingly. This use of labels is inspired by previous information flow control techniques used in programming languages such as Jif <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref> and systems such as Asbestos <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. While these approaches use labels to control and track how information flows among system components, we only need to use labels to determine the placement of data and computation.</p><p>We assume that organizations have policies to determine data sensitivity; we hypothesize that in many cases, organizations can perform labeling programmatically at the time of importing data into HybrEx Bigtable by running a MapReduce job. For example, if an organization has a file-naming convention that indicates the sensitivity of a document, it can run a MapReduce job that labels data according to file names.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">System Partitioning</head><p>Since the HybrEx model utilizes both private and public clouds, any system that implements the HybrEx model has to partition its components, i.e., it needs to place some components in the public cloud and others in the private cloud. This naturally raises two sub-questions -i) how to keep public components from accessing HybrEx Bigtable In order to concretely discuss the two questions of system partitioning for Bigtable, we briefly introduce its three main components -the master, tablet servers, and Chubby. The master is responsible for the overall management of the system. Tablet servers manage stored data and handle read and write requests. Chubby provides meta data consistency and reliability. With these components, we can rephrase the two questions of system partitioning as follows. First, when utilizing both private and public clouds, we need to place tablet servers in both clouds as they directly handle data. Thus, we must keep public tablet servers from handling private data. Second, we avoid placing the master and Chubby in the public cloud as we need to trust them for overall correctness. However, the master, tablet servers, and Chubby communicate with each other frequently for correct functioning of the system. Thus, we need to reduce the wide-area communication overhead between public tablet servers, the master, and Chubby.</p><p>In order to address these issues, we introduce two new components that we refer to as the shadow master and the shadow Chubby as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 3</ref>. These components are public counterparts to the master and Chubby that run in the public cloud. Each shadow component is a restricted version of its private counterpart, and does not have any access to information regarding private data. Moreover, we only allow tablet servers in the public cloud to communicate with these shadow components. An immediate benefit of this architecture is the ability to avoid the master-slave wide-area communications, as it mostly localizes the communications among system components; the components in the private cloud do not communicate with the components in the public cloud for the most part, and vice versa.</p><p>HybrEx MapReduce Since both Bigtable and MapReduce have a similar master-slave architecture, we apply the same general approach to system partitioning; we partition the main components of the original MapReduce, the master and the workers. The master has its restricted public counterpart, the shadow master, and we place the workers in both private and public clouds as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 4</ref>. As in HybrEx Bigtable, this architecture avoids the master-slave wide-area communications.</p><p>However, MapReduce has a critical difference from Bigtable in terms of wide-area communication overhead as some MapReduce jobs require shuffling of intermediate data over the wide-area as shown in Section 2. Thus, we introduce a new component called shuffle proxies that transfer intermediate data over the wide-area on behalf of the workers. This is different from the original MapReduce that allows the workers to directly transfer intermediate data among them.</p><p>Shuffle proxies give us the benefit of having a separate architectural component where we can apply optimization techniques to reduce the wide-area overhead. We are exploring techniques such as caching, aggregation, compression, and deduplication of intermediate data.</p><p>We recognize that using a public cloud in addition to a private cloud gives more computing power, which can lead to better performance despite the wide-area overhead. For example, in a small-scale experiment involving 5 local machines in Buffalo and 5 Emulab machines in Utah, the execution time of Hadoop sorting 20GB of input data turns out to be faster over the wide-area (702 sec with all 10 machines over the wide-area vs. 937 sec with 5 local machines). However, overhead reduction is still important to benefit a broad range of applications and system configurations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Integrity</head><p>The last question is how to provide integrity for data and computation in the public cloud, as our basic assumption is that it is not safe to trust the public cloud. To address the question of data integrity, HybrEx Bigtable keeps the hashes of the public data in the private cloud. HybrEx Bigtable can verify the integrity either when there is a request for the public data or proactively by sampling.</p><p>For computation integrity, HybrEx MapReduce checks the integrity of the results from the public cloud in two modes that provide different levels of fidelity. The first mode is full integrity checking, where the private cloud re-executes every Map and Reduce task that the public cloud has executed. HybrEx MapReduce provides this mainly as a means to enable auditing at a later time, e.g., when an organization wants to verify the correctness of past computations from the public cloud.</p><p>Obviously, the overhead of doing the full integrity checking can be costly. Thus, HybrEx MapReduce provides quick integrity checking, where the private cloud selectively checks the integrity of the results from the public cloud. HybrEx MapReduce provides this mainly to check the integrity at runtime for probabilistic detection of suspicious activities in the public cloud. For this purpose, we store data items that we call inspection points in the private cloud. Inspection points can be either new synthetic data items that we add to the public data or existing public data items selected randomly for the purpose of verification. For example, for a MapReduce job that counts words in a public document, we can either add new unique words to the document or select existing words at random from the document, and store them in the private cloud. We can verify that the result from the public cloud contains the accurate counts of these words by running the same job in the private cloud with the inspection points. The frequency, overhead, and effectiveness of inspection points are our current subjects of investigation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Related Work</head><p>In addition to the previous work on cloud security, partitioning, and information flow control discussed in Section 1 and 3, the recent line of work on hybrid clouds, cloud accountability, security and privacy in MapReduce, and untrusted public clouds is closely related. Notably, CloudNet <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref> proposes a VPN-like network to provide secure and seamless resource integration between private and public clouds. The work on accountable virtual machines (AVM) <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref> proposes an accountability scheme for virtualized environments. Since the AVM approach is basically VM logging-andreplaying, it is effectively the same as our full integrity checking, potentially with more overhead. Airavat <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref> provides security and privacy guarantees in MapReduce by mandatory access control and differential privacy. Recent works such as Depot <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref> and SPORC <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref> also assume public clouds as an untrusted environment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusions and Future Work</head><p>In this paper, we start from the position that it is fundamentally difficult to secure public clouds, and then outline an execution model called the HybrEx model that uses partitioning of data and computation as a way to provide confidentiality and privacy. We discuss how we can realize this model in one specific execution environment, MapReduce over Bigtable.</p><p>We are currently implementing HybrEx MapReduce and HybrEx Bigtable. Moving forward, we believe that the HybrEx model could be useful for other execution environments such as VM-based hybrid clouds and smartphones interacting with clouds. We plan to explore the feasibility of applying the HybrEx model in these environments.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Fig. 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1: The Architecture of the HybrEx Model</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Fig. 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig. 2: Execution Categories for HybrEx MapReduce</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Fig- ure 2(c) depicts this category. In vertical partitioning, HybrEx MapReduce workers in the public cloud execute Map and Reduce tasks using public data as the input, shuffle intermediate data among them, and store the result in the public cloud. Workers in the private cloud do the same with private data. In general, HybrEx MapReduce can run a MapReduce job this way when the job can process private and public data in isolation. Many applications belong to this cate- gory such as separate indexing of private and public web pages of an organization, pattern search (grep), etc.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Fig. 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Fig. 3: The Architecture of HybrEx Bigtable unauthorized information (e.g., private data), and ii) how to reduce the wide-area communication overhead if the communications between private and public components are necessary and become a bottleneck. We discuss how we are addressing these issues in HybrEx Bigtable and HybrEx MapReduce.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Fig. 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Fig. 4: The Architecture of HybrEx MapReduce</figDesc></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> http://open.blogs.nytimes.com/2007/11/01/ self-service-prorated-super-computing-fun/</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> http://pig.apache.org/ 3 http://hive.apache.org/</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Formal Analysis of SAML 2.0 Web Browser Single Sign-On: Breaking the SAML-based Single Sign-On for Google Apps</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Armando</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACM FMSE</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bigtable: A Distributed Storage System for Structured Data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">USENIX OSDI</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Secure Web Applications via Automatic Partitioning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Chong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACM SOSP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">MapReduce: Simplified Data Processing on Large Clusters</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Dean</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ghemawat</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">USENIX OSDI</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Labels and Event Processes in the Asbestos Operating System</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Efstathopoulos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACM SOSP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Group Collaboration using Untrusted Cloud Resources</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Feldman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">USENIX OSDI</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fully Homomorphic Encryption Using Ideal Lattices</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Gentry</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACM STOC</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Accountable Virtual Machines</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Haeberlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">USENIX OSDI</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPAA)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="104" to="191" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Depot: Cloud Storage with Minimal Trust</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Mahajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">USENIX OSDI</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Decentralized Model for Information Flow Control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Myers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Liskov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACM SOSP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
				<ptr target="http://www.circleid.com/posts/20090226_cloud_computing_hype_security" />
		<title level="m">Survey: Cloud Computing &apos;No Hype&apos;, But Fear of Security and Control Slowing Adoption</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pci</forename><surname>Dss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.pcisecuritystandards.org/documents/pci_dss_v2.pdf" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Forecast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://gigaom.com/2010/01/01/on-the-rise-of-hybrid-clouds" />
		<title level="m">The Rise of Hybrid Clouds</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">You, Get Off of My Cloud: Exploring Information Leakage in Third-Party Compute Clouds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Ristenpart</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACM CCS</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Airavat: Security and Privacy for MapReduce</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Roy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">USENIX NSDI</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards Trusted Cloud Computing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Santos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">USENIX HotCloud</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">CloudBurst: Highly Sensitive Read Mapping with MapReduce</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Schatz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bioinformatics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1363" to="1369" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Keynote: Making Hadoop Enterprise Ready with Amazon Elastic MapReduce</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Sirota</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Hadoop Summit</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Case for Enterprise-Ready Virtual Private Clouds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Wood</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">USENIX HotCloud</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Untrusted Hosts and Confidentiality: Secure Program Partitioning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Zdancewic</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACM SOSP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using Replication and Partitioning to Build Secure Distributed Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IEEE Oakland</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
