<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/atharsefid/Desktop/grobid-0.5.3/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.3" ident="GROBID" when="2020-09-29T02:02+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Sleepless in Seattle No Longer</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joshua</forename><surname>Reich</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Columbia University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country>Microsoft Research</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michel</forename><surname>Goraczko</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Columbia University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country>Microsoft Research</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aman</forename><surname>Kansal</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Columbia University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country>Microsoft Research</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jitendra</forename><surname>Padhye</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Columbia University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country>Microsoft Research</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Sleepless in Seattle No Longer</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>In enterprise networks, idle desktop machines rarely sleep, because users (and IT departments) want them to be always accessible. While a number of solutions have been proposed, few have been evaluated via real deployments. We have built and deployed a lightweight sleep proxy system at Microsoft Research. Our system has been operational for six months, and has over 50 active users. This paper focuses on providing a detailed description of our implementation and test deployment , the first we are aware of on an operational network. Overall, we find that our lightweight approach effected significant energy savings by allowing user machines to sleep (most sleeping over 50% of the time) while maintaining their network accessibility to user satisfaction. However, much potential sleep was lost due to interference from IT management tasks. We identify fixing this issue as the main path to improving energy savings, and provide suggestions for doing so. We also address a number of issues overlooked by prior work, including complications caused by IPsec. Finally, we find that if certain cloud-based applications become more widely adopted in the enterprise, more specialized proxy reaction policies will need be adopted. We believe our experience and insights will prove useful in guiding the design and deployment of future sleep solutions for enterprise networks.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>A number of studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[30,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">41,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">6]</ref> have noted that most office machines are left on irrespective of user activity. At Microsoft Research, we find hundreds of desktop machines awake, day or night -a significant waste of both energy and money. Indeed, potential savings can amount to millions of dollars per year for large enterprises <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">[40]</ref>.</p><p>As businesses become more energy conscious, more desktops may be replaced by laptops. However, currently desktops comprise the majority of enterprise machines <ref type="bibr">[18]</ref>, with hundreds of millions additional desktops being sold every year <ref type="bibr">[22,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">27,</ref><ref type="bibr">18]</ref>. Where users make heavy use of local resources (e.g., programming, engineering, finance), desktops continue to be the platform of choice. Hence, managing desktop power consumption is an area of both active research <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[30,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">41,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">6]</ref> and commercial <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr">39,</ref><ref type="bibr">33]</ref> interest.</p><p>The most common reason that desktops are kept idling is that users and IT administrators want remote access to machines at will. Users typically want to log into their machines or access files remotely <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>, while IT administrators need remote access to backup, patch, and otherwise maintain machines. A number of solutions to this problem have been proposed <ref type="bibr">[33,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">6,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">30]</ref>. The core idea behind these is to allow a machine to sleep, while a sleep proxy maintains that machine's network presence, waking the machine when necessary. Some of these proposals rely on specialized NIC hardware <ref type="bibr">[33,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">3]</ref>; others advocate use of network-based proxies <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">30]</ref>.</p><p>Unfortunately, most previous work has been evaluated either using small testbeds <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">30,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">6]</ref> or trace-based simulations <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[30]</ref>. We are not aware of any paper detailing the deployment of any of these proxying solutions in an operational enterprise network on actual user machines. 1 This is disconcerting: systems that work well on testbeds often encounter potentially serious challenges when deployed in operational networks.</p><p>This paper aims to fill that gap. We describe the design and deployment of a network-based sleep proxy on our corporate network. Our design expands on the light-weight network proxy approach proposed in <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">30]</ref>, avoiding hardware modification <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref> and the overhead of virtualization <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17]</ref>. Our architecture comprises two core components: a per-subnet sleep proxy, and a sleep notifier program that runs on each client. The sleep notifier alerts the sleep proxy just before the client goes to sleep. In response, the proxy sends out ARP probes <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref> to ensure that all future traffic meant for the sleeping client is delivered to the proxy instead. The proxy then monitors this traffic applying a reaction policy: responding to some packets on the client's behalf, waking the sleeping client for certain specified traffic (using Wake-on-LAN (WOL) <ref type="bibr">[43]</ref> packets), and ignoring the rest. Our reaction policy of waking for incoming TCP connection attempts on listening ports was chosen both in keeping with our goal for a light-weight, easily deployable system and based on the performance predictions of <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[30]</ref>. We provide in-depth discussion of the merits of this and alternative approaches in Sec. 3.</p><p>Our system has been operational for over six months, and currently has over 50 active users. Our software is deployed on user's primary workstations, not test machines. Indeed, this preliminary deployment has been so successful that our IT department has begun recommending our system to users. We have instrumented our system extensively; capturing numerous details about sleep and wakeup periods, why machines wake up and why they stay up. Instead of using generic estimates of PC power con-sumption, we use a sophisticated software-based, modeldriven system, Joulemeter, to estimate power draw.</p><p>In this paper, we focus on providing a thorough description of our implementation and its performance in the wild. We describe a number of practical issues we encountered when deploying a light-weight sleep proxy in a corporate network, many of which have been overlooked by previous work. For example, our implementation must not only deal with vanilla IPv4 and IPv6 packets, but also tunneled packets. Our corporate network uses IPsec, and we find that a seemingly minor implementation choice in this setup, almost entirely ameliorates the overhead of dealing with this traffic. We describe race conditions that arise when the sleep proxy attempts to redirect traffic from sleeping client to itself, and provide a practical solution. We show how issues such as DHCP lease expiration and proxy failure can be handled without the need for a more complex reaction policy.</p><p>The highlights of our deployment experience and performance assessment are: A light-weight system using a simple reaction policy can produce significant savings. By analyzing trace data from our system, we find that our system allowed the clients to sleep quite well. Many machines slept over 50% of the time, despite use of a simple reaction policy. However, the average power savings was only 20%, casting a pall over the optimistic predictions made in <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[30,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">3]</ref>. IT servers and applications proved a major impediment to sleep. The main cause of reduced power savings in our enterprise network was due to the IT setup. We find that while users do access their machines remotely, remote accesses by IT applications are the primary cause of both machines being woken (fitful sleep) and being kept awake (insomnia). IT server connection attempts repeatedly woke sleeping machines. In one extreme case, a single machine was contacted over 400 times within a twoweek period. Additionally, some of the locally running IT applications (e.g., virus scanners) kept machines up by temporarily disabling sleep functionality. We also identify bugs in common software (e.g., Adobe Flash player) that interfere with proper sleeping. Fortunately, it appears there is significant room for improving the compatibility of IT setup and effective sleep. We discuss IT setup impediments and remedies further in Sec. 7.6. The rise of cloud-based applications may demand more complex reaction policies. Three of our users required support for two popular cloud-based applications, LiveMesh and LiveSynch. Machines running these, or similar, applications must initiate TCP connections to the cloud server, which are used to inform them of any pending updates. These connections can either be periodic, or long-lived, but it must be initiated by client. We refer to cloud applications of this type as persistent 2 . Con-2 Many cloud-based applications including most "software as a sersequently, to support such cloud-based applications the sleep proxy will need to keep some additional state which may be as simple as sending TCP keep-alives or as complex as running a virtualized client-side of the application. While this did not pose a major issue in our operational environment/population, as/where the predominance of persistent cloud applications increases, reaction policies supportive of this model will be needed.</p><p>Overall, we believe that the insights gleaned from our experience will be useful in guiding the design and deployment of future sleep solutions in enterprise networks.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related work</head><p>While the basic concept of sleep proxying has been known for some time <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref>, it has received much renewed attention lately <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">29,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">3]</ref>. Among recent publications, the two most closely related to our work are <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[29]</ref>.</p><p>In <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>, the authors describe a hardware-based solution. They augment the NIC with a GumStix <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[20]</ref> device, which is essentially a small form factor, low-powered PC. Once the host machine goes to sleep, the GumStix device takes over. It handles select applications (e.g., file downloads) on behalf of the host PC, but wakes up the host PC for more complex operations. While this approach is more flexible than the sleep proxy we have built, it is far less practical for two reasons. Not only is additional hardware required on every PC, but both applications and host OS modification are required to enable state transfer between host PC and GumStix device. Both these requirements are a substantial barrier to widespread deployment of this technology. In contrast, our approach requires neither extra hardware, nor application modifications.</p><p>In <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[29]</ref>, the authors carry out an extensive trace-based study of network traffic, arguing for a network-based sleep proxy. Their primary finding is that in an enterprise environment, broadcast and multicast traffic related to routing and service discovery cause substantial network 'chatter", most of which can be safely ignored by a sleep proxy. They also posit that most unicast traffic directed to a host after it has gone to sleep can also be ignored, so long as the host is woken when traffic meant for a set of pre-defined applications arrive (early work had focused on avoiding disrupting existing TCP connections <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">23]</ref>). Based on these insights, they propose a number of sleep proxy designs.</p><p>While our proxy design builds upon the insights of <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[29]</ref>, we make several additional contributions in this paper. First, unlike <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[29]</ref>, our design includes a client-side agent, which considerably simplifies the overall architecture, making it robust, and virtually configuration-free. Second, we build and deploy our sleep proxies in a real operational network on users' primary workstations. In contrast, the prototype in <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[29]</ref> was tested only a small testbed without real users, and did not address challenges such as IPsec traffic and proxy failures. Third, our instrumentation measures sleep and wakeup behavior of operational machines. We document why machines do not sleep, when and why they wake, etc. Fourth, our deployment includes a model-based power measurement competent. Since machine power usage can vary by 2.5x while awake, our power estimates provide significantly greater fidelity than the "one size fits all" model used by <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[29]</ref>.</p><p>Two pieces of concurrently published work address alternative sleep proxying architectures that make use of a networked sleep proxy. <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref> implements a stub-based reaction policy along the lines of <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref> and evaluates it in an academic network, while <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17]</ref> runs client machines within a hypervisor and migrates these to the sleep proxy machine. We provide further comparison in Sec. 3.3.</p><p>We now turn to commercial systems. Intel offers two hardware-based solutions, Remote Wakeup Technology (RWT) <ref type="bibr">[33]</ref> and Active Management Technology (AMT) <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>, that can remotely wake up a sleeping machine. AMT is primarily meant for management tasks (e.g., out of band access for asset discovery, remote troubleshooting). RWT is more closely related to our work. RWT requires the NIC of the sleeping machine to maintain a persistent TCP connection to an authorized server. The NIC wakes up the host machine upon receiving a special message over this TCP connection. RWT requires modification of client applications and works only with Intel hardware. Even the wakeup service has to be digitally signed by Intel. In contrast, our solution is entirely software-based, hardware-agnostic, and requires no application modification.</p><p>Apple has recently released a sleep proxy geared toward home networks that works only with select Apple hardware <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>. For enterprise networks, systems such as Adaptiva <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref> and Verdiem <ref type="bibr">[39]</ref> are available. The primary focus of these systems is to enable the system administrator to estimate power usage, and wake up sleeping machines to perform management tasks such as patching. A number of industry participants are trying to standardize basic sleep proxy functionality <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref>.</p><p>Several other approaches to saving power, such as power-proportional computing <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref>, dynamic voltage and frequency scaling <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[34]</ref>, the TickLess kernel <ref type="bibr">[37]</ref> and OSlevel power management <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[35]</ref> have been investigated, and can be used in conjunction with our system. Researchers have also looked at networking hardware and software stacks as potential targets for power savings. Examples include <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[21,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">30,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">11]</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">38,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">26]</ref> examine data center power consumption and savings approaches.</p><p>Prior work has shown that CPU utilization and certain performance counters can be used to estimate computer energy use <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[32,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">19]</ref>. Our power estimation technology provides enhanced accuracy by considering additional factors not considered in prior work, such as processor DVFS states and monitor power.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Design Goals &amp; Alternatives</head><p>As discussed earlier, enterprise users often do not let their machines sleep as they may require remote access. Our goal in deploying a sleep proxy is to encourage users to allow their machines to sleep -by ensuring their machine will wake on remote access attempts. We now describe the basic functionality required from a sleep proxy, define our design goals, and describe design alternatives. Before we begin, we note that our use of the term "sleep" refers to ACPI S3 (suspend to RAM) <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. Our system supports ACPI S4 (hibernate) and S5 (power off) as well.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Basic sleep proxy functionality</head><p>A sleep proxy detects when a sleep client machine (M ) has gone to sleep, typically because that machine's idle timeout had been reached. <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">3</ref> The proxy then monitors network traffic destined for M . Based on a pre-defined reaction policy, the sleep proxy will, (a) respond to some of the traffic on behalf of M (e.g. ARP requests for M ), (b) wake M for selected traffic (e.g. TCP SYNs for M ) and (c) ignore the remainder.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Design goals</head><p>Our goal is to build a practical, deployable sleep proxy for typical corporate networks, composed of desktop machines with wired connectivity. In a typical usage scenario, the user's machine goes to sleep, and wakes automatically on remote connection attempts.</p><p>The design of our sleep proxy was directed by four goals. (a) The system had to save as much power as possible, (b) while minimizing disruptions to users. It is critically important to ensure a sleeping machine is always woken when the user desires access: otherwise no one would use the system. Furthermore, the system had to be (c) easy to deploy and maintain, since we operated without the benefit of a large IT staff. We explicitly decided not to add hardware to client machines, as it makes deployment significantly harder. Finally, we required the architecture be (d) scalable and extensible, since the system had to operate in a dynamic live network It was not our goal to support laptops per se as they offered much less opportunity for power savings. They consume much less power when active, and are more often put to sleep by users. Thus, while some of the work we have done is applicable to laptops, we do not address laptop-specific challenges such as mobility in our work.</p><p>As all the machines in our network run Windows, some details of our implementation are Windows specific. However, our architecture is designed to be OS agnostic.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Design alternatives</head><p>We now consider three design alternatives, and evaluate them in light of our requirements.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.1">NIC Pattern Matching</head><p>The first potential approach is to simply use the combination of Wake-On-Pattern+ARP Offload. This capability is available on most modern wired NICs. How it works: The NIC effectively acts as the sleep proxy for the machine. It responds to incoming ARPs on behalf of the sleeping machine (ARP Offload), thereby maintaining the machine's network presence. The NIC can be programmed to detect specific patterns in incoming traffic, and wake up the host machine if a packet with specified pattern arrives (Wake-On-Pattern). The interface for specifying patterns <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[28]</ref> includes built-in support for IPv4 and IPv6 TCP-SYNs; one only need specify additional information (e.g., ports). Raw bit patterns can also be specified. Pros: These NICs are available on most modern machines, so no additional hardware needs to be deployed. Cons: We found that for our purposes the capabilities offered by these NICs were not adequate. Our corporate network is quite complex: it supports IPv4, IPv6, v6-over-v4 and requires IPsec. To ensure machines were woken whenever users required access, we had to handle packets requiring flexible inspection (e.g. a TCP SYN in an ESP packet carried in an IPv6 packet, tunneled in an IPv4 packet -Sec. 4.3.2). While such packets may be detected by explicit bit-pattern matching, the number of wakeup patterns needed is a multiple of the number of listening ports (to detect tunneled variations) plus several base patterns for standard WOL functionality. NICs on older machines can support as few as four wake patterns and are limited to detecting matches in the beginning of the packet which restricts the ability to detect tunneled packets. Moreover, future needs (e.g., support for persistent cloud applications) may dictate stateful reaction policies or deeper packet inspection, beyond current NIC capabilities. Thus, this approach fails criteria (b) and (d).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.2">Virtualization</head><p>How it works: Users install a hypervisor on their desktop, and then install and use a VM on top of the hypervisor <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17]</ref>. When the desktop machine needs to sleep, the VM is migrated to a hosting server. When necessary, (e.g. a CPU intensive application is run), the desktop machine is woken, and the VM migrated back. Pros: This approach is attractive because if the migration can be made seamless, the desktop does not have be woken up for transactions of even moderate complexity that can be carried out on the hosting server. As the machine can go to sleep without interrupting existing network connections, the machines can go to sleep much more often, and hence the power savings may be greater. Cons: To deploy a system based on this approach, we would have had to install hypervisor on the end user systems and boot their existing OS as a VM. Most users would not have agreed to such a drastic change to their work environment. Apart from taking a performance hit, virtualization may encounter problems with a number of common end-user devices (e.g., cameras, external drives), whose drivers do not always work well when virtualized.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.3">Network-Based Sleep Proxies</head><p>This approach was proposed in <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref>, its feasibility recently given careful study by <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[29]</ref>. How it works: This approach relies on a separate machine acting as a sleep proxy for the sleeping machine. The sleep proxy detects when a client goes to sleep. It then modifies Ethernet routing (Sec. 4.3.1) to ensure that all packets destined for the sleeping machine are delivered to the sleep proxy instead. The proxy examines the packets, and wakes up the sleeping client when needed, by sending a Wake-On-LAN (WOL) <ref type="bibr">[43]</ref> packet. Pros: Very little hardware support is required from the client machine -the client NIC only needs to support WOL. As the sleep proxy runs on a separate, general purpose computer, it has great flexibility in handling incoming traffic for the sleeping machine. The sleep proxy can do complex, conditional packet parsing and can even wake the sleeping machine based on non-network events such as requests by system administrators, users entering the building (with support from building access systems), etc. This design also scales well (Sec. 7.5.2). Cons: This design requires deployment of a sleep proxy on a separate machine (generally one per subnet supported). In most variations a client-side application must be installed as well.</p><p>We have chosen this approach as it is both very easy to deploy and requires minimal changes to user machines. It affords great scalability and flexibility as the sleep proxy can be changed without disturbing the client machines. We have chosen to use light-weight reaction policy which simplifies both client and proxy software complexity and allows a very large number of hosts to be handled by a single proxy. This reaction policy does cause existing network connections are broken. We argue that this is not an issue for typical corporate workloads (Sec. 4.4), although this may change if persistent cloud computing applications play a greater role in corporate environments.</p><p>Contrastingly, <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref> uses a stub-based reaction policy, capable of maintaining existing network connections and waking the host somewhat more infrequently. This comes at the cost of implementation complexity and will allow fewer clients to be hosted on a sleep proxy. Their implementation uses an ESX server that would preclude either low-power sleep proxies (Sec. 6) or peered proxying (Sec. 8). Their reaction policy faces the same impediments from sleep-unfriendly IT setups as ours -by far the main source of lost sleep opportunities in our environment -as IT tasks generally require waking clients. The overall architecture of our system is shown in Figure 1. We require one sleep proxy per subnet. We also required the clients to install a small background service 4 , sleep notifier. In this section, we will focus on the design of the sleep proxy and the sleep notifier which form the core of our solution. We discuss Joulemeter in Sec. 5.1</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Architecture</head><p>As discussed earlier, a sleep proxy responds to some traffic, wakes the sleep client for other traffic, and ignores the rest. Our choice of reaction policy is similar to that of the proxy scheme (proxy3), which <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[29]</ref> found provided the highest simulated power savings. This reaction policy, whose rationale is discussed in Sec. 4.4, responds mechanically to IP resolution requests (e.g., ARP) and wakes the sleep client only on TCP connection attempts to listening ports <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">5</ref> , ignoring other traffic.</p><p>Before digging into design details (Secs. 4.2 and 4.3), we provide a quick overview of how our system works.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">System Overview</head><p>Imagine a sleep client M running sleep notifier. M 's sleep notifier registers with the OS to receive notification when the machine is about to go to sleep. At such time, the OS alerts the sleep notifier. M 's sleep notifier then alerts the sleep proxy S that M is going to sleep, providing a list of M 's TCP ports in the listening state (actively listening for incoming connections). Assume that the SSH port, 22, is one such port.</p><p>Upon receiving the notification, S adds M to its list of proxied clients and sends out an ARP probe (Sec. 4.3.1), re-mapping the switched Ethernet to direct future packets for M to the network port at which S resides. S now begins receiving traffic that was meant for M . S responds to ARP requests and IPv6 Neighbor Discovery packets as if it were M , thereby maintaining M 's network presence and ensuring traffic for M continues to arrive at S.</p><p>Some time later a remote client C attempts to connect to the sleeping machine M , using SSH. As the first transport-layer action taken in establishing this new connection, C sends a TCP SYN on port 22 to M which the switched Ethernet routes to S.</p><p>Upon examining the packet, S determines that it is a TCP SYN meant for M and destined to a port on which M was listening when it when to sleep. S therefore wakes M up by sending it a WOL packet (Sec. 3.3.3), removes M from the proxied client list, and drops the TCP SYN. As M wakes up, it sends its own ARP probes, which ensure that future traffic meant for M will arrive at M 's network port. Meanwhile, C retransmits this SYN following the normal TCP timeout. The retransmitted SYN arrives at M , who responds as normal, thereby establishing the TCP connection without C being any the wiser, except for a small delay -quantified in Sec. 7.5.1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">The Sleep Notifier</head><p>Installing the sleep notifier on sleep clients greatly simplifies the overall design. As the service runs on user desktops, our aim is to make the sleep notifier code robust and stateless, requiring as simple configuration as possible.</p><p>The primary purpose of the sleep notifier is to notify the sleep proxy when the machine is going to sleep. Just before a machine is put to sleep, the Windows OS sends out a 'get ready for sleep" (a Win32 PowerManagementEvent) event to all the processes and drivers running on a machine, allowing them to prepare for sleep. The sleep notifier registers to receive this event. Upon receiving the event, the notifier immediately broadcasts a sleep notification packets (encapsulated in a UDP packet to port 9999), containing a "going-to-sleep" opcode and list of the sleep client's listening TCP ports, to the subnet broadcast address. For reliability it retransmits the packet three times.</p><p>In keeping with our light-weight approach, sleep notification packets are broadcast. The sleep client does not need to know the identity of the sleep proxy and requires no configuration nor stable storage, as there is no state to be kept. The sleep notification packet obviates the need for active probing sleep clients to determine sleep status (as done in <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[29]</ref>) or which ports should be proxied ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[29]</ref> restricted proxied ports to a manually pre-configured set).</p><p>Since the sleep notifier may have less than two seconds in which to send the sleep notification packet before the machine falls asleep 6 , it is possible, albeit unlikely, that the notification packets will not be sent in time. Consequently, the sleep notifier also sends out periodic heartbeats when the machine is awake. These heartbeats are identical to the sleep notification packet, save that they use a "heartbeat" opcode. In our current implementation, heartbeats are sent out every 5 minutes, with some jittering. When the sleep proxy misses two consecutive heartbeats from a client, it immediately sends a WOL packet to that client. If, after sending the WOL, neither a heartbeat nor a sleep notification is subsequently received from the client, the proxy assumes that the machine has left the network and removes it from the list of proxied sleep clients.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">The Sleep Proxy</head><p>The sleep proxy needs to monitor incoming traffic to the sleep client and also wake that client by sending a WOL packet on the subnet broadcast address <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">7</ref> . Redirecting traffic destined for a given machine to another machine outside of its local subnet requires substantial support from routers. Thus, the sleep proxy has to run either on the subnet router itself, or on some other subnet machine. Running a sleep proxy on the subnet router was not possible, so we use one dedicated machine per subnet to act as a sleep proxy for machines in those subnets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.1">Rerouting</head><p>Like most enterprise networks, our network is a switched Ethernet network. Thus, unicast traffic for a host is not generally visible to other hosts on the network. Thus, upon receiving the sleep notification from a client, the sleep proxy needs to ensure that the traffic destined for sleeping clients is re-routed to the sleep proxy's NIC.</p><p>While there are a few ways to affect such re-routing, we have found sending ARP probes <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref>, as shown in <ref type="figure">Fig.  2</ref>, to be the most reliable method. A machine uses these ARP probes to advertise its MAC and IP address, and to perform duplicate address detection (DAD). Also, the subnet switches refresh/remap their internal routing tables upon receiving these probes.</p><p>Thus, when a sleep proxy receives a sleep notification from a client, it issues specially crafted ARP probes pretending to be the sleep client (refer again to <ref type="figure">Fig. 2</ref>  <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>: ARP probe for sleep client M This ensures that subsequent network traffic meant for the sleeping machine is delivered to the sleep proxy instead. <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">8</ref> When a sleeping machine wakes (either because the sleep proxy woke it, or because it was woken for some other reason), it will naturally send out a fresh set of ARP probes generated by the OS to ensure that it can re-use the same IP address that it had before it went to sleep. This has two nice side effects. First, the subnet switches now begin forwarding traffic meant for the sleeping (and now awake) machine, back to that machine, instead of the sleep proxy. Second, as these probes are broadcast, the sleep proxy can see them, allowing it to immediately recognize when clients have woken and cease proxying.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.2">Reaction Policy</head><p>As discussed earlier our sleep proxy reaction policy responds to IP address resolution traffic, examines incoming TCP connection attempts, and ignores all other traffic. This means that (a) current TCP connections are broken and (b) UDP applications are not supported.</p><p>Intuitively, the former would seem to be a safe strategy for many applications. The sleep proxy is not responsible for putting a machine to sleep. That decision is taken by the local OS. If the local OS deemed it safe to put a machine to sleep while it had TCP connections open, then clearly the applications to which those TCP connections correspond have not placed requests to prevent sleep (a standard feature of modern OSes). Moreover, most common corporate network applications are inherently disconnection tolerant (e.g., email, web browser).</p><p>As for the latter, in our network, practically all desktop applications use TCP. Users typically access their machines either via SMB (to retrieve files) or via Remote Desktop. Upon initiation, both these applications start new TCP connections, and hence send corresponding SYNs. Routine maintenance is handled via RPC calls, and this traffic also goes over TCP. Additionally, it given the flexible parsing power of our sleep proxy, it should not be difficult to extend our technique to cover UDP traffic meant to initiate new connections for particular applications requiring such (e.g., NFS version 2).</p><p>The impact of ignoring non-TCP traffic and breaking currently existing TCP is difficult to estimate empirically. <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">8</ref> An alternate way of doing this would be to replace M.M AC ADDR with the sleep proxy's MAC address, however this could cause the DAD mechanism to be triggered if the sleep client were to wake very quickly after sleep.</p><p>However, we believe the proof is in the pudding: after months of running our code, none of our users or IT staff have complained that their machines did not wake on remote access and the only applications which we received request support for were the two cloud-based applications run by a small minority of users. <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[29]</ref> provides a more detailed discussion of our reaction policy and comparison with other possibilities.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Implementation Challenges</head><p>IPsec: Responding to IP address resolution traffic is easy: the sleep proxy simply issue ARP responses and Neighbor Discovery advertisements as if it were the sleeping client. Handling TCP connection attempts is more complicated. To detect an incoming TCP connection attempt the sleep proxy must examine the packet's IP header confirming it was destined to a currently proxied machine, and contains a TCP SYN with a destination port on which that machine had been listening. While it is easy to parse a TCP SYN contained in a vanilla IPv4 or IPv6 packet, our network (like most corporate networks) is more complicated in both its use of IPv6 tunneling and IPsec ESP authentication <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">9</ref> . Tunneling comes in three flavors, ISATAP, 6over4, and Teredo <ref type="bibr">[36]</ref>. Our current implementation handles ISATAP and 6over4. ISATAP packets are already unwrapped for the sleep proxy by the ISATAP router and arrive as IPv6 packets on the sleep client's ISATAP IPv6 address. Thus these packets require no additional processing. 6over4 packets arrive as IPv4 packets whose next protocol is 6over4. The inner packet is then removed and parsed as a standard IPv6 packet. Our current implementation does not handle Teredo wrapping, since it is being phased out in favor of the first two mechanisms.</p><p>The use of IPsec <ref type="bibr">[42]</ref> presents a number of challenges. Imagine a remote machine C trying to connect to sleeping machine M using TCP. Let S be the sleep proxy. If IPsec is in use, there are two possibilities. Either C has not communicated with M in recent past, or it has.</p><p>If C has not recently communicated with M it would first try to establish a new security association by doing IPsec key exchange (IKE). The IKE packets are sent via UDP. The IKE sent by C end up at S. Recall, however, that our sleep proxy wakes up packets only on receiving TCP SYNs. Thus, the sleep proxy would never wake up M . However, Windows optimizes connection establishment by requiring C to send a TCP SYN "in the clear" as it begins the key exchange <ref type="bibr">[42]</ref>. This is done to speed up the connection establishment: TCP handshake can happen in parallel with IPsec handshake. This works in our favor: the sleep proxy can detect the TCP SYN transmit-ted by C, and wake up M , which can then finish the key exchange. Otherwise, M would need to be woken for every IKE attempt. As we shall see later, in our network this would have lead to many spurious wake-ups.</p><p>Conversely, if C has recently communicated with M , it may have cached the security association information. Since our network uses Encapsulated Security Payload (ESP) <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[25]</ref> protocol, C would encrypt the TCP SYN it sends. While the TCP SYN would end up at S, there is no way for S to decode the packet. This would have been incompatible with our reaction policy, except that our network uses ESP only with integrity service: the payload itself is not encrypted. Thus, S can parse the packet, inspect it, and wake M if needed.</p><p>Thus by choosing an IPsec setup in which both ESP payload encryption is disabled and enabling TCP connection establishment optimization, the need for running a heavier-weight reaction policy is ameliorated. ARP probe timing: The sleep proxy cannot simply send out ARP probes as soon as it receives the sleep notification from a client, as that client may send other packets before the network card sleeps. If ARP probes from the sleep proxy intermingle with traffic generated from the client that is about to fall asleep, the spanning tree protocol may end up in state where packets meant for the sleeping machine are not routed to the sleep proxy. In our early implementations, this problem created much heartache.</p><p>To avoid this problem, after receiving the sleep notification, the sleep proxy begins pinging that sleep client. The sleep proxy waits for five consecutive ping failures before sending out ARP probes and thereby taking over for the sleeping client. Daily wakeup &amp; DHCP lease expiration: Currently, the sleep proxy wakes all sleeping clients at 5AM. The primary reason is to allow these machines to initiate any backup or scanning activity. The wakeup also obviates the need for the sleep proxy to handle DHCP traffic on behalf of the clients. In our network, DHCP leases are valid for 30 days. When the client is awake, it renews the lease every day. Furthermore, it also renews the lease when it wakes up. As each client is guaranteed to wake up at least once a day, we did not need to implement DHCP renewal on our sleep proxy. The same mechanism also protects against address black-holing: whereby a sleep proxy keeps holding on to the address of a machine that has departed the network. If heartbeats are not seen for a sleep client after the daily wakeup, that machine is inferred to have left the network (as described earlier). Failure of sleep proxy: In our current implementation, each subnet is served by a single sleep proxy. This creates a single point of failure. We have designed, but not yet implemented a primary-backup solution for ensuring additional reliability. Another possibility is to design a purely peer-to-peer solution (Sec. 8). Our design does offer protection against a sleep proxy crashing, and restarting. The sleep proxy stores the MAC addresses of all the machines that it is proxying for in a log maintained on non-volatile network storage. Upon restarting, the sleep proxy checks the log, and proactively wakes up all the machines by sending them WOL packets. This ensures that the sleep proxy starts operations in a consistent state. Multi-homed machines: The sleep proxy architecture can easily handle multi-homed machines as long as (i) the sleep notification goes out on all interfaces and (ii) a sleep proxy is available on each network that receives incoming connection attempts. Manual wakeup: Apart from the "automatic" wakeup described so far, we also provide for remote, manual wakeup of sleeping clients. This is achieved by maintaining a website outside our corporate firewall. Every sleep proxy maintains an open TCP connection to this web server. Users can type in the name of their machine on this website. The web service sends the name to every sleep proxy, and if a sleep proxy has the specified machine as a client, it wakes that machine up by sending it a magic packet. This service provides a "last resort" wakeup alternative and also allowed the small minority of cloud application users to manually reconnect cloud apps.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Instrumentation</head><p>Our sleep proxy keeps a detailed log of its interactions with clients, including when and why the clients go to sleep or wake up. On client side, we use Joulemeter, to estimate the power consumption of the clients, and gather information about why clients stay awake. Joulemeter is installed as a separate, optional service on clients.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Monitoring power consumption</head><p>To quantify the energy savings of our approach, we desired an accurate method of estimating our deployment's power consumption. Different machine makes and models consume power at differing rates. Further, a given machine consumes vastly different power depending on its CPU utilization level, P-state and whether its monitors are on or off. For instance, the power usage of an HP xw4300 workstation with two monitors varied from 141W to 240W with processor utilization, and changed by an additional 120W with monitor power state for a total variation of 2.5X.</p><p>However, desktop workstations do not typically have built-in instrumentation to measure power usage, and we wished to avoid attaching external power-meters to each machine for the same reasons we rejected hardware augmented sleep proxying approaches. Consequently, we used a software solution, Joulemeter, that produces power usage estimates based on hardware activity and pre-calibrated machine models. The key principle behind Joulemeter's energy estimation is to use a machine specific power model. The model consists of a set of equations that relate the hardware configuration and resource utilization levels to power usage. Our current model takes into account processor Pstates, processor utilization, disk I/O levels, and whether the monitor(s) are on or off. The power model for a specific hardware configuration is learned via calibrationcontrolled experiments in a laboratory settings. Once the power model is known, the machine's power consumption at run time can be estimated by monitoring CPU utilization (and P-state), disk utilization and monitor status. We omit the details of model construction due to lack of space. For a preliminary introduction see <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[24]</ref>. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Fig. 3</ref> shows Joulemeter estimates versus measured power consumption (using a hardware power meter) for a HP d530 workstation with 2.66GHz Pentium CPU running a workload generator that loaded the CPU and disk at random. The estimates were generated using the calibrated model produced from a different workstation with the same model and CPU. The results shown confirm Joulemeter's estimates track closely with the actual power consumption. In practice, no two systems are exactly alike. Still, in validation testing we found Joulemeter predictions to be accurate within 20%</p><p>In our deployment Joulemeter generated power readings were averaged over 30 second intervals and periodically uploaded to the database. We have built up a library of power models covering most of our client machines.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Monitoring machine insomnia</head><p>To determine why a machine is awake, Joulemeter relies on two sources. First, it periodically checks the lastUserInput timer provided by the OS. This timer provides the time of last user activity. We compare the value of this timer to the idle timeout (a typical Windows default value is 30 minutes). If user activity has occurred more recently than the idle timeout, we assume that the machine is being kept awake by user activity. We note that due to various technical issues this timer is not always available, so we cannot always determine whether the user is active.</p><p>We also find that machines often stay awake even when the idle period exceeds this duration. To determine the reasons behind this, we rely on powercfg.exe utility that ships as part of Windows 7. The utility can often (but not always) shed light on why a machine is staying up by detailing requests to the OS for the machine to remain awake. For example, a remote machine may be holding a file open or a defragmenting routine may be running. Joulemeter periodically collects this information and reports it to the central database. Analysis of this information is presented in Sec. 7.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Implementation and Deployment</head><p>Our deployment consisted of 6 proxies (one for each of our network's 6 wired subnets), 51 clients, an SQL database, and the manual wakeup webservice mentioned earlier (standard IIS webserver with code written using ASP.NET). Most of the code is written in C# (5000 lines).</p><p>Only the sleep proxy contains any significant amount of unmanaged code. The sleep proxy relies on PCAP to capture and examine incoming packets. A small custom driver allows the sleep proxy to craft and inject ARP probes while bypassing the network stack. The primary data structure in the sleep proxy is a hashtable used to keep track of clients and their status. We first used ordinary desktop machines as proxies and have begun migrating to the low-powered, small-form-factor machines drawing less than 25 watts of power.</p><p>On client side, apart from the required sleep notifier service, the clients install three optional applications: Joulemeter, a GUI program displaying sleep statistics and estimated energy savings, and an auto-updater service that keeps client-side code up-to-date. During client installation, we ensured that Wake-On-LAN was enabled and ARP offload (which is enabled by default for certain cards in Windows 7) was disabled on the client's NIC. We also set the idle timeout to 30 minutes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Results</head><p>This section is guided by several overarching questions. What is the sleep and wake behavior of machines in our system? How much power did our solution save? What might be done to obtain additional power savings? What impact did our setup have on user experience? Was the sleep proxy architecture scalable? For the impatient reader, we highlight our main insights at this section's end (Sec. 7.6).</p><p>We begin by describing the details of our dataset.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.1">Dataset Overview</head><p>While our deployment has been active for half a year in various stages, for the rest of this section we focus on the 45 day period from November 19th, 2009 through January 3, 2010. During this time, we gathered data from 51 distinct machines belonging to 50 distinct users. As users installed our software at differing times, not all machines provided data for the entire period (although most did). <ref type="figure">Fig. 4(a)</ref> shows the cumulative distribution of trace </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.1.1">Machines in our study</head><p>As we noted in Sec. 5.1, machine power consumption depends on the particulars of that machine's hardware configuration. The hardware configuration of machines in our deployment was varied, but not overly so. Of the 51 machines, 43 are HP and 6 were Dell. Only one of the machines has an AMD processor, the rest having Intel CPUs. Most of the machines are dual or quad cored. The CPU frequencies vary from 2-3.4GHz. Twenty seven machines had one monitor, 20 had two, and five had three. Five machines ran Windows Vista, all the rest ran Windows 7.</p><p>As we wake up machines for incoming TCP SYNs only on listening ports, it is worth examining the number of listening TCP ports on each machine. This number, of course, varies over time, as active processes and settings change. <ref type="figure">Fig. 4(b)</ref> shows the min, max, and average number of listening ports by machine. One machine had 35 ports open simultaneously!</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.1.2">Traffic</head><p>Since all traffic destined for sleeping clients arrives at their sleep proxies, we can examine this traffic in centralized manner, without installing sniffers on individual machines. While we have deployed a sleep proxy on each of our six subnets, 59% of our machines are connected to the largest subnet. We have seen as many as 800 active machines on this subnet. We examined in detail a trace of all (23 million) packets arriving at the sleep proxy serving this subnet during a typical work week (5.5 days).</p><p>Of this traffic, 96% were multicast and broadcast packets. Of the multicast packets, 12.31% were ARP requests, which the sleep proxy examined and replied to as needed. The vast majority of the multicast traffic was safely ignorable <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[29]</ref>. The remaining 4% traffic was unicast: destined either to the proxy itself, or to the sleeping clients. 75% of these packets were wrapped by ESP and 8.4% were tunneled v6-over-v4 packets -underscoring the importance of parsing such packets. 7% of the total unicast packets were UDP (mostly IPsec related) and 3% were ICMP, which the sleep proxy ignores. Most of the remaining traffic was TCP, and the proxy was able to ignore the vast majority of it. During this time, we woke sleeping clients for just 747 TCP SYNs. Our analysis of the traffic data confirmed the importance of filtering TCP SYNs based on port. More than half of incoming TCP connection attempts were destined to ports on which the sleep client was not listening. If we had woken clients without filtering by port, we would have had more spurious wake-ups than valid ones.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.2">Sleep/Wake Behavior</head><p>We note that five of our 51 clients did not sleep at all, as their their users manually disabled sleep functionality. <ref type="figure">Fig. 5(a)</ref> shows the percentage of time each machine spent sleeping, as a CDF across all machines. The uniform slope of the CDF demonstrates that the average sleep time was quite variable, with 50% of the clients sleeping more than half the time. <ref type="figure">Fig. 5(b)</ref> plots the CDF of the average number of sleep-to-wake transitions per day for the machines. Most machines average fewer than seven daily wake-ups. Later, we will see that most of these wake-ups were caused by IT management traffic (e.g., updates) arriving for a sleeping machine.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.2.1">Aggregate sleep/wake behavior</head><p>We now examine the duration of sleep and awake intervals. Note that no sleep interval is longer than 1440 minutes because of the daily 5AM wakeup. The CDF of length of sleep and wake intervals is shown in <ref type="figure">Fig. 5(c)</ref>, while <ref type="figure">Fig. 5(d)</ref> shows the time-weighted CDF (i.e., contribution of intervals at or below a given length to the total sleep or wake time). By comparing these two figures, we see that while most sleep and awake intervals are under one hour, the majority of both sleep and awake time comprises intervals over one hour. This implies that insomnia should be our first focus in attempting to reduce power usage (Sec. 7.3.2).</p><p>The awake interval CDF in <ref type="figure">Fig. 5</ref>(c) demonstrates a bimodal distribution with abrupt changes in slope at around two minutes, and at 30 minutes. This indicates that awake periods of two and 30 minutes are prevalent in our trace.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.2.2">Individual sleep/wake behavior</head><p>Figs. 6(b) and 6(a) show the 10th, 50th, and 90th percentile of wake and sleep intervals for each machine. The machines are sorted in order of 10th percentile. Notably, for around half of the machines the 10th percentile lies around two minutes, while for other half it lies around 30 minutes, corresponding to the jumps seen in <ref type="figure">Fig. 5(c)</ref>.</p><p>We closely inspected a number of these awake periods. The prevalence of both two and 30 minute awake periods is easily understood: these being the idle timeouts after WOL wakeup and user activity respectively. When looking at our special 5AM wakeup (which we know was not user-initiated -Sec. 4.4) we saw a much greater than normal proportion of two minute wakes which is precisely what we would expect. shows that for about a quarter of the machines, the median sleep interval is under 10 minutes. For one machine all sleep intervals were under a minute. This machine appears to have some driver configuration issue that causes almost immediate wake upon sleep and was unique in our data set. Such intervals add very little to overall sleep duration and indicate potential sleep problems which will be examined further in Sec. 7.3. <ref type="figure">Fig. 7(a)</ref> shows the causes of wake-ups. We divide these into three categories: manual wake-up using our web site, wake-up by proxy due to incoming traffic, and other. The last bucket includes wake-ups caused by users walking up to the machine, any timer-based wake-ups caused by the BIOS, as well as occasional WOL packets sent by a commercial wakeup solution being tested by our IT department. We were able to confirm for 33% of these that the user did in fact initiate wakeup (by checking lastUserInput -Sec. 5.2) and for 50% of these the user definitively did not wake the machine. The remaining 27% could not be determined as lastUserInput was unavailable.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.2.3">Why do machines wake up?</head><p>We see that while the web site was used in a few cases, it is not statistically significant. The majority of wakeups caused by the sleep proxy are due to incoming TCP SYNs. The ports to which these SYNs were destined to are shown in <ref type="figure">Fig. 7(b)</ref>.</p><p>Remote Procedure Calls (port 135) were the overwhelmingly largest source of wakeup triggers, followed  <ref type="formula">(445)</ref>. SMB is the main mechanism used for remote file system access in our network. The two other notable ports are UPnP (2869) and Remote Desktop (3389). In our network, Remote Desktop is the primary mechanism for interactive remote machine access. We can see Remote Desktop is not a major wakeup source. In fact, only 39% of the machines were ever woken up due to Remote Desktop requests. Therefore, it would seem that while users leave their machines on for potential remote access, interactive remote access is used relatively rarely.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.2.4">Who wakes up machines?</head><p>There were slightly over 300 IP addresses requesters whose incoming connection attempts caused wake-ups. Most of these only attempted to connect to a single sleep client. However, a sizable minority attempted to connect to multiple clients as seen in <ref type="figure">Fig. 8(a)</ref>. We were able to verify that all the requesters who woke 20 or more sleep clients were machines belonging to our IT department. These machines perform a variety of management actions such as verifying patch status and checking security policies. We will see later that our IT configuration is sleep-unfriendly in other ways as well (Sec. 7.3.2). <ref type="figure">Fig. 8(b)</ref> shows the number of wakeup events caused by requester. Just as most requesters only connect to a single machine, many only cause only one wakeup and most cause only a handful. However, again a large minority of requesters cause many wake-ups each. IT-owned machines again make a large portion of this group. Interestingly, several of the most active requesters actually connect to only one or a handful of machines. In fact, the most active requester with over 400 requests connected to only two machines, and that too in in a span of just two weeks! We are currently investigating the role of this requester further.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.3">Why Machines Don't Sleep Better</head><p>While we have seen that our solution is fairly successful at enabling machines to sleep <ref type="figure">(Fig. 5(a)</ref>), we wanted to investigate whether more idle time could be harvested. We begin by noting that most machines are not being woken overly often <ref type="figure">(Fig. 5(b)</ref>). However, a small subset of machines suffer from "crying-baby-syndrome" being woken as soon as they fall asleep. Sec. 7.2.4. These machines are being bombarded by frequent connection attempts that interrupt their sleep often. If a machine with a standard 30 minute idle timeout wakes 12 times a day, one quarter of the day will have been spent awake due to wake-ups alone. It appears that configuration issues are responsible for much of this behavior.</p><p>However, most sleep clients are being kept awake for other reasons the majority of the time. In fact, when not being kept awake, these machines manage to sleep well, sustaining few wakeup events per day. We now consider whether these machines would have benefited from a more aggressive idle timeout, and then look at the problem of insomniac machines.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.3.1">Aggressive idle timeout</head><p>As mentioned in Sec. 7.2.2, it appears that setting the idle timeout more aggressively could result in some power savings. We now consider how much could be saved with a 5-minute idle timeout (this is 1/3rd the EnergyStar guidelines recommendation <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref>).</p><p>To do so, we examined each wake interval to see why the machine was being kept up. Recall from Sec. 5.2 that a machine may be kept awake because the user is active, the machine has woken up recently, or a stay-awake request placed by a local application with the OS.</p><p>We divided the total awake time into three components, recoverable, unknown, and unrecoverable. Recoverable time was time in which the machine could have slept if the idle timeout had been set more aggressively. This time was the sum of periods in which the user had been active within the past five minutes or the machine had been woken within the past five minutes. The unknown time was the time for which insufficient data was available to diagnose cause of wakefulness. The unrecoverable time consisted of all other time (i.e., an application had placed a stay-awake request with the OS). Thus the recoverable time is a lower bound on the awake time that could have been saved by setting a more aggressive idle timeout. The sum of recoverable and unknown time provides the upper bound. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Fig. 9</ref> breaks the total wake time as percentage of uptime into these three components on a per-machine basis. We see that on most machines the impact would be relatively small. These machines are being kept up by local application stay-awake requests, to which we now turn.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.3.2">Insomnia</head><p>We now look more closely at which local applications keep machines awake. We label this phenomenon insomnia. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 10(a)</ref> plots the fraction of awake time a given machine was kept awake by local applications requesting OS to prevent sleep. We see that the majority of awake time is in fact due to such stay-awake requests. So which applications cause these stay-awake requests? <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig.  10(b)</ref> shows the percentage of requests initiated by various applications. The news here is heartening. Four of the top sources (Security Policy Agent, Windefend, Forefront, and Bitlocker) are all applications mandated by our IT department. It may be possible to reconfigure or even re-write these applications to minimize and coordinate the duration of time they are active (and thus preventing sleep). At least three more (Flash, Quicktime and Audio Stream) are the result of code or driver bugs. For example, certain older versions of Flash player may keep a machine awake by playing silence even after the audio clip has finished (Windows prevents sleep when audio streams are active). The third-highest request source is SMB. SMB's default behavior prevents a machine whose files are being accessed from sleeping. Careful changes to this behavior may allow for greater sleep opportunities.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.4">Power savings</head><p>PC consumption varied, averaging from 89-143W for individual machines. The lowest draw we saw was 50W idling. The highest was 191W heavily loaded. While sleeping, all machines drew 1-2W. Monitors generally added from 30-60W when on. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 11</ref>(a) illustrates the lower bound on power savings on a per machine basis. This lower bound is calculated with the assumption that had the machine stayed up instead of sleeping, it would have consumed power at the lowest rate seen in the entire non-sleeping portion of the trace. This represents part of the reason we saw less power savings than that predicted by previous work (which assumed machines consumed power at a constant rate irrespective of activity level). The average across all machines is about 20%, although variation is considerable. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 11</ref>(b), shows aggregate power consumption for a both a representative one-week period beginning 12/3/09 and the winter break (beginning 12/24/09). During the representative week, weekend power consumption is low, spiking only at the 5AM wakeup. During the work-week, power use peaks during the work day before declining into an overnight trough and bottoms out early on Friday. In contrast we can see a markedly different pattern for the Mid-Winter week with almost no increase in activity during the day from the day preceding Christmas (which fell on Friday) through the following Monday. By the Tuesday following the holiday, we begin to see a similar level of activity to that of the representative week, albeit at a lower amplitude, as employees begin returning from the holiday. Interestingly, the power consumption over the Christmas weekend (12/26-12/27) weekend was slightly higher than during a normal weekend (12/5-12/6).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.5">Micro-Benchmarks</head><p>We now validate our architectural approach by examining wakeup delay time and sleep proxy scalability.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.5.1">Wakeup delay</head><p>The energy saved by our system comes at a cost: the user experiences additional startup latency the first time a connection (e.g., ssh login or samba file access) to a sleep  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 11</ref>: Power Draw and Savings client is attempted since that client fell asleep. This happens because sleep client takes time to both wake and begin responding to an incoming TCP connection attempt. To make the system usable, we need to minimize the startup latency encountered by interactive transactions. The user-perceived startup latency consists of several components: the delay involved in sending the WOL magic packet, the time required to wake up the machine, and the time required to perform any applicationspecific actions. To quantify these component latencies, we present a simple, but representative example.</p><p>Two machines, M1 and M2 were connected to the same subnet. M1 was ran a simple TCP sink, and was put to sleep. Thereafter, sleep proxy S1 started proxying for M1. From M2, we attempted to establish a TCP connection to the the sink on M1. The packet trace of the connection establishment is summarized in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>.</p><p>The total latency is about 8.5 seconds, but the sleep proxy itself consumes only 40 milliseconds, even though it is on a busy subnet and proxying for several other machines. The largest component is the wake-up delay (i.e., time required for M2 to wake up and become active). This is roughly the delay between steps 2 and 4 (about 5.5 seconds). The remaining TCP-retransmit delay occurs between steps 4 and 5 (about 3 seconds). This delay is incurred while M1 waits to retransmit the TCP SYN the second time, following regular TCP timeout algorithm <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[31]</ref>.</p><p>Specific applications will usually encounter slightly higher latencies, as the machine needs to perform additional, application-specific actions. For example, when M1 tried to list a directory on M2 via SMB, the transaction took 13.37 seconds when M2 was asleep. The additional delay was incurred while M2 re-connected with the domain controller, and obtained security credentials to determine whether to allow M1 access.</p><p>We stress that this delay is incurred only for the transaction that wakes the machine. Subsequent transactions experience normal latencies. While our experience is that users do not mind this one-off penalty, both the wake-up and retransmit delays can be addressed. A number of research and engineering efforts are underway to address the former. The latter can be shortened either by having M1 retransmit TCP SYN more aggressively, or having S1 "replay" the TCP SYN.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.5.2">Scalability</head><p>Our current deployment uses one sleep proxy per subnet. The load on these sleep proxies is a potential concern. We find that the CPU load on a sleep server rarely exceeds 5%. The total traffic (broadcast inclusive) seen by the sleep server is also quite low (90th percentile is 250Kbps). We conclude sleep proxy operations do not require substantial resources, and a single sleep proxy could easily handle very large subnets if necessary. Conversely for reasonably sized subnets, the sleep proxy could be located on a client machine without noticeably degrading the user experience (Sec. 8).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.6">Summary</head><p>Insomnia is the foremost cause of lost sleep. Thus improving the energy savings of systems like ours, the main focus should be on addressing sources of wakefulness. IT applications are the main source of both insomnia and fitful sleeping. Several uncoordinated IT applications for patching, security, and network testing all woke machines and kept them awake. While we studied one particular IT setup, practically all IT setups will interfere with sleep to some extent -dependent on quantity, aggressiveness and degree of coordination of IT applications. Misconfiguration can result in crying-baby syndrome Requiring administrators to diagnose and resolve the minority of machines suffering this issue. Use of more aggressive idle timeouts is of secondary benefit. In enterprise systems behind firewalls, wakeups will occur because of valid incoming TCP connection attempts and in well configured setups, the number of wakeups caused by IT/misconfiguration will be minimal. Thus savings from more aggressive idle timeouts will be minor. Incoming TCP connection attempts need to be filtered by listening port. More incoming TCP connection attempts arrived for non-listening ports, than listening ones.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8">Conclusion &amp; Future Work</head><p>We have designed and deployed a light-weight networkbased sleep proxy in an operation enterprise network on over 50 user workstations -the first such deployment of which we are aware. During our work, we uncovered and addressed several practical issues that must be addressed by light-weight sleep proxying systems in enterprise networks. Our system has functioned both to user satisfaction and our own specification for the past several months, providing significant sleep opportunities and power savings using a simple reaction policy. However, we find that significantly more power savings could be achieved by altering the IT setup. Additionally, certain classes of cloud applications require specialized reaction policies. Should use of such persistent cloud applications become more widespread, our reaction policy would need adjustment.</p><p>We conclude with a brief discussion of future possibilities and concerns. IT application coordination and configuration: Currently IT maintenance tasks are uncoordinated and consequently will keep machines awake during each of their separate execution time periods. Devising methodologies that schedule these tasks to overlap as much as possible can significantly increase sleep opportunities. P2P sleep proxy: Our current setup requires the use of a dedicated (albeit low-power) sleep proxy machine on each subnet. We are working on a p2p architecture in which machines fall asleep one after the other, while the "last man standing" keeps watch for the entire subnet. Security: While the sleep proxying system does not pose a traditional security concern, we do note that many machines waking simultaneously could cause significant power spikes. To reduce the risk of this being exploited by an attacker, proxies can rate limit WOL packets sent.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: System block diagram. Blocks shaded gray represent existing components that are not modified in any way for the sleep proxy to work. Blocks with dashed outlines are part of our instrumentation setup.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Measured and predicted power consumption</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 4: Trace Length and Listening Port Distribution lengths of individual machines. Our users were a self selecting group, so their behavior may not be representative of all user populations.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Figure 6: Per-machine Sleep/Awake Intervals</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 5: Aggregate Sleep/Wake statistics by NETBIOS (139) and SMB (445). SMB is the main mechanism used for remote file system access in our network. The two other notable ports are UPnP (2869) and Remote Desktop (3389). In our network, Remote Desktop is the primary mechanism for interactive remote machine access. We can see Remote Desktop is not a major wakeup source. In fact, only 39% of the machines were ever woken up due to Remote Desktop requests. Therefore, it would seem that while users leave their machines on for potential remote access, interactive remote access is used relatively rarely.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>(</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 8: Who causes wake-ups?</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 9 :</head><label>9</label><figDesc>Figure 9: Awake Time as Percentage of Uptime. Broken Into Components Unknown, Recoverable, and Unrecoverable using Aggressive Idle Timeout</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>) .</head><label>.</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Field 
Value 
Ethernet 
Source Addr 
M.M AC Addr 
Header 
Destination Addr 
FF:FF:FF:FF:FF 
Sender MAC Addr 
M.M AC Addr 
ARP 
Sender IP Addr 
0.0.0.0 
Request 
Target MAC Addr 
00:00:00:00:00:00 
Target IP Addr 
M.IP Addr 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Concurrent work [4], provides the first study of sleep proxy deployment in an academic network.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> In Windows, the idle timeout is typically 30 minutes from power up / last user activity, and two minutes for any other wake cause (e.g., scheduled wakeup, WOL).</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> A daemon, in Unix terminology. 5 There being no reason to wake the machine for connections to nonlistening ports, which would just be ignored anyway.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="6"> The sleep notifier cannot reliably force the system to remain awake once the notification is broadcast 7 This packet must be broadcast since at the time it is sent, the subnet&apos;s routing is set to deliver all packets meant for the sleeping host to the sleep proxy.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="9"> Note that tunneling and IPsec can be (and indeed are) used together. Our sleep proxy routinely sees and handles TCP SYNs that are encapsulated in an ESP payload, which is carried in an IPv6 packet, which is tunneled inside an IPv4 packet.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Advanced Configuration and Power Interfae</title>
		<ptr target="http://www.acpi.info/" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>revison 4.0.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Adaptive Technologies</title>
		<ptr target="http://www.adaptiva.com/" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Somniloquy: augmenting network interfaces to reduce pc energy usage</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Agarwal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Hodges</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Chandra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Scott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bahl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NSDI&apos;09</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Berkeley, CA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sleepserver: A software-only approach for reducing the energy consumption of pcs within enterprise environments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Agarwal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Savage</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">USENIX ATC</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A scalable, commodity data center network architecture</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Al-Fares</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Loukissas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Vahdat</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">SIGCOMM Comput. Commun. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="63" to="74" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Enabling an energy-efficient future internet through selectively connected end systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Allman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Christensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Nordman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Paxson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Hotnets. ACM SIGCOMM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007-11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<ptr target="http://www.intel.com/technology/platform-technology/intel-amt/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Intel Active Management Technology (AMT</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Apple Wake On Lan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.macworld.com/article/142468/2009/08/wakeondemand.html" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The case for energy-proportional computing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Barroso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Hlzle</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Computer</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">40</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Complete system power estimation: A trickledown approach based on performance events</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Bircher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>John</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ISPASS</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A simulation study of a new green bittorrent</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Blackburn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Christensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Workshop on Green Communications. IEEE Internation Conference on Communications</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Power awareness in network design and routing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Chabarek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Sommers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Barford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Estan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Tsiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Wright</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">INFOCOM 2008</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">IPv4 Address conflict detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Cheshire</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>RFC 4227</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The next frontier for communications networks: Power management</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Christensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Gunaratne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Nordman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>George</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computer Communications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1758" to="1770" />
			<date type="published" when="2004-12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Enabling power management for network-attached computers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Christensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Gulledge</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Int. J. Netw. Manag</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="120" to="130" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<ptr target="T.Committee.www.ecma-international.org/publications/files/drafts/tc32-tg21-2009-150.doc" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ECMA</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009-11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Litegreen: Saving energy in networked desktops using virtualization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Das</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Padala</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Padmanabhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ramjee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Shin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">USENIX ATC</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Power provisioning for a warehouse-sized computer</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Fan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W.-D</forename><surname>Weber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Barroso</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the International Symposium on Computer Architecture (ISCA)</title>
		<meeting>the International Symposium on Computer Architecture (ISCA)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Gumstix. www.gumstix.com</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Greening of the internet</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">SIGCOMM</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A network connection proxy to enable hosts to sleep and save energy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Jimeno</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Christensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Nordman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Performance Computing and Communications Conference</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008-12" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="101" to="110" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fine-grained energy profiling for power-aware application design</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kansal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">HotMetrics08</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Security Architecture for the Internet Protocol</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Kent</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Seo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4301</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Energy aware network operations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Mahadevan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Sharma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Banerjee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Ranganathan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Global Internet Symposium</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009-04" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Global pc market suffering first decline since dot com crash</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Maisto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009-09" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Adding and Deleting Wake on LAN Patterns</title>
		<ptr target="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ff543710.aspx" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Skilled in the art of being idle: Reducing energy waste in networked systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Nedevschi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Chandrashekar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Nordman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ratnasamy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Taft</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NSDI</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009-04" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reducing network energy consumption via sleeping and rate-adaptation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Nedevschi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Popa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Iannaccone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ratnasamy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Wetherall</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NSDI&apos;08</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Berkeley, CA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Tranmission control protocol</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Postel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>RFC 793</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A comparison of high-level full-system power models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Rivoire</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Ranganathan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Kozyrakis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">HotPower&apos;08</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Energy efficient real-time scheduling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sinha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Chandrakasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page">458</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Koala: a platform for os-level power management</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Snowdon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">Le</forename><surname>Sueur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Petters</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Heiser</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EuroSys &apos;09: Proceedings of the 4th ACM European conference on Computer systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="289" to="302" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Greening the internet w/ nano data centers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Valancius</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Laoutaris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Massoulie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Diot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rodriguez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">How much money are your idle pc wasting. Forrester Researech Reports</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Washburn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008-12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">After-hours power status of office equipment in the usa. Energy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Webber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Roberson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Mcwhinney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Pinckard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Busch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006-11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
