<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/atharsefid/Desktop/grobid-0.5.3/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.3" ident="GROBID" when="2020-09-29T02:04+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">DarkNOC: Dashboard for Honeypot Management</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bertrand</forename><surname>Sobesto</surname></persName>
							<email>bsobesto@umd.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michel</forename><surname>Cukier</surname></persName>
							<email>mcukier@umd.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matti</forename><surname>Hiltunen</surname></persName>
							<email>hiltunen@research.att.com</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dave</forename><surname>Kormann</surname></persName>
							<email>davek@research.att.com</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gregg</forename><surname>Vesonder</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robin</forename><surname>Berthier</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Clark School of Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Coordinated Science Laboratory Information Trust Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">AT&amp;T Labs Research</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Maryland College Park</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>180 Park Ave. Florham Park</addrLine>
									<region>MD, NJ</region>
									<country>USA, USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>IL</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">DarkNOC: Dashboard for Honeypot Management</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Protecting computer and information systems from security attacks is becoming an increasingly important task for system administrators. Honeypots are a technology often used to detect attacks and collect information about techniques and targets (e.g., services, ports, operating systems) of attacks. However, managing a large and complex network of honeypots becomes a challenge given the amount of data collected as well as the risk that the honeypots may become infected and start attacking other machines. In this paper, we present DarkNOC, a management and monitoring tool for complex honeynets consisting of different types of honeypots as well as other data collection devices. DarkNOC has been actively used to manage a honeynet consisting of multiple subnets and hundreds of IP addresses. This paper describes the architecture and a number of case studies demonstrating the use of DarkNOC.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Because of the value of the data they store and the resources they provide, information systems become targets for attackers and must be protected. To better secure computer systems from external threats, security researchers aim to understand attackers and the different techniques they use to compromise computers and achieve their goals. One possible approach is to use a target computer, called a honeypot, which is not used by normal users. Therefore, all the activity towards this computer can be considered malicious.</p><p>Individual honeypots or networks of honeypots have been used to conduct various studies of attackers <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">9]</ref> and analysis of cyber crimes such as unsollicited electronic mails, phishing <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref>, identity theft and denial of service. The computer security community has used honeypots to analyze different techniques deployed by the attackers to reach their objectives. Attackers' arsenal includes distributed denial of service <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[24]</ref>, botnets <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>, worms <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref> or SPAM <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref>. However few studies focus on the usage of honeypots data to help network administrators to better protect their production networks. Honeypot deployment is challenging and the architecture of such networks is complex. For example, distributed honeynets require secure tunnels and different levels of protection must be in place to ensure a total containment of attacks targeting the honeypots. In addition, honeynets require constant monitoring to guarantee that protection systems (for example firewalls, traffic shappers) and data collection are operating correctly. Depending on the size of the honeynet, the volume of data collected can be important and impacts significantly data processing and extraction. To be integrated as a security tool, honeypots data must be presented and translated in meaningful way to network administrators.</p><p>In this paper, we introduce DarkNOC, a solution designed to efficiently process large amount of malicious traffic received by a large honeynet, and to provide a user-friendly Web interface to highlight potential compromised hosts to security administrators, as well as to provide the overall network security status. DarkNOC is used to manage the UMD honeynet, a network of 2,000 honeypots from which information about attacks is continuously extracted and provided to the security team to help them better protect the production network.</p><p>The rest of the paper is organized as follows. In Section 2, we provide an overview of the architecture and operation of DarkNOC. In Section 3, we describe the outputs and views provided by the DarkNOC. We provide a number of case studies using DarkNOC in Section 4. Finally we review the related work in Section 5, we provide some remarks on future work in Section 6 and conclude the paper in Section 7.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">DarkNOC Architecture</head><p>This section describes what DarkNOC does, how it collects data, and its internal structure.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">System Architecture</head><p>DarkNOC manages multiple types of honeypots and information sources as illustrated in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>. The UMD honeynet consists of low interaction honeypots (LIHs) such as Nepenthes <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref> as well as high-interaction honeypots (HIHs) consisting of virtual or physical machines running real operating systems, applications, and services <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. The UMD honeynet supports multiple subnets consisting of IP addresses contributed by different organizations participating in the research. DarkNOC collects multiple sources of information from different devices (e.g., NetFlow from Gateway, Snort events from Snort Sensors <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[20]</ref>, and malware from Nepenthes), analyzes the data, and presents it to users in an efficient and actionable manner. The details of the data views and their use in analyzing security incidents are discussed in Sections 3 and 4.</p><p>The current information sources consist of the following:</p><p>• NetFlow Data: DarkNOC uses nfdump 1 to extract NetFlow data collected on the main gateway of the honeypots. The flow data provides enough information to determine the number of attackers, the different source and destination IP addresses, and the different source and destination ports. Specifically, each NetFlow record summarizes communication between two network end points (defined by the IP addresses and port numbers of the end points) including the time, duration, and numbers of bytes and packets (see example below), but does not contain any payload information (i.e., content of the messages transmitted). • Snort Events: Snort <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[20]</ref> is an Intrusion Detection System (IDS) for detecting attacks and potential intrusions. Snort provides information about the types of attacks used against the honeypots.</p><p>• Malware Collection: Nepenthes acts as a passive malware collector by emulating common service vulnerabilities and allowing attackers to inject the malware binaries. Nepenthes provides a log of each malware submission containing information such as the date and the vulnerability used but also the binary injected. This allows DarkNOC to see what kinds of malware are successfully uploaded, the security signatures, and port used. It also allows to measure the efficiency of the security solution protecting the network.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">DarkNOC Software Architecture</head><p>The design of the DarkNOC software architecture was driven by the following constraints:</p><p>• The aesthetics from the user's point of view: The user interface should be easy to access and the important data should be automatically highlighted. This interface should be highly portable so that users can use different operating systems and access the system from different geographic locations (i.e., not tied to one dedicated machine).</p><p>• Speed: The user interface must be fast and the user should not have to wait for the results to be displayed. Processing high volumes of data can be time consuming and if the processing is started only when the user requests a data view, the response time may not be satisfactory. Therefore, our system uses data pre-processing when possible to ensure fast response.</p><p>• Data validity: The data displayed should be reasonably up to date and reflect the current activity.</p><p>To meet these requirements, the application software has been divided into three different parts: 1) a graphical Web front-end, 2) back-end, and 3) alerting module. The front-end generates a Web page displaying the different information. The back-end extracts the necessary data from the flows and creates the different graphs.</p><p>Back-end Module: Written in Perl, the back-end module is a background process that updates the information displayed by the front-end every 5 minutes based on the NetFlow data. The separation of flow processing from the display was necessary to guarantee a fast response time at the user interface, because the extraction of flow <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>: System architecture data can be time consuming. Since the flow data is updated every 5 minutes by the flow collector, a continuous live update of the displayed views is unnecessary. However it requires the tool to process the new flow files within 5 minutes. DarkNOC provides information for the last 24 hours and the last 5 minutes. Two different processes generate the 24 hours and 5 minutes statistics. For about 2,000 IP addresses, an average of 15,995 flows are generated every 5 minutes representing about 5 million flows per day. It takes an average of 7.4 seconds to process a newly created flow file. Given this number, DarkNOC is able to process almost a hundred times more flows within 5 minutes. Generating the statistics on the last 24 hours is computationally more expensive and longer. It takes an average of 130 seconds. However, it is not necessary for this process to finish within 5 minutes.</p><p>A lock file prevents multiple executions of this process at the same time. For each subnet and the global view, the back-end generates the different graphs, the list of destination ports, the list of attackers and the list of targeted honeypots. The graphs are created using RRDTool <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2</ref> , an open source tool for storage and retrieval of time series.</p><p>Graphical User Interface: The graphical user interface organizes the different data necessary to present a summary of the honeypots activity. Web technologies such as the PHP language and Cascading Style Sheets are used. A Web page is extremely portable and requires no configuration on the client side. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2</ref> shows the homepage of DarkNOC. The content is described in Section 3. The graphical user interface first provides a global view of the activity of the honeypots: the data displayed includes all the subnets. The user has then the possibility to reduce the scope of analysis to one subnet. To prevent unauthorized access, the application uses an HTTP authentication over SSL to protect DarkNOC's directory on the Web Server. Apache is configured to authenticate users against an LDAP server where all accounts are centralized. User objects belonging to the group DarkNOC have access to the application. Because of legal and confidentiality reasons it is necessary to filter the information displayed by DarkNOC. Once authenticated DarkNOC retrieves the user name stored in the $ SERVER['PHP AUTH USER'] variable and matches it with the user's table in the database to determine which subnets to display or not. If the user is allowed to access more than one subnet, DarkNOC will reflect the user's rights in the global view but also in the subnet selector. If the user has access to a single subnet, the subnet will be automatically selected with no possibility to select another one.</p><p>Alerting Module: The alerting module is a process executing a specific query on the flow data. The results are sent by email to a specific group of users. Users have the possibility to create their own flow query based on the nfdump filter syntax and to specify the recipients of the alerts. The module is currently launched twice a day: at 6:00 AM and at 6:00 PM. It can be executed more frequently if more real-time alerts are required.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Display Description</head><p>The layout of the graphical user interface of DarkNOC presented in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2</ref> organizes the different pieces of information gathered from the most global and important to the most detailed concerning the current activity of the honeypots. The user interface of DarkNOC has been developed to ease the comparison of the different sources of information and the comparison of the different subnets.</p><p>The Web page provided by DarkNOC is divided into three different sections: 1) status of the subnets, 2) flowbased information, and 3) Snort events. Each section will provide information that will reduce the number of possible explanations when an anomaly in the traffic is identified in DarkNOC. The first screen provided is a global view of the honeypots activity. The user can select a specific subnet to drill-down to a more detailed view of the subnet activity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Subnet Status and Network Traffic</head><p>The first part of the Web page shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 3</ref> is composed of a table giving the status of the low interac- tion honeypots (LIH) running Nepenthes, the status of the tunnels to different organizations, and the number of malware collected for each subnet since the initialization of DarkNOC. The notion of a tunnel is specific to the UMD honeynet. It allows to redirect the network traffic from remote locations to the honeypot network transparently. Hence, it is possible to use other participating organizations' IP addresses. A graph representing the incoming and outgoing traffic in bytes per seconds is included in the status section as well. This section provides essential indications on the state of the main components of the UMD honeynet, i.e. tunnels and main gateway. The graph gives an overview of the UMD honeynet infrastructure load and can help to detect anomalies in the traffic.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">NetFlow Data</head><p>The NetFlow section provides information extracted from the NetFlow data collected at the edge of the honeypots network. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 5</ref> presents a graph showing the number of attackers over time for each subnet of the honeypot network. Each unique IP address that does not belong to the honeypots is considered a unique attacker. The graphical user interface provides several graphs that display the number of attackers at different time scales: one day, one week, and one month. These two graphs shown in Figures 5 and 6 make it easy to observe the activity of the honeypots for each subnet. Comparing the numbers of flows and attackers can reveal attack characteristics. For example, an increase of the number of flows while the number of attackers remains relatively steady means that one or several offenders may have launched an attack that generates large amounts of flows such as port scanning and bruteforce activities. It can also mean that a large network behind a network address translation system is compromised and targeting the UMD honeynet. DarkNOC also makes it easy to compare trends between the different subnets. For example, it is straightforward to identify peaks in the number of attackers or flows that occur at the same time in different subnets, as well as changes in the attacks directed to only one of the subnets, indicating a targeted attack. The tables in <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref> show the top and bottom 10 ports targeted by the attackers during the last 24 hours. For each port, the number of flows and the percentage of the total number of flows are provided. It makes it easy to identify the most popular services and to protect the network accordingly. The severity of an attack is not related to the number of flows it will generate. Attacks towards common ports tend to hide smaller attacks against less popular ports. This is why we also decided to display the bottom 10 ports targeted.</p><p>Finally, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 7</ref> represents a word cloud of the top 20 attackers' IP addresses. The top 20 IP addresses are determined using the number of flows involved in the communications between the attacker and the honeypots. The size of the font displaying the IP address reflects the number of flows generated for that IP address. The same representation is used for the top 20 targeted honeypots. These word clouds are updated every 5 minutes using a 24-hour window. The IP addresses presented in the word clouds are clickable: The user can obtain the lists of honeypots contacted, services and Snort events related to the selected IP address in a separate window. Since the honeypot network often hosts different experiments with different configurations, the port tables and the targeted honeypots make it possible to determine what is attracting the attackers the most.  <ref type="figure">Figure 8</ref> shows a table of the last 10 Snort events collected on the honeypot network. This table allows honeypot administrators to immediately identify attacks generating high volumes of traffic. For example, a brute-force attack against a Microsoft SQL server will generate a spike in the traffic curves and the corresponding events will appear immediately in this table.</p><p>The graph in <ref type="figure">Figure 9</ref> provides a trend in the number of Snort events recorded the current day, the past few days, and the past few weeks. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 10</ref> shows the top and bottom 10 Snort signatures tables. The tables provide the signature name, the number of events for each signature and the percentage. Large scale attacks such as port scanning or brute-force attacks may generate several events. As a consequence, smaller but still important attacks may not appear in the top 10 signatures. This is why the bottom 10 Snort signatures are also provided. As an example, consider the snort signature SHELLCODE NOOP shown in the Bottom 10 Snort events of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 10</ref>. This signature indi- The injection was successful and Nepenthes captured and logged the malware submission: </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Case Study</head><p>This section details the UMD honeynet, the honeypot network deployed at the University of Maryland and also describes how DarkNOC is used to operate and maintain this particular network.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">UMD Honeynet</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.1">Introduction</head><p>The honeypot network hosted at the University of Maryland was initially built in 2004 with unused IP addresses of the campus network. More recently, other organizations joined the initiative: AT&amp;T Labs, the University of Illinois at Urbana Champaign, and the Laboratoire d'Analyse et d'Architecture des Systèmes (LAAS) in Toulouse, France. Each of these organizations contributes to the UMD honeynet by providing ranges of public IP addresses.</p><p>The objective of the UMD honeynet is to provide the infrastructure to support honeypot-based experiments. The network features a centralized data collection and guarantees a realistic but controlled and flexible environment to safely deploy experiments. The advantages of the present architecture are multiple:</p><p>• A single gateway collects and stores the stores Snort events, flow data and network traffic, providing visibility across the full range of exposed networks.</p><p>• The experiments are easy to deploy without the need to create tunnels or to setup specific network configurations.</p><p>• The UMD honeynet is scalable, new organizations can join the project by providing range of IP addresses.  The complexity of managing and monitoring such a network was the primary motivation for the development of DarkNOC. This section will discuss the application of the tool to that problem.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.2">Architecture</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">UMD DarkNOC Implementation</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.1">Subnet Status</head><p>The subnet status section is specific to the UMD honeynet. Each organization involved in the UMD honeynet provides one or more ranges of IP addresses called subnets. For example, the University of Maryland provides two distinct subnets: a subnet of the campus internal network and a subnet at the border network. The failure of a Honeymole tunnel is a significant event for the network, as it implies loss of an entire subnet; the subnet status display allows a manager to quickly assess the status of the tunnels and act on any issues.</p><p>Each subnet hosts a low interaction honeypot run by Nepenthes to collect malware. Depending on the network configuration, a Honeymole tunnel may be established to redirect the traffic to Maryland. DarkNOC monitors the quantity of malware collected, the status of the Honeymole tunnels, and the status of the low interaction honeypots.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.2">Compromised Honeypots Detection</head><p>Some experiments deployed on the UMD honeynet may present significant risks. In the likely event of a honeypot being compromised, the attacker may use the machine to attack other hosts on the Internet. These attacks are generally easily detectable: <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 12</ref> shows that the volume of outgoing traffic is substantially greater than the incoming traffic. In this case, a honeypot was used as a proxy server.   <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 13</ref> shows an increase in the number of flows just before midnight on Thursday night.</p><p>2. The number of attackers presented in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_11">Figure 14</ref> remains relatively steady. This suggests that a fixed set of attackers is generating a large volume of traffic.</p><p>3. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 15</ref> shows that port 22 is very active. As SSH sessions do not usually generate many flows, we can assume that the attacker is using a bruteforce attack against several IP addresses hosted within the UMD honeynet.</p><p>4. The word cloud of the honeypots targeted showed that the IP addresses of this specific SSH experiment were targeted.</p><p>DarkNOC provided several indications on the nature of the attack responsible for the spike in traffic network and flows. That night, the health monitoring system of the experiment reported several times that the machine was overloaded and the SSH server failed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.4">Using Honeypots as a Security Tool</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Compromised Hosts Detection</head><p>The network traffic observed within an honeypot network is considered malicious. A healthy host would not normally communicate with the honeypots. We can therefore use the UMD honeynet to detect compromised hosts on the Maryland campus network. We assume that if a computer on campus appears in the flow data, that means the host is compomised. The alerting module queries the flow data to identify these hosts. This method is efficient at detecting scanners: the use of subnets from both local and remote sites means that a scanner is likely to eventually visit the UMD honeynet whether its probes are directed locally or at the Internet.</p><p>When a compromised machine is detected, the alerting module analyzes the event and generates an email that is sent to the IT Security Officer for further analysis. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_12">Fig- ure 16</ref> is an example of such a report. For each host, the number of flows, packets and bytes are provided. The report is also available on the Web interface of Dark-NOC, it is possible to vizualize the flows associated with the alert. This technique helps to identify compromised hosts and misconfiguration as well. When this alerting system was first launched, the IT team figured that even if a host was tagged as blocked in their systems the compromised host was still able to communicate on the network and to continue its malicious activity. The analysis is performed every 12 hours and each participating organization gets notified of the eventual compromises of their systems. The choice of running the analysis at this frequency was chosen based on the feedback provided by the security team of the University of Maryland. The team wanted to receive a report early in the morning and  </p><formula xml:id="formula_0">---------------Analysis Report --------------- Flow</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Security Profiling</head><p>Honeypots can provide relevant information regarding attackers and their techniques to compromise a computer. DarkNOC brings together enough information from different datasets to establish a security profile of a network. This profile includes the services targeted, the number of malware uploaded and the types of attacks. The objective is to help the security officers and network administrators to understand where to focus their efforts and to identify weaknesses and misconfigurations. DarkNOC can also be used to evaluate the performance of the security policy in place. The attacks detected and the malware uploaded on the honeypots are good indicators of the efficiency of an IPS device.</p><p>Attack techniques are constantly evolving as new vulnerabilities are discovered regularly. The honeypots can help to identify the current trends and to update the security policy accordingly.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Related Work</head><p>Lance Spitzner defines honeypots as a security tool whose value lies in being probed, attacked, or compromised <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[21]</ref>. In other words these are highly monitoring computer systems meant to attract hackers, analyze their modus operandi and profile them <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[19]</ref>. Placed in production environments, honeypots take an active part in the security of a network by providing information on attackers and attacks' patterns. Niels Provos introduces two types of honeypots <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[18]</ref>: high interaction honeypots that involve the deployment of real operating systems on real or virtual machines, and low interaction honeypots that are computer software emulating operating systems and services.</p><p>Companies and researchers currently deploy honeypots networks at different scales. Also known as honeynets, these honeypots networks can be limited to few IP addresses on the local network or distributed systems in several locations such as the Leurre.com project <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref>, the Internet Motion Sensor <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref>, SGNET <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref> or the honeynet initiative from CAIDA <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[23]</ref>.</p><p>Levine et al. demonstrated the usefulness of deploying honeypots accross large enterprise networks <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref>. In their study, Snort <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[20]</ref> was used to detect compromised computers accross Georgia Tech network. In DarkNOC a similar detection has been made possible by using the flow data. We assume that any traffic seen on the honeypot network is malicious.</p><p>The visualization and data analysis of malicious network activity has been the focus of a variety of commercial and open source products. On the commercial side, security companies such as Tenable and Sourcefire offer threat management products that collect logs from multiple devices and generate alerts to inform security analysts about potential intrusions. The main limitation of these solutions with respect to our goal is that they are not tailored to honeypot management and honeynet data collection and so they require additional effort to integrate honeypots in the organization security data analysis suite. Arbor Network is another commercial security vendor that offers a threat management product but the difference with the previous solutions is that they leverage their customer networks to instrument dark IP space at a large scale. As a result, they offer a global view of malicious network activity through their Atlas portal 4 , which provides functionalities similar to DarkNOC, with graphs and tables for top attacks, top threat sources and attack trends.</p><p>On the open source side, the main honeynet management solution has been Honeywall <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>  Other open source projects that are not specifically tailored for honeypots include Alienvault <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>, Aanval 5 , Nfsight <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref> and NVisionIP <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref>. Alienvault and Aanval are network and system log management solutions that can only process Snort alerts and syslog events while Nfsight works exclusively with Netflow and has been designed for large-scale processing and security visualization of Netflow. NVisionIP processes global network Netflow data to specifically detect attacks and misuses.</p><p>Visoottiviseth et al. present a distributed honeypot framework using low interaction honeypots <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[22]</ref> running the honeyd daemon <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17]</ref>. More specifically, they describe the working of the honeyd logs centralization and their analysis <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[22]</ref>. The framework only works with Honeyd log files. The level of interaction of our framework is also different since we are running low interaction honeypots as well as high interaction honeypots.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Future Work</head><p>We are working on a number of extensions and improvements on DarkNOC. The first extension will be the addition of a malware section in the user interface. This new section will provide more information about the malware collection including a graph showing the number of uploads per day but also some indications on the methods used to upload the malicious software and its name. The second improvement will be the implementation of the automatic detection of compromised honeypots in the alerting module. This detection will allow DarkNOC to automatically block the outbound traffic of compromised honeypots. Currently, only the detection of compromised non-honeypot hosts of an organization is automated. The graphical user interface of DarkNOC can also be enhanced. There is no option that allows to select and display the activity of a specific period of the day. It would be useful to be able to choose on a graph a particular moment of the day and see the activity at this precise time.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusion</head><p>In this paper we presented DarkNOC, a honeypot network management and monitoring tool. DarkNOC provides a summary of the activity of the honeypots in the network. This summary is generated from different sources of data including Netflow, malware collected by the Nepenthes low interaction honeypots and attacks detected by the Snort intrusion detection system. Brought together, these data sources provide important resources to help network administrators, security teams, and security researchers understand attacks and protect systems. DarkNOC can be used the detect traffic anomalies and identify interesting case study for research purposes. Since it is important to detect quickly any compromised honeypots in the honeynet, DarkNOC provides administrators of these networks information regarding the health of the systems. Security teams may find a particular interest in DarkNOC since it can be used to detect compromised honeypots as well as compromised hosts on their non-honeypots networks. To sum up an organization using DarkNOC can have a better understanding of:</p><p>• the most targeted systems,</p><p>• the attackers, the attacks and their origin, but also, DarkNOC helps:</p><p>• to obtain an overview of Honeynets activity,</p><p>• to identify security tools and devices misconfiguration.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: DarkNOC's graphic user interface</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Subnets status section</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 6 presents a graph showing the number of flows over time for each subnet of the honeypot network. Separate graphs are used to display the number of flows at different time scales.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5: Number of attackers</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Figure 7: Attacker word cloud</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 10 :</head><label>10</label><figDesc>Figure 10: Top and bottom 10 Snort signatures</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 11</head><label>11</label><figDesc>Figure 11 shows the current architecture of the UMD honeynet and the different institutions involved in the project. A tunneling program called Honeymole 3 redi-</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure 11 :</head><label>11</label><figDesc>Figure 11: UMD honeynet architecture</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Figure 12 :</head><label>12</label><figDesc>Figure 12: Network traffic (04/18/2011)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Figure 13 :</head><label>13</label><figDesc>Figure 13: 06/03/2011, number of Flows</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head>Figure 14 :</head><label>14</label><figDesc>Figure 14: 06/03/2011, number of attackers</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head>Figure 16 :</head><label>16</label><figDesc>Figure 16: Alerting module report</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Time Window: 2011/06/06.06:00:00-2011/06/06.18:00:01</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Number of hosts detected: 3 
To access the online version of the report: 
https://xxx.xxx.xxx.xxx/darknoc/alert_hosts.php?report=263 

xxx.xxx.xxx.xxx (X.umd.edu) 
-Number of flows: 1 
-Number of packets: 1 
-Number of bytes: 51 
To visualize the flows: 
https://xxx.xxx.xxx.xxx/darknoc/alert_hosts.php?id=1124 

yyy.yyy.yyy.yyy (Y.umd.edu) 
-Number of flows: 10 
-Number of packets: 10 
-Number of bytes: 1915 
To visualize the flows: 
https://xxx.xxx.xxx.xxx/darknoc/alert_hosts.php?id=1125 

zzz.zzz.zzz.zzz (Z.umd.edu) 
-Number of flows: 10 
-Number of packets: 10 
-Number of bytes: 1915 
To visualize the flows: 
https://xxx.xxx.xxx.xxx/darknoc/alert_hosts.php?id=1126 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>developed by the Honeynet Project. The Honeywall is a bootable CD-Rom that installs a Linux-based network gateway to manage and control honeypots as well as visualizing and analyz- ing honeynet logs. Compared to DarkNOC, Honeywall has a more capabilities to actively limit outgoing traffic but it has been designed for small honeypot network. The data processing capabilities of DarkNOC were designed for large scale and multi-site deployments. The objec- tive of the DarkNOC project is to provide a flexible and powerful analysis program. It is adjustable to fit differ- ent honeypots configurations. However Honeywall is a all-in-one solution for small scale honeypot networks. It 4 http://atlas.arbor.net provides routing, capture and analysis capabilities. In- tegrating Honeywall in an existing large-scale honeypot network is more challenging.</figDesc><table></table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> http://oss.oetiker.ch/rrdtool/</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> http://www.honeynet.org.pt/index.php/HoneyMole</note>

			<note place="foot" n="5"> http://www.aanval.com/</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgement</head><p>The authors thank the Office for Information Technology at the University of Maryland. In particular we thank Gerry Sneeringer and his team for allowing the deployment of the UMD honeynet, providing feedback on DarkNOC and investigating the compromises detected by the application.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Characterization of attackers&apos; activities in honeypot traffic using principal component analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Almotairi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Mohay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zimmermann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2008 IFIP International Conference on Network and Parallel Computing</title>
		<meeting>the 2008 IFIP International Conference on Network and Parallel Computing<address><addrLine>Washington, DC, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE Computer Society</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="147" to="154" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Know Your Enemy: Tracking Botnets (using honeynets to learn more about bots)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Bacher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thorsten</forename><surname>Holz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Markus</forename><surname>Kotter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Georg</forename><surname>Wicherski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008-08" />
			<publisher>The Honeynet Project</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The nepenthes platform: An efficient approach to collect malware</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Baecher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Koetter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Holz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Dornseif</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Freiling</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of RAID&apos;2006</title>
		<meeting>RAID&apos;2006</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="165" to="184" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The internet motion sensor: A distributed blackhole monitoring system</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Bailey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Evan</forename><surname>Cooke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Farnam</forename><surname>Jahanian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jose</forename><surname>Nazario</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Watson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Network and Distributed System Security Symposium (NDSS 05</title>
		<meeting>Network and Distributed System Security Symposium (NDSS 05</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="167" to="179" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An evaluation of connection characteristics for separating network attacks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Berthier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Cukier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Security and Networks</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="110" to="124" />
			<date type="published" when="2009-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nfsight: netflowbased network awareness tool</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Berthier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Cukier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hiltunen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kormann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Vesonder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Sheleheda</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 24th USENIX LISA</title>
		<meeting>the 24th USENIX LISA</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Alienvault: the future of security information management</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeramiah</forename><surname>Bowling</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Linux J</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010-03" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The honeywall cd-rom. Security Privacy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Chamales</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="77" to="79" />
			<date type="published" when="2004-04" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A year in the life of the irish honeynet: attacked, probed and bruised but still fighting</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Curran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Colman</forename><surname>Morrissey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Colm</forename><surname>Fagan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Colm</forename><surname>Murphy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O&amp;apos;</forename><surname>Brian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gerry</forename><surname>Donnell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Fitzpatrick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Condit</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Inf. Knowl. Syst. Manag</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="201" to="213" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<publisher>December</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why phishing works</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Rachna Dhamija</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marti</forename><surname>Tygar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Hearst</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI conference on Human Factors in computing systems, CHI &apos;06</title>
		<meeting>the SIGCHI conference on Human Factors in computing systems, CHI &apos;06<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="581" to="590" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Experiences with the noah honeynet testbed to detect new internet worms. IT Security Incident Management and IT Forensics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jan</forename><surname>Kohlrausch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Conference on</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">0</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13" to="26" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nvisionip: netflow visualizations of system state for security situational awareness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kiran</forename><surname>Lakkaraju</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Yurcik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adam</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2004 ACM workshop on Visualization and data mining for computer security, VizSEC/DMSEC &apos;04</title>
		<meeting>the 2004 ACM workshop on Visualization and data mining for computer security, VizSEC/DMSEC &apos;04<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="65" to="72" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sgnet: A worldwide deployable framework to support the analysis of malware threat models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Corrado</forename><surname>Leita</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marc</forename><surname>Dacier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2008 Seventh European Dependable Computing Conference</title>
		<meeting>the 2008 Seventh European Dependable Computing Conference<address><addrLine>Washington, DC, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE Computer Society</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="99" to="109" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Use of Honeynets to Detect Exploited Systems Across Large Enterprise Networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Levine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Labella</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Owen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Contis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Culver</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE Workshop on Information Assurance, IEEE Systems, Man and Cybernetics Society</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE Workshop on Information Assurance, IEEE Systems, Man and Cybernetics Society<address><addrLine>West Point, NY</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="92" to="99" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">HoneySpam: Honeypots Fighting Spam at the Source</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ro</forename><surname>Mauro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Francesca</forename><surname>Mazzoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="77" to="83" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Leurre.com: on the advantages of deploying a large scale distributed honeypot platform</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fabien</forename><surname>Pouget</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marc</forename><surname>Dacier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Van Hau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Pham</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ECCE&apos;05, E-Crime and Computer Conference</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Monaco</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005-03" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="29" to="30" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Honeyd: A Virtual Honeypot Daemon</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Niels</forename><surname>Provos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003-02" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Center for Information Technology Integration, University of Michigan</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Virtual honeypots: from botnet tracking to intrusion detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Niels</forename><surname>Provos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thorsten</forename><surname>Holz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Addison-Wesley</forename><surname>Professional</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>first edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Profiling attacker behavior following ssh compromises</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Ramsbrock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robin</forename><surname>Berthier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michel</forename><surname>Cukier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 37th Annual IEEE/IFIP International Conference on Dependable Systems and Networks, DSN &apos;07</title>
		<meeting>the 37th Annual IEEE/IFIP International Conference on Dependable Systems and Networks, DSN &apos;07<address><addrLine>Washington, DC, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE Computer Society</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="119" to="124" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Snort -lightweight intrusion detection for networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Roesch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 13th USENIX LISA</title>
		<meeting>the 13th USENIX LISA</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Honeypots: Tracking Hackers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Spitzner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Addison-Wesley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<publisher>Longman Publishing Co., Inc</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Boston, MA, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distributed honeypot log management and visualization of attacker geographical distribution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Visoottiviseth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Jaralrungroj</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Phoomrungraungsuk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Kultanon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Computer Science and Software Engineering (JCSSE), 2011 Eighth International Joint Conference on</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011-05" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="23" to="28" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scalability, fidelity, and containment in the potemkin virtual honeyfarm</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Vrable</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Justin</forename><surname>Ma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jay</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Moore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Erik</forename><surname>Vandekieft</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Snoeren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Geoffrey</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Voelker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stefan</forename><surname>Savage</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">SIGOPS Oper. Syst. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="148" to="162" />
			<date type="published" when="2005-10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Honeypots for distributed denial of service attacks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nathalie</forename><surname>Weiler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 11th IEEE International Workshops on Enabling Technologies: nfrastructure for Collaborative Enterprises</title>
		<meeting>the 11th IEEE International Workshops on Enabling Technologies: nfrastructure for Collaborative Enterprises<address><addrLine>Washington, DC, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE Computer Society</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="109" to="114" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
