<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/atharsefid/Desktop/grobid-0.5.3/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.3" ident="GROBID" when="2020-09-29T02:04+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Truly Non-blocking Writes</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luis</forename><surname>Useche</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Florida International University † IBM Research</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ricardo</forename><surname>Koller</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Florida International University † IBM Research</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Raju</forename><surname>Rangaswami</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Florida International University † IBM Research</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Akshat</forename><surname>Verma</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Florida International University † IBM Research</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Truly Non-blocking Writes</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Writing data within user or operating system memory often encounters the classic read-before-write problem whereby the page written to must first be read from the backing store, effectively blocking the writing process before modifications are made. Unfortunately, the large gap between memory and storage access performance adversely affects workloads that require substantial read-before-write operations when accessing memory. In this paper, we present techniques that make writes to memory truly non-blocking. The basic approach involves absorbing writes immediately in temporary buffer pages and asynchronously merging the updates after reading in the on-disk version of the page. Doing so improves system performance by first, reducing blocking of processes and second, improving the parallelism of data retrieval from the backing store leading to better throughput for read-before-write operations. We analyze the potential benefits of our approach using full-system memory access traces for several benchmark workloads and present techniques that commodity operating systems can employ to implement non-blocking writes.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Writing data to main memory is extremely fast. Well, ... most of the time. When using demand-paged virtual memory and file systems, the main memory caches a subset of the data contained within a backing store, typically a hard disk or SSD (array) device. However, memory references are done at a much smaller granularity (32 or 64 bit words) than is possible in backing stores. When data not present in memory is read or modified by the process, the operating system (OS) must fetch an entire page, typically 4KB or 8KB in commodity OSes, that contain the few bytes referenced by the processor. Page fetches occur in two scenarios: (1) a page mapped to the process address space (anonymous or file system page cache page) not resident in physical memory gets accessed by a machine instruction (e.g., <ref type="bibr">LOAD</ref>  fetch blocks the process, the performance of the running process during that time is limited by the performance of the backing store. For read references, such blocking cannot be avoided since there is no other provision to correctly generate the data being read. Interestingly, the same blocking approach has been applied to handle write references in commodity operating systems and hypervisors till today (e.g., see recent Linux 2.6.34.5 and Xen 4.1.0 kernels). These include write references to swap-backed process memory or disk-backed file system pages, either directly (for anonymous and memory mapped pages) or via system calls (for OS cached pages). Thus, the writing process blocks in case the page being referenced is not in core memory until the referenced page is synchronously read from the backing store, leading to a read-beforewrite requirement <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref>. This paper demonstrates that writes can and should be handled differently and proposes an approach to eliminate blocking for all write references to memory. We observe that in case of write references, instead of blocking the process to read in the page, the operating system can absorb such writes in temporary buffer pages and allow the process to continue executing immediately. The operating system can issue the page read I/O to the backing store asynchronously and merge the update later when the page has been read into memory. A graphical representation of this process ap-pears in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>.</p><p>The proposed approach improves system performance in two ways. First, it immediately unblocks the process which is then free to execute subsequent instructions and make progress; the originally blocking page fetch operation can now overlap with useful computation. Second, it improves the parallelism of data retrieval from the backing store by creating the ability to keep many outstanding I/O (OIO) operations to handle multiple page fetches by a single process at the same time. Doing so leads to better throughput for both SSD and hard disk based backing stores, both of which offer better I/O throughput with multiple outstanding I/O operations. For example, we found an almost 5x increase in IOPS for a PCIe OCZ Revodrive 160GB SSD when the number of OIO were increased from 1 to 16.</p><p>In the next section, we motivate the need for nonblocking writes in commodity systems. We then present our approach to make all memory write references nonblocking ( §3). We quantify the potential benefits of our approach using full system memory access traces for a variety of workloads ( §4). Finally, we summarize our work and point to future directions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Motivating Non-blocking Writes</head><p>In this section, we identify technology trends and workload behaviors that motivate non-blocking writes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Trends in Page Fault Rates</head><p>Two trends point to the likelihood of increasing page fault rates in systems. First, multi-core systems and virtualization are changing memory footprints fundamentally. Higher application tenancy ratios and corresponding increase in in-memory working sets demand ever-increasing amounts of DRAM, a resource that incurs high cost and energy consumption. A second trend that is now evident is that the memory hierarchy is also changing fundamentally. High-performance flash-based SSDs are becoming mainstream as backing store devices and now vendors are introducing SSDs in servers as well <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">6]</ref>. Researchers have already begun designing hybrid memory systems and flash-based virtual memory and file system caching systems that are motivated by these trends <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">9]</ref>. Thus, we can expect an increasing off-loading of the traditionally DRAM-resident working set data to this additional high-performance SSD layer in the storage stack, indicating a move to higher page fault rates in future systems.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">read-before-write: For Real?</head><p>How common is read-before-write in reality? Intuitively, read-before-write occurs when a page in the backing store is overwritten. Here, it is important to differentiate over-writes from allocation-writes. While the former modifies an existing page incurring a read-before-write </p><formula xml:id="formula_0">B T E C F P H 2 J T P D S S S P 1 0 0 S P 2 0 S P 4 0 S P 6 0 S P 8 0 T C T B T S % Non-Block Faults Workload 50% 25%</formula><p>Figure 2: Fraction of page faults that benefit from nonblocking writes for various workloads with two memory sizes: 50% and 25% of each workload's footprint. operation, the latter allocates a new page on the fly to write into and is thus free from read-before-write.</p><p>As mentioned before, page over-writes causing readbefore-write can occur for both virtual memory pages and file system pages. To estimate the occurrence of read-before-write in real workloads, we analyzed full system memory access traces for a heterogeneous set of workloads including server, image processing, and developer workloads. These workloads are summarized in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>.</p><p>We built a memory simulator that reports the number of page faults, the number of write faults that incur readbefore-write operations, and the number of write faults that can truly benefit from non-blocking writes. The distinction between the latter two lies in the consideration that some non-blocking writes of read-before-write operations are quickly followed by a blocking read fault to the same page, thereby eliminating any potential benefit due to the non-blocking write. We provide more details on how this data was collected and analyzed, and the simulator we built in Section 4. <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> shows that with a DRAM provisioned for storing 50% of the the total memory pages referenced, there is a substantial fraction -as much as 80% -of the total page faults (including both read and write faults) that can benefit from non-blocking writes for a variety of workloads.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Alternatives to Non-blocking Writes</head><p>To the best of our knowledge, we are not aware of any prior work that explicitly identifies or addresses the readbefore-write problem. We now consider alternate optimizations that can possibly achieve the two goals of non-blocking writes, i.e., reduce blocking of process execution and increase parallelism of access to the backing store.</p><p>One approach to reducing the blocking of processes is provisioning adequate DRAM to eliminate write page faults. However, for both process memory and file system writes, the footprint of a workload is unpredictable and potentially unbounded. Moreover, as discussed earlier, technology trends do not support this as a viable solution; faster devices that serve as more cost effective and energy-efficient replacement for DRAM to store relatively cold data are becoming available.</p><p>Prefetching <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref> is an alternative approach that can reduce blocking by anticipating memory accesses and prefetching necessary pages to eliminate page faults. Moreover, it can also increase the efficiency of access to the storage back-end by issuing multiple page prefetch requests simultaneously. Prefetching has been demonstrated as valuable when using an SSD-backed virtual memory system <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref>. Unfortunately, prefetching can incur both false positive and false negative fetches that pollute memory. With non-blocking writes, pages are only brought to memory when they are accessed. Fortunately, the two methods are not exclusive and can be used in conjunction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Solution Approach</head><p>Page over-writes can be either supervised or unsupervised by the OS. Supervised page over-writes occur via system calls, typically to file system data and metadata pages. Un-supervised page over-writes occur in user pages and memory mapped file pages.</p><p>For supervised over-write to an out-of-core page, the OS has all the information it needs to set up the nonblocking write. Once the application makes an OS pagemodifying system call, the OS can allocate a buffer to temporarily store the data. It can then use the offset and size information from the system call parameters to set up the asynchronous read of the relevant file pages and atomically merge these with the saved data after the read is completed. In case a non-blocking write to the overwritten page is already in progress, the new data is stored in the same buffer to be merged when the in-progress asynchronous read completes.</p><p>For an un-supervised over-write to an out-of-core page, the processor would generate a page fault. Commodity processors provide the reference address and the instruction that generated the page fault to the OS. Unfortunately, the number of bytes accessed by the instruction generating the page fault is usually not available. Modern processor architectures (e.g., x86) provide complex instructions that can perform multi-word writes in the same instruction <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>. In the rest of the section, we present three approaches to implement non-blocking writes in case of un-supervised page over-writes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Full Feature Hardware</head><p>This solution assumes that the processor provides all the information needed to implement non-blocking writes when interrupted due to a page fault. With such hardware, the OS can use the virtual address as well as the number of bytes accessed on a page fault and proceed similarly to the solution for the supervised over-write. In the future, processor manufacturers could augment CPU page fault interrupts with such information if not available. The advantage of this approach is that the hardware provides all the information needed and no additional time needs to be spent by the OS to determine such information. If such support is not universal, the solution described above becomes architecture dependent.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Opcode Disassembly</head><p>A second solution is to disassemble the opcode of the instruction that generated the page fault to extract the number of bytes written to the page. Opcode disassembly functionality for several commodity ISAs is implemented in several important systems software projects that need to perform binary analysis or translation such as QEMU <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>, VMware <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref>, and the Linux kernel. Although these implementations are highly optimized, disassembly would still increase the computation demand in the time-critical page fault handler. This solution can be implemented for any machine architecture.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Page Diff-Merge</head><p>Our last solution uses a page diff-merge technique as illustrated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 3</ref>. On a write fault, we write the modifications in two temporary pages using the available single-step feature on modern processors: a 0-page initialized with all zero bits and an 1-page initialized with all ones. With these two pages available, the OS can construct the new version of the page read asynchronously using a merge technique that performs bitwise or and and with the 0-page and 1-page respectively. This approach is architecture-independent and no special hardware is necessary. Unfortunately, it adds even more time and space overhead than opcode disassembly because of the additional data operations and page faults incurred, one each for writing to the 0-page and 1-page.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Quantifying Benefits</head><p>In this section, we quantify the potential benefits of nonblocking writes using several workloads.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Full System Memory Traces</head><p>We modified the QEMU machine emulator <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>   <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>, and SPECpower <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref>. SPX X indicates the percentage of load in the system. PM is set to the small-small configuration used by <ref type="bibr">Riska et al.[12]</ref>.</p><p>between jumps and jump return points) is sent to the inline compiler, we insert code for recording each load and store instruction. Since the addresses used by loads and stores may be unknown at translation block compile time, the appropriate register values are recorded at run time. Guest virtual address to guest physical address translation is obtained via a custom extension to the software TLB managed by QEMU. The memory accesses go through a cache simulator (code borrowed from valgrind <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>) at runtime. The caches used were a 64KB I1 instruction cache, a 64KB D1 data cache and a 4MB L2 data cache, all using lines of 64 bytes. Timestamps were assigned by mapping instruction counts to wall-clock time based on execution times observed in real hardware. We ran Linux on the modified QEMU emulator configured with 1GB of physical memory and trace the workloads detailed in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. The emulator itself ran on a 2.93 GHz Intel Xeon X7350 processor. The traces we collected included both userlevel and kernel memory references and included the following information: emulator time-stamp, instructioncount, process CR3, virtual address, physical address, access-mode (R/W), machine-mode (kernel/user), page access privileges.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Virtual Memory Simulation</head><p>We built a virtual memory simulator that given a memory size and a memory trace, simulates hits, misses, and evictions of memory pages. On every memory reference, it reports the timestamp, operation mode (read or write), and event (hit, miss, or evict). More importantly, the simulator is designed to report the number of write faults that can benefit from non-blocking writes. To do so, the simulator must (i) be able to distinguish over-writes from allocation-writes, and (ii) determine which write faults can really benefit from non-blocking writes.</p><p>As discussed previously, allocation-writes do not trigger I/O operations while over-writes may. Unfortunately, we do not have sufficient information in our traces to entirely distinguish one from the other. In order to minimize the occurrence of false positives when detecting over-writes, we use two heuristics. First, we consider the first write access to every page in the trace conservatively as an allocation write by default. Second, we use both the virtual and physical addresses to uniquely identify a page, instead of just the virtual address or the physical address alone. This eliminates false positives in detecting overwrites when the same virtual address is reused to map to a different physical address or vice-versa.</p><p>Finally, the simulator also employs a model to predict I/O latency for various values of OIO which is then used to determine when an asynchronous read related to a non-blocking write would complete. Using an approximation proposed by Gulati et al. that latency varies linearly with OIO <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref> and training this model on a few points with a real SSD (PCIe OCZ Revodrive 160GB), we were able to predict the latency of the device for any arbitrary OIO value.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Fraction of Non-blocking Write Faults</head><p>We measured the fraction of page faults that benefit from non-blocking writes for all workloads in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. <ref type="figure">Fig- ure 2</ref> shows these results. When the provisioned DRAM is half of the total memory footprint (total size of memory referenced) for each workload, 2-88% of the faults are write faults that benefit from non-blocking writes. When the provisioned DRAM is reduced to a fourth of the memory footprints, the fraction of non-blocking write faults is 7-42%. This implies that there is substantial potential for improving the overall performance of page fault related work for many of these workloads. For some workloads, a reduction in memory size causes a reduction in the percentage of non-blocking writes. For these workloads, higher page fault rates (as reduced memory sizes) lead to more of the pages involved in non-blocking writes being selected for eviction. Our simulator correctly revokes the non-blocking write status for such pages given that they must now block for the completion of the background read before they can be evicted.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Outstanding Write Faults</head><p>While the fraction of non-blocking write faults are partially indicative, they do not suggest how the absolute number of simultaneous non-blocking writes vary over time. To address this consideration, we define the outstanding write faults (OWF) as the number of write faults that can still benefit from non-blocking writes at any time during the execution of a process. OWF gets incremented each time there is a write to an out-of-core page. An asynchronous read to the page is also initiated at that time and the page is marked as in-io. When there is a read reference by the process to an in-io page, or an in-io page is evicted, or if the simulated asynchronous read due to an in-io page completes, the OWF value gets decremented. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 4</ref> reports the expected value (time-weighted average) of the OWF for each of the workloads when the DRAM size is configured to be 50% or 25% of the total memory footprint. First, we note that all workloads show values greater than zero, indicating that each can benefit from non-blocking writes. For most workloads, the OWF ranges from 2 to 33, indicating a healthy opportunity for parallelizing the asynchronous reads due to non-blocking writes. The two exceptions are EC, which has the lowest OWF value (0.005), and H2, which has an exceptionally high OWF value (1259.07).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.5">Estimating Overall Savings</head><p>To estimate how non-blocking writes would impact execution times, we revisit the percentage of page faults that can benefit from non-blocking writes (discussed earlier in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>). This gives an upper bound on the savings in running time that our set of benchmarks could have with non-blocking writes. With 50% DRAM provisioning relative to memory footprint size, half of the workloads show 20% or less page faults that benefit from non-blocking writes. However, the range is 30% to 80% for the remaining half which incur more paging activity. Combining this finding with those from previous studies which show that applications using paging and are heavily optimized spend more than 40% on disk I/O <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref>, we could estimate an overall reduction of 12% to 32% in application execution times for these workloads.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.6">Overhead</head><p>Non-blocking writes are not free from overhead. The temporary buffer pages that hold modifications while the asynchronous read is in progress consume additional memory resources. The average memory overhead of the system is proportional to the E[OWF] of the application since the system must buffer data for each outstanding write fault. This number, as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 4</ref>, is usually low. On average, we see an E[OWF] close to 10. If we assume a conservative 8KB (two pages) for each OWF as per the page diff-merge technique, we would use 80 KB of memory, representing a nominal overhead. Our worst case, H2, has an E[OWF] of less than 1300, which results in roughly 10MB of overhead using the same calculation as above.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Non-blocking writes via the page diff-merge technique. The step numbers match the ones in Figure 1. Rectangles refer to pages in memory.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Expected OWF for various workloads with two different memory sizes: 50% and 25% of workload footprint.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>block (i.e., binary blocks</head><label></label><figDesc>to collect full system memory traces for the x86 architecture. We modified the software-MMU version of QEMU and in- serted tracing code at binary translation points. Specifi- cally, each time a translation</figDesc><table>Workload 

ID 
Footprint 
Exec. Time 
# References 
(MB) 
(secs) 
(×10 6 ) 

batik 
BT 
149 
17.60 
25 
eclipse 
EC 
223 
7.20 
11 
fop 
FP 
144 
11.16 
32 
h2 
H2 
722 
44.19 
386 
jython 
JT 
540 
49.68 
128 
pmd 
PD 
170 
20.86 
60 
tomcat 
TC 
215 
33.39 
118 
tradebeans 
TB 
337 
23.84 
87 
tradesoap 
TS 
335 
31.56 
84 
postmark 
SS 
256 
9.9 
69 
specpower-20 
SP20 
218 
22 
44 
specpower-40 
SP40 
224 
22 
48 
specpower-60 
SP60 
214 
22 
53 
specpower-80 
SP80 
214 
22 
60 
specpower-100 
SP100 
211 
22 
63 

Table 1: Workloads include a mix of DaCapo benchmark 
suite 9.12 [3], PostMark </table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusions and Future Work</head><p>We presented non-blocking writes, a technique that eliminates the blocking read-before-write requirement incurred in handling write page faults. Non-blocking writes absorb modifications to out-of-core pages in temporary buffer pages allowing the process to continue immediately, while reading-in the page and merging changes later asynchronously. We quantified the benefits of non-blocking writes and estimated a savings in execution time of 12-32% across a variety of workloads. The natural next step for our work will involve an actual operating system implementation of non-blocking writes to accurately quantify its benefits for real workloads.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Valgrind</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://valgrind.org/" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">QEMU, a fast and portable dynamic translator</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bellard</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the USENIX ATC</title>
		<meeting>of the USENIX ATC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005-04" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The DaCapo benchmarks: Java benchmarking development and analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Blackburn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Et</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of OOPSLA</title>
		<meeting>of OOPSLA<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006-10" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="169" to="190" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automated io load balancing across storage devices</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gulati</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Ahmad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kumar</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Basil</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">FAST (2010)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="169" to="182" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Solid state storage technology for Proliant servers</title>
		<ptr target="http://h20000.www2.hp.com/bc/docs/support/SupportManual/c01580706/c01580706.pdf" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">HP</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Sun pushes SSDs in servers to reduce costs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Infoworld</forename><surname>Article</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.infoworld.com/t/hardware/sun-pushes-ssds-in-servers\-reduce-costs-improve-performance-980" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Intel 64 and IA-32 Architectures Software Developers Manual. Specification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Intel</forename><surname>Corporation</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">PostMark: A New File System Benchmark</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katcher</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>TR3022</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Network Appliance Inc</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997-10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical Report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Flashcache: a nand flash memory file cache for low power web servers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kgil</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mudge</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the 2006 international conference on Compilers, architecture and synthesis for embedded systems</title>
		<meeting>of the 2006 international conference on Compilers, architecture and synthesis for embedded systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006-10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Identifying shades of green: the specpower benchmarks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lange</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K.-D</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="95" to="97" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Design and Implementation of the 4.4 BSD Operating System</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mckusick</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Bostic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Karels</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Quar-Terman</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="0196" />
			<publisher>Addison Wesley</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page">163</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluating block-level optimization through the io path</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Riska</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Larkby-Lahet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Riedel</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the USENIX ATC</title>
		<meeting>of the USENIX ATC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Revisiting the Virtual Memory Hierarchy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Saxena</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Swift</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Flashvm</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of USENIX ATC</title>
		<meeting>of USENIX ATC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why does file system prefetching work?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shriver</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Small</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Smith</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of USENIX ATC</title>
		<meeting>of USENIX ATC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">VMWare ESX Server User&apos;s Manual Version</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vmware</forename><surname>Inc</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.vmware.com/support/pubs/esx_pubs.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
