<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/atharsefid/Desktop/grobid-0.5.3/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.3" ident="GROBID" when="2020-09-29T02:05+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Nested QoS: Providing Flexible Performance in Shared IO Environment</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hui</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Rice University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Varman</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Rice University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Nested QoS: Providing Flexible Performance in Shared IO Environment</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The increasing popularity of storage and server consolidation introduces new challenges for resource management. In this paper we propose a Nested QoS service model that offers multiple response time guarantees for a work-load based on its burstiness. The client workload is filtered into classes based on the Service Level Objective (SLO) and scheduled to provide requests in each class a stipulated response time guarantee. The Nested QoS model provides an intuitive, enforceable, and verifiable SLO between provider and client. The server capacity in the nested model is reduced significantly over a traditional SLO while the performance is only marginally affected.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Large virtualized data centers that multiplex shared resources among hundreds of paying clients form the backbone of the growing cloud IT infrastructure. The increased use of VM-based server consolidation in such data centers introduces new challenges for resource management, capacity provisioning, and guaranteeing application performance. Service Level Objectives (SLOs) are employed to assure clients a level of performance QoS like minimum throughput or maximum response time. The server should provide sufficient capacity to meet the stipulated QoS goals, while avoiding over-provisioning that leads to increased infrastructure and operational costs. Accurate provisioning is complicated by the bursty nature of storage workloads <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">9]</ref> and sharing by multiple client VMs. Performance SLOs range from simply providing a specified floor on average throughput (e.g. IOPS) to providing guarantees on the response time of requests. The former can be readily supported using weighted Fair Queuing approaches (see Section 6); providing response-time guarantees requires that the input stream be suitably constrained.</p><p>In this paper we propose a Nested QoS service model that offers a spectrum of response time guarantees based on the burstiness of the workload. It formalizes the observation that a disproportionate fraction of server capacity is used to handle the small tail of highly bursty requests. In <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref> we described a workload decomposition scheme to identify and schedule these requests to reduce capacity. However, this framework is not backed by a formal underlying SLO model; the difficulty is in coming up with a suitable specification. For instance, while the client may be satisfied with an agreement that guarantees 95% of its requests will have a response time of less than 20ms, the provider can only make such an assurance if the workload satisfies some constraints on burstiness and throughput. Further, the model should be intuitive, easy to enforce, and mutually verifiable in case of dispute. The Nested QoS model provides a formal (but intuitive and enforceable) way to specify the notion of graduated QoS, where a single client's SLO is specified in the form of a spectrum of response times rather than a single worst-case guarantee. The model properly generalizes SLOs based on a single response time guarantee (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref>).</p><p>In Section 2 we describe the Nested QoS model and its implementation. In Sections 3 and 4 we demonstrate how it can reduce capacity in single client and shared client environments respectively. It's still useful in a nonoversubscribed environment because of economy reason ( improved server utilization and reduced cost). Analysis of the server capacity is presented in Section 5. Our work is related to the ideas of differentiated service classes in computer networks <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref> [12] <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref>. However, we believe our model and analysis are different from these works, and the decomposition and evaluation of storage traces is new.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">System Model</head><p>The workload W of a client consists of a sequence of requests. <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> shows the framework of our Nested QoS service model. The performance SLO is determined by multiple nested classes C 1 , C 2 · · · C n . Class C i is specified by three parameters: (σ i , ρ i , δ i ), where (σ i , ρ i ) are token bucket <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref> parameters and δ i is the response time guarantee. C i consists of the maximally-sized subsequence of requests of W that is compliant with a (σ i , ρ i ) token bucket: that is, the number of requests in any interval of length t is upper bounded by σ i + ρ i t, and no other request of W can be added to the sequence without violating the constraint. The token bucket provides an envelope on the traffic admitted to each class by limiting its burst size (σ i ) and arrival rate (ρ i ). All requests in C i have a response time limit of δ i . Nesting requires that σ i ≤ σ i+1 , ρ i ≤ ρ i+1 and δ i ≤ δ i+1 .</p><p>For example, a 3-class Nested QoS model <ref type="bibr">(30, 120 IOPS, 500ms)</ref>, <ref type="bibr">(20, 110 IOPS, 50ms</ref>), (10, 100 IOPS, 5ms) indicates that: all the requests in the workload that lie within the (10, 100 IOPS) envelope have a response time guarantee of 5ms; the requests within the less restrictive <ref type="bibr">(20, 110 IOPS)</ref> arrival constraint have a latency bound of 50ms, while those conforming to the <ref type="bibr">(30, 120 IOPS)</ref> arrival bound have a latency limit of 500ms.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">z Class 1 (σ1, ρ1, δ1) Class 2 (σ2, ρ2, δ2񮽙)</formula><p>Class 3 (σ3, ρ3, δ3)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 1. Nested QoS Framework</head><p>Requests Arrival</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">Classifier (σ1, ρ1) Classifier (σ2, ρ2) Classifier (σ3, ρ3) Q1, δ1 Q3, δ3 Q2, δ2</formula><p>Figure 2. Nested Traffic Envelopes <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> shows an implementation of the model. It consists of two components: request classification and request scheduling (not shown in the <ref type="figure">figure)</ref>. The former is implemented using a cascade of token buckets, B 1 , B 2 · · · B n (innermost is B 1 ). The buckets filter the arriving workload so that queue Q 1 receives all requests of class C 1 , Q 2 receives requests of C 2 − C 1 , and Q 3 receives requests of C 3 − C 2 . By ensuring that requests in queue Q i meet a response time of δ i , the SLO of the Nested QoS model can be met. The scheduler services requests across the queues within a client based on their deadlines using an Earliest Deadline First (EDF) policy. To give an example of request classification, <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref> shows the filtering of the Exchange workload as it goes through the token bucket network.</p><p>B i has parameters (σ i , ρ i ) that regulates the number of requests that pass through it in any interval. Initially B i has σ i tokens; an arriving request removes a token from the bucket (if there is one) and passes thorough to B i−1 (or Q 1 if i is 1); if there are no tokens in B i the request goes into the queue Q i+1 instead. B i is filed with tokens at a constant rate ρ i , but the maximum number of tokens is capped at σ i . In Section 5 we compute the capacity required to meet the SLO specified by the Nested QoS model parameters.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Nested QoS for a Single Workload</head><p>We describe how the Nested QoS parameters of a workload will typically be determined. The client first decides the number of classes and their sizes (as a fraction of workload size) by empirically profiling the workload to achieve a satisfactory tradeoff between capacity required (cost) and performance. (Usually three classes appear to be sufficient over a variety of workloads.) Using a decomposition algorithm (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref>) one can determine the minimum capacity κ 1 required for a fraction f 1 of the workload to meet the deadline δ 1 . We choose ρ 1 = κ 1 and σ 1 = ρ 1 δ 1 . We similarly profile each of the classes, and set ρ 2 = max{κ 1 , κ 2 } and σ 1 ≤ σ 2 ≤ ρ 2 δ 2 , and ρ 3 = max{κ 2 , κ 3 } and σ 2 ≤ σ 3 ≤ ρ 3 δ 3 .  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>. Capacity Requirement for Nested QoS and Single level QoS</head><p>We implemented the Nested QoS model in a processdriven system simulator and evaluated the performance separately with five block-level storage workloads (W1-W5) from UMass Storage Repository <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref> and SNIA IOTTA Repository <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>: WebSearch1, WebSearch2, FinTrans, OLTP, Exchange. WebSearch1, WebSearch2 are traces from a web search engine and consist of user web Exchange trace is from Microsoft Exchange Server. The parameters for each workload are as follows: δ 1 = 5ms (all workloads); σ 1 = 3 (W1,W2,W3), σ 1 = 4 (W4), and σ 1 = 33 (W5); ρ 1 = 650 (W1, W2), ρ 1 = 600 (W3), ρ 1 = 400 (W4) and ρ 1 = 6600 (W5). For the other classes, σ i+1 = 2σ i , δ i+1 = 10δ i and ρ i+1 = ρ i . The values were found by profiling the workloads to guarantee more than 90% requests in C 1 . <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 4</ref> compares the capacity required by the workloads for the Nested and Single-Level QoS models. The capacity is significantly reduced by spreading the requests over multiple classes. <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref> shows the distribution of response times. In each case a large percentage (92%+) of the workload meets the 5ms response time bound, and a tiny 0.1% or less requires more than 50ms. The capacity required for Nested QoS is several times smaller than that for a Single-Level QoS, while the service seen by the clients is only minimally degraded .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Nested QoS for Concurrent Workloads</head><p>In a shared environment, each VM workload is independently decomposed into classes based on its Nested QoS parameters. The server provides capacity κ j for VM j based on its capacity estimate using the formula of Section 5, and provisions a total capacity of Σ j κ j . A standard Fair Scheduler allocates the capacity to each VM in proportion to its κ j . When VM j is scheduled it chooses a request from its queues with the smallest deadline. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 6</ref> shows the organization for serving multiple clients. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>. The architecture of Nested QoS model in a VM Environment</head><p>We compare the performance of WF2Q <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>, and pClock <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref> with scheduling of requested streams decomposed by Nested QoS. The former two methods try to provide 100% guarantees and their performance degrades appreciably if the capacity provisioned is less than that required. We employ two concurrent workloads WebSearch and FinTrans from two VMs. The parameters setting are: σ 1 = 16, ρ 1 = 320, δ 1 = 50ms for WebSearch, and σ 1 = 8, ρ 1 = 160, δ 1 = 50ms for FinTrans. For both workloads, σ i+1 = 2σ i , δ i+1 = 10δ i , ρ i+1 = ρ i . <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Fig-  ures 7 (a) (b)</ref> show the performance of the three schedulers with the server capacity of 528 IOPS. The weight of the two VMs is 2 : 1 based on their capacity requirements. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 7</ref>(c) for the WebSearch workload shows that with Nested QoS 97% of the workload meets the 50ms response time bound, while pClock and WF2Q can only guarantee 70% and 48% respectively. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 7(d)</ref> shows a similar performance for FinTrans. We see that Nested QoS can provide better performance guarantees than both pClock and WF2Q.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Analysis</head><p>The workload W consists of a sequence of requests arriving at times 1, 2, 3, .... The decomposition splits W into classes C 1 , C 2 , · · · C n . C i consists of the requests of W that are output by the token bucket B i . All requests in C i have a response time no more than δ i . From the nested definition, we require that σ i ≤ σ i+1 , ρ i ≤ ρ i+1 and δ i ≤ δ i+1 . The problem is to estimate the server capacity required to meet the SLO. We present here only the result for special case where all ρ i are equal to ρ; this is also the case used in all the experimental evaluations in this paper. We define a busy period to be an interval in which there are one or more requests in the system. Lemma 1 The capacity required for all requests to meet their deadlines in the Nested QoS model, when all ρ i are equal to ρ, is given by: max 1≤j≤n {σ j /δ j + ρ(1 − δ 1 /δ j ), ρ}. Proof: We bound the maximum number of requests that need to finish by time t ≥ 0, where t = 0 is the start of the busy period. All requests with a deadline t or less must have arrived in the interval [0, t − δ 1 ], since δ 1 is the smallest response time bound. Requests with response time bound δ j have, by definition, been passed by B j . The maximum number of requests with deadline t that could have been admitted by B j in [0, t − δ 1 ] is N j (t) = σ j + ρ(t − δ 1 ). The server capacity κ j required to finish the N j (t) requests by t is no more than N j (t)/t = (σ j − ρδ 1 )/t + ρ. First, if σ j &lt; ρδ 1 then κ j is no more than ρ. Otherwise, we consider two cases: t ≥ δ j and t &lt; δ j . If t ≥ δ j the maximum value of N j (t)/t is reached for t = δ j and we get κ j no more than σ j /δ j + ρ(1 − δ 1 /δ j ). If t &lt; δ j , all the requests admitted by B j have a deadline less than δ j and hence must belong to class C j−1 or smaller; in this case κ j equals S j−1 . Putting the cases together, the Lemma follows. The following workload shows the capacity estimate is tight: a burst of σ n requests at t = 0 followed by requests arriving at the uniform rate ρ, will require the capacity estimated by the Lemma.</p><p>We end with an interesting case when the class parameters are multiples of the base value.</p><p>Lemma 2: Let α = δ i+1 /δ i , β = σ i+1 /σ i and λ = β/α be constants. The server capacity required to meet SLOs is no more than: max 1≤j≤n {ρ, λ j (σ 1 /δ 1 ) + ρ(1 − 1/λ j )}. For λ &lt; 1, the server capacity is bounded by σ 1 /δ 1 + ρ, which is less than twice the capacity required for servicing C 1 .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Related Work</head><p>The simplest QoS model provides each client i a guaranteed server bandwidth of B i IOPS. The server capacity is divided among the active clients in proportion to their guaranteed bandwidths, so that client i receives an allocation of C ×w i , where C is the server capacity, w i = B i / j∈A B j and A is the set of active clients. As long as the provisioned capacity C and the set of admitted clients A satisfy C ≥ j∈A B j , the QoS guarantees for all clients can be met. A large number of algorithms have been proposed for proportional resource sharing e.g. Fair Queuing <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>, WFQ <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">5]</ref>, WF2Q <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>, Start Time Fair Queuing <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>, SelfClocking <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref> etc. The general idea is to emulate the behavior of an ideal (continuous) Generalized Processor Sharing (GPS) scheduler in a discrete system, and divide the resource at a fine granularity in proportion to client weights. With proportional allocation, it is not possible to specify an independent response time requirement that is unrelated to its throughput. The WF2Q algorithm <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref> guarantees that the worst-case response time of a request of client i is bounded by the time to serve all its queued requests at a uniform rate B i without any additional delay. QoS models and algorithms for providing throughput guarantees when system capacity can vary, were presented in <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref>.</p><p>A second QoS model focuses on providing latency controls along with proportional sharing <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">10]</ref>. In addition to providing minimum bandwidth guarantees, individual requests are guaranteed a maximum response time provided the client traffic satisfies stipulated constraints on burst size and arrival rate. Cruz et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">5]</ref> utilize the service curves concept to regulate workload patterns and arrival rates. They provide the SCED algorithm to schedule workloads specified by a given set of service curves. However, a major problem of the SCED algorithm is that it may result in starvation of a client which uses spare system capacity. <ref type="bibr">Gulati et al.</ref> propose an algorithm pClock <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref>, which uses a token bucket to control the arrival burst size and flow rate, and provide a synchronization scheme to avoid starvation; further, by setting the deadline of a request to be as late as possible the method attains greater flexibility in scheduling spare capacity. An issue not addressed by these methods is the impact on QoS guarantees of a badly behaved workload which violates its arrival constraints. Since these methods do not isolate the non-compliant part of the workload from its well-behaved portions, even small violations can lead to  More closely related to nested QoS are network QoS models where traffic shaping is used to decompose the workloads, and provide performance guarantees in terms of bandwidth and latency. Typically, arriving network traffic is made to conform to a token-bucket model by regulating the arrivals, and dropping requests that do not conform to the bucket parameters. With this drop-and-retransmission mechanism, the workload performance is guaranteed for the admitted portion of the workload, and the server utilization is maximized. However, drop-and-retransmission is not generally acceptable in storage systems, whose protocols do not support automatic retry. The Nested QoS model classifies different portions of the workload into different classes and schedules them with different response time bounds. Empirical study of storage workloads to show the benefits of exempting a fraction of the workload from response time bounds was shown in <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref>, and used in the design of a slack-based two-level scheduler for a single client workload in <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref>. However, there was no formal QoS model underlying the approach, that precluded specifying a well-defined SLO.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusions and Future Work</head><p>The Nested QoS model provides several advantages over usual SLO specifications: (i) large reduction in server capacity without significant performance loss, (ii) accurate analytical estimation of the server capacity, (iii) providing flexible SLOs to clients with different performance/cost tradeoffs, and (iv) providing a clear conceptual structure of SLOs in workload decomposition. Our work continues to explore alternative implementations, capacity estimation for unrestricted parameters, relating workload characteristics with nested model parameters, semantic restrictions on decomposition, scheduling multiple decomposed workloads on a shared server, and a Linux block-level implementation.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4. Capacity Requirement for Nested QoS and Single level QoS</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 . Decomposition of workload into differente b S e a r c h 1 W e b S e a r c h 1 F i n T r a n s O L T P E x c h a n g e Overall percentage guaranteedFigure 5 .</head><label>35</label><figDesc>Figure 3. Decomposition of workload into different classes</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 6</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Figure 6. The architecture of Nested QoS model in a VM Environment</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 7 .</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Figure 7. Performance for Multiplexing</figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Storage Performance Council (UMass Trace Repository)</title>
		<ptr target="http://traces.cs.umass.edu/index.php/Storage" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
				<ptr target="http://iotta.snia.org" />
		<title level="m">SNIA: IOTTA Repository</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">W F 2 Q: Worst-case fair weighted fair queueing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C R</forename><surname>Bennett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">INFOCOM (1)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="120" to="128" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Performance Guarantees in Communication Networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C.-S</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher>
			<pubPlace>London, UK</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quality of service guarantees in virtual circuit switched networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Cruz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Journal on Selected Areas in Communications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1048" to="1056" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A self-clocked fair queueing scheme for broadband applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Golestani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">INFOCOMM&apos;94</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994-04" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="636" to="646" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Start-time fair queueing: a scheduling algorithm for integrated services packet switching networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Goyal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Vin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE/ACM Trans. Netw</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="690" to="704" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How fair is fair queuing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Greenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Madras</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="568" to="598" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Storage workload characterization and consolidation in virtualized environments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gulati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Ahmad</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Workshop on Virtualization Performance: Analysis, Characterization, and Tools (VPACT &apos;09)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">pClock: An arrival curve based approach for QoS in shared storage systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gulati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Merchant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Varman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACM SIGMETRICS</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">mClock: Handling Throughput Variability for Hypervisor IO Scheduling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gulati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Merchant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Varman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">USENIX OSDI</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Network calculus: a theory of deterministic queuing systems for the internet</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J.-Y. Le</forename><surname>Boudec</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Thiran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<publisher>SpringerVerlag</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Berlin, Heidelberg</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Workload decomposition for qos in hosted storage services</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Doshi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Varman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Graduated QoS by decomposing bursts: Don&apos;t let the tail wag your server</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Doshi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Varman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">29th IEEE International Conference on Distributed Computing Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Everest: Scaling down peak loads through i/o off-loading</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Narayanan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Donnelly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Thereska</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Elnikety</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rowstron</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of OSDI</title>
		<meeting>OSDI</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">QoS In Packet Networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<pubPlace>USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scheduling for quality of service guarantees via service curves</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Sariowan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Cruz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Polyzos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the International Conference on Computer Communications and Networks</title>
		<meeting>the International Conference on Computer Communications and Networks</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="512" to="520" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
