<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/atharsefid/Desktop/grobid-0.5.3/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.3" ident="GROBID" when="2020-09-29T02:12+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">WALDIO: Eliminating the Filesystem Journaling in Resolving the Journaling of Journal Anomaly WALDIO: Eliminating the Filesystem Journaling in Resolving the Journaling of Journal Anomaly</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>July 8-10. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wongun</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Keonwoo</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hankeun</forename><surname>Son</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hanyang</forename><surname>University</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wook-Hee</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Beomseok</forename><surname>Nam</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wongun</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Keonwoo</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hankeun</forename><surname>Son</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wook-Hee</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Ulsan National Institute of Science and Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Ulsan</settlement>
									<country key="KR">Korea</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Beomseok</forename><surname>Nam</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Ulsan National Institute of Science and Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Ulsan</settlement>
									<country key="KR">Korea</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Youjip</forename><surname>Won</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Youjip Won</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Dept. of Computer Software</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Ulsan National Institute of Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Hanyang University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">USENIX Association</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit4">Hanyang University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Seoul</settlement>
									<country key="KR">Korea</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">WALDIO: Eliminating the Filesystem Journaling in Resolving the Journaling of Journal Anomaly WALDIO: Eliminating the Filesystem Journaling in Resolving the Journaling of Journal Anomaly</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2015 USENIX Annual Technical Conference (USENIC ATC &apos;15)</title>
						<meeting>the 2015 USENIX Annual Technical Conference (USENIC ATC &apos;15) <address><addrLine>Santa Clara, CA, USA</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page">235</biblScope>
							<date type="published">July 8-10. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>This paper is included in the Open access to the Proceedings of the 2015 USENIX Annual Technical Conference (USENIX ATC &apos;15) is sponsored by USENIX.</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>This work is dedicated to resolve the Journaling of Journal Anomaly in Android IO stack. We orchestrate SQLite and EXT4 filesystem so that SQLite&apos;s file-backed jour-naling activity can dispense with the expensive filesys-tem intervention, the journaling, without compromising the file integrity under unexpected filesystem failure. In storing the logs, we exploit the direct IO to suppress the filesystem interference. This work consists of three key ingredients: (i) Preallocation with Explicit Journaling, (ii) Header Embedding, and (iii) Group Synchronization. Preallocation with Explicit Journaling eliminates the filesystem journaling properly protecting the file meta-data against the unexpected system crash. We redesign the SQLite B-tree structure with Header Embedding to make it direct IO compatible and block IO friendly. With Group Synch, we minimize the synchronization overhead of direct IO and make the SQLite operation NAND Flash friendly. Combining the three technical ingredients , we develop a new journal mode in SQLite, the WALDIO. We implement it on the commercially available smartphone. WALDIO mode achieves 5.1× performance (insert/sec) against WAL mode which is the fastest jour-naling mode in SQLite. It yields 2.7× performance (in-serts/sec) against the LS-MVBT, the fastest SQLite jour-naling mode known to public. WALDIO mode achieves 7.4× performance (insert/sec) against WAL mode when it is relieved from the overhead of explicitly synchronizing individual log-commit operations. WALDIO mode reduces the IO volume to 1/6 compared against the WAL mode.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Smart device, e.g. smartphone, smart TV, and smart pad, firmly position themselves as mainstream computing device. The mobile DRAM and mobile NAND Flash sales for smart device account for 30% <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[41]</ref> and 40% <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[8]</ref> of the world DRAM sales and NAND Flash sales, respectively.</p><p>In the smartphone, the storage subsystem is arguably the main governing factor for performance <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[23]</ref>.</p><p>Android IO stack suffers from the excessive IO behavior. Sending two character message, 'Hi', through the text messaging application yields at least 48 KByte of writes to the storage device. This anomalous amplification is due to the uncoordinated interaction between SQLite and EXT4 filesystem. The broken relationship between the EXT4 filesystem and SQLite is caused by the fact that SQLite synchronizes each change in the database file or in rollback journal file through fsync()/fdatasync() and that each call to fsync()/fdatasync() triggers the bulky EXT4 journal module to log the updated metadata. This phenomenon is called Journaling of Journal Anomaly <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[19]</ref>.</p><p>There have been a number of efforts to mitigate the Journaling of Journal anomaly <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[19,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">27,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">35,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">25,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">38]</ref>. These works either modify SQLite to reduce the number of fsync() calls <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[19,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">27]</ref> or modify the filesystem to mitigate the overhead of a single fsync() <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[19,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">35,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">25,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">38]</ref>. While the overheads may vary, these works still need to journal the metadata of the SQLite journal file for each database transaction.</p><p>In this work, we dedicate our effort in resolving Journaling of Journal anomaly. We orchestrate EXT4 filesystem and SQLite so that SQLite can dispense with the expensive filesystem journaling in maintaining its journal file without compromising the file integrity under the unexpected system failure. We successfully eliminate the root cause for Journaling of Journal anomaly, the filesystem journaling. In our optimization effort, SQLite exploits "direct IO" in updating its journal file. Our work consists of three key technical ingredients: (i) Block Preallocation with Explicit Journaling, (ii) Header Embedding and (iii) Group Synch.</p><p>• Preallocation with Explicit Journaling: We preallocate the data blocks to the SQLite journal file and explicitly journal the file metadata. The subse-quent direct IO based log-commit operation does not incur any metadata update and the filesystem journaling can be eliminated. Via explicit journaling, the SQLite journal file is protected by the underlying filesystem against the unexpected system failure.</p><p>• Header Embedding: We develop Header Embedding and re-design the journal file structure. With Header Embedding, the fragmented SQLite journal file structure becomes 4 KByte aligned. The Header Embedding makes the SQLite journaling operation direct IO compatible and block IO friendly.</p><p>• Group Synchronization: With Group Synchronization (Group Synch in short), we aggregate multiple logs and to synchronize them as a single unit. Group synch effectively reduces the overhead of synchronizing the direct IO based log-commit operation to the storage surface. It significantly improves the performance via aligning the IO with NAND Flash page size.</p><p>Combining all these techniques, we develop a new SQLite journal mode, the WALDIO. We implement the WALDIO mode in commercially available smartphone model (Samsung Galaxy S5). WALDIO mode with persistent direct IO exhibits 5.1× performance (insert/sec) and 2.7× performance (insert/sec) against WAL mode which is the fastest stock SQLite journal mode and LS-MVBT <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[27]</ref> mode which is the fastest SQLite journal mode known to public, respectively. Smartphone with non-removable battery can potentially make the direct IO a persistent operation for practical purpose, in which case WALDIO yields 7.4× performance (insert/sec) against WAL mode and 4.0× performance (insert/sec) against LS-MVBT mode, respectively. The improvement in update and delete follow the similar trend. WALDIO mode reduces the write volume of SQLite to 1/6 compared to WAL mode.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Background</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">SQLite</head><p>SQLite is a serverless embedded DBMS. SQLite is the way of maintaining the records in various smartphone platforms, e.g. Android, iOS, Tizen and etc. and is widely used as the embedded DBMS for desktop applications, e.g. Chrome web browser, Firefox, Adobe Acrobat reader, Skype <ref type="bibr">[40]</ref>.</p><p>SQLite adopts B-tree for its database. The size of the B-tree node is power of two ranging from 512 Byte to 64 KByte. Default node size is 1024 Byte. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 1</ref> illustrates the leaf node structure. The B-tree node consists of the page header, the index array and the cell array. The page header resides at the beginning of the node. Next to the page header, there exists an index array. Each index points the variable size record. The record, which is called cell in SQLite, is allocated from the end of the node. The index array and the records grow in the opposite direction. When a cell is deleted, the space occupied by the deleted record is marked as dead. The page header maintains the number of the deleted cells. The deleted cells are weaved together as a linked list. SQLite allocates a new node when there is no more free space in the page or the deleted area.  <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[39,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">29,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">10]</ref>, SQLite does not have its own storage management module. SQLite heavily relies on the underlying filesystem to persistently manage its information and to protect it against unexpected system failure. SQLite uses file to maintain the log for crash recovery. For transactional guarantee, SQLite explicitly synchronizes, i.e. fdatasync(), the log file and the database file after committing the log or after updating the database, respectively.</p><p>SQLite provides six journal modes: DELETE, TRUNCATE, PERSIST, WAL, MEMORY and OFF. As the name suggests, MEMORY mode and OFF mode maintain the journal information in memory and does not maintain the journal information, respectively. The remaining four journal modes can be categorized into two: rollback journal and rollforward journal. DELETE, TRUNCATE and PERSIST modes are for rollback and WAL mode is for rollforward journaling, respectively. In the rollback journal mode, the SQLite operation, e.g. INSERT, DELETE and UPDATE, consists of three phases: (i) logging, (ii) database update and (iii) log reset. The three SQLite journal modes in rollback journaling share the first and the second phase. In logging phase, SQLite updates the journal header and logs the old database pages (undo log) in the journal file. In database update phase, the updated database pages are written to the database file. The objective of the log-reset phase is to mark that a given transaction has successfully completed. In the third phase (log reset), there is minor difference among the three SQLite journal modes. In DELETE mode, SQLite deletes the journal file. In TRUNCATE mode, SQLite truncates the journal file to 0. In PERSIST mode, SQLite puts special mark at the beginning of the journal file to denote that the transaction has completed. While the difference is subtle, it bears the profound implication on the filesystem journaling overhead. In DELETE mode, SQLite always needs to create the new journal file in the logging phase. Creating a file accompanies the large amount of metadata updates; the directory block, inode table, block bitmap and etc. All these metadata need to be journaled by the filesystem when fsync()/fdatasync() is called.</p><p>TRUNCATE mode retains the inode and deallocates the file blocks. Since TRUNCATE mode does not create the journal file, it yields smaller amount of metadata update compared to DELETE mode. As a result, when fsync()/fdatasync() is called in the logging phase, it yields smaller amount of EXT4 journal IO compared to DELETE mode.</p><p>PERSIST mode recycles not only the inode but also the file blocks. In PERSIST mode, the "logging" updates only the time related fields in the file metadata, e.g. mtime. Compared against TRUNCATE mode, the PERSIST mode further reduces the amount of metadata to be fsync()'ed in the logging phase. Via replacing the fsync() with fdatasync(), PERSIST mode achieves more reduction on the amount of metadata journaled in the "logging" phase <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[19]</ref>.</p><p>In WAL mode, SQLite appends the header and a set of updated database pages to the log file (redo log). We call this file as WAL file for convenience's sake. When the database table is closed or the number of committed database pages in WAL file reaches the predefined maximum, the committed database pages in WAL file are checkpointed to the database file. SQLite provides two options to synchronize the committed logs: Full Sync and Normal Sync. In Full Sync, SQLite calls fsync()/fdatasync() after each log-commit to persistently store the logs. In Normal Sync, SQLite calls fsync()/fdatasync() after each checkpoint. In Normal Sync option, the committed logs reside in the buffer cache till they are either checkpointed by SQLite or flushed by OS. The logs in the buffer cache are subject to loss in case of unexpected system failure, e.g. power failure, or operating system crash <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[6]</ref> and the durability of a transaction can be compromised. The default option is Full Sync.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">EXT4 Journaling</head><p>EXT4 filesystem provides three journal modes; Journal, Ordered and Writeback. The Ordered mode is the most widely used one. In Ordered mode, the filesystem logs only the updated metadata. When logging the metadata, the filesystem flushes all the data blocks related to the updated metadata and then it logs the updated metadata. EXT4 journaling module is bulky. An EXT4 journal transaction consists of a 4 KByte journal header, a set of 4 KByte journal records each of which corresponds to the updated filesystem block and a 4 KByte journal commit block. EXT4 journaling module is activated either on regular basis, e.g. in 5 sec interval, or via an explicit call to fsync() or fdatasync().</p><p>EXT4 journaling module functions efficiently when it is triggered in sufficiently large interval, e.g. in every 5 sec. With the large interval, the journal descriptor and the journal commit block pair carries sufficiently large amount of journal records in a single journal transaction. The overhead of journal descriptor and journal commit block is insignificant. SQLite drives the EXT4 filesystem in a way which, we carefully believe, has not been foreseen before and brings unacceptable inefficiency in Android IO stack. SQLite calls fdatasync() very frequently, typically after very few number of 4 KByte writes <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[19]</ref>. In fdatasync(), appending a 4 KByte block to a file accompanies at least 12 KByte of EXT4 journal writes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Analysis of Journaling of Journal Anomaly</head><p>We overhaul the interaction between the SQLite and EXT4. SQLite inserts one 100 Byte record into an empty database table and we examine the block level IO behavior of the underlying filesystem. We use open-source benchmark, Mobibench <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[31]</ref> and MOST <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[18]</ref> to generate the workload and to analyze the IO trace, respectively. We examine the IO behavior under five SQLite journal modes: OFF, WAL, DELETE, TRUNCATE, and PERSIST. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Fig. 2</ref> illustrates the block access patterns of SQL INSERT operations under five SQLite journaling modes. We mark SQLite journal related IO's and SQLite database related IO's with '+' and 'x', respectively. Each '+' and 'x' mark is annotated with the respective IO size in KByte unit. In the X-Y plane, the EXT4 journal region is marked with the light-grey background. The '+' marked IO's in the light-grey region correspond to the EXT4 journal writes for the SQLite journal file; Journaling of Journal overhead. We annotate each write in EXT4 data region with its type; the writes to journal file can be for journal header (H) or for journal record (P), respectively.</p><p>In OFF mode, SQLite synchronizes only the database file and does not accompany any SQLite journaling related IO <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(Fig. 2(a)</ref>). EXT4 filesystem writes two data blocks for database file and journals the respective metadata. The total 3 blocks are written in EXT4 journal re- gion: one page of journal descriptor, one page for updated metadata and one page of journal commit mark.</p><p>In WAL mode ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Fig. 2(b)</ref>), SQLite writes the redo log to WAL file and synchronizes the WAL file via fdatasync(). As a result of calling fdatasync(), EXT4 journals the updated metadata of the journal file, separately synchronizing the journal descriptor and journal commit mark. Since the committed database pages are checkpointed to the database file in batched manner, we do not observe any IO on the database file in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Fig. 2(b)</ref>. The third fsync() is for synchronizing the updated database file (phase 2: update the database). PERSIST mode carries an additional fsync() to persistently store the reset mark in the log file (phase 3: log-reset).</p><p>The Journaling of Journal overhead for DELETE, TRUNCATE and PERSIST mode corresponds to 44 KByte, 36 KByte and 40 KByte, respectively. These differences are due to the way in which the SQLite journal mode resets the log file. The WAL mode yields the smallest JOJ overhead, 20 KByte. naling activity accounts for more than 50% of the IO. While WAL mode yields the smallest amount of total IO, it is still subject to extreme IO inefficiency. In WAL, the filesystem journaling accounts for 70% of the entire IO traffic (20 KByte out of 28 KByte). WAL mode yields the smallest IO overhead and in the mean time, bears the largest room for improvement when the filesystem journaling overhead is eliminated.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Direct IO and SQLite</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Direct IO</head><p>Direct IO is a filesystem feature which allows the user to read and to write the data directly from and to the storage device. In direct IO, the data block is immediately written to the storage device bypassing the page cache. Direct IO based write, DIO write for short, returns when the data blocks reach the writeback cache of the storage device.</p><p>DBMS <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[13,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">3]</ref> and Virtual Machine Monitor <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[28,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">33]</ref> use direct IO to manage the storage device with minimum file system intervention. SQLite maintains the logs in a journal file. It uses buffered write in storing the log to the journal file and explicitly synchronizes the journal file via fsync()/fdatasync() for durability guarantee. Flushing the logs in the buffer cache can accompany the expensive filesystem journaling. If SQLite uses direct IO to write the log to the journal file, it can save the filesystem from expensive filesystem journaling activity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Writing a Block to the Storage</head><p>We examine the three ways to write a block to the storage device: (i) write() followed by fsync(), (ii) write() followed by fdatasync() and (iii) DIO write(). These approaches differ in a way in which the filesystem handles the updated metadata. In fsync(), EXT4 filesystem journals the updated metadata for the respective file. In fdatasync(), EXT4 filesystem journals the updated metadata only when the file block is allocated (or deallocated). DIO write by itself does not entail any filesystem journaling. We can categorize the write operations into two types: allocating write and non-allocating write. Allocating write is a write system call which requires an allocation of a new filesystem block.  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Fig. 3(b)</ref> schematically illustrate the IO paths of three different ways of writing 4 KByte to the storage device, for allocating and non-allocating write, respectively. For both allocating and non-allocating write, fsync() journals the updated metadata. In allocating write, fdatasync() exhibits the identical behavior as fsync(). In non-allocating write, fdatasync() does not journal any metadata. For both allocating and non-allocating write, direct IO does not accompany the filesystem journaling. In direct IO, the updated metadata, if there is any, can be subject to loss.</p><p>SQLite provides two options to synchronize the database (or journal) file: via fsync() and via fdatasync(). Android platform legitimately uses fdatasync() in SQLite to reduce the filesystem journaling overhead. Overhauling the IO behavior, we find an important caveat to resolve the Journaling of Journal anomaly, the EXT4 journaling overhead. In nonallocating write, "DIO write" yields the same behavior, though not precisely identical, with the "buffered write followed by fdatasync()" from the filesystem journaling's point of view; in delivering the data blocks to the storage, they both are free from the filesystem journaling.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Eliminating Filesystem Journaling in Android IO</head><p>We propose to use direct IO based write operation for committing the logs to the SQLite journal file so that the logs are directly written to the storage and the activity of committing the logs does not accompany any updates in the page cache entries; neither the data block nor the metadata. With this approach, the synchronization activity of SQLite, e.g. fdatasync(), does not trigger any filesystem journaling related IO. Our scheme consists of three key technical ingredients: (i) Preallocation with Explicit Journaling, (ii) Header Embedding, and (iii) Group Synch. Combining all these, we develop a new SQLite journal mode, WALDIO.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Preallocation with Explicit Journaling</head><p>The prime concern is to eliminate the interference of the EXT4 journaling in the log-commit operation and at the same time to protect the metadata of the journal file. We develop Preallocation with Explicit Journaling, where (i) we preallocate a certain amount of initialized blocks for a WAL file and (ii) journal the metadata for the created WAL file via explicitly calling fdatasync(). In this approach, we do rely on filesystem journaling to protect the metadata of the SQLite journal file, but suppress the every log-commit operation to accompany filesystem journaling. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Fig. 4</ref> schematically illustrates the detailed process; (i) WAL file is preallocated with the initialized blocks (labeled as 1), (ii) the metadata of the WAL file is synchronized to disk via fdatasync() (labeled as 2), and (iii) the logs are committed to WAL file via direct IO (labeled as 3, 4 and 5). EXT4 filesystem maintains an initialized flag for each data block. A file block is said to be initialized when this flag is set. Any attempts to read the uninitialized Being pre-allocated with the file blocks, the direct IO based log-commit operation becomes non-allocating write, where both the page cache entries and the metadata of the WAL file remain intact. The log-commit operation in WALDIO mode leaves no room for filesystem journaling module to interfere with. WALDIO mode saves the SQLite from the expensive filesystem journaling. When the WAL file is created or extended, WALDIO calls fdatasync() to synchronize the file metadata. With Explicit journaling, the WAL file becomes robust against the system failure.</p><p>In Preallocation, a special care needs to be taken to initialize the allocated blocks. Otherwise, the logs written in WALDIO mode may not be readable after unexpected system failure. Let us explain why. The fallocate() system call of EXT4 returns the uninitialized blocks. They are initialized when they are written for the first time. When a block is written with direct IO, the filesystem sets the respective initialized flag if it has not been initialized yet. However, since DIO write does not accompany the filesystem journaling, the updated flag is subject to loss under the unexpected system failure. While the dirty page cache entries and the updated metadata are synchronized to the storage in every few seconds, e.g. 5 sec, the contents in the writeback cache of the storage device are written to the storage surface in much shorter interval, e.g. in typically a few msec. Under the unexpected system failure, therefore, the logs written with direct IO may become unreadable even when they actually exist in the storage due to the unavailability of the initialized flag.</p><p>We propose three approaches to initialize the allocated blocks and subsequently to guard the stale contents in the allocated blocks against the exposure. The first and the easiest approach is to zero-fill the allocated blocks prior to use. In the second and the third approaches, we exploit the discard (or trim) command in the eMMC storage <ref type="bibr">[1]</ref> to guard the stale content against the exposure. The discard command takes the list of the logical block addresses as an input and asks the eMMC storage to remove the mapping table entries for the respective logical blocks. In the second approach, we mount the filesystem with discard option and modify fallocate() to allocate the blocks with initialized flag set. When a filesystem uses discard mount option, it issues a discard command when the file blocks are deallocated. To force the fallocate() to return the blocks with initialized flags set, we port the existing NO HIDE STALE patch <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[34]</ref> to Linux source for Samsung Galaxy S5. In the third approach, we modify the fallocate() to allocate the blocks with initialized flag set and to discard the allocated blocks. We embed the discard command to the NO HIDE STALE patch <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[34]</ref> developed for the second approach and we develop a new flag NO HIDE STALE DISCARD for fallocate().</p><p>The main difference between the second and the third approach is the time when the blocks are unmapped. In the second and third approaches, the file blocks are unmapped when they are deallocated and when they are allocated, respectively. In the second approach, the filesystem issues discard command for all deallocated blocks. Meanwhile, in the third approach, the filesystem discards only the file blocks allocated to WAL file. The third approach yields the smaller overhead than the second one.</p><p>Each of these three approaches has pros and cons. The zero-fill operation accompanies IO overhead. Using discard mount option may slow down the filesystem <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">[37]</ref>. Many recent smartphone devices including our test platform Galaxy S5 mount the filesystem with discard option. We implement all these schemes in our test platform. Via implementing all three schemes, one can choose the right scheme to initialize the allocated blocks subject to the available features of the underlying filesystem and storage device.</p><p>There exists an important implementation specific issue which deserves further attention. The discard command is designed to make the garbage collection more efficient <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[21]</ref>. It is not designed to hide the stale content. The eMMC standard <ref type="bibr">[1]</ref> does not define what needs to be read when the discarded blocks are accessed. Some eMMC products, e.g. the one used by Samsung Galaxy S5 (Part No. MBC4GC), return all 0's when the discarded block is accessed. To use the discard command to hide the stale content, one needs to assure that the given eMMC product does not leak the stale content, i.e. is guaranteed to return all 0's or all 1's when the discarded block is accessed. Otherwise, one needs to take the resort to use trim command even though it is subject to larger overhead. The trim command is defined to return all 0's or all 1's when the trimmed block is accessed <ref type="bibr">[1]</ref>. On the same token, one also needs to assure that the given eMMC product does not ignore the discard command from the host in any circumstances, e.g. when the eMMC device is busy for performing background garbage collection.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Header Embedding</head><p>The direct IO operation fails when the IO size is not sector aligned. In SQLite, neither the redo log nor the undo log structures are sector aligned. Full fledged DBMS to align its database and cache organization for efficient block device interaction <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">29,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">39]</ref>. We reorganize the structure of SQLite WAL file and the database page to integrate direct IO into SQLite. Figures in <ref type="figure">Fig. 5</ref> illustrate the redo and undo log structures of SQLite, respectively. B-tree node size is 4 KByte. The undo log of SQLite consists of 4 Byte prefix (page number), the 4 KByte journal record, and 4 Byte checksum <ref type="figure">(Fig. 5(a)</ref>). Each of these components is separately written with write(). In WAL file, a redo log consists of 24 Byte frame header and 4 KByte WAL frame <ref type="figure">(Fig. 5(b)</ref>). They are written separately as well. This fragmented data structure of SQLite bars the use of direct IO in managing its journal file. We examine the DIO write performance under varying IO size from 512 Byte to 16 KByte <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">(Fig. 6)</ref>. The sequential write performance of Samsung Galaxy S5 reaches over 70 MByte/sec. With 512 Byte IO size, the sequential write is subject to extreme inefficiency yielding mere 2 MByte/sec. This is because the IO size is not aligned with the block size. We observe larger degree of performance improvement when the IO size is aligned with the filesystem block size, 4 KByte, or NAND Flash page size, 8 KByte, respectively. This trend persists beyond 16 KByte IO size. This simple experiment provides an important direction for our optimization effort; Align the IO with the filesystem block size and with the NAND Flash page size.</p><p>We develop Header Embedding to align the SQLite IO with the filesystem block size. Instead of maintaining the header outside the log record, we embed the WAL header and the frame header into the header page and the WAL frame, respectively. In WALDIO, we set the Btree node size to 4 KByte. WAL header is placed at the free space between database header and schema table in the root node of database B-tree. We harbor the 24 Byte frame header at the end of WAL-frame. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Fig. 7</ref> illustrates the log structure with header embedding. Embedding the frame header into the B-tree node, the available space in the B-tree node decreases. We physically examine the free spaces in B-tree nodes of SQLite. With few exceptions, there exists sufficient room to harbor 24 Byte field. Reserving 24 Byte for Header in the node, therefore, will not increase the number of nodes in the B-tree. We examine the efficiency of the different aligning schemes for redo log structure. In page padding, SQLite pads the WAL header and WAL frame header to make them 4 KByte aligned. We examine four schemes: WAL (the original one), WAL with page padding, WALDIO with page padding, and WALDIO with header embedding. We perform 1,000 INSERT operations and examine the total IO volume. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Fig. 8</ref>   structure, we reduce the IO volume to EXT4 Data region to 1/3 from 12.3 MByte to 4.4 MByte. With simple modification on the log structure accompanied by direct IO, the total IO volume decreases to 1/6 from 29.0 MByte to 4.6 MByte. The performance result will be dealt with in section 6.3.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Group Synchronization</head><p>Each layer in the IO stack, e.g. DBMS, filesystem, and block device layer, aggregates the IO's on its own way to remove the IO bottleneck <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[9,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">5]</ref>. While WALDIO mode is successful in eliminating the filesystem journaling overhead, the individual log-commit operations are separately issued to the storage device. This nature of direct IO bars the underlying Operating System from aggregating and coalescing the IO's. If the logs are immediately synchronized to the storage surface after they are written with direct IO, the storage behavior is subject to further inefficiency since the storage device loses the opportunity to exploit its writeback cache. In this situation, the IO size plays a rather critical role in the storage performance. When the IO size is not properly aligned with the NAND Flash page size, it may cause read-modifywrite problem <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">24]</ref>, proper handling of which requires complicated firmware technique such as subpage mapping <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[22]</ref>.</p><p>We develop Group Synchronization (Group Synch) to mitigate the synchronization overhead of the direct IO based log-commit operation. In Group Synch, we employ frame buffer and grouping interval. All log records which have been written during a grouping interval are maintained at the frame buffer. When the group- Group Commit from DBMS <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[9,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">11]</ref> and Anticipatory disk scheduling from Operating System <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[17]</ref>.</p><p>Figures in <ref type="figure">Fig. 9</ref> schematically illustrates the IO behavior in writing three blocks to the storage. In <ref type="figure">Fig. 9(a)</ref>, each of three blocks is written with separate write()'s (buffered IO) and then fdatasync() is called to synchronize them. We observe two sets of writes: dark gray ones and the light gray ones. The dark gray blocks correspond to data blocks. They are flushed to the disk with a single IO request. The set of light gray blocks correspond to EXT4 journal writes. In <ref type="figure">Fig. 9(b)</ref>, each of three blocks is separately written via direct IO. Each of the IO requests is synchronously delivered to disk, yielding significant overhead. <ref type="figure">Fig. 9(c)</ref> illustrates the IO behavior in the Group Synch. The IO requests are first accumulated at the frame buffer and then flushed to the disk as a single DIO write. With Group Synch, the three blocks are written with single IO without accompanying the filesystem journaling. The benefit of Group Synch is twofold: reduce the the overhead for synchronizing the DIO write's and align the IO with NAND Flash page size.</p><p>Group synch provides weaker transactional guarantee than the other SQLite journaling modes since larger number of logs may get lost under system failure. However, we carefully conjecture that the difference may be less than significant if the frame buffer size is properly set. In our limited empirical study, we find that a single SQLite transactions updates a number of database tables and indexes. For example, in contact manager application of Android, inserting an address book entry yields more than 8 logs to to the WAL file. We currently set the frame buffer size to four pages (16 KByte).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4">Durability</head><p>WALDIO should use Full Sync option to make the result of log-commit operation durable. When the WALDIO mode is used with Full Sync option, the log commit operation consists of two phases: (i) writing a log to the storage via DIO write and (ii) flush the writeback cache of the storage device via calling fdatasync() <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Fig. 10)</ref>. For better performance, we exploit Reliable Write command of eMMC standard <ref type="bibr">[1]</ref> and implement persistent direct IO, PDIO. With PDIO write, WALDIO mode writes the logs directly to the storage surface bypassing the writeback cache of the Flash storage <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Fig. 10)</ref>. The blocks written with persistent direct IO are guaranteed to survive the power crash. With PDIO write, we can dispense with Full Sync option since each log-commit becomes immediately durable. Non-removable battery in the smartphone can potentially make the DIO write a persistent one. Different from the logs in the buffer cache <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Fig. 10)</ref>, the logs in the writeback cache of the storage can survive the warm failure, e.g. Operating System crash <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[6]</ref> or kernel-panic <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[14]</ref>. It is very unlikely that the software bugs power off the device unexpectedly; Lue et.al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[35]</ref> reported that only 0.05% of AOSP software defect reports are related to the unexpected power failure. Also, as long as the power supply leaves some slack for eMMC to flush its writeback cache (typically a few msec), the content in the writeback cache will eventually be written to the storage surface. Given the rarity of the occasion, some application developers may prefer trading the perfect durability guarantee with the almost perfect durability guarantee with performance boost. For the device with non-removable battery, we carefully argue that WALDIO makes the Normal Sync option as one of the feasible choices for transactional guarantee for practical purpose.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Experiment</head><p>We examine the performance of WALDIO mode. We compare the behavior of the six SQLite journal modes: DELETE, TRUNCATE, PERSIST, WAL, LS-MVBT <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[27]</ref> and WALDIO. We implement these techniques in the recent smartphone model (Galaxy S5, Samsung, Android 4.4.2 (KitKat), Qualcomm MSM8974 Quadcore 2.5 GHz, 2 GByte DRAM, 32 GByte eMMC with 8 Kbyte page). We examine the performance of SQLite operations; INSERT, UPDATE and DELETE. We use Mobibench <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[31]</ref> and MOST <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[18]</ref> to generate the workload and to analyze the trace, respectively. We use NO HIDE STALE DISCARD flag in Preallocation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">IO Access Pattern</head><p>We first examine the IO access pattern of the newly proposed journal mode, WALDIO. With WALDIO mode, we insert a single 100 Byte record. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 11</ref> illustrates the result. In WALDIO, INSERT operation generates single page write <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Fig. 11(a)</ref>). Be reminded that a single INSERT of 100 Byte record yields 80 KByte page writes and 28 KByte page writes in DELETE mode and WAL mode, respectively <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">(Table 1)</ref>. For illustrative purpose, we also show the IO accesses when the journal file is created ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 11(b)</ref>) and when the journal file is extended <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Fig. 11(c)</ref>), respectively. To visualize the improvement on IO volume, we examine the IO trace for 10 INSERT operations in WAL mode <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Fig. 12(a)</ref>) and in WALDIO mode <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Fig. 12(b)</ref>), respectively. In this figure, the center and the radius of each circle denote the start address and the size of an IO, respectively. The circle radius is linearly proportional to the actual IO size. In WAL mode, each log-commit writes </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Performance of Header Embedding</head><p>We examine the performance of four different page aligning schemes in WALDIO: sector padding, 4 KByte page padding, 8 KByte page padding and Header Embedding. We include the SQLite performance in WAL mode as the baseline. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 13</ref> illustrates the result. When the WAL file is sector padded (sector aligned), employing direct IO barely brings any performance gain against the WAL mode. When IO size is not aligned with the filesystem block size, the overhead of synchronously writing each data block offsets the benefit of eliminating the filesystem journaling overhead. When the WAL file structure is aligned with block size (4 KByte), the performance increases by 60% against the WAL. When the WAL file structure is aligned with NAND Flash page size <ref type="bibr">(8 KByte)</ref>, the SQLite performance increases by 100% against WAL. Via embedding the frame header information into the WAL frame, the SQLite yields 2.1× performance against WAL mode from 587 insert/sec to 1239 insert/sec.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3">WALDIO, the performance</head><p>We discuss the performance impact of WALDIO journal mode against existing SQLite journal modes: DELETE, TRUNCATE, PERSIST, WAL and LS-MVBT <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[27]</ref>. In WALDIO, we examine the performance under three synchronization options: (i) Full Sync, WALDIO-FS, (ii) Persis- tent Direct IO, WALDIO-PD and (iii) Normal Sync, WALDIO-NS. We examine the WALDIO performance with and without Group Synch. In Group Synch, the frame buffer size is set to 16 KByte with 2 msec grouping interval. We perform each of INSERT, UPDATE and DELETE operations 1,000 times and measure the performance. We put everything together in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 14</ref>. The results in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 14</ref> are categorized into five groups: stock SQLite journal modes, LS-MVBT, WALDIO with Full Sync option, WALDIO with persistent direct IO and WALDIO with Normal Sync option. In stock SQLite journal modes, WAL mode yields the best performance (587 insert/sec). With LS-MVBT, SQLite yields 1083 insert/sec performance. With LS-MVBT, the SQLite performance increases by 80% from the WAL mode. In all these journals modes, SQLite issues fdatasync() after every logcommit.</p><p>In  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 14</ref>: Performance Summary, NoGS: without Group Synch, GS4: Group Sync size = 4 pages against stock WAL mode and 2.5× performance against LS-MVBT, respectively. Group Sync improves the performance by 120% from 1219 insert/sec to 2729 insert/sec. Group Synch is successful in eliminating the overhead of guaranteeing the durability.</p><p>With persistent DIO, WALDIO performance increases by 10% against WALDIO with Full Sync option. Bypassing the writeback cache at the storage device brings significant improvement. The performance under persistent DIO corresponds to 5.1 × performance against stock WAL mode and 2.8× performance against LS-MVBT, respectively.</p><p>In Normal Sync, the individual DIO based logcommit operations are relieved from the burden of calling the expensive fdatasync(). With Group Synch with 16 KByte frame buffer, WALDIO achieves 4332 insert/sec. The performance increases by more than 35% against the case where individual log-commits are persistently written to the storage surface; from 2967 insert/sec (WALDIO-PD) to 4332 insert/sec (WALDIO-NS). The WALDIO exhibits dramatic 7.4× and 4.0× performance compared against the WAL and the LS-MVBT, respectively. DELETE and UPDATE operations exhibit the similar performance gain with the INSERT operation. Table 2 illustrates the performance numbers for individual modes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.4">IO Volume</head><p>We examine the total IO volume for performing 1,000 SQLite operations, insert, update and delete. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 15</ref> illustrates the result. We limit our discussion to insert operation due to the space limit. In rollback journal modes <ref type="bibr">(DELETE, TRUNCATE and PERSIST)</ref>, as much as total 90 MByte is written to disk and 60% of which are for EXT4 journal writes. Via using WAL mode, the total page writes decreases to 29 MByte. LS-MVBT further de-  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Related Work</head><p>While not everybody entirely agrees <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[35]</ref>, the performance of the smartphone is governed by the performance of the storage device, not by the performance of the airlinks <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[23]</ref>. In Android, it is reported that more than 70% page writes generated by the smartphone application are for filesystem journal and dominant fraction of which are generated by SQLite DBMS <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[32]</ref>. The excessive filesystem journaling activity is due to the fact that the SQLite maintains a separate rollback journal file and synchronizes the every update in the rollback journal file via fsync() <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[19]</ref>. Tizen <ref type="bibr">[16]</ref> also suffers from JOJ anomaly <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[26]</ref>.</p><p>Jeong et. al. applied various IO optimization techniques, e.g. WAL mode, F2FS <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[30]</ref>, external journaling and polling based IO and achieved 300% performance improvement against stock Android IO stack with DELETE journal mode <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[19]</ref>. Shen et. al. modified the EXT4 journal module and achieved 7% performance improvement against WAL mode <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[38]</ref>. <ref type="bibr">Kim et. al. proposed</ref> to use LS-MVBT (Multiversion B-tree with Lazy Split) instead of B-tree in SQLite database <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[27]</ref>. LS-MVBT weaves the crash recovery information into the database file so that SQLite does not have to maintain separate file for crash recovery. LS-MVBT brings 80% performance gain against WAL mode in SQLite.</p><p>There are a number of benchmark programs for Android IO performance <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">18,</ref><ref type="bibr">2]</ref>. Kim et. al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[25]</ref> proposed to maintain the EXT4 journal region at NVRAM and to exploit its byte-granularity accessibility. Lue et. al. proposed to maintain the SQLite rollback journal file at DRAM <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[35]</ref> in the smartphone. Chidambaram et. al. proposed OPTFS to reduce the fsync() overhead involved in EXT4 journaling <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[7]</ref>. Kang et. al. proposed a transactional API for block device so that filesystem operations are free from the journaling overhead <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[20]</ref>. Piernas et. al. proposed to maintain the data and the metadata on the different blocks and maintains only single copy of metadata <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[36]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8">Conclusion</head><p>In this work, we successfully resolve the Journaling of Journal Anomaly in Android IO stack. We remove the root cause for excessive IO behavior in Android IO stack: the filesystem journaling. We develop a novel SQLite journal mode, WALDIO. In WALDIO mode, SQLite uses direct IO for log-commit operation so that it does not entail the expensive filesystem journaling. We develop Preallocation with Explicit Journaling, Header Embedding and Group Synch to enable the SQLite to exploit the direct IO semantics without compromising the filesystem integrity optimizing its performance for NAND Flash storage. The proposed features are implemented on the commercially available smartphone. WALDIO achieves as much as 7.4× increase against WAL mode and as much as 4.0× increase against LS-MVBT, respectively. With WALDIO mode, SQLite generates only 1/6 of the IO volume generated by SQLite in WAL mode.</p><p>Despite the dramatic improvement, WALDIO mode does not cost any major changes on the existing interface definitions of SQLite or of the filesystem, nor the introduction of the new ones. It is achieved by the minimal set of right modifications.</p><p>The contribution of this work should be viewed not only from the performance perspective but also from the NAND Flash endurance point of view. We carefully believe that via decreasing the IO volume generated by SQLite to 1/6, WALDIO can make the TLC NAND Flash not an infeasible choice for storage device in Android platform. Adoption of TLC NAND Flash in Android device can significantly reduce the cost of the smartphone and can make it available to wider community in the world.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: SQLite B-tree node structure, node size = 4 KByte, PH: Page header Different from the large scale DBMS [39, 29, 10], SQLite does not have its own storage management module. SQLite heavily relies on the underlying filesystem to persistently manage its information and to protect it against unexpected system failure. SQLite uses file to maintain the log for crash recovery. For transactional guarantee, SQLite explicitly synchronizes, i.e.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: SQLite Block IO pattern (H: Journal Header or WAL Frame Header, P: DB page)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Fig. 2 (</head><label>2</label><figDesc>c), Fig. 2(d), and Fig. 2(e) illustrate block access patterns for rollback journal modes; DELETE, TRUNCATE and PERSIST, respectively. The rollback jour- nal modes synchronize both the rollback journal file and the database file after they are updated. Compared to WAL mode, the filesystem journaling overhead doubles. In all these rollback journal modes (Fig. 2(c), Fig. 2(d), and Fig. 2(e)), the first and the second fsync() are for syn- chronizing the rollback journal file (phase 1: logging).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Writing a block with fsync(), fdatasync() and direct IO Fig. 3(a) and Fig. 3(b) schematically illustrate the IO paths of three different ways of writing 4 KByte to the storage device, for allocating and non-allocating write, respectively. For both allocating and non-allocating write, fsync() journals the updated metadata. In allocating write, fdatasync() exhibits the identical behavior as fsync(). In non-allocating write, fdatasync()</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Preallocation with Explicit Journaling, 1: Preallocate the initialized blocks, 2: Journal the updated metadata, fdatasync(), 3, 4, and 5: Commit the logs with DIO</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Figure 5: Journal file structure of SQLite, node size: 4 KByte</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Figure 7: SQLite database page structure with Header Embedding (PH: Page Header, FH: Frame Header)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 8 :</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Figure 8: Total IO volume: 1000 INSERT in SQLite (PP: page pading, HE: header embedding)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>(</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 9: Writing three blocks to storage: fdatasync(), direct IO vs. Group Synch</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 10: Making the log-commit durable: WAL with Full Sync, WALDIO with Full Sync, WALDIO with PDIO, WALDIO with Normal Sync</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Figure 12 :</head><label>12</label><figDesc>Figure 12: IO trace for ten INSERTs: WAL mode vs. WALDIO mode (Full Sync option)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head>Figure 11 :</head><label>11</label><figDesc>Figure 11: IO accesses in WALDIO mode (P+H: Header embedding WAL Frame, 3P: three DB Pages)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head>Figure 13 :</head><label>13</label><figDesc>Figure 13: Page Aligning Schemes: Sector aligning, 4 KByte aligning, 8 KByte Aligning vs. Header Embedding (Full Sync)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>Table 1 summarizes</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>the traffic volume for five SQLite 
journal modes. In all SQLite journal modes, the filesys-
tem intervention is overly excessive; the filesystem jour-

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>, total 12.3 MByte is written to filesystem data region. The fragmented log structure puts unnecessary stress on the storage device. Via properly aligning the log</head><label></label><figDesc>illustrates the result. In WAL mode, total 29 MByte is written. Among 29.0 MByte, file data and EXT4 journal writes account for 12.3 MByte and 16.7 MByte, respectively. The size of WAL log record is 4120 Byte (24 Byte header and 4096 Byte frame). In committing 1,000 log entries of 4120 Byte each</figDesc><table>0 

5 

10 

15 

20 

25 

30 

35 

40 

45 

W 
A 
L 

W 
A 
L 
( 
P 
P 
) 

W 
A 
L 
D 
I 
O 
( 
P 
P 
) 

W 
A 
L 
D 
I 
O 
( 
H 
E 
) 

Volume(MB) 

EXT4 Data 

EXT4 Journal 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>SQLite performance (WALDIO-FS: WALDIO 
with Full Sync, WALDIO-PD: WALDIO with Persistent 
Direct IO, WALDIO-NS: WALDIO with Normal Sync, 
NoGS: Without Group Synch, GS: Group Synch with 4 
pages) 

0 

20 

40 

60 

80 

100 

I U D I U D I U D I U D I U D I U D 

Volume(MB) 

DEL TRU PER WAL LSM DIO 

Filesystem journal 
File Data/File Metadata 

Figure 15: IO volume for 1000 INSERTs, DEL: DELETE, 
TRU: TRUNCATE, PER: PERSIST, WAL: WAL, LSM: 
LS-MVBT, DIO: WALDIO </table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="9">Acknowledgments</head><p>We would like to thank the anonymous reviewers for their insightful comments and feedback. Special thanks go to our shepherd Theodore Ts'o whose constructive comment and advice have made our work further mature and rigorous. We also would like to thank Yongseok Jo at EFTECH, Dongjun Shin, Seunghwan Hyun, Dongil Park and Heegyu Kim at Samsung Electronics for their advice on revising this paper. Finally, we like to thank our colleague Seongjin Lee for his help in preparing the manuscript. This work is sponsored by IT R&amp;D program from MKE/KEIT (No. 10041608, Embedded system Software for New-memory based Smart Device) and by ICT R&amp;D program of MSIP/IITP (No.1I2221-14-1005).</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mysql Homepage</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.mysql.com/" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding Flash IO Patterns</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bouganim</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Jonsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>And Bonnet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Uflip</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of CIDR</title>
		<meeting>of CIDR<address><addrLine>Asilomar, CA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009-01" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bigtable: A Distributed Storage System for Structured Data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chang</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Dean</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ghemawat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Hsieh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Wal-Lach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Burrows</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Chandra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Fikes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gruber</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Trans. Comput. Syst</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="4" />
			<date type="published" when="2008-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The rio file cache: Surviving operating system crashes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chen</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chandra</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Aycock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Ra-Jamani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lowell</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of ASPLOS</title>
		<meeting>of ASPLOS<address><addrLine>Cambridge, MA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1966-09" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimistic Crash Consistency</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chidambaram</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Pillai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Arpaci-Dusseau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Arpaci-Dusseau</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of ACM SOSP 2013</title>
		<meeting>of ACM SOSP 2013<address><addrLine>Farminton, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">NAND Flash Market annual report</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chinaflashmarket</forename><forename type="middle">Com</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Implementation Techniques for Main Memory Database Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dewitt</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Katz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Olken</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Shapiro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Stonebraker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wood</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the ACM SIGMOD</title>
		<meeting>of the ACM SIGMOD<address><addrLine>Boston, MA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Principles of Database buffer management</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Effelsberg</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haerder</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Trans. on Database Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="560" to="595" />
			<date type="published" when="1984-12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Varieties of Concurrency Control in IMS/VS Fast Path</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gawlick</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kinkade</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Database Eng. Bull</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="10" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Great Android Police Storage Benchmark: 11 Modern Devices Compared</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gingrich</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.androidpolice.com/tags/rl-benchmark/" />
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Oracle and storage IOs, explanations and experience at CERN</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Grancher</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of JPCS CHEP</title>
		<meeting>of JPCS CHEP<address><addrLine>Prague, Czech</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009-03" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Characterization of linux kernel behavior under errors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Kalbarczyk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Iyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of DSN 2003</title>
		<meeting>of DSN 2003<address><addrLine>San Francisco, CA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reimplementing the Cedar File System Using Logging and Group Commit</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hagmann</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">SIGOPS Oper. Syst. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="155" to="162" />
			<date type="published" when="1987-11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anticipatory Scheduling: A Disk Scheduling Framework to Overcome Deceptive Idleness in Synchronous I/O</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Iyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Druschel</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of ACM SOSP</title>
		<meeting>of ACM SOSP<address><addrLine>Banff, Alberta, Canada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001-10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Framework for Analyzing Android I/O Stack Behavior: From Generating the Workload to Analyzing the Trace</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeong</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Hwang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Won</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Future Internet</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="591" to="610" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">I/O Stack Optimization for Smartphones</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeong</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Son</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Won</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of USENIX ATC 2013</title>
		<meeting>of USENIX ATC 2013<address><addrLine>San Jose, CA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Transactional FTL for SQLite Databases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kang</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W.-H</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S.-W</forename><surname>Moon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Oh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G.-H</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Min</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>X-Ftl</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of ACM SIGMOD 2013</title>
		<meeting>of ACM SIGMOD 2013<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding implications of trim, discard, and background command for emmc storage device</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kim</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Kang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Min</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eom</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of IEEE GCCE</title>
		<meeting>of IEEE GCCE<address><addrLine>Tokyo, Japan</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Partial page buffering for consumer devices with flash storage</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kim</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kang</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of IEEE ICCE-Berlin</title>
		<meeting>of IEEE ICCE-Berlin<address><addrLine>Berlin, Germany</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Revisiting storage for smartphones</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kim</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Agrawal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ungureanu</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of USENIX FAST 2012</title>
		<meeting>of USENIX FAST 2012<address><addrLine>San Jose, CA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">BPLRU: A Buffer Management Scheme for Improving Random Writes in Flash Storage</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kim</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ahn</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of USENIX FAST</title>
		<meeting>of USENIX FAST<address><addrLine>San Jose, CA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reducing Excessive Journaling Overhead with Small-Sized NVRAM for Mobile Devices</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kim</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Min</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eom</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Consumer Electronics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">IO Workload Characterization Of Tizen Based Consumer Electronics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kim</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Won</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of IEEE ISCE</title>
		<meeting>of IEEE ISCE<address><addrLine>Jeju, Korea</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Resolving Journaling of Journal Anomaly in Android I/O: Multi-Version Btree with Lazy Split</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kim</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W.-H</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nam</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Won</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of USENIX FAST</title>
		<meeting>of USENIX FAST<address><addrLine>Santa Clara, CA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">kvm: the Linux virtual machine monitor</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kivity</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kamay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Laor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lublin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liguori</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the Linux Symposium</title>
		<meeting>of the Linux Symposium<address><addrLine>Ottawa, Ontario, Canada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Database Buffer paging in virtual storage systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lang</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Wood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fernandez</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Trans. on Database Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="339" to="351" />
			<date type="published" when="1977-12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A New File System for Flash Storage</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lee</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Sim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Hwang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cho</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>F2fs</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of USENIX FAST 2015</title>
		<meeting>of USENIX FAST 2015<address><addrLine>San Jose, CA, US</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Mobile Benchmark Tool (MOBIBENCH)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lee</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://github.com/ESOS-Lab/Mobibench" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Smart Layers and Dumb Result: IO Characterization of an Android-based Smartphone</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lee</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Won</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of EMSOFT 2012</title>
		<meeting>of EMSOFT 2012<address><addrLine>Tampere, Finland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012-10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A New Disk I/O Model of Virtualized Cloud Environment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Liao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jin</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhang</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Parallel and Distributed Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1129" to="1138" />
			<date type="published" when="2013-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
				<ptr target="http://patchwork.ozlabs.org/patch/153251/" />
		<title level="m">Z. vfs: add falloc fl no hide stale flag in fallocate</title>
		<imprint/>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>LIU</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">qNVRAM: quasi NonVolatile RAM for Low Overhead Persistency Enforcement in Smartphones</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luo</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Tian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiang</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of USENIX HotStorage</title>
		<meeting>of USENIX HotStorage<address><addrLine>PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Philadelphia</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A New Journaling File System Without Meta-data Duplication</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Piernas</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Cortes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Garc´iagarc´ia</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Dualfs</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of ICS</title>
		<meeting>of ICS<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">REDHAT&quot;. &quot;performance of trim command on ext4 filesystem</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Journaling of Journal Is (Almost) Free</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Shen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhu</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. USENIX FAST</title>
		<meeting>USENIX FAST<address><addrLine>Santa Clara, CA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Silberschatz</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Korth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sudarshan</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Database System Concepts</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>McGraw-Hill</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Global mobile dram revenue rises 6%</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Trendforce</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.dramexchange.com/WeeklyResearch/Post/5/3904.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
