<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/atharsefid/Desktop/grobid-0.5.3/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.3" ident="GROBID" when="2020-10-16T20:10+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Editorial for the Joint Workshop on Bibliometric-enhanced Information Retrieval and Natural Language Processing for Digital Libraries (BIRNDL) at JCDL 2016</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Mayr</surname></persName>
							<email>philipp.mayr@gesis.org</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">GESIS -Leibniz-Institute for the Social Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Cologne</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">Introduction</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ingo</forename><surname>Frommholz</surname></persName>
							<email>ingo.frommholz@beds.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Institute for Research in Applicable Computing</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Bedfordshire</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Luton</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guillaume</forename><surname>Cabanac</surname></persName>
							<email>guillaume.cabanac@univ-tlse3.fr</email>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">UMR 5505</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Toulouse</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">IRIT</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dietmar</forename><surname>Wolfram</surname></persName>
							<email>dwolfram@uwm.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">School of Information Studies</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Editorial for the Joint Workshop on Bibliometric-enhanced Information Retrieval and Natural Language Processing for Digital Libraries (BIRNDL) at JCDL 2016</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>After the success of two parent workshops series -the 1st NLPIR4DL workshop in 2009, and the series of three Bibliometric-enhanced Information Retrieval (BIR) workshops in <ref type="bibr">2014</ref><ref type="bibr">, 2015</ref> at JCDL 2016 <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref> will investigate how natural language processing, information retrieval, scientometric and recommendation techniques can advance the state-of-the-art in scholarly document understanding, analysis and retrieval at scale. Researchers are in need of assistive technologies to track developments in an area, identify the approaches used to solve a research problem over time and summarize research trends. Digital libraries require semantic search, question-answering as well as automated recommendation and reviewing systems to manage and retrieve answers from scholarly databases. Full document text analysis can help to design semantic search, translation and summarization systems; citation and social network analyses can help digital libraries to visualize scientific trends, bibliometrics and relationships and influences of works and authors. These approaches can be supplemented with the metadata supplied by digital libraries, such as usage data. This workshop will be relevant to scholars in several fields of computer science, information science and computational linguistics; it will also be of importance for all stakeholders in the publication pipeline: implementers, publishers and policymakers -with this workshop we hope to bring a number of these contributors together. Today's publishers continue to seek new ways to be relevant to their consumers, in disseminating the right published works to their audience.</p><p>Formal citation metrics are increasingly a factor in decision-making by universities and funding bodies worldwide, making the need for research in such topics more pressing.</p><p>The BIRNDL event was split into two parts: the regular research paper track and the CL-SciSumm Shared Task system track.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Overview of the papers</head><p>The workshop featured one keynote talk, three paper sessions and one poster and demo interactive session. The BIRNDL organizers have accepted 5 long and 4 short papers for presentation in the research paper track. The CL-SciSumm organizers have accepted 9 system papers in the CL-SciSumm track. All papers in both tracks are included in the proceedings. The following briefly outlines the keynote and three paper sessions. The system papers in the CL-SciSumm track are outline in an overview paper <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Keynote</head><p>Dietmar Wolfram provided the keynote address on "Bibliometrics, Information Retrieval and Natural Language Processing: Natural Synergies to Support Digital Library Research" <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. Until recently, methods developed for IR and bibliometrics that can be mutually beneficial have not been widely explored. This is changing as evidenced by recent themed meetings that have brought together researchers with interests that bridge both areas. Similarly, applications of language-based methods have provided new tools for research in bibliometrics and IR. The presenter discussed examples of the synergies that exist at the intersections of these three areas, not only for IR system design and evaluation, but also to provide insights into the structure of disciplines and their research communities.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Session 1</head><p>In their article "Multiple In-text Reference Phenomenon", Bertin and Atanassova studied the distribution of multiple in-text references (MIR), which are based on sentences with more than one reference <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. A corpus of 80,000 PLOS papers was used for the analysis and references were counted based on the publications' IMRaD structure. The results revealed, for instance, that 41% of sentences with citations contain MIRs, with more than half of them in the introduction. Potential applications of this study comprised works on clustering, co-citation networks and summarization.</p><p>Citations to retracted paper were the focus of the contribution "Post Retraction Citations in Context" by Halevi and Bar-Ilan <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. Citations to retracted articles might put the credibility of scientific work in jeopardy, hence it is a field worth studying. The authors discuss 5 case studies of retracted papers and the BIRNDL 2016 Joint Workshop on Bibliometric-enhanced Information Retrieval and NLP for Digital Libraries negative, positive and neutral citations they received after retraction. The authors expressed their concern about the fact that retracted articles still attract citations, and provide some recommendation for publishers.</p><p>In his paper "Incorporating Satellite Documents into Co-citation Networks for Scientific Paper Searches", Masaki Eto examined the use of enlarged cocitation networks to improve IR search performance for documents from the Open Access Subset of PubMed Central <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref>. Satellite documents to expand the network of linkages beyond direct co-citations were identified based on search terms appearing in documents co-cited with a seed document. Results of the study revealed that the proposed method provided better search performance than a baseline approach that did not incorporate the enlarged network.</p><p>To master the huge amount of scientific literature produced nowadays and make sense of the rich pool of knowledge they provide, Ronzano et al. introduced the Scientific Knowledge Miner project <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>. Based on a previous text mining project, SKM aims at extending the existing Dr. Inventor Scientific Text Mining Framework, and offers services like summarization and citation recommendation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Session 2</head><p>Ha Jin Kim, Juyoung An, Yoo Kyung Jeong and Min Song presented the results of their research on "Exploring the Leading Authors and Journals in Major Topics by Citation Sentences and Topic Modeling" <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>. The authors employed an Author-Journal-Topic (AJT) model to identify leading journals and authors in the area of Oncology along with major topics that are shared among researchers.</p><p>A key finding was that influential authors and journals identified using topic modeling did not necessarily correspond to those identified using citation-based measures. The authors concluded that the AJT model may be used to identify latent meaning in citation sentences.</p><p>Aravind Sesagiri Raamkumar, Schubert Foo, and Natalie Pang tackled a compelling question every scientist wonders while writing: "What papers should I cite from my reading list? User evaluation of a manuscript preparatory assistive task" <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref>. They introduced techniques for shortlisting papers from a personal bibliography and discussed their effectiveness based on user evaluations. A panel of 116 users -balanced between students and staff members -rated the recommendations according to a variety of criteria, such as relevance, usefulness, importance, and certainty. Their positive feedback stresses the usefulness and relevance of this paper recommendation contribution.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Session 3</head><p>Jevin West and Jason Portenoy focusedon a largely ignored facet of scholarly papers -the equations <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref>, in their paper, "Delineating Fields Using Mathematical Jargon". They extracted mathematical symbols from Latex source files in the arXiv repository, performed an analysis of the distribution of these symbols across different fields and calculated the "jargon distance" between fields. The main research goal of their paper was to find ways to utilize equations and formal notation in scholarly recommendation.</p><p>Joseph Mariani, Gil Francopoulo, and Patrick Paroubek discussed "A study of reuse and plagiarism in speech and natural language processing papers" <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref>. They designed an algorithm based on n-gram comparisons to detect (self-)reuse and (self-)plagiarism. It was tested on the NLP4NLP dataset comprising about 65k NLP papers published during the past five decades. Results stress frequent self-plagiarism while uncommon plagiarism in the scientific literature of NLP.</p><p>Philipp Mayr presented a case study "How do practitioners, PhD students and postdocs in the social sciences assess topic-specific recommendations?" where different types of researchers in the social sciences assessed the relevance of search term, author name and journal name recommendations according to their research topics <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref>. His results showed that simple bibliometric-enhanced recommendation services can be useful where they are integrated in an interactive retrieval task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.5">CL-SciSumm Shared Task</head><p>As part of this workshop, our colleagues at the National University of Singapore organized the CL-SciSumm Shared Task 2016 6 -a shared task on scientific paper summarization in the Computational Linguistics domain. This proceedings includes an outline of their Shared Task, as well as detailed system reports from the ten participating systems who completed the Task <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Outlook</head><p>This workshop is the first step to foster a reflection on the interdisciplinarity and the benefits that the disciplines Bibliometrics, IR and NLP can drive from it in a digital libraries context. In the future we plan follow-up workshops at IR, NLP and Digital Libraries venues. Furthermore we are working with the International Journal on Digital Libraries to offer a special issue on topics discussed at BIRNDL, for extended versions of BIRNDL workshop papers, shared task descriptions, as well as a general call for submissions. 7</p></div>
			<note place="foot" n="5"> http://wing.comp.nus.edu.sg/birndl-jcdl2016/ BIRNDL 2016 Joint Workshop on Bibliometric-enhanced Information Retrieval and NLP for Digital Libraries</note>

			<note place="foot" n="6"> http://wing.comp.nus.edu.sg/cl-scisumm2016/ 7 See information at http://wing.comp.nus.edu.sg/birndl-jcdl2016. BIRNDL 2016 Joint Workshop on Bibliometric-enhanced Information Retrieval and NLP for Digital Libraries</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Acknowledgments</head><p>We are indebted to the referees who contributed to the review process: <ref type="figure">Colin</ref>  </p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Cabanac</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Chandrasekaran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Frommholz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Jaidka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Kan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Mayr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Wolfram</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Joint Workshop on Bibliometric-enhanced Information Retrieval and Natural Language Processing for Digital Libraries (BIRNDL 2016). In: JCDL &apos;16: Proceedings of the 16th ACM/IEEE-CS on Joint Conference on Digital Libraries</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="299" to="300" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overview of the CLSciSumm 2016 Shared Task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Jaidka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Chandrasekaran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Rustagi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Kan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the Joint Workshop on Bibliometricenhanced Information Retrieval and Natural Language Processing for Digital Libraries (BIRNDL2016)</title>
		<meeting>of the Joint Workshop on Bibliometricenhanced Information Retrieval and Natural Language essing for Digital Libraries (BIRNDL2016)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Wolfram</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the Joint Workshop on Bibliometric-enhanced Information Retrieval and Natural Language Processing for Digital Libraries (BIRNDL2016)</title>
		<meeting>of the Joint Workshop on Bibliometric-enhanced Information Retrieval and Natural Language essing for Digital Libraries (BIRNDL2016)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6" to="13" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Bibliometrics, Information Retrieval and Natural Language Processing: Natural Synergies to Support Digital Library Research</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multiple In-text Reference Aggregation Phenomenon</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Bertin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Atanassova</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the Joint Workshop on Bibliometric-enhanced Information Retrieval and Natural Language Processing for Digital Libraries (BIRNDL2016)</title>
		<meeting>of the Joint Workshop on Bibliometric-enhanced Information Retrieval and Natural Language essing for Digital Libraries (BIRNDL2016)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="14" to="22" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Post Retraction Citations in Context</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Halevi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bar-Ilan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the Joint Workshop on Bibliometric-enhanced Information Retrieval and Natural Language Processing for Digital Libraries (BIRNDL2016)</title>
		<meeting>of the Joint Workshop on Bibliometric-enhanced Information Retrieval and Natural Language essing for Digital Libraries (BIRNDL2016)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="23" to="29" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Incorporating Satellite Documents into Co-citation Networks for Scientific Paper Searches</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Eto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the Joint Workshop on Bibliometric-enhanced Information Retrieval and Natural Language Processing for Digital Libraries (BIRNDL2016)</title>
		<meeting>of the Joint Workshop on Bibliometric-enhanced Information Retrieval and Natural Language essing for Digital Libraries (BIRNDL2016)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="30" to="35" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Making Sense of Massive Amounts of Scientific Publications: the Scientific Knowledge Miner Project</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Ronzano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Freire</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Saez-Trumper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Saggion</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the Joint Workshop on Bibliometric-enhanced Information Retrieval and Natural Language Processing for Digital Libraries</title>
		<meeting>of the Joint Workshop on Bibliometric-enhanced Information Retrieval and Natural Language essing for Digital Libraries</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="36" to="41" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exploring the leading authors and journals in major topics by citation sentences and topic modeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>An</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Jeong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the Joint Workshop on Bibliometric-enhanced Information Retrieval and Natural Language Processing for Digital Libraries</title>
		<meeting>of the Joint Workshop on Bibliometric-enhanced Information Retrieval and Natural Language essing for Digital Libraries</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="42" to="50" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What papers should I cite from my reading list? User evaluation of a manuscript preparatory assistive task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Raamkumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Foo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Pang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the Joint Workshop on Bibliometric-enhanced Information Retrieval and Natural Language Processing for Digital Libraries</title>
		<meeting>of the Joint Workshop on Bibliometric-enhanced Information Retrieval and Natural Language essing for Digital Libraries</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="51" to="62" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Delineating Fields Using Mathematical Jargon</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>West</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Portenoy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the Joint Workshop on Bibliometric-enhanced Information Retrieval and Natural Language Processing for Digital Libraries (BIRNDL2016)</title>
		<meeting>of the Joint Workshop on Bibliometric-enhanced Information Retrieval and Natural Language essing for Digital Libraries (BIRNDL2016)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="63" to="71" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A study of reuse and plagiarism in speech and natural language processing papers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Mariani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Francopoulo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Paroubek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the Joint Workshop on Bibliometric-enhanced Information Retrieval and Natural Language Processing for Digital Libraries</title>
		<meeting>of the Joint Workshop on Bibliometric-enhanced Information Retrieval and Natural Language essing for Digital Libraries</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="72" to="83" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How do practitioners, PhD students and postdocs in the social sciences assess topic-specific recommendations?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Mayr</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the Joint Workshop on Bibliometric-enhanced Information Retrieval and Natural Language Processing for Digital Libraries</title>
		<meeting>of the Joint Workshop on Bibliometric-enhanced Information Retrieval and Natural Language essing for Digital Libraries</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="84" to="92" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">BIRNDL 2016 Joint Workshop on Bibliometric-enhanced Information Retrieval and NLP for Digital Libraries</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
