<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/atharsefid/Desktop/grobid-0.5.3/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.3" ident="GROBID" when="2020-10-16T20:10+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Chinese-to-Japanese Patent Machine Translation based on Syntactic Pre-ordering for WAT 2015</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katsuhito</forename><surname>Sudoh</surname></persName>
							<email>sudoh.katsuhito@lab.ntt.co.jp</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">NTT Communication Science Laboratories</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masaaki</forename><surname>Nagata</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">NTT Communication Science Laboratories</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Chinese-to-Japanese Patent Machine Translation based on Syntactic Pre-ordering for WAT 2015</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>This paper presents our Chinese-to-Japanese patent machine translation system for WAT 2015 (Group ID: ntt) that uses syntactic pre-ordering over Chinese dependency structures. A head word and its modifier words are reordered by handwritten rules or a learning-to-rank model. Our system outperforms baseline phrase-based machine translations and competes with baseline tree-to-string machine translations.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Patent documents, which well-structured written documents that describe the technical details of inventions, are expected to have almost no semantic ambiguities caused by indirect or rhetorical expressions. Due to this aspect, patent documents are good candidates for literal translation, which most machine translation (MT) approaches aim to do.</p><p>One technical challenge for patent machine translation is the complex syntactic structure of patent documents, which typically have long sentences that complicate MT reordering, especially for the word order in distant languages. Chinese and Japanese have similar word order in noun modifiers but different subject-verb-object order, requiring long distance reordering in translation. In this year's WAT evaluation campaign ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Nakazawa et al., 2015)</ref>, we tackle long distance reordering by syntactic pre-ordering based on Chinese dependency structures ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Sudoh et al., 2014</ref>) in a Chinese-to-Japanese patent translation task.</p><p>Our system basically consists of three components: Chinese syntactic analysis (word segmentation, part-of-speech (POS) tagging, and dependency parsing) adapted to patent documents; dependency-based syntactic pre-ordering with hand-written rules or a learning-to-rank model; and a standard phrase-based statistical MT. This paper describes our system's details and discusses our evaluation results. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> shows a brief workflow of our Chineseto-Japanese MT system. Its basic architecture is standard with syntactic pre-ordering. Input sentences are first applied to word segmentation and POS tagging, parsed into dependency trees, reordered using pre-ordering rules or a pre-ordering model, and finally translated into Japanese by a phrase-based statistical MT.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">System Overview</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Chinese Syntactic Analysis: Word Segmentation, Part-of-Speech Tagging, and Dependency Parsing</head><p>Word segmentation and POS tagging are solved jointly ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Suzuki et al., 2012</ref>) for better Chinese word segmentation based on the POS tag sequences. The dependency parser produces un-typed dependency trees. The Chinese analysis models were trained using in-house Chinese treebanks in the patent domain (about 35,000 sentences) as well as the standard Penn Chinese Treebank dataset <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Sudoh et al., 2014</ref>). The training also utilized unlabeled Chinese patent documents (about 100 G bytes) for semi-supervised training ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Suzuki et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Sudoh et al., 2014</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Syntactic Pre-ordering</head><p>We compared two different syntactic pre-ordering approaches, rule-based and data-driven, in this evaluation campaign.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Rule-based Pre-ordering</head><p>Rule-based pre-ordering is an intuitive approach that generates target language word order based on linguistic knowledge and analysis. For example, in an English-to-Japanese patent MT, a very simple pre-ordering rule called Head Finalization ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Isozaki et al., 2012)</ref> gives very successful results. Our pre-ordering rules are based on Head Final Chinese ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Han et al., 2012</ref>) developed for Chinese HPSG trees. We modified the HPSG-oriented rules for dependency structure, but their basic actions are almost the same. One expected advantage of rule-based pre-ordering is that its stability is independent on bilingual corpora, while modelbased approaches basically depend on bilingual corpora to determine which reordering is the best.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Data-driven Pre-ordering by</head><p>Learning-to-Rank</p><p>Data-driven pre-ordering obtains the most probable reordering of a source language sentence that is monotone with the target language counterpart. It learns rules or models using reordering oracles over word-aligned bilingual corpora. We used a learning-to-rank approach with Ranking SVMs <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Yang et al., 2012)</ref>, which reorders the head word and its modifier words in a dependency tree based on their ranks. The features resemble those by <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Yang et al. (2012)</ref>; we did not use label-related ones because our dependency trees do not have labels. The reordering oracles were determined to maximize Kendall's τ over automatic word alignment in a similar manner to <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Hoshino et al. (2015)</ref>. The only difference is the tree structure; <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Hoshino et al. (2015)</ref> used binary trees and just considered monotone or reverse for two child nodes of each tree node. But we use dependency trees and have to consider all the possible permutation over one head word and one or more modifier words.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Evaluation</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Setup</head><p>We trained a word n-gram language model and two different phrase-based translation models by the above different pre-ordering approaches. We used all of the supplied Chinese-Japanese bilingual training corpora of one million sentence pairs (except for long sentences over 64 words) for the MT models: phrase tables, lexicalized reordering tables, and word 5-gram language models using standard Moses and KenLM training parameters. We applied modified Kneser-Ney phrase table smoothing with an additional phrase scoring option: --KneserNey. The model weights were optimized by standard Minimum Error Rate Training (MERT), but we compared five independent MERT runs and chose the best weights for the development test set. The distortion limits were also chosen from 0, 3, 6, and 9 by comparing the results of the MERT runs. We chose 9 both for the rule-based and data-driven pre-ordering.</p><p>The pre-ordering model for the data-driven method was trained by the word alignment used for the phrase table by a Ranking SVM implementation with Liblinear <ref type="bibr">1</ref> . Its soft margin parameter C was chosen by the ranking accuracy on the development set. <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> shows the official evaluation results by the organizers in Pairwise Cloudsourcing Evaluation scores (Human), RIBES, and BLEU. Our rulebased system showed slightly better performance in RIBES and BLEU than the tree-to-string baseline, but the difference may not be significant. The performances of our systems were lower than the tree-to-string baseline in the Human evaluation. With respect to the difference in the pre-ordering approaches, the rule-based system outperformed the data-driven one.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Official Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Discussion</head><p>One critical concern is the difference between tree-to-string baseline and our pre-ordering systems. Syntactic pre-ordering based on child ranking/classification is a simple approximation of a A comparison between the results by rule-based and data-driven pre-ordering systems suggests our pre-ordering rules work robustly. Even though we expected model-based pre-ordering to capture the complex reordering phenomena in the dependency structure, it gave worse results than the rule-based one. One possible reason is the noisy automatic word alignment in the bilingual corpora; using better word alignment (manual annotation or supervised word alignment) is promising to learn a consistent pre-ordering model ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Hoshino et al., 2015)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4">Issues for Context-aware Machine Translation</head><p>We did not include any context-aware constraints or features in our system, because it translated every sentence independently. We just tried using domain-dependent translation models based on the given category information (chemistry, electricity, mechanical engineering, and physics), but they did not work effectively in our pilot test.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>This paper presented our pre-ordering-based system for Chinese-to-Japanese patent MT for the WAT 2015 evaluation campaign. Our results showed that pre-ordering had similar MT performance to the tree-to-string baseline, but it was slightly worse in the human evaluation. Future</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Brief workflow of our Chinese-toJapanese MT system. Gray resources are in-house ones.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>Table 1 : Official evaluation results in Pair- wise Cloudsourcing Evaluation scores (Human), RIBES, and BLEU. RIBES and BLEU are based on MeCab Japanese word segmentation.</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Scores in 
bold are the best ones. 
System 
Human RIBES BLEU 
Organizer PBMT 
n/a 
0.781 0.382 
Organizer T2S 
20.75 
0.814 0.394 
Ours rule-based 
16.25 
0.822 0.406 
Ours data-driven 
8.00 
0.812 0.399 

standard tree-to-string MT 2 . The tree-to-string MT 
can compare different reordering hypotheses; our 
pre-ordering just chooses one-best pre-ordering. 
</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> http://www.csie.ntu.edu.tw/˜cjlin/libsvmtools/</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> Theoretically this is not true, since phrase-based MT can use phrases that have non-syntactic spans. The effect of these phenomena has not reported yet in the field of pre-ordering; they introduce more ambiguities in phrasal translations, but the ambiguities may work both positively and negatively. The use of non-syntactic spans was proposed as an extention in tree-to-string MT (Zollmann and Venugopal, 2006; Zhang et al., 2011). work will investigate sophisticated pre-ordering methodology such as pre-ordering lattices or forest-based pre-ordering and better word alignment for data-driven pre-ordering.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We thank Dr. Jun Suzuki for his great help on the Chinese dependency parsing. The basis of our preordering rules was developed in cooperation with Dr. Dan Han, whom we thank. Finally, we greatly appreciate the workshop organizers for this valuable evaluation campaign.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Head Finalization Reordering for Chinese-to-Japanese Machine Translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katsuhito</forename><surname>Sudoh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xianchao</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Duh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hajime</forename><surname>Tsukada</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masaaki</forename><surname>Nagata</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Sixth Workshop on Syntax, Semantics and Structure in Statistical Translation</title>
		<meeting>the Sixth Workshop on Syntax, Semantics and Structure in Statistical Translation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="57" to="66" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discriminative Preordering Meets Kendall&apos;s τ Maximization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sho</forename><surname>Hoshino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yusuke</forename><surname>Miyao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katsuhito</forename><surname>Sudoh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katsuhiko</forename><surname>Hayashi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masaaki</forename><surname>Nagata</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Short Papers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="139" to="144" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">HPSG-Based Preprocessing for English-to-Japanese Translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hideki</forename><surname>Isozaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katsuhito</forename><surname>Sudoh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hajime</forename><surname>Tsukada</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Duh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Transactions on Asian Language Information Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">11</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overview of the 2nd Workshop on Asian Translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Toshiaki</forename><surname>Nakazawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hideya</forename><surname>Mino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Isao</forename><surname>Goto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Graham</forename><surname>Neubig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sadao</forename><surname>Kurohashi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eiichiro</forename><surname>Sumita</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2nd Workshop on Asian Translation (WAT2015)</title>
		<meeting>the 2nd Workshop on Asian Translation (WAT2015)<address><addrLine>Kyoto, Japan, October</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katsuhito</forename><surname>Sudoh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jun</forename><surname>Suzuki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yasuhiro</forename><surname>Akiba</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hajime</forename><surname>Tsukada</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masaaki</forename><surname>Nagata</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Korean-to-Japanese Statistical Machine Translation System for Patent Documents</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>English/Chinese</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 20th Annual Meeting of the Association for Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 20th Annual Meeting of the Association for Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="606" to="609" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>in Japanese</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">񮽙</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An Empirical Study of Semi-supervised Structured Conditional Models for Dependency Parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jun</forename><surname>Suzuki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hideki</forename><surname>Isozaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xavier</forename><surname>Carreras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Collins</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2009 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2009 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="551" to="560" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Joint Natural Language Analysis using Augmented Lagrangian</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jun</forename><surname>Suzuki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Duh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masaaki</forename><surname>Nagata</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 18th Annual Meeting of the Association for Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 18th Annual Meeting of the Association for Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1284" to="1287" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>in Japanese; 񮽙 񮽙񮽙񮽙񮽙񮽙񮽙񮽙񮽙</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Ranking-based Approach to Word Reordering for Statistical Machine Translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nan</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mu</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dongdong</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nenghai</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 50th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 50th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Long Papers</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="912" to="920" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Binarized forest to string translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hao</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Licheng</forename><surname>Fang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peng</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaoyun</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="835" to="845" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Syntax augmented machine translation via chart parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andreas</forename><surname>Zollmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ashish</forename><surname>Venugopal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings on the Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation</title>
		<meeting>on the Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="138" to="141" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
