<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/atharsefid/Desktop/grobid-0.5.3/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.3" ident="GROBID" when="2020-09-29T02:30+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Improving Efficiency and Enhancing Concurrency of Untrusted Storage</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Cachin</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">IBM Research</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Zurich Research Laboratory</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>CH-8803</postCode>
									<settlement>Rüschlikon</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Idit</forename><surname>Keidar</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Electrical Engineering, Technion</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>32000</postCode>
									<settlement>Haifa</settlement>
									<country key="IL">Israel</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Shraer</surname></persName>
							<email>shralex@tx.technion.ac.il</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Electrical Engineering, Technion</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>32000</postCode>
									<settlement>Haifa</settlement>
									<country key="IL">Israel</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Improving Efficiency and Enhancing Concurrency of Untrusted Storage</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Many users no longer keep all their data on local storage. Instead, it often resides on remote, online service providers. Examples include network filesystems, online collaboration servers such as Wikis, repositories using versioning tools like SVN, and web-based email providers. Because the data resides in another trust domain, users need methods for protecting the remotely stored data. We are interested in the integrity of stored data and consider an untrusted server providing a storage service to multiple clients that connect to the server using an asyn-chronous network. The clients locally maintain a small amount of trusted memory but do not communicate with each other. In this model, some malicious actions by the server can never be prevented. For example, the server may use an outdated value in the reply to a reader and omit a more recent update. The SUNDR system [2, 4] showed how such attacks can be exposed and made easily detectable. It ensures that whenever the server causes the views of two clients to differ in a single operation, the two clients may never again see each other&apos;s updates after that. Such a divergence can easily be detected through out-of-band communication. SUNDR guarantees that the read and write operations observed by every client are atomic, preserving linearizabil-ity, and, furthermore, that for any operation visible to multiple clients, the sequence of operations occurring before that operation is the same. This notion has been called fork-linearizability. For a system with n clients, the SUNDR protocol incurs a communication overhead proportional to n 2 bits per operation. Recently Cachin et al. [1] presented a more efficient fork-linearizable storage protocol with only O(n) communication overhead per operation and showed that no fork-linearizable storage protocol is wait-free, even in executions where the server is correct. This means that even in the failure-free case, concurrent operations by different clients may slow each other down. Indeed, no existing fork-linearizable storage protocols guarantees progress for correct clients when other clients fail by crashing, even if the server is correct. In ongoing work, we have examined two weaker consistency conditions that have been introduced recently: fork-sequential-consistency [5] and fork-* consistency [3]. Can they guarantee wait-freedom for operations by concurrent clients? We have discovered that neither of them allows linearizability and wait-freedom when the server is correct. Moreover, we show that fork-* consistency allows violations of causality in the sense that a client reads an outdated value from storage, although there was a more recent update that influenced the client. We introduce a new storage access protocol that eliminates all these problems and achieves a notion that we call weak fork-linearizability. In particular, in every execution where the server is correct, the protocol is linearizable and wait-free, i.e., clients never wait for each other, even if some clients crash. If the server is faulty, the protocol still guarantees causality, data integrity, and linearizability for all but the last operation observed by every client. At the cost of exchanging only a small amount of information, clients can detect whether their states are consistent. In case a violation is detected, they can roll back to the latest consistent state. The protocol is efficient, requires only a single round of message exchange between a client and the server for every operation and has a communication overhead of only O(n) bits per request.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient forklinearizable access to untrusted shared memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Cachin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shraer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. 26th ACM Symposium on Principles of Distributed Computing (PODC)</title>
		<meeting>26th ACM Symposium on Principles of Distributed Computing (PODC)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Secure untrusted data repository (SUNDR)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Krohn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mazires</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Shasha</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. 6th Symp. Operating Systems Design and Implementation (OSDI)</title>
		<meeting>6th Symp. Operating Systems Design and Implementation (OSDI)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Beyond one-third faulty replicas in Byzantine fault-tolerant systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mazì Eres</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. 4th Symp. Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI)</title>
		<meeting>4th Symp. Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Building secure file systems out of Byzantine storage</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mazì Eres</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Shasha</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. 21st ACM Symposium on Principles of Distributed Computing (PODC)</title>
		<meeting>21st ACM Symposium on Principles of Distributed Computing (PODC)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On consistency of encrypted files</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Oprea</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Reiter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. 20th International Conference on Distributed Computing (DISC</title>
		<editor>S. Dolev</editor>
		<meeting>20th International Conference on Distributed Computing (DISC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">4167</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
