<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/atharsefid/Desktop/grobid-0.5.3/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.3" ident="GROBID" when="2020-09-29T02:31+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Provenance-based Belief</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adriane</forename><surname>Chapman</surname></persName>
							<email>achapman@mitre.org</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">The MITRE Corporation</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Barbara</forename><surname>Blaustein</surname></persName>
							<email>bblaustein@mitre.org</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">The MITRE Corporation</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Elsaesser</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">The MITRE Corporation</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Provenance-based Belief</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Provenance has been touted as a basis to establish trust in data. Intuitively, belief in a hypothesis should depend on how much one trusts the relevant data. However, current proposals to assess trust based solely on provenance are insufficient for rigourous decision making. We describe a model of provenance and belief that is necessary and sufficient to incorporate &quot;trust in the data&quot; in a way that supports normative inference. The model is based on the observation that provenance can be viewed as a causal structure which can be used to compute belief from assessments of the accuracy of sources and transformations that produced relevant data. In our model, data sources are like sensors with associated conditional probability tables. Provenance identifies dependencies among sensors. Together, this information allows construction of causal networks that can be used to compute the belief in a state of the world based on observation of data. This model formalizes the role of source accuracy, and provides a method for formally assessing belief that uses only information in the provenance store, not the contents of the data.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>The Open Provenance Model (OPM) <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[14]</ref> says, "We assume that provenance of objects (whether digital or not) is represented by an annotated causality graph". While it is possible to argue about whether every provenance graph reflects true causality, this paper focuses on those domains in which reports about the world are collected and fused. In applications such as biosurveillance or global warming, we want to determine how much to believe derived data.</p><p>Many assume that knowing the source of data and how it was manipulated, i.e., its provenance, is sufficient to allow a user of the data to make decisions based on how much they trust the data. Researchers are developing methods to use trust metrics on the assumption that they will exist. For example, Dai, et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref> assume that a measure of trust of a data item's source(s) exist and propose to use it to return the most trustworthy results for a query.</p><p>However, most provenance systems simply record the origin of data and the processes used to transform original data <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">13]</ref>. In these systems, a user reviews the provenance of a data item and arrives at her personal belief in the veracity of data based on subjective assessment of its provenance. In other words, data veracity or trust is based on a "gut feeling" that is derived externally of provenance management systems. Even probabilistic databases <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">11]</ref> merely store the assigned probabilities and manipulate them appropriately during query execution, but do not provide for probability combinations through manipulations other than those described in the relational algebra.</p><p>Previous works in computing trust <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[15]</ref> or data quality based on provenance <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref> require information that might exist in the data but is not in a typical provenance store. For instance, <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[15]</ref> require information such as the "reasonableness of data." Moreover, many data quality metrics are based on content <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>, uncertainty of the data <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>, timeliness as calculated with data expiry age <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref>, or accuracy of the data <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>, all of which are based on information in the data, not the provenance. Our proposed model is based solely upon information that uses and augments a provenance graph. Consider the following example.</p><p>Example: While planning for a trip to Kilimanjaro, you notice a State Department advisory cautioning about a report of an outbreak of Dengue Hemorrhagic Fever (DHF). On the other hand, your favorite adventure hiking blog merely reports stomach flu.</p><p>The provenance for these reports is in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>  overstating the situation? Should you trust the report and alter your travel plans?</p><p>With current models of provenance, our intrepid hiker has two options. The first is to view the provenance of the reports, assign a "gut feeling" about each based on the sources that contributed to the reports, and then fuse these to arrive at a belief in the final report. The second option is to obtain the original reports, assess the accuracy, data quality, timeliness, etc. that went into creating those reports and use those assessments to determine if the reports correctly indicate existence of DHF symptoms. Unfortunately for our hiker, Option 1 incorrectly equates the (fused) accuracy of the report's source(s) with the probability that DHF symptoms are present at Kilimanjaro and, therefore, exhibits the Base Rate Fallacy <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[17]</ref>. Option 2 requires more information than exists in the provenance store. Further, such information may not exist by the time a decision must be made. <ref type="table">(It is  impossible</ref>  The main requirement is that the provenance system be extended to capture accuracy (sensitivity and specificity) of sources. When this is so, the computations needed to support decision making are straightforward and efficiently performed by off-the-shelf Bayesian network algorithms. Our model relies on information in the provenance store about how information is propagated through the graph, and how accurate each source is. This information is used to compute belief in derived data items.</p><p>Section 2 describes the models that underlie our approach. The model developed to compute belief based upon provenance information is presented in Section 3. Section 4 describes our planned future work and conclusions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Provenance Foundations</head><p>We follow the OPM convention and represent artifact and process entities as nodes <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[14]</ref>. In particular we are concerned with artifacts, or data objects, and process nodes that are connected via edges or relationships. A lineage graph, then, is a triple, consisting of a graph identifier G, a set of nodes, N, and a set of edges, E. Provenance information forms a Directed Acyclic Graph (DAG). This paper is not concerned with the implementation of the graphs, which could be relational, RDF, XML, etc.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Belief, Evidence, and Causality</head><p>We are interested in using provenance to support decision making. For instance, should you go to Kilimanjaro, not go, or acquire additional data that might clarify your travel decision? If we are to use provenance to make such decisions in a rigorous manner, we must augment it with probabilities <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[12]</ref>.</p><p>In order to formalize our derivations, we employ propositional semantics. A proposition is a sentence expressing something true or false. Belief in a proposition is one's subjective probability that the proposition is true. Notationally, belief in proposition C that there are symptoms of DHF at Kilimanjaro is written p(C).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">The influence of evidence on belief</head><p>Belief often is not static; rather, it is influenced by evidence. In the example, it stands to reason that one's prior belief in the presence of DHF symptoms at Kilimanjaro, p(C), might increase in light of one or both of the reports. Belief in proposition C in light of proposition E is written p(C|E) and called the conditional probability of C given E. The definition of conditional probability is:</p><p>(1)</p><p>In words, the probability C is true (e.g., DHF symptoms are present at Kilimanjaro) given E (the State Department or blog report) is the proportion of the times one expects C and E to co-occur when E occurs. By division, p(C⋀E) = p(E|C) * p(C). Substituting this identity in (1) yields Bayes' rule:</p><p>Where p(E) = p(E|C) * p(C) + p(E| ¬C) * p(¬C).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Source accuracy and weight of evidence</head><p>Accuracy is the proportion of true results -both positive and negative -in all the results produced by a source. Thus, both components of accuracy, -a source's true positive rate p(E|C) and a source's true negative rate p(¬ E| ¬C) [equal to 1-p(E| ¬C)] are required to calculate belief in proposition C given evidence E. Note that p(C|E) is not equal to the accuracy of the source or the sources true positive rate p(E|C) or p(E).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.">Causal chains</head><p>In this exposition we denote evidence by E and the state of the world by C in part to evoke the idea that evidence (i.e., data) is an effect caused by a state of the world. In our example, E is either the State Department advisory or the blog report, and C is the disease symptom that engendered that report.</p><p>The occurrence of a symptom DHF is likely not the primary concern of our hiker, but rather it is the possibility of the presence of DHF that is the ultimate concern. An advantage of causal models is that they can be extended to represent a chain of causes and effects that allows us to address sequences where the effects represented by data can be traced back to the original source.</p><p>Let us denote the presence of DHF at Kilimanjaro by S. The causal network that captures the knowledge that S may have caused the symptom C that engendered report E is: S  C  E.</p><p>Without going into details, note that Bayes' rule is the normative way to compute p(S|C) and that using a chain of conditional probabilities it is straightforward to compute the belief p(S|E). <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">1</ref> This means that provenance graphs such as depicted in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> can be translated into causal Bayesian networks that support inference about evidence provided by data. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4.">Integrating causal reasoning with provenance</head><p>One issue of significance is that causal networks begin someplace and that someone must provide the a priori probability of each node that has no parent. In our example, there are four such nodes. But notice that these nodes represent data and not what caused the data to be observed (possibly incorrectly). In reality, the state of interest to our hiker is DHF which may have caused the reports at the head of the provenance graph but is not represented in the graph. Without knowing the probability of DHF at Kilimanjaro before any evidence was acquired, it is impossible to compute p(DHF|reports). This illustrates that a provenance graph is not sufficient for inference; an external domain model must augment it.</p><p>From the exposition above, it should be clear that for a single source of a single piece of data (about a single external cause) we require the probability the source will <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">1</ref> In practice these computations are performed using algorithms that implement Bayesian belief networks and are available in a number of off-the-shelf systems. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2</ref> The translation from a provenance graph to a causal Bayesian network is direct since provenance forms a directed acyclic graph.</p><p>report the data when the causing state is true and the probability the source might report the data when the causing state is not true (i.e., the probability the source issues an incorrect report). But our exposition was only about a single source and a single data item. There are only two other cases:  In this case, the conditional probabilities for E must specify the probability of each state of E for every possible combination of states of C1-Cn.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4.1.">Generating conditional probability tables</head><p>There are three possible ways to enumerate such a conditional probability table. The least desirable is to ask an expert on the sources. This can be an onerous task prone to cognitive biases.</p><p>A second way is to use a learning algorithm. For each combination of values of the C nodes, one would initially assign equal probability to each possible value of E. These probabilities would be updated as one obtained verification of the accuracy of the sources, as in <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[16]</ref>. The problem with this approach is that it requires knowledge of results which may be in short supply for rare events (e.g., how many times have you assessed the accuracy of health alerts by the US embassy in Tanzania?).</p><p>A third way to produce such tables, which we are investigating in our research, is to create a set of causal models that utilize the probability of prior sources. For example, if all predecessors of E have a common ancestor in the provenance graph, that means they are not conditionally independent from node E's point of view. In such a case p(E | C1), …, p(E | Cn), and p(E | C1 &amp; … &amp; C2) might be assumed to be approximately the same when C1-Cn are of the same class having members with approximately the same accuracy in repeating what the common source says.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4.2.">Independence and the Single Source Problem</head><p>Utilizing the causal reasoning described above, a large problem in the provenance world is solved automatically: the single source problem. For example, knowing that an assertion that Iraq was developing weapons of mass destruction was based on a single source code-named "Curveball", as opposed to four independent sources, might have influenced belief in the WMD assertion.</p><p>Meanwhile, four independent sources should create a higher belief in the resulting report <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref>. Because provenance is a DAG, this can be accounted for with conditional probabilities. Moreover, partial dependencies in the graph, such as the one that exists in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> (the Villiage clinic report is shared by many), are also automatically comprehended by the use of causal reasoning.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4.3.">Impact of Processes</head><p>Processes have a large impact on the belief of their derived data. Consider in our example, the process "Embassy Forward". Suppose this was done via a disenchanted intern, whose selection of what material to copy and forward was done haphazardly. The final Travel Advisory could look very different from one created by the bright, excited intern who fully read and understood the Tanzanian Ministry of Health's report. Initially, all processes can use a default conditional probability table.</p><p>However, these could be altered if some information is known about a specific process; e.g. the good intern's conditional probability table would be the identity matrix while the bad intern's table would give less credence to the information produced. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 3</ref> contains samples of all three conditional probability tables for the "Embassy Forward" process.  <ref type="table">Tables for Default  processes</ref>, and modifications when better background knowledge exists for the "Embassy Forward" process. E1 is the Tanzanian Report, E2 is the intern output.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Default Good Intern Bad Intern</head><formula xml:id="formula_1">E1\E2 T F E1\E2 T F E1\E2 T F T .9 .1 T 1 0 T .8 .2 F .1 .9 F 0 1 F .4 .6</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Conclusions and Future Work</head><p>In this work, we highlight the need to formally model and compute trust utilizing provenance information. Unlike previous works, we rely purely upon the graphical structure contained in the provenance store to provide a base assessment of the belief in the final resulting data item. If the user has any extra knowledge about the quality of the processes utilized during transformations, this can be incorporated for a better calculation of belief, but is not required for a basic calculation. This approach has two major benefits. First, it decouples the assessment of belief from any information that is not directly stored in the provenance graph. Second, it gracefully accounts for independent, shared source and single-source reports.</p><p>We intend to explore further areas of research. First, we wish to build on this work to refine the model for computing belief based on initial assessments of source quality (separate from the data produced by that source) as well as better automatic computation of process effect on transformed evidence. Second, we will apply these belief models to inform users of the likelihood of different hypothesis. For instance, we could use the belief in the reports, as discussed herein, to propose a hypothesis that better explains the evidence.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Bibliography</head></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Provenance Information for Dengue Hemoragic Fever Symptoms Report</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>to measure the accuracy of a report on predicted corn consumption in 2010 until 2010 is over and the results have been tallied.)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 (</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2(a) depicts single cause C, or multiple independent sources of data. This graph structure means that p(C | E1 &amp; … &amp; En) = p(C|E1) * … * p(C|En). Therefore, to support inference we need only the individual conditional probabilities associated with each source (E nodes).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 2 (</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2(b) shows data derived from multiple sources. In this case, the conditional probabilities for E must specify the probability of each state of E for every possible combination of states of C1-Cn.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 2 : Sample Causal Graphs (a) single cause, (b) multiple sources</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Sample Causal Graphs (a) single cause, (b) multiple sources</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 3 : Conditional Probability</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Conditional Probability Tables for Default processes, and modifications when better background knowledge exists for the "Embassy Forward" process. E1 is the Tanzanian Report, E2 is the intern output.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>. In light of the blog posting, might the State Department be</figDesc><table>Report of 
suspected 
Dengue 
Hemorrhagic 
Fever 

Adventure 
Hiking 
Blog: 
Stomach 
Flu 

Hiker 
eye-witness 
accounts of 
rashes, 
vomiting 

Embassy 
forward 

Local hospital 
reports 
increased 
rates of fever 

Village clinic 
reports of 
stomach flu 

US State Dept. 
Travel Advisory: 
Dengue Hemorrhagic 
Fever 

Prolonged 
high rainfall 

Tanzania 
Ministry of 
Health 
analysis 

Internet 
café 
posting 

</table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scientific Exploration in the Era of Ocean Observatories</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Baptista</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Howe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Freire</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C T</forename><surname>Maier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Silva</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Computing in Science &amp; Engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="53" to="58" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A Flexible and Generic Data Quality Metamodel</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Becker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Mcmullen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Hetherington-Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">ULDBs: Databases with Uncertainty and Lineage</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Benjelloun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Sarma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Halevy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Widom</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">VLDB Seoul</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="953" to="964" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Query Processing Techniques for Compliance with Data Confidence Policies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Dai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Murat</forename><surname>Kantarcioglu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elisa</forename><surname>Bertino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ebru</forename><surname>Celikel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bhavani</forename><surname>Thuraisingham</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">SDM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="49" to="67" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quality Measures in Uncertain Data Management</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Dekeijzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Vankeulen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scalable Uncertainty Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4772</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="104" to="115" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Integrating conflicting data: the role of source dependence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Dong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Berti-Equille</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Srivastava</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">VLDB</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="550" to="561" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Believe It or Not: Adding Belief Annotations to Databases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Gatterbauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Balazinska</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Khoussainova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Suciu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PVLDB</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards content trust of web resources</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Gil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Artz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Web Semant</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="227" to="239" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Trust on the World Wide Web: A Survey</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Golbeck</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Found. Trends Web Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using Web Data Provenance for Quality Assessment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Hartig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">SWPM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Ives</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Karvounarakis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The ORCHESTRA Collaborative Data Sharing System</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Taylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Tannen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Talukdar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Jacob</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Pereira</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">SIGMOD Record</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="26" to="32" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scoring Rules and the Inevitability of Probability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Lindley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Statistical Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="26" />
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Data lineage model for Taverna workflows with lightweight anotation requirements</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Missier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Belhajjame</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Goble</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Berlin / Heidelberg</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Open Provenance Model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Moreau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Freire</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Futrelle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mcgrath</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Myers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Paulson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Southampton</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring Data Believability: A Provenance Approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Prat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Madnick</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 41st Annual Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences</title>
		<meeting>the 41st Annual Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE Computer Society</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluating Provenance-based Trust for ScientificWorkflows</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Rajbhandari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Wootten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Ali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Rana</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Evaluating Provenance-based Trust for ScientificWorkflows</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Judgment under uncertainty: Heuristics and biases</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
