<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/atharsefid/Desktop/grobid-0.5.3/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.3" ident="GROBID" when="2020-09-29T02:33+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A Data-Driven Reflection on 36 Years of Security and Privacy Research</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="1980">1980-2015. 1993-2015. 1997-2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aniqua</forename><surname>Baset</surname></persName>
							<email>aniqua@cs.utah.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computing</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Utah</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tamara</forename><surname>Denning</surname></persName>
							<email>tdenning@cs.utah.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computing</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Utah</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A Data-Driven Reflection on 36 Years of Security and Privacy Research</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">the USENIX Security Symposium (1993-2015), and the Network and Distributed System Security Symposium</title>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="1980">1980-2015. 1993-2015. 1997-2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>We analyze and present data via the perspective of topics trends and authorship. We believe our work serves to contextualize the academic field of computer security and privacy research via one of the first data-driven analyses. An interactive visualization of the topics and corresponding pub-lications is available at https://secprivmeta.net.</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Meta-research-research about research-allows us, as a community, to examine trends in our research and make informed decisions regarding the course of our future research activities. Additionally, overviews of past research are particularly useful for researchers or conferences new to the field. In this work we use topic modeling to identify topics within the field of security and privacy research using the publications of</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>As computing systems are pervading every aspect of our life, from the mundane (e.g., electronic payments) to the futuristic (e.g., IoT, virtual reality), security and privacy concerns surrounding these technologies are growing in number and seriousness. As a result, we are seeing security and privacy turning into an essential component in the design of any computer system or application. With this paradigm shift, the research field of security and privacy is experiencing an upsurge of interest from a broader spectrum of researchers and professionals. However, the lack of a structured, data-driven analysis of the current and past research trends of this field can obstruct the big picture view of the security and privacy landscape for the researchers or professionals outside or new to the field. To that end, in this paper, we present our metaresearch-research about research-and discuss the trends in past 36 years of security and privacy research <ref type="bibr">(from 1980- 2015)</ref>. We base our analysis on the publications from four of the top-tier conferences in the field-the IEEE Symposium on Security &amp; Privacy (S&amp;P), the ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS), the USENIX Security Symposium (USENIX), and the Network and Distributed System Security Symposium (NDSS). We apply the technique of topic modeling to infer and categorize the publications into different security and privacy topics (e.g., browser security, secure computation, anonymity). We analyze trends over time: recently prominent topics (e.g., mobile apps and browser security), diminishing topics, and topics (e.g., access control) that have been steady over time. We next analyze the trends in authorship such as author retention, author accumulation over time, and inter-topic author movement. We also investigate intra-topic entropy to determine which topics have a particularly small (e.g., Java security) or large (e.g., browser security) authorship pool. We also analyze trends in topics with respect to academics versus non-academics authors.</p><p>While some of the results in this paper may be folk knowledge in the community, we pursue a structured method for generating a list of research topics and analyzing those. We believe that this is a first step towards building a richer body of introspective scholarship that will aid in understanding the landscape of security and privacy research for a broader spectrum of audience.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Identifying research topics</head><p>The first and foremost task needed for our analysis is to identify the research topics within the security and privacy field since not all conferences that we study categorize their publications: for example, USENIX does not. Additionally, CCS uses different categorizations than S&amp;P, which uses keywords. Finally, we want to explore categorizations driven directly from the text of the publications. Therefore, to get a datadriven, cohesive categorization across different conference publications, we use generative topic modeling to extract a list of topics from a textual corpus-the full publication contents of S&amp;P, CCS, USENIX, and NDSS. Specifically, we choose to use Latent Dirichlet allocation (LDA) <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[8]</ref>, which is a wellaccepted and widely-used technique in the machine learning community. To provide context for our work, we first provide a brief overview of LDA in Section 2.1. Next, in Section 2.2, we describe our methodologies of all of the steps involved in inferring the security and privacy research topics-from collecting data to getting a refined, labeled list of topics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Background: LDA</head><p>Conceptually, LDA considers documents to be equivalent to bags-of-words. It then assumes that these bags were (hypothetically) generated by one or more topics that exist latent within the corpus. From the input documents (bags) and a topic number, LDA tries to find out the latent distribution of topics over words-and hence, the distribution of a document over topics. As output, LDA produces:</p><p>• a list of word-sets that represent different topics, along with the weight of each word in the set; and</p><p>• topic distribution of each document in the corpus (i.e., a list of all topics with their associated topic portion-e.g., 60% in Topic A, 15% in Topic B, etc.).</p><p>While LDA-and topic modeling in general-is a useful technique to infer topics from documents, it is hard to evaluate whether or not a model is high-quality. There is no clear-cut way to examine whether the generated topics are meaningful and coherent, or to determine whether the assignments of topics to documents are appropriate. To overcome some of these problems, several metrics have been proposed to measure the quality of a topic or an overall model <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[30]</ref>. However, a high-scoring topic is not always a high-quality topic for people <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[10]</ref>. For the latter it is necessary to incorporate human perception in the process of topic modeling <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[9]</ref>. Some recent works on topic modeling have been focused on designing interactive topic modeling that can adapt to human input; however, this line of work is still in progress. In this work, we focus on using regular LDA and add post-processing steps to sanitize the resulting topic model. It should be noted that the manual tweaking of topic models is not uncommon in topic modeling works. For example, Hall et al. used hand-seeded words to improve topic coverage when topics were otherwise missing from the model <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[13]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Our methodologies 2.2.1 Data collection</head><p>We performed our study on publications from S&amp;P , CCS , USENIX , and NDSS <ref type="bibr">(1997)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1998)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1999)</ref><ref type="bibr">(2000)</ref><ref type="bibr">(2001)</ref><ref type="bibr">(2002)</ref><ref type="bibr">(2003)</ref><ref type="bibr">(2004)</ref><ref type="bibr">(2005)</ref><ref type="bibr">(2006)</ref><ref type="bibr">(2007)</ref><ref type="bibr">(2008)</ref><ref type="bibr">(2009)</ref><ref type="bibr">(2010)</ref><ref type="bibr">(2011)</ref><ref type="bibr">(2012)</ref><ref type="bibr">(2013)</ref><ref type="bibr">(2014)</ref><ref type="bibr">(2015)</ref>. The distribution of the publications is presented in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>. For each venue and conference year, we collected: (a) the full content of all publications; (b) all publication titles, authors, and affiliations; and (c) corresponding  <ref type="bibr">1993</ref><ref type="bibr">-1994</ref><ref type="bibr">, 1996</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">-2015</ref><ref type="bibr">1066</ref><ref type="bibr">NDSS 1997</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">-2015</ref><ref type="bibr">456 S&amp;P 1980</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">-2015</ref><ref type="bibr">932 USENIX 1993</ref><ref type="bibr">, 1995</ref><ref type="bibr">-96, 1998</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">-2015</ref> session names for all publications * .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.2">Pre-Processing</head><p>Pre-processing the input documents is a crucial step in the modeling process since the basis of topic modeling is the words within a document and their frequency. We therefore take some time to indicate the pre-processing that we performed on the publications.</p><p>Step 1. Most of the publications were available in PDF format, although a few were only available in PostScript, HTML, or text formats. To get the corresponding text version of the PDF, PostScript, and HTML publications we used the PDFBox <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>, ps2ascii <ref type="bibr">[4]</ref>, and html2text <ref type="bibr">[3]</ref> tools, respectively. From full text of the publications we then extracted the main body of each publication, leaving out the title, author information, acknowledgement, and references.</p><p>Step 2. For some PDF formats, the text conversions are very noisy. We noticed the following problems in the the converted text of some of the PDF formats:</p><p>1. ligatures like "fi", "fl", "ffi", or "ffl" had been converted to '.', '-', or a space; 2. homo-glyphs had been converted to their similar looking counterpart, e.g. "rn" → "m", "cl" → "d" 3. words had been fragmented: e.g., "determination" → "deter mination" 4. words had been coupled together: e.g., "this publication presents" → "thispublicationpresents"</p><p>We tackled these problems as follows. For all nondictionary words, we went through the possible homoglyphs and checked whether replacing a glyph with its counterpart made the word a dictionary word (2). We also ran a spell checker (1, 2, 3, 4). We manually verified any changes before committing them. This is important in cases such as system names, which are sometimes treated as misspelled words by the spell checker. For words that were fragmented (3), we fixed them by looking for sequences of non-dictionary words such that merging them results in a dictionary word.</p><p>Step 3. In order to match different forms of words we converted them to a more standardized form using lemmatization.</p><p>For example, "attacks", "attacked", and "attacking" all correspond to a single form: "attack". Lemmatization is a standard process in linguistics for converting different inflected forms of a word to a single version <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[19]</ref>. We used the Stanford CoreNLP tool for the lemmatization <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>.</p><p>Topic modeling does not take into account multi-word phrases. So, we decided to convert technical phrases (e.g., 'man in the middle') to single hyphenated words (e.g., 'manin-the-middle'). The problem was identifying such phrases. We noticed that most common phrases like this were available at least once in their hyphenated forms in the corpus. Therefore, we examined all hyphenated words for technically meaningful word groups and converted their non-hyphenated versions to a canonical hyphenated form † . We also converted phrases that ended with '-based', '-system', '-related' or '-dependent' to the base phrase ‡ .</p><p>To handle the acronyms, we created a list from the publication corpus by searching for phrases that matched forms similar to <ref type="bibr">'Axxx Bxxx Cxxx (ABC)</ref>'. After manually verifying the acronym-full-form pairs, we converted the acronyms to their full forms and represented them as hyphenated phrases (see above). To handle acronyms with multiple (overloaded) meanings, we only converted an acronym to its full form if the full form appeared in the same publication. For some common acronyms like SSL and HTTP, we did not necessarily expect that people would include the full form somewhere in the publication; so, for common acronyms, we chose to use the short form as default and converted the full forms to acronyms. Interested readers can check the acronym list online at http://secprivmeta.net.</p><p>Finally, we removed all numbers § and symbols from words with the exception of hyphens ('-'), dots ('.'), and slashes ('/'). We also converted all non-acronym text to lower case.</p><p>Step 4. We created a stopword list: the list of words to be ignored during topic modeling. Using a stopword list reduces the chance of getting a "junk" topic. We included words in the list that had low IDF (Inverse Document Frequency) values, the most common English words <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[5]</ref>, and words that appeared in only one document (in order to avoid algorithm/system names appearing as topic words).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.3">Topic Modeling</head><p>We performed LDA topic modeling on the text from a total of 3019 publications. Among the 3062 publications we collected, we discarded 39 of them for pdf-to-text conversion problems and 3 others because their full texts were not available online.</p><p>We used the MALLET tool to perform the topic modeling <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[21]</ref>. MALLET optimizes the LDA hyperparameters over multiple iterations. We generated different models by vary- † For example, "webapplication" and "web application" were both converted to "web-application" ‡ For example, "context-based" would become "context." § One exception is numbers starting with "802."</p><p>ing the number of topics, the number of iterations, and the starting hyperparameter values. To evaluate the quality of the generated models, we used averaged topic Pointwise Mutual Information (PMI). As defined by Newman et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[26]</ref>, PMI of a topic t is as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">PMI(t, w 1..N ) = N−1 ∑ i=1 N ∑ j=i+1 log( D(w i , w j ) D(w i ) + D(w j ) )</formula><p>where w 1..N are the top N words of a topic t, D(w i ) and D(w j ) are the numbers of documents where word w i and w j appeared respectively, and D(w i , w j ) is the number of documents where both words w i and w j appeared ¶ . As described in Section 2.1, there is no commonly accepted way to evaluate a model and topic quality metrics do not always match with human judgment. Therefore, we manually examined the top 5 highest-scoring models according to the average PMI scores. There is no one perfect model: a human might find multiple topics in different high-scoring models to be good, but those topics might not all appear in a single model. We manually selected one of the 5 top-scoring models and performed post-processing in order to refine its quality. The model we finally chose had a total of 118 topics; after post-processing and excluding some method-based topics, we had a total of 95 topics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.4">Post-Processing</head><p>In this section we explain how we refined the topics in our model. There were some "mixed" topics where two completely different concepts mixed together because of some common words they share (which is not uncommon to experience in topic modeling <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[9]</ref>). For example, we had a mixed topic that had both garbled circuit and integrated circuit publications. These two different kinds of publications were (logically) in the same topic because they share words like 'circuit,' 'gate,' and 'bit.' We used the following process to fix such mixed topics:</p><p>1. For each pair of publications in a topic, we found the correlation between the publications by computing the Kullback-Leibler divergence of their topic distributions <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[14]</ref>. 2. We created a graph where vertices represent publications in a topic and edge weight between two vertices is the correlation value between the corresponding publications. 3. We ran a graph modularity algorithm to identify different sub-communities in the graph. 4. We analyzed the publications in different subcommunities to check if they are valid sub-community.</p><p>The intuition behind this process is that if a topic has publications from different domains, the topic distribution of a publication from one domain will be different from the topic distribution of a publication from a different domain, while the distributions of publications from the same domain will be close to each other. Therefore, we would be able to detect different sub-domains via sub-communities in the graph.</p><p>When we found sub-communities in a topic that represented sub-domains, we either created a new topic to move the publications from one sub-domain or moved them to an already existing topic, if appropriate. For example, for the garbled circuit and integrated circuit topic we moved the publications in the integrated circuits publications to an already existing hardware topic.</p><p>We also merged some topics. For example, we had two topics that were related to mobile apps. For our trend analysis and other computations, we consider these two topics as one.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.5">Topic Labeling</head><p>We labelled a topic according to the top words in that topic, the top publications that appear in the topic, their keywords or CCS index (if available), and session name (if available).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.6">Assigning Documents</head><p>As mentioned in Section 2.1, each document has a percentage for every topic in the model. We applied thresholds in order to have "yes/no" assignments of documents to topics for our trend analysis. For each topic, we computed the mean + 2 * standard deviation value of the topic percentage of all documents (for that topic) and used that as the threshold.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Topics in security and privacy research</head><p>We now describe the topics themselves from our refined topic model. All of the topics are listed in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref> .</p><p>In the table, timeline for each topic appears to the right of the topic title which shows the publication count for the topic for each year . All timelines use the same scale and the highest bar corresponds to 20 publications (though Mobile Apps has more than 20 publications in its peak year, we use a general threshold of maximum 20 publications in order to keep the bars of small number of publications legible).</p><p>In the table, the topics are shown grouped by categories. Throughout this paper categories are referenced in small capitals. The categories (and their orderings) are not meant to be definitive; rather, they were formed via researcher inspection and are meant to aid in viewing and discussing the data.</p><p>Several topics do not fit well into the defined categories (e.g., Electronic Voting, E-commerce) and are thus placed in a MISCELLANEOUS category. The topics under METHODS are We encourage readers to check our interactive visualization at http: //secprivmeta.net for better understanding of the topics.</p><p>a slightly different kind of topic: they represent the techniques that were used in publications rather than the research topics or domains of the publications. For example, a publication might belong to User Study topic if it reports on a user study or to Machine Learning if machine learning was used in the course of the study. Four method topics not listed in the table are Probabilistic Methods, Performance Evaluation, Graphs, Hash Trees, Vectors and Matrices, and Logic. We excluded these because they are more general ideas that do not represent the main subject of the publication and because they have remained in publications at a fairly constant rate throughout the conferences' history (in contrast to Machine Learning or User Study, which are topics that show definite changes over time). We included System Calls and String Matching and Regular Expressions because these topics have publications that strongly identify with the topics and the publications do not belong to other topics.</p><p>As topics from similar domains share common words, some publications from one topic might instead be found in a highly related topic. For example, some public-key cryptography publications can be found under the Cryptographic Protocols or Encryption topics instead of the Public-Key Cryptography topic. Topics under FORMALISM category are another such example.</p><p>There are some research themes that did not appear as one single topic in our topic model, despite the fact that researchers might think to create such a topic. Instead, the publications related to those themes ended up in different topics. We posit that this is possibly because the words used in the publications from these domains are not cohesive enough in our corpus to form their own topics. For example, there is no one "Privacy" topic that includes all sorts of privacy publications. However, there is a Data Privacy topic. This is quite an old topic that helped to have enough publications to form a cohesive group of words in the publications to constitute a topic. Newer privacy publications, that are different than data privacy, ended up in different but relevant topics. For example, the publication <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[24]</ref> that describes privacy preserving payment protocol is under the E-commerce topic.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Investigating the inferred topics</head><p>We now delve into analyzing the inferred topics and corresponding publications to uncover trends over time, trends in authorship, trends in topics with respect to academics versus non-academics authors, etc.</p><p>How has the appearance of topics changed over time? Are there some categories that are/were more prominent than others? <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 1</ref> gives an overall idea of trends in different topic categories. We provide the timeline with respect to categories instead of the individual topics in order to see what happened to a group of topics rather than trends in individual ones.   For example, it is more interesting to see what happened to the CRYPTO category as a whole than the different trends in Crypto &amp; Number Theory and Encryption. For each category and year we present the number of publications from that category over the total publication counts for that year. It can be seen from the timeline that FORMALISM topics were the most prominent ones during 1980s (proportionately). Around 1993 their proportion started to decrease, while CRYPTO topics started to become prominent. From the early 2000s the field became more diverse; publications are distributed over a larger number of categories rather than one or two having dominance as in the 1980s and 1990s.</p><p>What are the topics that are strongly emerging or that have experienced a recent surge of publications?</p><p>We next identify the topics in the field that have experienced a recent upsurge in publications. We calculated 2-year period moving averages for each of the topic timelines. We then considered topics with strong upward trends in their moving averages to be prominent. These topics are (in the order of their total publication count in last 3 years): Mobile Apps, Verifiable Computation &amp; ZK Proofs, Machine Learning, Program Exploitations, Side-Channel Attacks, SSL/TLS, Binary Analysis, Control Flow, Memory exploits &amp; defenses, Bitcoin/Crypto-currency, and VMs &amp; virtualization. The JavaScript Security and Browser Security topics did not make into this list. However, if we consider them together, they qualify as prominent. Another interesting topic is Bitcoin/Crypto-Currency which is showing a steep trend in the last two years <ref type="bibr">(2014)</ref><ref type="bibr">(2015)</ref>. It is much newer than the other topics and therefore has fewer publications, so did not make in the list.</p><p>Are there any topics that are dying out, or do all topics continue to have publications?</p><p>While new topics regularly arose-adding to the list of active topics-no topics particularly died out and ceased to appear. Two exceptions to this are Databases and Java Security, which have not appeared in any publication since 2010. However, this does not necessarily mean that databases ceased to be a subject for research. Older publications on this theme appeared in Databases, while newer publications on this theme most likely appear in Data Privacy, in which common themes are re-identification, preserving privacy during database queries, and similar. Some other topics that appeared in only 2 publications since 2010 are Group Communication, Institutional Security, and Software &amp; Trust. Software &amp; Trust is a topic that predominantly appears in the earlier years of the research and is one that primarily seems based on characteristic language usage of the time rather than a strongly cohesive topic theme.</p><p>Are there any topics that have been "slow and steady" over the years, or do all topics experience fluctuation?</p><p>Most of the topics have some inactive years. We present the exceptions, which have continuously appeared each year since their start in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 3</ref>. There are also a handful of steady topics; that is, topics that tended to have 1-2 publications each year (with a maximum of 1-2 year gaps) since the 1980s. These topics are: Access Control, Intrusion/Anomaly Detection, Files and File Systems, Cards and Tokens, Security Policies, Security Labeling, and Covert Channels. Another topic that has kept showing up since the 80s is Network Design; however, the context of the publications of this topic has changed over time. While late 90s publications discussed ATM networks, the recent ones are mostly focused on Software Defined Networks.</p><p>Do authors tend to publish continuously, or do they come and go?  We analyze how the sets of authors change over time. For this, we calculate the Jaccard index of author sets for contiguous periods,</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">J(A 1 , A 2 ) = (|A 1 ∩ A 2 |)/(|A 1 | + |A 2 | − |A 1 ∩ A 2 |);</formula><p>where, A 1 and A 2 are the sets of authors who published in period p 1 and p 2 , respectively. Intuitively, this gives us the proportion of common authors in contiguous periods. We use a two year time period; that is, we calculate the Jaccard index using the set of authors who published during 1980-1981 and the set of authors who published during <ref type="bibr">1982-1983 (next for 1982-1983 and 1984-1985</ref>, and so on). When generating these sets we only considered authors who have published at least 5 publications. We use this same concept-a retention metric via the Jaccard index-to calculate the proportion of similar topics in contiguous periods. Both the author and topic trends are presented in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Fig. 2</ref>, which shows the flux of the authorship and topic pools from year to year.</p><p>From approximately 1984-1991 topics showed an upward trend, indicating an increased overlap of topics in consecutive periods. In contrast, during the same time period there was a steep decline in authorship overlap, suggesting large churn in the authorship pool. This suggests that new authors joined the field while authors in general began publish more on established topics.</p><p>Author retention was the lowest for 1990-1991, which also aligns with the lowest topic overlap. This might be taken to suggest that new authors joined the field and brought in new topics; however, as we note in previous discussion, this was primarily not the case.</p><p>After approximately 1991, both authors and topics show overall upward trends, indicating decreasing flux. It is apparent that in recent years both topics and authors tend to appear more continuously.  We next examine whether new topics are often introduced by new authors or whether authors publishing from existing topics begin the new topics. We find that most of the topics were started by authors from existing topics, except for the topics listed in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 4</ref>, which were introduced by authors who had not previously published in the conferences we studied.</p><p>Which topics have a small core of authors ("tight")? Which have a broad variety of authors ("diverse")?</p><p>We measure the diversity of authorship in a topic using Shannon entropy,</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">E t = − ∑ A i=1 p i * log(p i );</formula><p>where p i is the probability of author i to publish in topic t and A is the total number of authors. Higher entropy indicates more diversity in the authorship pool. The 15 diverse topics (in decreasing entropy order) and the 15 tight topics (in increasing entropy order) are presented in <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 5</ref>. Hardware: Low-Level has the most diverse authorship. We posit that this is because this topic is applied to different domains, thereby diversifying authorship. The next most diverse topic is Security Policies, which has appeared almost every year since the beginning of the corpus; we posit that this has helped the topic to increase its authorship pool. In fact, most of the topics in the diverse end have a large number of publications. Notably, some of the topics with low entropy also have high publication counts: Databases and FORMALISM topics. While Games &amp; Game Theory and Malicious Hardware are close-knit in terms of authorship, these topics have fewer publications than many of the other topics, so it is not surprising that the authorship is not diverse.</p><p>How has industry and government participation in research changed over time?</p><p>We now examine the trends in authorship affiliations. We divide authors' affiliations into 5 categories: Academics, Industry, Government, Non-Profit/Research Institutes, and Independent Researchers. <ref type="figure">Fig. 3</ref> shows the proportion of each category of affiliation in publications for each year. In the figure, 'Academics', 'Industry', 'Academic + Industry', 'Govt', and 'Academics + Govt' represent the publications from the groups as their names suggest. However, these categories in the figure also include all collaborations with Non-Profit/Research Institutes or Independent Researchers. The 'Other' category in the figure contains publications from all other combinations: for example, publications with authors from both Industry and Government. It is evident from the figure that a smaller percentage of publications are being published from just Industry or just Government in recent years. Instead, they are collaborating more with Academics than they did in the 1980s and early 1990s. Around 2001 the Academics-only publications has started to dominate and the proportion has been steadily rising since then.</p><p>Do industry or government entities publish on the same things that academics do or do they focus on different topics? Has this changed over time or held steady?</p><p>We next analyze the similarity between the overall topic distributions versus the topic distributions of Industry (and their collaborations) and Government (and their collaborations) using Jensen-Shannon divergence <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[11]</ref>. We find that Industry publication topics are closely aligned to the overall trend of topic publications than that of Government publications.</p><p>To provide more insight on the different interests expressed by Industry (and their collaborations) and Government (and their collaborations), we contrast their recent top 15 topics with the overall top topics <ref type="bibr">(2010)</ref><ref type="bibr">(2011)</ref><ref type="bibr">(2012)</ref><ref type="bibr">(2013)</ref><ref type="bibr">(2014)</ref><ref type="bibr">(2015)</ref> in <ref type="figure">Fig. 4</ref>.</p><p>Are there any topics for which the non-academics are most interested in than the academics?</p><p>For most of the topics, the number of publications from Industry and Government (including collaborations with Academics) are fewer than the Academics (including their nonIndustry, non-Government collaborations). However, the exceptional topics where Industry and Government publications outnumber the Academics publications are: Formal specification &amp; verification, Network authentication, Formal methods, <ref type="bibr">Software &amp; trust, Formal methods &amp; verification, Databases, Security labeling, and Crypto &amp; number theory.</ref> We find that among these topics Software &amp; Trust, Formal Specification &amp; Verification, Formal Methods, and Databases in fact have more publications from just non-Academics than from Academics or Academic collaborations. All the topics in the list above are some of the oldest topics. Given the dominance of non-Academic publications during the 1980s and 1990s, it is not too surprising to see that these are the topics with a prominence of non-Academics authors.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Related work</head><p>While the security and privacy research field lacks much formalized meta-research, several past invited papers and panel talks presented expert insights.</p><p>On its 20th anniversary, IEEE S&amp;P had a number of panel talks reflecting on the past and considering the future. These panels were on: operating systems <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[12]</ref>, covert channels <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[23]</ref>, formal methods <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[22]</ref>, networking <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[16,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">27]</ref>, evaluation criteria and commercial technology <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[18]</ref>, ubiquitous computing <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[31]</ref>, hardware <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[25]</ref>, software technology <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[28]</ref>, and assurance <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[29]</ref>. IEEE S&amp;P also had three invited meta-papers on its 30th anniversary. Bishop et al. discussed 30 years of IEEE S&amp;P by, for example, mentioning particularly prominent papers from a given year <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[7]</ref>. Landwehr presented the history of government funding in security research <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[17]</ref>. Last, Maughan et al. discussed the transitioning of security research to practice <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[20]</ref>.</p><p>NDSS at its 20th anniversary in 2013 had a keynote talk on 20 years of security research in network and distributed systems <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[15]</ref>. The content of the talk was both expert insight and some analysis of the prevalence of certain words (e.g., 'PGP') in the NDSS paper abstracts.</p><p>These papers, talks, and panels were very informative and incorporated expert knowledge. However, they were not formalized studies of the corpus of published papers, and were largely restricted to S&amp;P and NDSS topics. In contrast, we seek to perform a data-driven study of publications from S&amp;P, CCS, USENIX, and NDSS.</p><p>Balzarotti has a data-driven analysis of publications and authorship on his website <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[6]</ref> . He supplies data such as average author count, acceptance rates, submitted papers, author nationalities, top authors, and collaboration networks. These results deal with paper metadata and do not include analysis on paper text or paper topic like ours.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>Security and privacy meta-research is an under-explored area of research. We have taken the first step towards a formalized, introspective study of the field of security and privacy research. We believe our work will provide a comprehensive view of the overall security and privacy field to new security researchers as well as researchers from different fields.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: The prevalence of publications in a given category over time.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Flux in the appearance of particular authors and topics over time, as given by the Jaccard index. A higher value means more overlap between consecutive time periods.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :Figure 4 :</head><label>34</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Author affiliations over the years, given as the proportion of that affiliation type for the given year.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Publication distribution at different venues 
Venue 
Years 
# of papers 

CCS 
</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 2 : 95 topics from the topic model, grouped into related categories. Categories are approximately ordered by age. Timelines for each topic show the paper count for each year (1980--2015). All timelines use the same scale. The highest bar correspond to 20 papers. (Mobile Apps actually peaked at 28 papers.)</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="true"><head>TABLE 2 : 95 topics from the topic model, grouped into related categories. Categories are approximately ordered by age. Timelines for each topic show the paper count for each year (1980-2015). All timelines use the same scale. The highest bar correspond to 20 papers. (Mobile Apps actually peaked at 28 papers.)</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Crypto 

Cryptographic protocols 

Key 
distribution/management 

Group communication 

Public-key cryptography 

Digital signature 

Network authentication 

Encryption 

Crypto &amp; number theory 

Random numbers 
Trust 

Trusted 
computing/system 

Trust management 

Software &amp; trust 
Formalism 

Formal methods 

Formal methods &amp; 
verification 

Formal specification &amp; 
verification 

Security labeling 

Security policies 
System 

File &amp; file system 
security 

Kernels 

Compartmentalization 

Storage security 
Hardware 

RFIDs &amp; ICs 

Low level 

Physical properties 

Malicious hardware 

Embedded &amp; hardware 
security 
Networks 

Attacks, defenses &amp; 
detections 

Network design 

Perimeter controls 

Traffic analysis: attacks 
&amp; defences 

Routing 

Web 

JavaScript security 

Browser security 

Web application vulnerabilities 

DOM &amp; documents 

Online services 
Auth 

Access control 

Passwords 

CAPTCHA 
Computation 
Secure (multiparty) 
computation 
Verifiable computation &amp; zero 
knowledge proofs 
Data 

Data privacy 

Databases 

Genomic privacy 
Malware 

Malware 
Viruses &amp; worms: propogation 
&amp; scanning 

Bots &amp; Botnet 

Intrusion/anomaly detection 
Programs 

Static &amp; dynamic analysis 

Binary code analysis 
Program exploitations: attacks 
&amp; defenses 
Vulnerabilities: exploits, 
disclosure &amp; patches 
(De)obfuscation &amp; 
decompilation 

Memory exploits &amp; defenses 

Control flow 

Information flow 

Java security 
Information leakage 

Covert channel 

Side-channel attack 
Memory disclosure attacks &amp; 
defenses 
Internet 

Domain Name System (DNS) 

SSL/TLS 

TCP/IP 
zgdfg 
zgdfg 

Mobile 

Mobile app 

Mobile devices 

Mobile network 

Location privacy/tracking 
Crime &amp; fraud 

Online crime 

Dark web 

Spam, scam &amp; fraud 

Online advertising 
Anonimity &amp; Censorship 

Censorship 

Tor 

Anonymity 

Peer-to-peer 
communications 

Social network &amp; 
(de)anonymization 
Virtual 

Virtual machines &amp; 
virtualization 

Cloud 

Client-server 
accountability 
Miscellaneous 

Fingerprints &amp; 
fingerprinting 

Real-world sensing 

Electronic voting 

Cards &amp; tokens 

(User) interfaces 

Encoding/decoding 

Automated analysis: 
protocols &amp; files 

Game &amp; game theory 

Wireless security 

Institutional security 

E-commerce 

Bitcoin &amp; 
crypto-currency 
Methods 

Machine learning 

User study 

String matching &amp; 
regular expressions 

System calls </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Steady topics since start 
Topic 
Start 
Network attacks, defenses, &amp; detection 1997 
(De)obfuscation &amp; decompilation 
2003 
Social networks &amp; (de)anonymization 2005 
Web application vulnerabilities 
2005 
Bots and Botnets 
2006 
Mobile apps 
2009 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Topics introduced by new authors 
Topic 
Start Topic 
Start 
Real-world sensing 
1985 Java security 
1996 
Viruses &amp; worms 
1988 Vulnerabilities 
1998 
Machine learning 
1992 JavaScript security 
1998 
Verifiable comp. &amp; ZK proofs 1993 Electronic voting 
1999 
Random numbers 
1995 P2P comm. 
2002 
Passwords 
1995 Memory disclosure 
2003 
Anonymity 
1996 Games &amp; game theory 2003 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Diverse and tight topics in terms of authorship 
Diverse 
Tight 
HW: low level 
Institutional security 
Security policies 
Malicious HWs 
Browser 
Game &amp; game theory 
Verifiable comp. &amp; ZK proofs Java 
Machine learning 
Genomics 
TCP/IP 
CAPTCHA 
Static &amp; dynamic analysis 
Online crime 
Data privacy 
Cloud 
Crypto protocols 
Memory disclosure 
Mobile app 
Databases 
Mobile devices 
Tor 
File &amp; file systems 
P2P communication 
Side-channels 
Bitcoin/crypto-currency 
(User) interfaces 
Automated analysis 
Client-server accountability HW: RFIDs &amp; ICs 

Do new authors introduce new topics to the conferences 
or are new topics begun by existing authors? 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot">¶ The proponents of PMI used external datasets to compute cooccurrences whreas we chose to use our publication corpus.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We would like to thank Dr. Vivek Srikumar for his guidance on topic modeling and Sahar Mehrpour for her help in the visualizations presented at https://secprivmeta.net.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Apache</forename><surname>Pdfbox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://pdfbox.apache.org" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Corenlp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://stanfordnlp.github.io/CoreNLP" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Stopwords</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.ranks.nl/stopwords" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
				<ptr target="http://s3.eurecom.fr/~balzarot/notes/top4_2018/" />
		<title level="m">System security circus</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Bishop</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Reflections on the 30th Anniversary of the IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Invited paper</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>David M Blei</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Latent Dirichlet Allocation. Journal of machine Learning research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="993" to="1022" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Care and feeding of topic models: Problems, diagnostics, and improvements. Handbook of mixed membership models and their applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jordan</forename><surname>Boyd-Graber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reading tea leaves: How humans interpret topic models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NIPS</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Jensen-shannon divergence and hilbert space embedding</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Bent Fuglede</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ISIT</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">20 Years of Operating Systems Security (Panel talk)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Virgil</forename><surname>Gligor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE S&amp;P</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Studying the history of ideas using topic models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Hall</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Kullback-leibler divergence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joyce</forename><surname>James</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Encyclopedia of Statistical Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">20 Years of Network and Distributed Systems Security: The Good, the Bad, and the Ugly (Keynote talk)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Kemmerer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<publisher>NDSS</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Network Security: Then and Now, or, 20 Years in 10 Minutes (Panel talk)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Kent</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE S&amp;P</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">History of US Government Investments in Cybersecurity Research: A Personal Perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Carl E Landwehr</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE S&amp;P</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Invited paper</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Twenty Years of Evaluation Criteria and Commercial Technology (Panel talk)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lipner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE S&amp;P</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Introduction to information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Natural Language Engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Crossing the&quot; Valley of Death&quot;: Transitioning Cybersecurity Research into Practice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Douglas</forename><surname>Maughan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>vited paper</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Mallet: A machine learning for language toolkit</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew Kachites</forename><surname>Mccallum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Twenty Years of Formal Methods (Panel talk)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Mclean</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE S&amp;P</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">20 Years of Covert Channel Modeling and Analysis (Panel talk)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Millen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE S&amp;P</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Privacy preserving payments in credit networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pedro</forename><surname>Moreno-Sanchez</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NDSS</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Hardware Environment (Panel talk)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Needham</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE S&amp;P</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic evaluation of topic coherence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Newman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL HLT</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Twenty Year Time Capsule Panel: The Future of Networking (Panel talk)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Orman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE S&amp;P</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Software Technology of the Future (Panel talk)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Shrobe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE S&amp;P</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">But It Should Be (Panel talk)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Snow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE S&amp;P</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>The Future Is Not Assured</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluation methods for topic models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Hanna M Wallach</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICML</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How Computers Will Be Used Differently in the Next Twenty Years (Panel talk)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Weiser</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE S&amp;P</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
