<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/atharsefid/Desktop/grobid-0.5.3/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.3" ident="GROBID" when="2020-09-29T02:40+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">This paper is included in the Proceedings of the 16th USENIX Conference on File and Storage Technologies. Open access to the Proceedings of the 16th USENIX Conference on File and Storage Technologies is sponsored by USENIX. FStream: Managing Flash Streams in the File System FStream: Managing Flash Streams in the File System</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eunhee</forename><surname>Rho</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Samsung Electronics. Co., Ltd</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Samsung Electronics Co</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>February 12-15</addrLine>
									<postCode>2018 •</postCode>
									<settlement>Oakland, Ltd</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kanchan</forename><surname>Joshi</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Samsung Electronics. Co., Ltd</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Samsung Electronics Co</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>February 12-15</addrLine>
									<postCode>2018 •</postCode>
									<settlement>Oakland, Ltd</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>Nitesh</roleName><forename type="first">Seung-Uk</forename><surname>Shin</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Samsung Electronics. Co., Ltd</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Samsung Electronics Co</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>February 12-15</addrLine>
									<postCode>2018 •</postCode>
									<settlement>Oakland, Ltd</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jagadeesh</forename><surname>Shetty</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Samsung Electronics. Co., Ltd</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Samsung Electronics Co</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>February 12-15</addrLine>
									<postCode>2018 •</postCode>
									<settlement>Oakland, Ltd</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joo-Young</forename><surname>Hwang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Samsung Electronics. Co., Ltd</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Samsung Electronics Co</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>February 12-15</addrLine>
									<postCode>2018 •</postCode>
									<settlement>Oakland, Ltd</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sangyeun</forename><surname>Cho</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Samsung Electronics. Co., Ltd</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Samsung Electronics Co</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>February 12-15</addrLine>
									<postCode>2018 •</postCode>
									<settlement>Oakland, Ltd</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><forename type="middle">Dg</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Samsung Electronics. Co., Ltd</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Samsung Electronics Co</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>February 12-15</addrLine>
									<postCode>2018 •</postCode>
									<settlement>Oakland, Ltd</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jaeheon</forename><surname>Jeong</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Samsung Electronics. Co., Ltd</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Samsung Electronics Co</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>February 12-15</addrLine>
									<postCode>2018 •</postCode>
									<settlement>Oakland, Ltd</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eunhee</forename><surname>Rho</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Samsung Electronics. Co., Ltd</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Samsung Electronics Co</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>February 12-15</addrLine>
									<postCode>2018 •</postCode>
									<settlement>Oakland, Ltd</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kanchan</forename><surname>Joshi</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Samsung Electronics. Co., Ltd</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Samsung Electronics Co</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>February 12-15</addrLine>
									<postCode>2018 •</postCode>
									<settlement>Oakland, Ltd</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>Nitesh</roleName><forename type="first">Seung-Uk</forename><surname>Shin</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Samsung Electronics. Co., Ltd</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Samsung Electronics Co</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>February 12-15</addrLine>
									<postCode>2018 •</postCode>
									<settlement>Oakland, Ltd</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jagadeesh</forename><surname>Shetty</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Samsung Electronics. Co., Ltd</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Samsung Electronics Co</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>February 12-15</addrLine>
									<postCode>2018 •</postCode>
									<settlement>Oakland, Ltd</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joo-Young</forename><surname>Hwang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Samsung Electronics. Co., Ltd</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Samsung Electronics Co</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>February 12-15</addrLine>
									<postCode>2018 •</postCode>
									<settlement>Oakland, Ltd</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sangyeun</forename><surname>Cho</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Samsung Electronics. Co., Ltd</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Samsung Electronics Co</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>February 12-15</addrLine>
									<postCode>2018 •</postCode>
									<settlement>Oakland, Ltd</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><forename type="middle">Dg</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Samsung Electronics. Co., Ltd</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Samsung Electronics Co</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>February 12-15</addrLine>
									<postCode>2018 •</postCode>
									<settlement>Oakland, Ltd</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jaeheon</forename><surname>Jeong</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Samsung Electronics. Co., Ltd</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Samsung Electronics Co</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>February 12-15</addrLine>
									<postCode>2018 •</postCode>
									<settlement>Oakland, Ltd</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">This paper is included in the Proceedings of the 16th USENIX Conference on File and Storage Technologies. Open access to the Proceedings of the 16th USENIX Conference on File and Storage Technologies is sponsored by USENIX. FStream: Managing Flash Streams in the File System FStream: Managing Flash Streams in the File System</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The performance and lifespan of a solid-state drive (SSD) depend not only on the current input workload but also on its internal media fragmentation formed over time, as stale data are spread over a wide range of physical space in an SSD. The recently proposed streams gives a means for the host system to control how data are placed on the physical media (abstracted by a stream) and effectively reduce the media fragmentation. This work proposes FStream, a file system approach to taking advantage of this facility. FStream extracts streams at the file system level and avoids complex application level data mapping to streams. Experimental results show that FStream enhances the filebench performance by 5%∼35% and reduces WAF (Write Amplification Factor) by 7%∼46%. For a NoSQL database benchmark, performance is improved by up to 38% and WAF is reduced by up to 81%.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Solid-state drives (SSDs) are rapidly replacing hard disk drives (HDDs) in enterprise data centers. SSDs maintain the traditional logical block device abstraction with the help from internal software, commonly known as flash translation layer (FTL). The FTL allows SSDs to substitute HDDs without complex modification in the block device interface of an OS.</p><p>Prior work has revealed, however, that this compatibility comes at a cost; when the underlying media is fragmented as a device is aged, the operational efficiency of the SSD deteriorates dramatically due to garbage collection overheads <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">13]</ref>. More specifically, a user write I/O translates into an amplified amount of actual media writes <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref>, which shortens device lifetime and hampers performance. The ratio of the actual media writes to the user I/O is called write amplification factor (WAF).</p><p>A large body of prior work has been undertaken to address the write amplification problem and the SSD wearout issue <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">7]</ref>. To the same end, we focus on how to take advantage of the multi-streamed SSD mechanism <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>. This mechanism opens up a way to dictate data placement on an SSD's underlying physical media, abstracted by streams. In principle, if the host system perfectly maps data having the same lifetime to the same streams, an SSD's write amplification becomes one, completely eliminating the media fragmentation problem.</p><p>Prior works have revealed two strategies to leverage streams. The first strategy would map application data to disparate streams based on an understanding of the expected lifetime of those data. For example, files in different levels of a log-structured merge tree could be assigned to a separate stream. Case studies show that this strategy works well for NoSQL databases like Cassandra and RocksDB <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">14]</ref>. Unfortunately, this applicationlevel customization strategy requires that a system designer understand her target application's internal working fairly well, remaining a challenge to the designer. The other strategy aimed to "automate" the process of mapping write I/O operations to an SSD stream with no application changes. For example, the recently proposed AutoStream scheme assigns a stream to each write request based on estimated lifetime from past LBA access patterns <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref>. However, this scheme has not been proven to work well under complex workload scenarios, particularly when the workload changes dynamically. Moreover, LBA based pattern detection is not practical when file data are updated in an out-of-place manner, as in copy-on-write and log-structured file systems. The above sketched strategies capture the two extremes in the design space-application level customization vs. block level full automation.</p><p>In this work, we take another strategy, where we separate streams at the file system layer. Our approach is motivated by the observation that file system metadata and journal data are short-lived and are good targets for separation from user data. Naturally, the primary component of our scheme, when applied to a journaling file sys-tem like ext4 and xfs, is to allocate a separate stream for metadata and journal data, respectively. As a corollary component of our scheme, we also propose to separate databases redo/undo log file as a distinct stream at the file system layer. We implement our scheme, FStream, in Linux ext4 and xfs file systems and perform experiments using a variety of workloads and a stream-capable NVMe (NVM Express) SSD. Our experiments show that FStream robustly achieves a near-optimal WAF (close to 1) across the workloads we examined. We make the following contributions in this work.</p><p>• We provide an automated multi-streaming of different types of file system generated data with respect to their lifetime; • We enhance the existing journaling file systems, ext4 and xfs, to use the multi-streamed SSDs with minimally invasive changes; and • We achieve stream classification for application data using file system layer information.</p><p>The remainder of this paper is organized as follows. First, we describe the background of our study in Section 2, with respect to the problems of previous multistream schemes. Section 3 describes FStream and its implementation details. We show experimental results in Section 4 and conclude in Section 5.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Background</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Write-amplification in SSDs</head><p>Flash memory has an inherent characteristic of erasebefore-program. Write, also called "program" operation, happens at the granularity of a NAND page. A page cannot be rewritten unless it is "erased" first. In-place update is not possible due to this erase-before-write characteristic. Hence, overwrite is handled by placing the data in a new page, and invalidating the previous one. Erase operation is done in the unit of a NAND block, which is a collection of multiple NAND pages. Before erasing a NAND block, all its valid pages need to be copied out elsewhere; this is done in a process called garbagecollection (GC). These valid page movements cause additional writes that consume bandwidth, thereby leading to performance degradation and fluctuation. These additional writes also reduce endurance as program-erase cycles are limited for NAND blocks. One way to measure GC overheads is write amplification factor (WAF), which is described as the ratio of writes performed on flash memory to writes requested from the host system.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>WAF =</head><p>Amount of writes committed to flash Amount of writes that arrived from the host WAF may soar more often than not as an SSD experiences aging <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Multi-streamed SSD</head><p>The multi-streamed SSD <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref> endeavors to keep WAF in check by focusing on the placement of data. It allows the host to pass a hint (stream ID) along with write requests. The stream ID provides a means to convey hints on lifetime of data that are getting written <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. The multistreamed SSD groups data having the same stream ID to be stored to the same NAND block. By avoiding mixing data of different lifetime, fragmentation is reduced inside NAND blocks. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> shows an example of how the data placement using multi-stream could reduce media fragmentation. Multi-stream is now a part of T10 (SCSI) standard, and under discussion in NVMe (NVM Express) working group. NVMe 1.3 specification introduces support for multi-stream in the form of "directives" <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. An NVMe write command has the provision to carry a stream ID.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Leveraging Streams</head><p>While the multi-streamed SSD provides the facility of segregating data into streams, its benefit largely depends upon how well the streams are leveraged by the host. Identifying what should and should not go into the same stream is of cardinal importance for maximum benefit. Previous work <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">14]</ref> shows benefits of applicationassigned streams. This approach has the benefit of determining data lifetime accurately, but it involves modifying the source code of the target application, leading to increased deployment effort. Also when multiple applications try to assign streams, a centralized stream assignment is required to avoid conflicts. Instead of direct assignment of stream IDs, recently Linux (from 4.13 kernel) supports fcntl() interface to send data lifetime hints to file systems to exploit the multi-streamed SSDs <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">6]</ref>. AutoStream <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref> takes stream management to the NVMe device driver layer. It monitors requests from file systems and estimates data lifetime. However, only limited information (e.g., request size, block addresses) is available in the driver layer, and even worse, the address-based algorithm may be ineffective under a copy-on-write file system.</p><p>Our approach, FStream, implements stream management intelligence at the file system layer. File systems have readily the information about file system generated data such as metadata and journal. To detect lifetime of user data, we take a simple yet efficient method which uses file's name or extension. For the sake of brevity, we do not cover the estimation of user data lifetime in detail at the file system layer.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">FStream</head><p>We start by highlighting the motivation behind employing multi-stream in file systems. This is followed by overview of ext4 and xfs on-disk layout and journaling methods. Then we delve into the details of Ext4Stream and XFStream, which are stream-aware variants of ext4 and xfs, respectively.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Motivation</head><p>Applications can have better knowledge about the lifetime and update frequency of data that they write than file systems do. However, applications do not know about the lifetime and update frequency of file system metadata. The file system metadata usually have different update frequencies than applications' data, and are often influenced by on-disk layout and write policy of a particular file system. Typically file systems keep data and metadata logically separated, but they may not remain "physically" separated on SSDs. While carrying out file operations, metadata writes may get mixed with data writes in the same NAND block or one type of metadata may get mixed with another type of metadata. File systems equipped with stream separation capability may reduce the mixing of applications' data and file system metadata, and improve WAF and performance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Ext4 metadata and journaling</head><p>The ext4 file system divides the disk-region in multiple equal-size regions called "block groups," as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>. Each block group contains data and their related metadata together which helps in reducing seeks for HDDs. Ext4 introduces flex-bg feature, which "clubs" a series of block groups whose metadata are consolidated in the first block group. Each file/directory requires an inode, which is of size 256 bytes by default. These inodes are stored in the inode table. inode bitmap and block bitmap are used for allocation of inodes and data blocks, respectively. Group descriptor contains the location of other metadata regions (inode table, block bitmap, inode bitmap) within the block group. Another type of metadata is a directory block. File-system consistency is achieved through writeahead logging in journal. Journal is a special file whose blocks reside in user data area, pre-allocated at the time of file system format. Ext4 has three journaling modes; data-writeback (metadata journaling), dataordered (metadata journaling + write data before metadata), and data-journal (data journaling). The default mode is data-ordered. Ext4 journals at a block granularity, i.e., even if few bytes of an inode are changed, the entire block (typically 4KiB) containing many inodes is journaled. For journaling it takes assistance from another component called journaling block device (JBD), which has its own kernel thread called jbd2. The journal area is written in a circular fashion. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref> shows journaling operation in the ordered mode. During a transaction, ext4 updates metadata in in-memory buffers, and informs the jbd2 thread to commit a transaction. jbd2 maintains a timer (default 5 seconds), on expiry of which it writes modified metadata into the journal area, apart from transaction related bookkeeping data. Once changes have been made durable,the transaction is considered committed. Then, the metadata changes in memory are flushed to their original locations by write-back threads, which is called checkpointing.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Xfs metadata and journaling</head><p>Similar to ext4, xfs also divides the disk region into multiple equal-size regions called allocation groups, as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4</ref>. The primary objective of allocation groups is to increase parallelism rather than disk locality, unlike EXT4 block groups. Each allocation group maintains its own superblock and other structures for free space management and inode allocation, thereby allowing parallel metadata operations. Free space management within an allocation group is done by using B+ trees. Inodes are allocated in chunks of 64. These chunks are managed in another B+ tree meant exclusively for inode allocation. For transaction safety, xfs implements metadata journaling. A separate region called "log" is created during file system creation (mkfs.xfs). Log is written in a circular fashion as transactions are performed. Xfs maintains many log buffers (default 8) in memory, which can record the changes for multiple transactions. Default commit interval is 30 seconds. During commit, modified log buffers are written to on-disk log area. Post commit, modified metadata buffers are scheduled for flushing to their actual disk locations. The journal stream mount option is to separate journal writes. We added a j streamid field in the journal s structure. When ext4 is mounted with the journal stream option, a stream ID is allocated and stored in the j streamid field. jbd2 passes this stream ID when it writes dirty buffers and descriptor blocks in a journal area using submit bh and related functions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Ext4Stream: Multi-stream in ext4</head><p>Ext4 makes use of buffer-head (bh) structures for various metadata buffers including inode, bitmaps, group descriptors and directory data blocks. We added a new field streamid in buffer-head to store a stream ID, and modified submit bh. While forming an I/O from bufferhead, this field is also set in bio, taking stream ID information to a lower layer. Ext4Stream maintains stream IDs for different metadata regions in its superblock, and, depending on the type of metadata buffer-head, it sets bh-&gt;streamid accordingly.</p><p>The inode stream mount option is to separate inode writes. Default inode size is 256 bytes, so single 4KiB FS block can store 16 inodes. Modification in one inode leads to writing of an entire 4KiB block. When Ext4Stream modifies inode buffer, it also sets bh-&gt;streamid with the stream ID meant for the inode stream.</p><p>The dir stream mount option is to keep directory blocks into its own stream. When a new file or subdirectory is created inside a directory, a new directory entry needs to be added. This triggers either update of an existing data block belonging to the directory or addition of a new data block. Directory blocks are organized in a htree; leaf nodes contain directory entries and non-leaf nodes contain indexing information. We assign a same stream ID for both types of directory blocks.</p><p>The misc stream is to keep inode/block bitmap blocks and group descriptor blocks into a stream. These regions receive updates during the creation/deletion of file/directory and when data blocks are allocated to file/directory. We group these regions into a single stream because they are of small size.</p><p>The fname stream helps to put data of certain special files into distinct stream. Motivation is to use this for separating undo/redo log for SQL and NoSQL databases.</p><p>The extn stream is to enable file extension based stream recognition. Data blocks of certain files, such as multimedia files, can be considered cold. Ext4Stream can parse extension of files during file creation. If it matches with some well-known extensions, file is assigned a different stream ID. This helps prevent hot or cold data blocks getting mixed with other types of data/metadata blocks. <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref> lists the streams we introduced to xfs. These streams can be enabled with the corresponding mount options listed in the table.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.5">XFStream: Multi-stream in xfs</head><p>Xfs implements its own metadata buffering rather than using page cache. The xfs buf t structure is used to represent a buffer. Apart from metadata, in-memory buffers of log are implemented via xfs buf t. When the buffer is flushed, a bio is prepared out of xfs buf t. We Mount-option Stream log stream</p><p>Separate writes occurring in log inode stream</p><p>Separate inode writes fname stream</p><p>Assign distinct stream to file(s) with specific name added a new field called streamid in xfs buf t, and used that to set the stream information in bio.</p><p>The log stream enables XFStream to perform writes in the log area with its own stream ID. Each mounted xfs volume is represented by a xfs mount t structure. We added the field log streamid in it, which is set when xfs is mounted with log stream. This field is used to convey stream information in xfs buf t representing the log buffer.</p><p>The inode stream mount option enables XFStream to separate inode writes into a stream. A new field ino streamid kept in xfs mount t is set to stream ID meant for inodes. This field is used to convey stream information in xfs buf t representing the inode buffer.</p><p>Finally, the fname stream enables XFStream to assign a distinct stream to file(s) with specific name(s).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Evaluation</head><p>Our experimental system configurations are as follows.</p><p>• System: Dell Poweredge R720 server with 32 cores and 32GB memory,</p><p>• OS: Linux kernel 4.5 with io-streamid support,</p><p>• SSD: Samsung PM963 480GB, with the allocation granularity 1 of 1.1GB, The SSD we used supports up to 9 streams; eight NVMe standard compliant streams and one default stream. If a write command does not specify its stream ID, it is written to the default stream.</p><p>We conduct experiments in two parts; the first part is to measure the benefit of separating file system metadata and journal. Each test starts with a fresh state involving device format and file system format. To reduce variance between the runs, we disable lazy journal and inode table initialization at the time of ext4 format. As a warming workload for filebench, we write a single file sequentially to fill 80% of logical device capacity, to ensure that 80% of the logical space stays valid throughout the test. Remaining logical space involves the actual experiment. The varmail and fileserver workloads included in the filebench are used to simulate mail server and file server workloads, respectively. The number of files in both workloads is set to 900,000; default values are used for other parameters. Each filebench workload is run for two hours with 14GB of files, performing deletion, creation, append, sync (only for varmail), and random read. Since the size of the workloads is smaller than that of RAM, vast majority of the operations that actually reach the device are likely to be write operations. In order to acquire WAF, we retrieve the number of NAND writes and host writes from FTL, and divide the former by the latter.</p><p>In the second part, we measure the benefits in dataintensive workloads by applying automatic stream assignment on certain application specific files. Previous work <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref> has reported improvement by modifying Cassandra source to categorize writes into multiple streams. FStream assigns distinct stream to Cassandra Commitlog through fname stream facility. Load phase involves loading 120,000,000 keys, followed by insertion of 80,000,000 keys during run phase.  The benefit of separating metadata or journal into different streams depends on the amount of metadata write traffic and degree of mixing among various I/O types. As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 5</ref>, Ext4Stream shows 35% performance increase and 25% WAF reduction than baseline ext4 for varmail. XFStream shows 22% performance increase and 14% WAF reduction for varmail compared to xfs. Both Ext4Stream and XFStream show more enhancements for varmail than for fileserver, because varmail is more metadata-intensive than fileserver, as shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 3</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Filebench results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Category</head><p>To investigate the effect of the stream separation for file systems without journaling, we disable the journal in ext4, denoted as ext4-nj. Under varmail workload, ext4-nj performs better than ext4 by 62%, which is mainly due to the removal of journal writes. Stream separation improves the performance and WAF of ext-nj by 26% and 46%, respectively.</p><p>A key observation in fileserver is that reducing metadata writes is more important for performance than reducing journal writes. xfs generates 16% more inode writes and 10% less journal writes for fileserver than ext4. Though the sum of metadata and journal writes is similar, xfs's performance is less than half of ext4's performance. The reason is that the metadata writes are random access while journal writes are sequential. Sequential writes are better for FTL's GC efficiency, and hence are good for performance and lifetime.</p><p>Another important observation comes from ext4 fileserver write distribution in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 3</ref> which shows 16% inode write, but only 0.2% other-meta which includes inode-bitmap as well. This is because of a jbd2 optimization. If a transaction modifies an already-dirty meta buffer, jbd2 delays its writeback by resetting its dirty timer, which is why inode/block bitmap buffer writes remain low despite large number of block/inode allocations.</p><p>As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Fig 5(b)</ref>, ext4 WAF remains close to one during the fileserver test. However, when ext4 is operated with data=journal mode (shown by ext4-DJ), WAF soars above 1.5 due to continuous mixing between journal and application-data. Ext4Stream-DJ eliminates this mixing and brings WAF down back to near one.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Cassandra results</head><p>Cassandra workloads are data-intensive. Database changes are first made to an in-memory structure, called "memtable", and are written to an on-disk commitlog file. The commitlog implements the consistency for Cassandra databases as file system journal does for ext4 and xfs. It is written far more often than file system journal. By separating the commitlog from databases, done by file systems through detecting the file name of commitlog files, we observe 38% throughput improvement and 81% WAF reduction. Cassandra commitlog files are named as commitlog-* with date and time information. With fname stream option, files with their names starting with commitlog flow into a single stream. Even if multiple instances of Cassandra run on a single SSD, commitlog files are written only to the stream assigned by fname stream.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusions</head><p>In this paper, we advocate an approach of applying multistream in the file system layer in order to address the SSD aging problem and GC overheads. Previous proposals of using multi-stream are either application level customization or block level full automation. We aimed to make a new step forward from those proposals. We separate streams at the file system level. We focused on the attributes of file system generated data, such as journal and metadata, because they are short-lived thus suitable for stream separation. We implemented an automatic separation of those file system generated data, with no need for user intervention. Not only have we provided fully automated separation of metadata and journal, but also we advise to separate the redo/undo logs used by applications to different streams. Physical data separation achieved by our stream separation scheme, FStream, helps FTL reduce GC overheads, and thereby enhance both performance and lifetime of SSDs. We applied FStream to ext4 and xfs and obtained encouraging results for various workloads that mimic real-life servers in data centers. Experimental results showed that our scheme enhances the filebench performance by 5%∼35% and reduces WAF by 7%∼46%. For a Cassandra workload, performance is improved by up to 38% and WAF is reduced by up to 81%.</p><p>Our proposal can bring sizable benefits in terms of SSD performance and lifetime. As future work, we consider applying FStream to log-structured file systems, like f2fs, and copy-on-write file systems, e.g., btrfs. We also plan to evaluate how allocation granularity and optimal write size affects the performance and endurance.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Data placement comparison for two write sequences. Here H=Hot, C=Cold, and we assume there are four pages per flash block.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Ext4 on-disk layout. For simplicity, we have not shown flex-bg.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Ext4 journal in ordered mode. Ext4 writes data and journal in sequence. Metadata blocks are written to their actual home location after they are persisted to the journal.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Xfs on-disk layout.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>•</head><label></label><figDesc>Benchmarks: filebench [12], YCSB (Yahoo! Cloud Serving Benchmark) 0.1.4 [4] on Cassandra 1.2.10 [10].</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5: Above graphs show performance and WAF improvement percentage obtained with multi-stream variants of file-systems. Here Ext4-NJ denotes Ext4 without journal, and Ext4-DJ denotes Ext4 with data journal.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="true"><head>Table 1 lists</head><label>1</label><figDesc>the streams we introduced in ext4. These streams can be enabled with the corresponding mount option listed in the table.</figDesc><table>Mount-option 
Stream 
journal-stream 
Separate journal writes 
inode-stream 
Separate inode writes 
dir-stream 
Separate directory blocks 
misc-stream 
Separate inode/block bitmap and 
group descriptor 
fname-stream 
Assign distinct stream to file(s) 
with specific name 
extn-stream 
File-extension based stream 

Table 1: Streams introduced in Ext4Stream. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Streams introduced in XFStream. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Distribution of I/O types during a filebench run. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> A multi-streamed SSD allocate and expand stream in the unit of allocation granularity</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<ptr target="http://www.nvmexpress.org/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The NVM Express</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Add support for write life time hints</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Axboe</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Managing flash memory in personal communication devices</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chiang</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M.-L</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chang</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R.-C</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of 1997 IEEE International Symposium on</title>
		<meeting>1997 IEEE International Symposium on</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="177" to="182" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Consumer Electronics, 1997. ISCE&apos;97</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Benchmarking cloud serving systems with ycsb</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cooper</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Silberstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Ramakrishnan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Sears</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 1st ACM symposium on Cloud computing</title>
		<meeting>the 1st ACM symposium on Cloud computing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="143" to="154" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Stream IDs and I/O hints</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Edge</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016-05" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Stream ID status update</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Edge</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017-03" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient identification of hot data for flash memory storage systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hsieh</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J.-W</forename><surname>Kuo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T.-W</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chang</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L.-P</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Transactions on Storage (TOS)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="22" to="40" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The multistreamed solid-state drive</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kang</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J.-U</forename><surname>Hyun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Maeng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cho</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">6th USENIX Workshop on Hot Topics in Storage and File Systems</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Philadelphia, PA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>USENIX Association</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A flashmemory based file system</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kawaguchi</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Nishioka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Motoda</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Usenix Winter</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="155" to="164" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lakshman</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Malik</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Cassandra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://cassandra.apache.org/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008-07" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The ssd anthology: Understanding ssds and new drivers from ocz</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shimpi</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://db-engines.com/en/ranking/wide+column+store" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tarasov</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Zadok</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shepler</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Filebench</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">A flexible framework for file system benchmarking. USENIX; login</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page">41</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Tiny-tail flash: Nearperfect elimination of garbage collection tail latencies in nand ssds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yan</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Hao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Tong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Sundararaman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Chien</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gunawi</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="15" to="28" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimizing nosql DB on flash: A case study of rocksdb</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Dou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Hou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cho</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2015 IEEE 15th Intl Conf on Scalable Computing and Communications</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1062" to="1069" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Autostream: automatic stream management for multistreamed ssds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Pandurangan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Balakrish-Nan</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 10th ACM International Systems and Storage Conference</title>
		<meeting>the 10th ACM International Systems and Storage Conference<address><addrLine>Haifa, Israel</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017-05-22" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">11</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
