<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/atharsefid/Desktop/grobid-0.5.3/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.3" ident="GROBID" when="2020-10-16T20:10+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Toshiba MT System Description for the WAT2015 Workshop</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Satoshi</forename><surname>Sonoh</surname></persName>
							<email>satoshi.sonoo@toshiba.co.jp</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Corporate Research &amp; Development Center</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Knowledge Media Laboratory</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Toshiba Corporation</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>1, Komukai Toshiba-cho, Saiwai-ku</addrLine>
									<postCode>212-8582</postCode>
									<settlement>Kawasaki</settlement>
									<country key="JP">JAPAN</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Satoshi</forename><surname>Kinoshita</surname></persName>
							<email>satoshi.kinoshita@toshiba.co.jp</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Corporate Research &amp; Development Center</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Knowledge Media Laboratory</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Toshiba Corporation</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>1, Komukai Toshiba-cho, Saiwai-ku</addrLine>
									<postCode>212-8582</postCode>
									<settlement>Kawasaki</settlement>
									<country key="JP">JAPAN</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Toshiba MT System Description for the WAT2015 Workshop</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>This paper provides the system description of Toshiba Machine Translation System for the 2nd Workshop on Asian Translation (WAT2015). We participated in all tasks that consist of &quot;sci-entific papers subtask&quot; and &quot;patents subtask&quot;. We submitted statistically post edited translation (SPE) results based on our rule based translation system and SMT for each language pair. In addition, we submitted system combination results between SPE and SMT with a recurrent neural language model (RNNLM). In experimental results, the system combination achieved higher BLEU scores than single system with reranking. We also obtained improvements in Chinese translation in crowdsourcing evaluations .</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Recently, statistical machine translation (SMT) has been broadly developed and successfully used in the portion of practicable systems. However, it is costly to make a large volume of parallel corpora in a wide range of domains for commercial use. For this reason, we have developed rule based machine translation (RBMT) system using a monolingual corpus in the target language. For example, target word selection is possible based on co-occurrence relationship extracted from a monolingual corpus ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Suzuki et al., 2005</ref>). Furthermore, we have developed a word sense disambiguation based on a monolingual corpus in the target domain, and it has been applied to Japanese-Korean and KoreanJapanese translation systems ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Kumano 2013</ref>). On the other hand, open Asian parallel corpora including ASPEC 1 , NTCIR PatentMT 2 and JPO Patent Corpus 3 are available for the research of machine translation systems. By using the parallel corpora, we have confirmed advantages which apply statistical post editing (SPE) to RBMT in domain adaptation <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Suzuki, 2011)</ref>.</p><p>In the last workshop ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Nakazawa et al., 2014</ref>), we participated in Japanese-English and Japanese-Chinese tasks with SPE approach and obtained higher evaluation results than RBMT. Meanwhile, RBMT showed better performance than SPE in the direct and relative comparison . In this workshop (WAT2015), we participated in all tasks including Japanese-English (ja-en), English-Japanese (en-ja), Japanese-Chinese (ja-zh) and ChineseJapanese (zh-ja) for "scientific paper subtask", and Chinese-Japanese (JPCzh-ja) and KoreanJapanese (JPCko-ja) for "patents subtask". Patents subtask is newly added, and its parallel corpus has 4 sections (Chemistry, Electricity, Mechanical Engineering and Physics).</p><p>In all the tasks, we submitted SPE translation results based on our RBMT and SMT. In addition, we submitted system combination results between SPE and SMT with recurrent neural language model (RNNLM; <ref type="bibr">Mikolov el al., 2010)</ref>. Section 2 and 3 describe the overview of our systems and some pre/post processing. The experimental results and official results are shown in Section 4 and 5. The analysis for the official results is discussed in Section 6 and finally, Section 7 concludes this paper. As for a contextaware translation, the description was omitted because our baseline system is the same as the last workshop (see ).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Overview of Toshiba System</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">RBMT System</head><p>Our RBMT system is basically a transfer-based machine translation ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Izuha et al., 2008</ref>). The core framework consists of morphological analysis, syntactic/semantic analysis, target word selection, structural transfer, syntactic generation and morphological generation. Furthermore, huge amount of rules as translation knowledge including word dictionaries can realize both high translation performance and flexibility of customization. As for Japanese-Korean translation, syntactic analysis and transfer are omitted because the languages are grammatically similar.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Statistical Post Editing</head><p>SPE using phrase-based SMT has been proposed and it is an efficient framework which is able to adapt translation output to target domains ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Michel et al., 2007)</ref>. We first translated source sentences of training data in ASPEC and JPO Patent Corpus by RBMT. Then we trained phrase-based model between translated sentences and reference sentences using Moses toolkit ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Kohen et al., 2007)</ref>. In the training, we used 1M sentences for ja-en, en-ja, JPCzh-ja and JPCko-ja, 0.67M for ja-zh and zh-ja in the training data. Japanese sentences were tokenized by JUMAN 4 , and Moses tokenizer for English, and Kytea <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Neubig et. al, 2011</ref>) for Chinese. We also trained 5-gram language models using <ref type="bibr">KenLM (Heafield et al., 2013)</ref>. In tuning and decoding, we set distortion limit to 0 for JPOko-ja in consideration of grammatical similarity and 6 for other language pairs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">System Combination using RNNLM</head><p>Although both SPE and SMT are based on a statistical model from the given corpora, they generate different translation candidates because SPE has some features from RBMT. If a better system can be selected from the candidates in each translation, we can get a better translation result.</p><p>Thus, we realized a system combination between SPE and SMT as n-best reranking using a RNNLM. The n-best reranking can be achieved using both basic features and RNNLM score. In tuning, we combined 100-best candidates of both SPE and SMT for dev-set, and ran MERT tuning by adding the RNNLM score to the basic features. In decoding, we re-ranked combined candidates by product-sum of the features including RNNLM score and tuned weights.</p><p>For ja-en, en-ja, ja-zh and zh-ja, we used RNNLMs trained by the first 500k sentences in the training data of ASPEC. For JPOzh-ja and JPOko-ja, we used 500k sentences which were evenly extracted from 4 sections in JPO Patent Corpus. All RNNLMs were trained with 500 hidden layers and 50 classes by RNNLM toolkit 5 .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Tuning</head><p>RBMT and pre/postprocessing</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Technical Term Dictionaries</head><p>As the preparation for each task, we selected technical term dictionaries by the same principle in the last workshop <ref type="bibr">(Sonoh el al., 2014</ref>). For JPOzh-ja, we used an additional patent dictionary, which is extracted from JPO ChineseJapanese dictionary <ref type="bibr">6</ref> . Furthermore, for JPOko-ja, we used n-gram probability dictionary, which was made from monolingual patent resources, in order to resolve word sense disambiguation ( ).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">English Word Correction</head><p>To improve translation of sentences including misspelled words in English, we applied correction processing based on an edited distance. We replaced the word considered as misspelling with a word which had the smallest edited distance in the training data. However, because SMT and SPE basically have robustness to the misspelling, we confined words to be replaced to words which remain as unknown words in SMT and SPE results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Japanese KATAKANA Normalization</head><p>In the case where a target language is Japanese; we applied normalization of KATAKANA notation. In advance of translation, we counted the frequency of KATAKANA notation, which has fluctuations of prolonged sound mark, in the target sentences of the training data. In the translation results, KATAKANA fluctuations were replaced with those of highly-frequent notations, such as "from スクリュ to スクリュー" and "from サーバー to サーバ". By applying normalization, we got improvements of about 0.5 BLEU in RBMT.</p><p>Furthermore, we replaced the ideographic comma "、" in number expression with a normal comma "," for translation results in Japanese.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Other Post Processing</head><p>In order to reduce unknown words in SMT, we applied RBMT to SMT results. For example, in ja-zh, we translated KATAKANA words, which remain in SMT results, into Chinese or English words, if the words were found in RBMT dictionaries. Also, Hangul words in SMT results of JPOko-ja were translated into Japanese words.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experimental Results</head><p>This section shows experimental results of our translation systems. <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1 and 2</ref> show the overall BLEU and RIBES scores for "scientific papers subtask" and "patents subtask", respectively. COMB means results of the system combination and Rerank means results of reranking using RNNLM (100-best for SMT and SPE, 200-best for COMB). In all tasks, SPE improves translation results of RBMT on the BLEU and RIBES. In tasks except JPOko-ja, SPE achieves performance equal to or better than phrase-based SMT.</p><p>Moreover, in most tasks, Rerank improves about 0.3-0.5 BLEU score, and COMB shows better performance than other systems. In JPOko-ja, SMT, SPE and COMB show very high performances which are close to 70 BLEU, and SMT with reranking achieves the highest BLEU and RIBES scores. In ja-en, en-ja, ja-zh and zh-ja, more than half of translations selected from SPE and the others selected from SMT. In particular SPE accounted for about 80% translations in ja-en, en-ja and zh-ja. On the other hand, more than half of translations selected from SMT in JPOzh-ja and JPOko-ja. <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 3</ref> shows the translation examples that COMB achieves better results than SPE with reranking in sentence-level BLEU.</p><p>Finally, we compared between phrase-based model and hierarchical phrase-based model. <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Ta- ble 4</ref> shows comparison in ja-zh task. In all systems including SPE, hierarchical phrase-based model improves about 0.4 BLEU. We applied hierarchical phrase-based model to ja-zh only, because significant improvements were not confirmed in other language pairs.   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Official Results</head><p>This section shows official results of our translation systems. We basically submitted two results, one is SPE <ref type="bibr">7</ref> and the other is the system combination between SPE and SMT. Furthermore, top two systems on the BLEU scores were evaluated by the crowdsourcing. In the crowdsourcing evaluation, pair-wise evaluation against the baseline system (phrase-based SMT) was performed by 5 evaluators, and HUMAN score was calculated ja-en SRC 揺動時に比べて，発電量は４０倍である。 REF</p><p>In comparison with the fluctuation, the electric power generation is the 40 twice. SPE Compared with the time of rocking, production of electricity is 40 times. COMB Compared with the time of fluctuations, the electric power generation is 40 times.</p><p>en-ja</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>SRC</head><p>SiO2 films showed excellent performance even at 430℃ or less, and the memory effect of Si dot MOS capacitor was confirmed.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">REF ＳｉＯ２膜は，４３０℃以下でも優れた性能を示し，ＳｉドットＭＯＳコンデンサのメモ リ効果を確認した。 SPE ＳｉＯ２膜は４３０℃でも優れた性能を示す以下であり，ＳｉドットＭＯＳキャパシタの 記憶効果が確認された。 COMB ＳｉＯ２膜は４３０℃でも優れた性能を示し，以下，ＳｉドットＭＯＳキャパシタの記憶 効果を確認した。 ja-zh SRC この擾乱からの回復についても考察した。 REF 对这种干扰的恢复也进行了考察。 SPE 考察了从该干扰恢复。 COMB 在这种干扰的恢复也进行了考察。 zh-ja SRC 还对在完成来所登记之前的各个环节进行了介绍。 REF 来所登録が完了するまでの流れ等も紹介した。 SPE 登録の完了までの各段階について紹介した。 COMB 登録が完了するまでの各段階について紹介した。 JPO zh-ja SRC 在固体中加入 BHT，混合物在丙酮中溶解。 REF ＢＨＴを固体に加え、混合物をアセトンに溶解する。 SPE 固体ＢＨＴを加え、この混合物は、アセトンに溶解した。 COMB 固体ＢＨＴを加え、混合物をアセトンに溶解した。 JPO ko-ja SRC 원재료 필름(1)에서의 비접합부의 적어도 일부를 덮도록 배치되어도 좋다. REF 原反フィルム１における非接合部の少なくとも一部を覆うように配置されてもよ い 。 SPE 原反フィルム１での非接合部の少なくとも一部を覆うように配置されてもよい。 COMB 原反フィルム１における非接合部の少なくとも一部を覆うように配置されてもよ い。</formula><p>based on majority voting ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Nakazawa et al., 2014</ref>). In WAT2015 results (Nakazawa et al., 2015), we note that Toshiba systems were ranked as one of the top three systems in human evaluation in ja-en, ja-zh and JPOzh-ja. Especially, ja-zh achieved the highest score although the BLEU score is lower than other systems. On the other hand, as for JPOko-ja, we got a comparatively high BLEU score, but were disappointed by its low HUMAN score. <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 5</ref> and 6 are the overall official results for each task, respectively. In ja-zh and zh-ja, COMB shows higher HUMAN score than SPE. On the other hand, SPE or SMT is higher than COMB in ja-en, JPOzh-ja and JPOko-ja. These results indicate that the system combination improves human evaluation of Chinese translation in the scientific documents, at least. We guess that the system combination between equivalent systems achieves complementary translation to improve human evaluations. For example, BLEU scores of SPE and SMT are nearly equal in ja-zh and zh-ja (shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Discussion</head><p>On receiving the crowdsourcing results, we analyzed differences between our system and Online A, which obtained the highest HUMAN score in JPOko-ja. <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 7</ref> shows the comparison between our system (COMB) and Online A. Here, 'Baseline' column is the HUMAN score in the result of crowdsourcing (official results) and the other was evaluated by inner evaluators. The inner evaluation was conducted excluding expressional differences as described in detail below. Although Online A achieves a very high HUMAN score to the baseline system, superior results of COMB over Online A are shown in the pair-wise evaluation.</p><p>We hypothesize that the significant difference between the crowdsourcing and the inner evaluators occurs from the evaluation of the number expressions, such as "システム(100)" and "システム 100". In the training data of JPOko-ja, a lot of brackets of numbers in the source sentences disappear in the target sentences. Thus, brackets are dropped in SPE and SMT. As for well-translated target sentences such as JPOko-ja, it is possible that evaluators in the crowdsourcing judged faithful translation as better by focusing on existence of brackets. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusion</head><p>The overview of Toshiba machine translation systems, which applied the statistical post editing and the system combination with RNNLM, is described in this paper. SPE and reranking with RNNLM achieved higher BLEU than phrase-based SMT in most language pairs. Furthermore, the system combination between SPE and SMT improved BLEU score in Japanese-English pair and JapaneseChinese pair. In the other hand, a straightforward correlation between automatic evaluation  and human evaluation is not confirmed in our system. We need to establish the combination of multi-systems for practical use purpose, taking advantage of their characteristics and qualities.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="true"><head>Table 1 : Overall BLEU and RIBES scores for "scientific papers subtask".</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>System Rerank 
ja-en 
en-ja 
ja-zh 
zh-ja 
BLEU RIBES BLEU RIBES BLEU RIBES BLEU RIBES 
RBMT No 
15.31 0.677 14.78 0.685 19.51 0.767 15.39 0.723 
SMT 
No 
17.41 0.620 25.17 0.642 28.20 0.810 36.34 0.815 
Yes 
17.85 0.619 25.37 0.643 28.46 0.809 36.69 0.815 
SPE 
No 
22.65 0.717 31.10 0.767 29.48 0.809 35.76 0.822 
Yes 
22.92 0.718 31.73 0.770 29.49 0.809 36.06 0.823 
COMB Yes 
23.00 0.716 31.82 0.770 29.60 0.810 37.47 0.827 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Overall BLEU and RIBES scores for "patents subtask". 

System Rerank 
JPOzh-ja 
JPOko-ja 
BLEU RIBES BLEU RIBES 
RBMT No 
25.81 0.764 51.28 0.902 
SMT 
No 
38.77 0.802 70.17 0.943 
Yes 
39.18 0.805 70.89 0.944 
SPE 
No 
39.01 0.813 68.47 0.940 
Yes 
39.30 0.811 68.76 0.940 
COMB Yes 
40.23 0.813 70.40 0.942 </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="true"><head>Table 4 : A Comparison of Phrase-based Model.</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>System hierarchical 
ja-zh 
BLEU 
RIBES 

SMT 
No 
28.46 
0.809 
Yes 
29.82 
0.810 
SPE 
No 
29.49 
0.809 
Yes 
29.89 
0.809 
COMB No 
29.60 
0.810 
Yes 
30.07 
0.817 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 3 : Translation examples indicating that COMB achieves better results than SPE in sentece-level BLEU.</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>The relationship between automatic 
evaluations and human evaluations. 

BLEU RIBES 

HUMAN 

Baseline COMB Online A 

COMB 70.51 
0.94 
3.00 
-
10.75 
Online A 55.05 
0.91 
38.75 -10.75 
-

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="true"><head>Table 5 : Overall official results for "scientific papers subtask". B, R and H mean BLEU, RIBES, HUMAN, respectively. HUMAN was evaluated by 5 evaluators using crowdsorcing.</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>System 
ja-en 
en-ja 
ja-zh 
zh-ja 
B 
R 
H 
B 
R 
H 
B 
R 
H 
B 
R 
H 
SPE 
22.89 0.719 25.00 32.06 0.771 40.25 30.17 0.813 2.50 35.85 0.825 -1.00 
COMB 23.00 0.716 21.25 31.82 0.770 
-
30.07 0.817 17.00 37.47 0.827 18.00 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" validated="false"><head>Table 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Overall official results for "patents subtask". 

System 
JPOzh-ja 
JPOko-ja 
B 
R 
H 
B 
R 
H 
SMT 
-
-
-
71.01 0.944 4.50 
SPE 
41.12 0.822 24.25 
-
-
-
COMB 41.82 0.821 14.50 70.51 0.942 3.00 </table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> http://lotus.kuee.kyoto-u.ac.jp/ASPEC/ 2 http://research.nii.ac.jp/ntcir/permission/ntcir-10/perm-en-PatentMT.html 3 http://lotus.kuee.kyoto-u.ac.jp/WAT/patent/ 48 Proceedings of the 2nd Workshop on Asian Translation (WAT2015), pages 48 53, Kyoto, Japan, 16th October 2015. 2015 Copyright is held by the author(s).</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> http://nlp.ist.i.kyoto-u.ac.jp/index.php?JUMAN</note>

			<note place="foot" n="5"> http://www.fit.vutbr.cz/~imikolov/rnnlm/ 6 https://alaginrc.nict.go.jp/resources/jpo-info/jpooutline.html#jpo-dic-zh</note>

			<note place="foot" n="7"> In JPOko-ja, because SMT showed higher BLEU score than SPE, we submitted SMT result.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning Translations from Monolingual Corpora</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hirokazu</forename><surname>Suzuki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Akira</forename><surname>Kumano</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of MT Summit X.Akira Kumano</title>
		<meeting>of MT Summit X.Akira Kumano</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="298" to="301" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Japio YEAR BOOK 2013. In Japanese</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improvement of Korean machine translation using statistical word selection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hiroyuki</forename><surname>Tanaka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Satoshi</forename><surname>Sonoh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Satoshi</forename><surname>Kinoshita</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Satoshi</forename><surname>Kamatani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the 3rd Symposium on Patent Information Processing</title>
		<meeting>of the 3rd Symposium on Patent Information essing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="100" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>In Japanese</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic Post-Editing based on SMT and its selective application by Sentence-Level Automatic Quality Evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hirokazu</forename><surname>Suzuki</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of MT Summit XIII</title>
		<meeting>of MT Summit XIII</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overview of the 1st Workshop on Asian Translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Toshiaki</forename><surname>Nakazawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hideya</forename><surname>Mino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Isao</forename><surname>Goto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sadao</forename><surname>Kurohashi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eiichiro</forename><surname>Sumita</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the 1st Workshop on Asian Translation</title>
		<meeting>of the 1st Workshop on Asian Translation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Toshiba MT System Description for the WAT2014 Workshop</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Satoshi</forename><surname>Sonoh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Satoshi</forename><surname>Kinoshita</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hiroyuki</forename><surname>Tanaka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Satoshi</forename><surname>Kamatani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the 1st Workshop on Asian Translation (WAT2014)</title>
		<meeting>of the 1st Workshop on Asian Translation (WAT2014)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recurrent neural network based language model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomas</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Karafiat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lukas</forename><surname>Burget</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jan</forename><surname>Cernocky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sanjeev</forename><surname>Khudanpur</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of INTERSPEECH 2010</title>
		<meeting>of INTERSPEECH 2010</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1045" to="1048" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Toshiba Rule-Based Translation System at NTCIR-7 PAT MT</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tatsuya</forename><surname>Izuha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Akira</forename><surname>Kumano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuka</forename><surname>Kuroda</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of NTCIR-7 Workshop Meeting</title>
		<meeting>of NTCIR-7 Workshop Meeting</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="430" to="434" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistical Phrase-based Post-editing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michel</forename><surname>Simard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cyril</forename><surname>Goutte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pierre</forename><surname>Isabell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of NAACL HLT 2007, ACL</title>
		<meeting>of NAACL HLT 2007, ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="508" to="515" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Moses: Open Source Toolkit for Statistical Machine Translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Kohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marcell</forename><surname>Federuci</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brooke</forename><surname>Cowan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Zens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Dyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the ACL</title>
		<meeting>of the ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="177" to="180" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Ondrej Bojar Alexandra Constantin and Evan Herbst</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pointwise Prediction for Robust, Adaptable Japanese Morphological Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Graham</forename><surname>Neubig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yosuke</forename><surname>Nakata</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shinsuke</forename><surname>Mori</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of ACL-HLT</title>
		<meeting>of ACL-HLT</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scalable modified Kneser-Ney language model estimation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kenneth</forename><surname>Heafield</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ivan</forename><surname>Pouzyrevsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Koehn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the ACL</title>
		<meeting>of the ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="690" to="696" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overview of the 2nd Workshop on Asian Translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Toshiaki</forename><surname>Nakazawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hideya</forename><surname>Mino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Isao</forename><surname>Goto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Graham</forename><surname>Neubig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sadao</forename><surname>Kurohashi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eiichiro</forename><surname>Sumita</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the 2nd Workshop on Asian Translation (WAT2015)</title>
		<meeting>of the 2nd Workshop on Asian Translation (WAT2015)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
