<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/atharsefid/Desktop/grobid-0.5.3/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.3" ident="GROBID" when="2020-09-29T02:48+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Privacy Aspects of Health Related Information Sharing in Online Social Networks</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sadegh</forename><surname>Torabi</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of British Columbia Vancouver</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>BC</region>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Konstantin</forename><surname>Beznosov</surname></persName>
							<email>beznosov@ece.ubc.ca</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of British Columbia Vancouver</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>BC</region>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Privacy Aspects of Health Related Information Sharing in Online Social Networks</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>1</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Index Terms-HRI</term>
					<term>OSN</term>
					<term>Risk Perceptions</term>
					<term>Behavioural Re- sponses</term>
					<term>Mechanical Turk</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Online social networks (OSNs) have formed virtual social networks where people meet and share information. Among all shared information, health related information (HRI) has received considerable attention from researchers and individual users. While considered beneficial, sharing HRI, which is personal in nature, comes with its privacy drawback. Privacy is a process of boundary regulation that is related to the individual and her perception of the surrounding environment. As a result, the subjective privacy risk perceptions associated with sharing HRI in OSN have driven people to adopt different types of behaviour, both in terms of HRI sharing and privacy risk mitigation. Through an online survey, we examined factors that affect users&apos; perceived privacy risks along with their risk-mitigating behaviour, when it comes to sharing HRI in OSNs. The results suggest that the majority (over 95%) of participants share some HRI, with the &quot;type&quot; and the &quot;recipient&quot; of the shared HRI being the key factors that affect the perceived privacy risk and the risk-mitigating behavioural responses.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>I. INTRODUCTION</head><p>Sharing health related information (HRI), 1 such as symptoms, treatments, prescriptions, and diet related information, could be beneficial for individuals and their social networks. For example, social pressure has been shown to be an effective incentive for losing weight and can influence people to make healthier lifestyle choices <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr">2]</ref>. In addition, patients with serious illnesses can learn from other individuals with similar conditions by connecting through the Internet <ref type="bibr">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">4]</ref>. Social support is also shown to be effective in maintaining physical and mental health during certain long-term medical treatments <ref type="bibr">[5]</ref>. In fact, the highly inter-connected nature of existing online social networks (OSNs), and the increasing number of OSN users have encouraged people to actively use OSNs for sharing different types of information, including HRI. According to recent Pew Internet report, about 23% of online users in the US have followed their friends' personal health experience in the past year, with a 3% increase compared to 2010 <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref>. Meanwhile, 16% of the surveyed participants reported going online to find others who shared similar health concerns <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>. Other surveys have also shown that sharing health related knowledge online is in fact becoming a leading habit among people <ref type="bibr">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">6,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">7]</ref>.</p><p>Despite the popularity of the OSNs and their large number of users, existing OSNs suffer from security and privacy issues, making them vulnerable to different attacks <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref>. Inherently, OSN users' HRI, which is thought to be personal and private by nature, might be subject to unintended disclosure. Privacy invasion, stalking, data re-identification (de-anonymisation), medical data misuse, and damaging personal data are a few examples of privacy and security related threats associated with unintended information disclosure <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">13,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">14]</ref>. In reality, depending on their knowledge and previous experience, people perceive privacy risks associated with sharing their HRI in OSNs differently <ref type="bibr">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">13,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[17]</ref>. Their behavioural responses to perceived privacy risks vary as well <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[18]</ref>. People may avoid risks by manipulating their information, or cope with the perceived risks for the sake of getting benefits, or simply avoid sharing their HRI if the perceived risks are high <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[18]</ref>. For example, a study by Velden and El-Emam showed that younger patients who used Facebook to share different personal information were not willing to share their HRI in Facebook and preferred to act as "regular" (i.e., with no disease) when communicating with their Facebook connections <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[17]</ref>. On the other hand, a study of US mothers who used online technologies to share or look for HRI showed that about 70% of them share HRI through their Facebook accounts <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[19]</ref>.</p><p>Motivated by the need for continuous assessment of users' subjective behaviours, we constructed an online survey to investigate existing practices of sharing HRI in OSNs. We also explored users' privacy risks perceptions and risk-mitigating behavioural responses. We recruited 166 active OSN users through Amazon Mechanical Turk (MTurk) <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[20]</ref> and surveyed their sharing behaviour for different HRI categories. We analyzed characteristics of HRI instances from the literature <ref type="bibr">[5- 7]</ref> to group them into 8 categories <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">(Table I</ref>). The majority of participants (95.8%), indicated sharing some HRI through their OSN accounts. Reasons for sharing varied, with "helping others" and "seeking help and social support" being the most popular (66.9% and 51.8% respectively). On the other hand, about half of the participants (49%) preferred not to share their HRI because of the "different" people among their OSN contacts, whom they did not want to share HRI with. Most participants (about 93%) considered the HRI type and its recipient to be the most significant factors affecting the magnitude of the privacy risks. Participants perceived lower privacy risks when sharing HRI with "select individual(s)" or "select group(s)," while their risk perceptions increased with the expansion of the receiver base to include "entire contacts" and "all other OSN users" respectively. In summary, this paper makes the following contributions:</p><p>• Reports quantitative data about OSN users' HRI sharing practices, perceived privacy risks, and risk-mitigating behaviours.</p><p>• Showes the role of OSNs in creating new contexts for sharing HRI.</p><p>• Highlights OSN users' privacy concerns and riskmitigating behaviour.</p><p>• Helps in understanding existing sharing practices and main privacy concerns, and contributes toward grounding into empirical data the research on HRI sharing in OSNs. We begin by discussing related work about HRI sharing in OSNs and its privacy related implications (Section II). Then, we present our research methodology (Section III), including design, execution and evaluation details of our online survey. Next, we report collected data about OSN users' HRI sharing practices, privacy risk perceptions and risk-mitigating behavioural responses (Section IV). In Section V, we discuss how the results. We conclude by discussing limitations and conclusions in Sections VI and Section VII respectively.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>II. RELATED WORK</head><p>There is a fine line between what to share and what to keep private. Altman <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[21,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">22]</ref> introduced "privacy regulation theory," which defines privacy as a dynamic process of boundary regulation in response to changes in our internal state and external conditions. People achieve better privacy by minimizing the difference between their "desired" and "achieved" (perceived) privacy levels. In order to achieve desired privacy levels, people need to maintain their privacy by developing a number of behavioural mechanisms (responses), and then expressing their desired privacy levels to others. Although Altman's privacy regulation theory was developed long before the OSN age, the virtual spaces created by existing OSNs are only considered as new contexts for applying privacy regulation theory <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[23]</ref>.</p><p>The benefits of sharing HRI within social networks has received considerable attention from the research community in recent years <ref type="bibr">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">4]</ref>. Skeels <ref type="bibr">[5]</ref> studied patients with serious health issues (breast cancer), and explored their personal health information (PHI) sharing behaviours in their social networks. She used a user-centric approach to capture users' requirements in order to design and evaluate an online interactive technology that facilitates PHI sharing, while preserving information privacy through transparent and usable interface. Although we aim at addressing similar problem (investigating HRI sharing practices), our study context is different. Skeels explored PHI sharing requirements in offline social network to inform the design of her patient-centric OSN, whereas we focus on the OSN context and the HRI sharing experience in general. Moreover, she studied patients with breast cancer only, while we target active OSN users regardless of their health conditions. Bulgurcu <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[18]</ref> studied OSN users' privacy perceptions and behavioural responses with respect to their perceived privacy threats and coping motivations. She combined "coping theory" <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[24]</ref> from psychology with privacy literature to identify how OSN users' privacy threat perceptions (assessment of the consequences of using OSN features) and coping perceptions (assessment of their control over using the feature), will determine their motivation to cope with a privacy threat. She studied OSN users' behavioural responses in the form of coping motivations and preferred behaviours (emotion-focused and problem-focused coping). <ref type="bibr">2</ref> In fact, individuals may undertake different risk-mitigating behaviours in response to perceived privacy threats, and therefore, in our study, we focus on the context of HRI sharing in OSNs and explore users' perceived privacy risks and behavioural responses respectively.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>III. METHODOLOGY</head><p>We studied recent literature on HRI sharing in OSNs and the associated privacy perceptions. To the best of our knowledge, previous studies, which applied different methodologies (interviews, focus groups, and surveys), were either limited to niche demographics (e.g., teenage patients, elderly patients, mothers with children in custody) <ref type="bibr">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">17,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">19,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">25,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">26]</ref>, or were focused on non-OSN users <ref type="bibr">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">27]</ref>. Although the literature on "information sharing security and privacy" was quite rich in content, it lacked the quantitative data on the HRI sharing practices of active OSN users. Moreover, the privacy aspects of HRI sharing in OSN were not clearly presented in the literature. Therefore, with the partial knowledge gained from literature, we decided to employ an online survey, as the first step toward building a better understanding of practices for HRI sharing by active OSN users' and their perceptions of associated privacy risks.</p><p>We aimed at providing descriptive statistics that quantify HRI sharing practices while highlighting the main privacyrelated issues. As a result, we surveyed active OSN users about their HRI sharing practices with their OSN peers. We also collected data about participants' perceived risks when sharing different HRI with various user groups. Finally, we collected OSN users' risk-mitigating behaviours at different risk levels.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A. Online Survey</head><p>We constructed an online survey 3 that consisted of four sections. In the first section, we collected participants' demographics along with information about their OSN accounts and usage. In the second section, participants reported how often they shared HRI, and identified reasons for and against sharing HRI in OSNs. Next, we asked participants to specify their perceived privacy risk levels when sharing different types of HRI with different users. In the fourth section, we asked participants to specify their preferred risk-mitigating behavioural response(s) at different levels of perceived privacy risks. Survey questions and response options are provided in Appendix A.</p><p>1) General Usage: We asked participants about the total number of active OSN accounts they maintained, and, for each active OSN account, we asked the following: (i) name of the OSN; (2) how often the OSN account was used; and (3) the preferred device for connecting to that OSN account (e.g., smartphone, laptop, tablet).</p><p>2) HRI Sharing Practices: We grouped a superset of HRI items found in the literature <ref type="bibr">[5]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref> into 8 unique HRI categories, as shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table I</ref>. For each category, we asked participants to rate the likelihood of sharing information from "never" to "always" on a 5-point Likert scale, to differentiate users who shared HRI from those who never did. We also asked participants to specify all reasons that would lead them to share and not share HRI, by selecting all that applied in the aggregated list of possible reasons.</p><p>3) Perceived Privacy Risks: To better understand users' privacy risk perceptions, we asked participants to identify how much each factor (HRI recipients, HRI category, used OSNs, and current health conditions) contributes to their perceived privacy risks (responses varied on a 5-point Likert scale from "does not affect at all" to "strongly affects"). Then, we asked participants to rate their perceived privacy risks of sharing information from each HRI category on a 5-point Likert scale, from "very low or no risks" to "extreme risks," when sharing with different users (select individuals, select groups, entire contacts, and all other OSN users).</p><p>4) Risk-Mitigating Behaviours: In the final section of the survey, we assumed different privacy risk levels ("very low or no risks" to "extreme risks"), and asked participants to indicate their preferred risk-mitigating behaviour(s) when sharing HRI in OSNs. We wanted to capture the preferred behavioural responses of participants in the presence of different risk levels, regardless of the perceived benefits, and describe their riskmitigating responses in terms of risk avoidance (not sharing) and coping behaviours (coping with threats by minimizing perceived risks).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B. Participant Recruitment</head><p>We recruited Amazon MTurk <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[20]</ref> workers through CrowdFlower <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[28]</ref>, a crowdsourcing website that provides different labour channels. MTurk workers, who were shown to be more educated and younger than the general population, can be considered as a reliable source of high-quality data for research involving human-subjects <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[29]</ref>. CrowdFlower was used to recruit "trusted" MTurk workers, who are identified by CrowdFlower considering different factors such as their prior completed jobs and reported activities. CrowdFlower also keeps track of users' IP addresses and used aliases (if any), and prevents multiple submissions from the same user upon request. Therefore, we used available features to limit participants to a single submission only. The posted recruitment job title, "An online survey of health related information sharing in online social networks," did not mention privacy, while in the instructions, participants were requested to complete an online survey about their HRI sharing practices, perceived privacy risks, and corresponding behavioural responses that would take less than 30 minutes of their time. Participants were compensated with $1 (US) through CrowdFlower for successfully completing the job.</p><p>The survey was conducted completely online, with participants' identities anonymized throughout the study. We minimized risk to participants by anonymizing submissions and excluding any personally identifiable information from generated results and published reports. As a requirement of UBC's Behavioural Research Ethics Boards (BREB) for conducting user studies, the recruiting material specified that participants should be 19 years of age and older. The study also required recruiting participants with at least one active OSN profile that they use regularly. After obtaining UBC's BREB approval for conducting our study, we started the data collection process by posting a job request on CrowdFlower. Participants were provided with a link to the survey website, where they reviewed a consent form describing the research, data collection and storage policies. To guarantee compensation by CrowdFlower, participants were required to prove survey submission by entering a unique 7-digit alpha-numeric code that was assigned to them by the survey website upon survey completion.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>C. Categorization of HRI Examples</head><p>Prior to conducting our survey, we reviewed the literature and found more than 30 different examples of HRI that people share online <ref type="bibr">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">30]</ref>. They include but not limited to the following: mental or physical conditions, healthy eating and dietary information, daily exercise routines, experience with a specific doctor, previous surgeries, symptoms and side  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A. Participant Demographics and OSN Usage</head><p>Out of the 191 participants, two did not consent to the study, and therefore were removed from further analysis. The majority of the remaining 189 participants were from the US (87.8%), followed by India (9.5%). We also received a single submission from participants residing in each of the following <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">4</ref> www.optimalworkshop.com </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Employment category</head><p>More than 18 different categories: IT (10.6%), Education (9%), Medical (7.9%), Banking (7.4%), and other categories including Student and Selfemployed countries: Australia, Philippines, Romania, Canada, and UK.</p><p>Since users' privacy risk perceptions and behaviour responses are highly dependent on the social environment and cultural context <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[22]</ref>, we discarded submissions made by participants residing outside of the US in order to minimize the effect of cultural differences in our analysis. We report the rest of our analysis on this sample of 166 participants from the USA. They represent users from at least 39 different states (24 participants did not specify their state), with California and Texas having the highest participation rates (8.4%), followed by New York and Arizona with 7.2% and 5.4% respectively (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1)</ref>. With approximately equal number of male (49.4%) and female (50.6%) participants, our sample had ages ranging between 19 and 70 (µ = 30.4, σ = 10). As <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table II</ref> shows, 59% of all participants were between 19 and 29 years old, with the majority (83.7%) being between 19 and 39. Approximately 40% had completed an undergraduate degree, while the rest had completed high school (25.3%), post-secondary (12.7%), and graduate degrees (10.2%). Our sample covered over 18 employment categories, with IT (10.6%), Education (9%), Medical (7.9%), and Banking (7.4%) being most popular.   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B. HRI Sharing Practices</head><p>To investigate sharing practices, we presented participants with eight HRI categories <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">(Table I)</ref>, and asked them to indicate on a 5-point Likert scale how regularly they shared information in each category. As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 3</ref>, and summarized in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table III</ref>, 63.3% of participants never shared information about their medical health records (e.g., x-rays, treatments, name and address, insurance policy number). More than half of participants (54.8%) never shared HRI of people in their custody (e.g., children and elderly parents), while 41.6% indicated never sharing other people's health related experience. Only 7 participants never shared any HRI in OSNs, while the rest (95.8%) indicated sharing.</p><p>To answer the question "why do you share HRI online?," participants selected all that applied from a list of common reasons obtained from the literature <ref type="bibr">[5]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>. The provided list of reasons, both for and against sharing HRI <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">(Tables IV and V)</ref>, represent general sharing motivation and are not related to any specific HRI category. As shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table IV</ref>, more than half of participants (66.9%) shared their health related knowledge and experience to "help others" in their social network, followed by "getting beneficial feedback" and "social support" as other reasons for sharing HRI online (51.8% and 48.2% respectively). On the other hand, for the HRI that the participants did not share in their OSNs, approximately half of them (49.4%) indicated not sharing HRI due to the existence of different people among their OSN contacts, while 43.4% of all participants considered their HRI to be personal and did not want to share it with anyone <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">(Table V)</ref>. Since we do not have exact information about users' actual behaviour, we can not assume that privacy-related issues were the only motivation preventing participants from sharing HRI online. However, the results indicate that about half of the participants did not share HRI in their OSN(s) due to its personal nature and due to the existence of different people in their social contacts, which might be an indication of privacy concerns. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>C. Perceived Privacy Risks</head><p>The subjective privacy risk perceptions of technology users is highly context dependent <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[23]</ref>. In the context of HRI sharing    in OSNs, the key factors are the following: (1) recipient of information; (2) HRI type and category; (3) the OSN where information is shared; and (4) the mental and physical health conditions of the individual at time of sharing. We asked participants to rate on a 5-point Likert scale how much each of the aforementioned four factors would affect their perceived privacy risks (responses varied between "does not affect" to "strongly affects"). While more than 85% of participants considered all four factors to affect their perceived privacy risks, results showed that the HRI "recipient" and its "type and category," extremely affected the perceived privacy risks of more than 1/4 of participants (approximately 30%).</p><note type="other">Healthy living Own Experience Useful found informaFon Mental and emoFonal health condiFons Physical health condiFons Medical health records Experience of somebody else HRI of people in your custody % of parFcipants Very low or no risk</note><p>With prior knowledge about the effect of information recipient and type on increasing perceived privacy risks when sharing information in OSN(s), we asked users to rate on a 5-points Likert scale their perceived privacy risks when sharing information from each HRI category with different user groups (responses varied from "very low or no risk" to "extreme risk"). We presented participants with the following user groups: select individual(s), select group(s), entire contact list, and all other OSN users. Although it was not explicitly mentioned to the participants, select individual(s) and group(s) implied trusted user categories. We tried to avoid using the word "trust" in order to minimize biased responses, while implying trust by presenting selective user choice when sharing HRI. Our aim was to capture users' perceived privacy risk variations with respect to the HRI category and the number of trusted recipients, and compare it with the perceived privacy risks of sharing with other user groups that possibly include untrusted users such as the participant's entire contact list or all other users in the OSN. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 4</ref> shows all participants' perceived privacy risks when sharing HRI with different user groups.</p><p>More than 66.9% of participants perceived very low or no risks when sharing "useful found information" with their "entire contacts" or "all other OSN users" (perceived privacy risks of sharing with select individual(s) and group(s) was 81.9% and 78.9% respectively). This low sensitivity toward sharing "useful found information" might be due to the nature of that type of HRI, which might not directly relate to a person's health. For other HRI categories such as "healthy living," "physical health conditions," "own experience," and "mental and emotional health conditions," the percentage of participants who perceived sharing HRI to be of "very low or no risks" decreased with respect to the extent in the recipient base. Interestingly, as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 4</ref>, the difference in the number of participants who perceived sharing aforementioned HRI categories to be of "very low or no risks" was significantly small when comparing sharing HRI with "entire contact list" and "all other OSN users". This might indicate that a portion of participants perceive privacy risks related to sharing HRI with their entire contact list to be similar to sharing with all other OSN users. From a different perspective, 16.3% of participants perceived sharing information about their "medical health records" to be of extreme risk, even if shared with select individuals (trusted individuals). Similarly, sharing "HRI of people in custody" raised high concerns by participants, with 13.3% of participants perceiving extreme privacy risks, even when sharing with select individuals. As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 4</ref>, participants' risk perceptions significantly increased when the recipients of information expanded from "select individuals" to "all other OSN users".</p><p>To find out if there is a significant difference in participants' perceived privacy risks when sharing HRI with different user groups, we performed the Friedman rank sum tests over all participants' responses. The Friedman test is a non-parametric statistical test similar to the parametric repeated measures ANOVA, which is used when the dependent variables are ordinal (e.g., Likert scale outcomes), and where the behaviours of the same sample of subjects are assessed for existing differences under differing conditions. For all HRI categories, the resulted p-values were equal to zero (p&lt;0.05). Therefore, we knew for sure that somewhere in the data, there exist a significant difference between participants' perceived privacy risks when sharing HRI with different user groups. To identify the actual location of the significant difference, the Friedman test was followed with a series of post hoc Wilcoxon tests on each combination of user categories. A separate null hypothesis was assumed for each pair of categories, in which we assumed that there was no significant change in the attitude when sharing every HRI between "select individual(s)" and "select group(s)," "select individual(s)" and "entire contacts," "select individual(s)" and "all other OSN users," and so on for all 6 combinations of user groups. To reduce the chances of obtaining false-positive results (type I errors) when multiple pair-wise tests were performed on a single set of data, we applied the Bonferroni adjustment (α new =0.0083) <ref type="bibr">5</ref> to a series of post hoc Wilcoxon matched pairs tests. The tests resulted no significant difference (p&gt;0.0083) in participants' perceived privacy risks when sharing "Healthy living" and "Useful found information" HRI categories between "entire contacts" and "all other OSN users," as shown in Tables VI and VIII. Moreover, no significant difference was found in participants' perceived privacy risks when sharing "Useful found information" between "select individual(s)" and "select group(s)" <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">(Table VIII)</ref>. For the rest of the pair-wise comparisons, we found significant difference (p&lt;0.0083) in participants' perceived privacy risks <ref type="bibr">5</ref> Considering the Bonferroni adjustment, α is divided by the number of pair-wise combinations in the user categories (αnew=0.05/6). when sharing different HRI categories between different user groups (see <ref type="bibr">Appendix B)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>D. Risk Mitigation and Behavioural Responses</head><p>We examined participants' risk-mitigating behavioural responses with respect to risk avoidance and coping theory <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[18]</ref>. We assumed that participants can avoid privacy risks by not sharing HRI (risks avoidance), while based on their perceived risks and level of control, they can cope with possible privacy threats by means of manipulating the source of the risks (the shared HRI, its recipients, and used OSN). We also assumed that participants were always able to share HRI without taking any preemptive risk-mitigating actions. In general, participants reported a diverse range of behaviours when exposed to different risk levels ("very low or no risks" to "extreme risk"), with 58.4% of participants choosing not to share HRI at extreme risk levels. At "acceptable privacy risk" levels, which appeared 2 nd in the Likert scale right after "very low or no risks," about 50% of participants preferred to cope with privacy threats by manipulating shared HRI and/or filtering its recipients.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>V. DISCUSSION</head><p>Our results contribute to better understanding of HRI practices in OSN, perceived privacy risks and preferred riskmitigating behaviours. We found that most active OSN users (about 96%), who indicated using their OSN account(s) on a daily basis, had shared some HRI in the past. While the majority of participants shared HRI, more than half of them never shared information about their medical health records and HRI of people in their custody. Participants might have never shared such information if they did not have online access to it in the first place. For example, participants might not have access to electronic health records, or simply did not have any dependents or people in their custody, and therefore, never shared their HRI in the OSN. However, results showed that even when sharing with select individuals (trusted individuals), sharing medical health records and information about people in custody were perceived as "high" or "extreme" risks for approximately 30% of participants.</p><p>After performing the Friedman and the post hoc Wilcoxon tests, the effect of "information recipient" and "HRI type and category" factors were clearly observed in increasing perceived privacy risks associated with sharing HRI in OSNs (Section IV-C). As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 4</ref>, for almost all HRI categories, the perceived privacy risks of sharing HRI in OSNs increased toward higher risk levels with respect to the expansion of the recipient base from "select individual(s)" and "select groups(s)" to include more recipients (i.e., "entire contacts" and "all other OSN users"). For "healthy living" and "useful found information" HRI categories, participants expressed their perceived privacy risks with lower granularity, where they indicated sharing HRI among different user group pairs with similar perceived risks <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">(Tables VI and VIII  in Appendix B)</ref>. Therefore, while different recipient groups affected the perceived privacy risk outcomes, different HRI categories were also shown to influence the results of the perceived privacy risks.</p><p>Medical health records may include personally identifiable information along with information that is directly related to an individual and her health, and therefore, participants' concerns regarding sharing such information is justifiable. However, HRI of people in custody has received considerable attention by participants as well. We believe that people handle HRI of other individuals in their custody with extra care and with a sense of responsibility toward protecting them against privacy threats. Moreover, the category "HRI of people in custody" represents an abstract view of all HRI related to a person in custody, including their medical health records. Therefore, participants might have considered an overall risk perception with respect to the most important HRI categories, which is the medical health records of people in their custody, and as a result, indicated high privacy concerns when sharing such HRI.</p><p>We explored risk-mitigating behaviours of participants at different risk levels. We found that even at extreme risk levels, 41.6% of participants shared HRI while minimizing risks using different techniques (manipulate shared HRI, filter recipients, and change used OSN). Furthermore, at "acceptable risk levels," which represents the lowest assumed risk level after "very low or no risks," more than half of participants preferred to mitigate privacy risks by manipulating and filtering shared HRI and its recipients respectively. Meanwhile, 19.3% of participants were extra cautious and preferred to avoid risks by not sharing HRI even at "acceptable risk levels". In 2012, a study of Europeans' perceptions, behaviours, and attitudes toward sharing HRI identified 3 sharing profiles: self-revealing (aware of risks but reveals information to gain benefits), indifferent, and cautious <ref type="bibr">[3]</ref>. We believe that our participants' behaviours could be profiled similarly, classifying participants who shared HRI regardless of the perceived risk levels as "indifferent," whereas "self-revealing" participants are those who were motivated to share their HRI but preferred to minimize risks by adopting available methods, and finally, "cautious" participants, who refused to share HRI under different circumstances.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A. Future Work</head><p>We believe our findings contribute to understanding of OSN users' behaviours and practices in terms of sharing HRI online. However, our survey questions were abstract and did not contain specific scenarios, and therefore, we think that by creating more realistic scenarios for sharing HRI in OSNs, and by placing participants in the context of sharing HRI in OSNs, we can capture users' behaviours in more details, resulting in more accurate findings with respect to risk perceptions and behavioural responses. Finally, prior studies showed that the existence of other factors such as benefits related to sharing HRI, could be considered as a motive for shaping users' perceptions and forming their behaviours, and therefore, we need to incorporate those factors in our scenarios to understand how they may affect users' perceived risks and risk-mitigating behavioural responses.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>VI. LIMITATIONS</head><p>There exist several limitations that relate to the participants and survey questions used in this study. First, the participants have different background, knowledge and HRI sharing experience, and therefore, increasing the subjectivity of their responses in terms of perceived privacy risks and behavioural responses. Second, the answers provided are self-reported and depend on the honesty and knowledge of the participants. Finally, the survey questions were based on the authors' knowledge and understanding of literature. To minimize threats to internal validity, we used an online crowdsourcing tool (CrowdFlower) to recruit MTurk workers, who represent a participant pool with different demographics and knowledge levels, resulting a sample similar or sometimes better than participant samples recruited using conventional methods (emails, flyers, online posts, and ads) <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[29,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">31]</ref>. Our recruited participants were from 39 different states in the US, with ages ranging between 19 and 70 years old, and almost equal male and female ratios. We informed the design of our survey questions and responses by findings from literature <ref type="bibr">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr">[5]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">18]</ref>. Moreover, we provided participants with open-ended response choices to express their answers in their own words when necessary. Finally, the survey was pre-tested and reviewed with a number of colleagues and coworkers with expertise in conducting user studies in order to achieve consistent understanding of the survey questions and the response choices.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A. Generalizability</head><p>Although our participants sample covered most states in the US (39 out of 50), and included participants from various age ranges, education levels, and employment categories, the generalizability (external validity) of our results could be hampered by the limited representativeness of the participants. Also, the majority of the participants represented Facebook users (about 96%), while recent statistics showed that about 67% of online US adults are Facebook users <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>. However, the aim of this study is to explore current users' behaviours and identify future research directions and therefore, results generalizability might not be considered as an outcome of the study. Nevertheless, we can always use commercial services to recruit larger number of participants and achieve a more representative sample of active OSN users.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>VII. CONCLUSION</head><p>Our survey contributes to understanding HRI sharing practices, risk perceptions and risk-mitigating behavioural responses. We quantified the HRI sharing practices in OSNs by showing that 95.8% of OSN users shared some HRI with their social peers. We found that participants were more sensitive toward sharing their medical health records, while considering sharing HRI of people in their custody with extra care. We investigated OSN users' risk-mitigating behaviours and found that some people (indifferent and cautious) tend to follow unique behaviours regardless of perceived risk levels, while others (self-revealing) behaved differently at the presence of variable risk levels.</p><p>While one might think that there are no new findings in our study, we found that previous studies were limited to niche user categories (patients, teenage OSN users, elderly people, etc.), and they did not provide a good understanding about the actual behaviours and concerns of active OSN users in terms of HRI sharing. Therefore, by providing quantitative evidence showing that HRI sharing is in fact a new application of existing OSNs, along with highlighting OSN users' privacy concerns and risk-mitigating behaviours, we are contributing towards building a solid ground for future studies that will address more specific issues regarding OSN users' behaviours and privacy concerns when it comes to sharing HRI. We calculated all p-values after applying a series of post hoc Wilcoxon matched pairs tests on the second question from Appendix A-D. For us to accept the alternative hypothesis, the p-value has to be less than the Bonferroni adjusted critical value, which in this instance is 0.0083. For the sake of simplicity, we only include tables that contain non-zero entries.      Entire contacts --------0.0018</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B. Questions About OSN Usage</head><p>All other OSN users ------------</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Fig. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1. Participants distribution among 39 states.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Fig. 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Fig. 3. Frequency of sharing HRI in OSNs.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 for details.</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2 for details. Out of the 140 participants who reported using their OSN account(s) every day, 135 (96.4%) were active Facebook users. We also asked about the preferred device for connecting to each OSN account (PC/Laptop, Tablet, or Smartphone). About 70% preferred to use a PC/Laptop and approximately 24% used their smartphones.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Fig. 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Fig. 4. Perceived privacy risks when sharing HRI with different user categories.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>TABLE I HRI CATEGORIES AND EXAMPLES.</head><label>I</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Category 
HRI Examples 

Healthy living 

dietary and healthy eating, physical exercise, 
mental exercise, emotional exercise, environ-
mental hazards 

Own experience 

experience with: previous surgeries, treatments 
and their side effects, symptoms, specific doctor 
or medical institute, health insurance companies 
and plans 
Useful found in-
formation 
books, articles, websites 

Mental and emo-
tional health con-
ditions 

sad, stressed, happy, excited, depressed, mental 
disorder 

Physical health 
conditions 

sick, injured, not feeling good, in good shape, 
tired 

Medical health 
records 

personal information and address, physician and 
medical institute information, insurance related 
information, x-rays, reports, appointments and 
schedule 

Experience 
of 
somebody else 

experience with: previous surgeries, treatments 
and their side effects, symptoms, specific doctor 
or medical institute, health insurance companies 
and plans 
HRI of people in 
your custody 
parents, children, and others 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table I .</head><label>I</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>To triangulate his categorization, we 
used an online card sorting tool OptimalSort 4 to run a closed 
card sorting exercise, where we asked 11 participants, mostly 
friends and colleagues, to group different HRI examples 
into predefined 8 categories. Seven participants grouped the 
majority of the HRI examples into categories similar to our 
predefined ones. 

IV. RESULTS 

On April 4th, 2013, 191 people successfully completed 
our survey. Overall, the vast majority of the participants 
have shared some HRI through their OSN accounts. While 
participants showed more concerns regarding the shared HRI 
type and its recipient(s), they adopted variable behavioural 
responses to mitigate different levels of risk. In this section, 
we first report participant demographics and their OSN usage 
specifications. Then, we present results concerning active OSN 
users' HRI sharing practices, regularity, and reasons. Next, we 
present participants' perceived privacy risks when sharing HRI 
with different users. Finally, we report participants' preferred 
behavioural responses when sensing different privacy risk 
levels. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>TABLE II PARTICIPANT DEMOGRAPHICS (166 ACTIVE OSN USERS FROM THE US).</head><label>II</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Gender 
49.4% 
Male 
50.6% 
Female 

Age 

All 
19-70 (µ=30.4, σ=10, median=28) 
59.0% 
19-29 
24.7% 
30-39 
8.4% 
40-49 
7.9% 
50+ 

Completed 
education 

25.3% 
high school 
12.7% 
post-secondary diploma 
39.8% 
undergraduate degree 
6.6% 
community college 
10.2% 
graduate degree (PhD or Masters) 
5.4% 
other 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>TABLE III HRI CATEGORIES AND % OF PARTICIPANTS WHO NEVER SHARED HRI FROM EACH CATEGORY. THE THIRD COLUMN REPRESENTS THE MEDIAN RANKING FROM THE LIKERT SCALE</head><label>III</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>HRI categories 
Participants Median 
Medical health records 
63.3% 
1 
HRI of people in your custody 
54.8% 
1 
Experience of somebody else 
41.6% 
2 
Own Experience 
21.1% 
3 
Mental and emotional health conditions 
20.5% 
3 
Physical health conditions 
16.3% 
3 
Healthy living 
15.7% 
3 
Useful found information 
9.0% 
3 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>TABLE IV REASONS FOR SHARING HRI ONLINE.</head><label>IV</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Reasons for sharing HRI 
Participants 
Help others by sharing personal experience and 
knowledge 
66.9% 

Seek help or social support 
51.8% 
Get benefits by receiving useful feedback from on-
line contacts 
48.2% 

Seek online interactions and make discussions 
44.0% 
Alleviate anxiety (sharing HRI makes me feel better 
and less stressed) 
38.6% 

Promote healthy living 
37.3% 
Other reasons 
6.6% 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7" validated="false"><head>TABLE V REASONS AGAINST SHARING HRI ONLINE.</head><label>V</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Reasons against sharing HRI 
Participants 
I have different people in my online contact list and 
I prefer not to share my HRI with all of them 
49.4% 

My HRI is personal and I do not share it with anyone 
43.4% 
I do not want to be treated as "the sick" person by 
my online contacts 
39.2% 

I do not want my online contacts to worry about me 
by receiving bad news about my health 
34.9% 

I do not want my online contacts to know about my 
HRI 
34.9% 

I prefer to share my HRI with my doctor 
30.1% 
I prefer to share my HRI offline 
22.3% 
My online contacts are not interested in my HRI 
20.5% 
Other reasons 
4.8% 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9" validated="false"><head>TABLE VI HEALTHY LIVING: P-VALUES FOR DIFFERENT RECIPIENT COMPARISONS.</head><label>VI</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10" validated="false"><head>TABLE VII OWN EXPERIENCE: P-VALUES FOR DIFFERENT RECIPIENT COMPARISONS.</head><label>VII</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> We define HRI as any type of information that is related to the health of an individual or people within her social network.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> Problem-focused coping occurs when an individual minimizes the perceived threats by targeting the source of the threat (e.g., using fake names when registering for an online service). Emotion-focused coping happens when an individual mitigates the perceived threats by underestimating the negative outcomes associated with it (e.g., thinking of the gained benefits instead of perceived threats).</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> We administered the survey on Enterprise Feedback Management (EFM), a Canadian-hosted survey solution complying with the Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act of British Columbia, where our university is located. This enterprise-level survey tool is web-based and is a comparable alternative to the US-based Survey Monkey.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS</head><p>We would like to thank all LERSSE members (Yazan Boshmaf, Pooya Jaferian, Hootan Rashtian, SanTsai Sun and Ildar Muslukhov) for their kind help, advice and feedback. We also would like to thank Hyoungshick Kim for his guidance and feedback during early stages of the project. This research is partially supported through funding from the NSERC Internetworked Systems Security Network (ISSNet).</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sizing up peers: Adolescent girls&apos; weight control and social comparison in the school context</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Mueller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Pearson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Turner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Health and Social Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="64" to="78" />
			<date type="published" when="2010-03" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Individual-versus group-based financial incentives for weight loss: A randomized, controlled trial</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Kullgren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Troxel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Loewenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Asch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Norton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Wesby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Tao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Volpp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">10.7326/0003-4819-158-7-201304020-00002</idno>
		<ptr target="+http://dx.doi.org/10.7326/0003-4819-158-7-201304020-00002" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annals of Internal Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">158</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="505" to="514" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Healthrelated information as personal data in Europe: Results from a representative survey in Eu27</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Lupiáñez-Villanueva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Lusoli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Bacigalupo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Maghiros</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Andrade</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Codagnone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Medicine 2.0: Ethical and legal issues. confidentiality and privacy</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Patient interest in sharing personal health record information: A web-based survey</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Zulman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Nazi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Turvey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Wagner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Woods</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>An</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">doi.org/10.1059/0003-4819-155-12-201112200-00002</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annals of Internal Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">155</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="805" to="810" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Sharing by design: Understanding and supporting personal health information sharing and collaboration within social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Skeels</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Washington</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Ph.D. dissertation</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The social life of health information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Fox</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Pew Research Center Report</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011-05" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Pew Research Center&apos;s Internet and American Life Project</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Fox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Duggan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013-01" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Health online 2013</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring Privacy Risk in Online Social Networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Becker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of W2SP 2009: Web 2.0 Security and Privacy</title>
		<meeting>W2SP 2009: Web 2.0 Security and Privacy</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009-05" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the leakage of personally identifiable information via online social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Krishnamurthy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Wills</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">WOSN &apos;09: Proceedings of the 2nd ACM Workshop on Online Social Networks</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7" to="12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">you might also like:&quot; privacy risks of collaborative filtering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Calandrino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kilzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Narayanan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Felten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Shmatikov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">10.1109/SP.2011.40</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/SP.2011.40" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2011 IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy, ser. SP &apos;11</title>
		<meeting>the 2011 IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy, ser. SP &apos;11<address><addrLine>Washington, DC, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE Computer Society</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="231" to="246" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information revelation and privacy in online social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Gross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Acquisti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">10.1145/1102199.1102214</idno>
		<ptr target="http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1102199.1102214" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2005 ACM Workshop on Privacy in the Electronic Society, ser. WPES &apos;05</title>
		<meeting>the 2005 ACM Workshop on Privacy in the Electronic Society, ser. WPES &apos;05<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="71" to="80" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Privacy and social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Eecke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Truyens</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computer Law and amp; Security Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="535" to="546" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The privacy risks of sharing health info online</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Campbell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>Reputation.com</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Of codes, genomes, and electronic health records: It&apos;s only sensitive if it hurts when you touch it</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Masys</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Usenix HealthSec Workshop</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012-08" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">How much of your personal health information should be online</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Mcgowan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.theatlantic.com/health/archive/2012/03/howmuchofyourpersonalhealthinformationshouldbeonline/254375/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social networking applications in health care: threats to the privacy and security of health information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2010 ICSE Workshop on Software Engineering in Health Care, ser. SEHC &apos;10</title>
		<meeting>the 2010 ICSE Workshop on Software Engineering in Health Care, ser. SEHC &apos;10<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="39" to="49" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="doi">10.1145/1809085.1809091</idno>
		<ptr target="http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1809085.1809091" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">not all my friends need to know&quot;: a qualitative study of teenage patients, privacy, and social media</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Velden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">El</forename><surname>Emam</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the American Medical Informatics Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="16" to="24" />
			<date type="published" when="2012-07" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Understanding the information privacyrelated perceptions and behaviors of an online social network user</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bulgurcu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012-08" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of British Columbia</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Ph.D. dissertation</note>
	<note>The Faculty of Graduate Studies, Business Administration</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">How U.S. moms share and spread HEALTH information</title>
		<ptr target="www.lucidmarketing.com" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Amazon Mechanical Turk</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.mturk.com/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The environment and social behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Altman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
			<pubPlace>Brooks/Cole Monterey, CA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Privacy regulation: culturally universal or culturally specific?</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Social Issues</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="66" to="84" />
			<date type="published" when="1977" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unpacking &quot;privacy&quot; for a networked world</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Palen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Dourish</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CHI &apos;03: Proceedings of the SIGCHI conference on Human factors in computing systems</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="129" to="136" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Fifty Years of the Research and Theory of RS Lazarus: An Analysis of Historical and Perennial Issues</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Lazarus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="366" to="388" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Coping theory and research: Past, present, and future</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Communicating the experience of chronic pain and illness through blogging</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Ressler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Bradshaw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Gualtieri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Chui</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Medical Internet Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">143</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sharing is caring, but not error free: Transparency of granular controls for sharing personal health information in social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Hartzler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Skeels</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mukai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Powell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Klasnja</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Pratt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">AMIA Annual Symposium</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="559" to="568" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Access to the medical record for patients and involved providers: Transparency through electronic tools</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Feeley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Shine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>1059/ 0003-4819-155-12-201112200-00010</idno>
		<ptr target="+http://dx.doi.org/10" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annals of Internal Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">155</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="853" to="854" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">CrowdFlower</title>
		<ptr target="www.crowdflower.com" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How does your password measure up? the effect of strength meters on password creation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Ur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Kelley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Komanduri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Maass</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Mazurek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Passaro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Shay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Vidas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Bauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. USENIX Security</title>
		<meeting>USENIX Security</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Health topics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Fox</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Pew Research Center Report</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluating online labor markets for experimental research: Amazon. com&apos;s mechanical turk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Berinsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Huber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Lenz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">APPENDIX A SURVEY QUESTIONS A. Questions About Participants&apos; Demographics 1) Gender: • Male • Female</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="351" to="368" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Political Analysis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">How old are you? (19 to 99) years old</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">What is your highest level of completed education? • Less than high school • High school (secondary school) • Diploma (post-secondary courses) • Undergraduate university degree (Bachelor&apos;s) • Graduate university degree</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>Masters&apos;s or PhD</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">• Community college or professional school (College degree)</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">•</forename><surname>Other</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>please specify</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">• A range of employment categories</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>or • Other. please specify</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Current country of residence? • Select from list, or • Other</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>please specify</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
