<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/atharsefid/Desktop/grobid-0.5.3/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.3" ident="GROBID" when="2020-09-29T02:54+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Lucky scheduling for energy-efficient heterogeneous multi-core systems</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vinicius</forename><surname>Petrucci</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Universidade Federal Fluminense</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="BR">Brazil</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Orlando</forename><surname>Loques</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Universidade Federal Fluminense</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="BR">Brazil</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Mossé</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Pittsburgh</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Lucky scheduling for energy-efficient heterogeneous multi-core systems</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Heterogeneous multi-core processors with big/high-performance and small/low-power cores have been proposed as an alternative design to improve energy efficiency over traditional homogeneous multi-cores. We make the case for proportional-share scheduling of threads in heterogeneous processor cores aimed at improving combined energy efficiency and performance. Our thread scheduling algorithm, lucky, is based on lottery scheduling and has been implemented using Linux performance monitoring and thread-to-core affinity capabilities at user-level. Our preliminary results show that lucky scheduling can provide better performance and energy savings over state-of-the-art heterogeneous-aware scheduling techniques.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Motivation &amp; background</head><p>Heterogeneous (or asymmetric) multi-core processors have been proposed as an alternative design to traditional homogeneous multi-cores to improve energy efficiency <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>. Such a heterogeneous platform includes cores with same ISA (instruction set architecture) but different power and performance characteristics. Recent research has shown that two types of cores (big high-performance vs small lowpower) are able to capture most of the power/performance benefits from core heterogeneity while running typical workloads <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">6,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">7]</ref>.</p><p>Having different core types in a multi-core system opens up new challenges and possibilities for power/energy management, thread scheduling and load balancing. Improvements in energy efficiency and performance can be achieved by allowing each thread to run on the core type (big or small) that is best suited for it. Thread-to-core assignment decisions leverage runtime observation of computeintensive vs memory-intensive execution phases of the threads <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">8]</ref>. An optimal energy-efficient thread assignment has to match the thread demands with the capabilities of the heterogeneous cores. We argue that, in addition to satisfying the threads' computational demands, thread scheduling has to provide fair allocation of the platform resources to the threads over time. Previous works have proposed taking advantage of performance counters provided by the hardware to determine the characteristics for the running threads and schedule them on the right core type <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">14]</ref>. To make thread scheduling decisions, these scheduling techniques calculate the thread bias through measuring either compute-intensity (IPC or IPS, instructions per cycle or per second) <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">8]</ref> or memory intensity (e.g., LLC miss rate) <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">12]</ref> which determines the thread execution efficiency between the core types. The intuition is that a thread with a high IPS ratio or low-memory intensity bias is expected to take best advantage of a big core rather than a small core.</p><p>Most of those scheduling algorithms <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">13]</ref> are unfair by design since they assign to big cores the threads that experience the highest bias towards those cores. As such, some threads can monopolize the available big cores and hinder the progress of other threads. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> shows the results of an experiment where one memory-intensive and three compute-intensive threads were running on a quadcore multi-core system with one big core and three small cores (Section 2 describes our experimental setup).</p><p>For this particular workload <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 1</ref>), we can observe a performance speedup of 1.47 times (energy consumption reduction of 37%) over running bias scheduling <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref> by simply providing equally fair sharing of the big core among all threads (25% for each thread). Using bias scheduling, the highest compute-intensive thread had possession of  <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Power and performance measures of heterogeneous cores the big core 96% of the workload execution time, leading to severe performance degradation of the other computeintensive threads. The workload execution time for each scheduling algorithm is the elapsed time of the last completed thread.</p><p>In this paper we make the case for proportional-share scheduling of threads to heterogeneous processor cores aimed at improving combined energy efficiency and performance. Our thread scheduling algorithm, lucky, is based on abstraction and mechanism of lottery scheduling <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref> to provide energy-aware proportional-share of the available big/small cores in the system. The running threads are given some number of tickets derived from runtime performance monitoring. The given tickets of a thread corresponds to its energy efficiency estimate and determine relative chance of all of the other threads competing for the available big cores.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Performance-asymmetric core system</head><p>We consider a multi-core system having the following core types: big/fast cores targeted for high-performance and small/slow cores optimized for low-power. Such a system with two distinct types of cores is able to capture most of the benefits from heterogeneity <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">6]</ref>.</p><p>We use the following performance-asymmetric multicore system in our experiments: a quad-core x86 64 chip capable of individual core frequency scaling where one core runs at 3.2Ghz and the other three cores run at 0.8Ghz. We consider that the die area of a big core is equivalent to three small cores (3:1 ratio) <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>. All cores share a L3 (last level) cache of 6MB and off-chip memory subsystem of 8GB. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> describes the power and performance characteristics of the heterogeneous cores in the system. Performance (capacity) of a core is defined as follows. We measured the highest thread IPC, by running the SPEC CPU benchmarks one thread at a time. Multiplying this number by the clock speed, we find out how many instructions can be executed in one second. We use MIPS (million instructions per second) as the measure of core computational capacity/performance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Core power/performance measures</head><p>Since our multi-core system includes identical cores only differing in clock frequency, we estimate core power consumption based on measurements <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref> of a heterogeneous platform configuration composed of typical big (Intel Xeon) and small (Intel Atom) cores <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. In our multi-core system model, a big core delivers 4-fold performance but a small core is 2.2 times more power-efficient (i.e., MIPS per Watt). A small core consumes on average much less power than a big core and is also attractive in terms of the performance obtained in proportion to the power consumed (power-peformance proportionality). This is because of its very low idle power (0.7W ) and wide dynamic power range between idle and peak power (0.7W to 2.15W ).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Thread performance characterization</head><p>We use Linux 2.6.34 kernel with perf monitoring tool to gather hardware performance events namely retired instructions and L3 cache misses in order to characterize the behavior of a thread execution in the multi-core system. We measure LLC misses per core since a LLC event is an event shared across all cores in the system <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. To individualize per core measures, we set up the Linux perf tool to read the 4E1 (L3 Cache Misses) raw register with different core selection masks.</p><p>Each core runs a separate thread and thus we monitor the performance counters for a given core (thread) for a given monitoring interval. Given these counters, we compute the MIPS (million instructions per second) to determine the CPU demands of a thread. Similarly, we obtain the number of LLC misses per second, LLCMS, to characterize memory demands, where each LLC miss represents an off-chip memory request.</p><p>We use real performance measurements when a thread is running on the same core type, and assume the next scheduling interval can be approximated by the current interval. To obtain the performance values of a thread running on different core types, previous works <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">8]</ref> require each thread to run on every core type. As noticed in <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref>, such a direct IPS measurement on different core types poses many practical issues and incurs much overhead. In contrast to those works, we use the equation MIPS j,k = α j · MIPS i,k + β j · LLCMS i,k + γ j to estimate the performance behavior of a thread k currently running on a given core type i when it is assigned to a different core type j in the next scheduling interval.</p><p>The linear regression model above is key to determine the energy efficiency (MIPS 2 /Watt) of a thread between big and small cores, as introduced in Section 3. The regression coefficients α j , β j and γ j are derived from offline performance data collected running programs from the SPEC 2006 benchmark suite (shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>) individually on each core type j. Running the method of least squares to <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>: Energy-efficiency ratio (big-to-small core) of threads when running on different core types the performance data yielded a coefficient correlation of approximately 98%. Note that such a performance characterization needs to be done only once at design stage. Given a set of representative workloads intended to run on the multi-core system, there is no need to recalibrate the parameters of the prediction model. Nevertheless, when substantial changes are observed in the behavior of the workloads, better results can be obtained by updating the coefficients of the prediction model or determining the coefficients online.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Lucky scheduling</head><p>Lucky scheduling carries out thread assignment to heterogeneous cores for optimized performance and energy savings. The assignment of threads to cores are periodic (reassignment interval) to cope with thread execution phase changes. Lucky scheduling builds on the concepts and mechanism from the lottery scheduler <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref> to implement such a dynamic scheduling strategy.</p><p>The novelty of lucky is in how the ticket assignment is done in the scheduling algorithm. Each thread receives a dynamic number of tickets which is determined by the energy efficiency ratio between running the thread on a big core vs small core.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Energy efficiency metric</head><p>The goal of the metric used by lucky scheduling to guide thread assignment decisions is to minimize the energy-delay product per instruction given by Watt/MIPS 2 , which can be rewritten as (Watt × S × S)/I 2 = (Energy × Delay)/I 2 . Thus lucky scheduling aims to minimize both the energy and the amount of time required to execute thread instructions <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. In fact, we maximize the inverse of the energydelay product, given by MIPS 2 /Watt, to facilitate the computation of the energy efficiency ratio between big and small cores. <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> shows a comparison of the energy efficiency ratio between big and small cores when running the CPU SPEC 2006 benchmarks on different core types. We can observe that the energy efficiency varies over different programs and can be used for guiding dynamic thread assignment decisions. Although not shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>, similar behavior exists for different execution phases of programs <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>. That is, some threads go through compute-intensive or memory-intensive phases where the MIPS 2 /Watt changes during the course of their executions <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>. We use this information to periodically reassign the running threads to big or small cores in an energy-efficient manner.</p><p>Looking at <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>, we observe that the zeusmp benchmark should run on a big core, whereas astar is best suited on a small core to improve energy efficiency. Bias scheduling <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>, for example, would map both programs on a small core type since both experience high memory stalls, about 14 million LLCMS. A typical compute-intensive thread has 1-2 million LLCMS. We also noted that bwaves is an instance of benchmark that bias scheduling would run it on a small core because of its high memory-intensive (29 millions of LLCMS). However, bwaves is best suited for a big core to improve energy efficiency.</p><p>The observations above indicate that explicitly taking into account the core power consumption in thread scheduling can improve energy-efficient scheduling decisions. Furthermore, different power/performance ratios can be observed in the design of heterogeneous multi-core systems. This makes it much more challenging to derive energyefficient thread assignment decisions based only on either computational demands (MIPS) <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">8]</ref> or memory stalls (LLC misses) <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">12]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Algorithm outline</head><p>We introduce the following notation for the heterogeneous multi-core system. Let N be the set of core types, N i be the set of cores of type i ∈ N, and M be the set of all available cores; that is M = N 1 ∪ N 2 ∪ . . . N n , where n = |N|. Each core of type i ∈ N has same computational capacity C i (million instructions per second) and peak/busy power B i and static/idle power I i (Watts).</p><p>Let K be the set of threads to run in the system. Each thread k ∈ K requires computational execution rate MIPS i,k and memory access rate LLCMS i,k when executing on core type i ∈ N. We estimate thread power consumption as P i,k = (B i − I i ) · (MIPS i,k / C i ) + I i , when thread k runs on a core of type i. We estimate the energy consumption (in Joules) as E = ∑ k∈K P k · S, given the configuration of each thread allocated to a core type in a given scheduling interval S (in seconds). The energy efficiency of a thread-to-core assignment is energy e f f iciency(i, k) = MIPS 2 i,k / P i,k in a given scheduling interval.</p><p>In lucky scheduling, the ticket allocation of a thread k ∈ K is determined periodically by its energy efficiency ratio between two types of cores: big and small cores (where N = {big, small}). A given thread is expected to run on a big vs small core proportionally to the number of tickets it holds. More precisely, allocating more tickets to a thread gives it a higher priority to run on a big core. This allows to adjust dynamically the priority of a given thread currently running on a small core to move to a big core, thereby reducing unfairness and improving overall performance in the system. The activity of always exchanging two running threads between different core types help preserve load balancing.</p><p>The initial thread assignment is given by the underlying operating system (OS) scheduler. Typically the OS assigns each thread to a core so that the workload is balanced across the available cores in the system. The algorithm of lucky scheduling is outlined as follows:</p><p>1. Measure MIPS i,k and LLCMS i,k of each thread k ∈ K running on a core of type i ∈ N and predict MIPS j,k on the other core of type j ∈ N − {i} (see Section 2.2)</p><p>2. Evaluate big core bene f it(k) = energy e f f iciency(b,k) energy e f f iciency(s,k) for each thread k, big core b, and small core s 3. Generate a number of tickets(k) = 100 · big core bene f it(k) to assign for each thread k 4. Determine winning ticket as a random number uniformly distributed between [0, total tickets) where total tickets = ∑ k∈K tickets(k)</p><p>5. Let T be the thread that holds winning ticket and F be the least-loaded big core in the system 6. If T is not running on a big core then swap thread T with a thread T that is running on F and has the minimum number of tickets</p><p>We exploit a lottery-based approach to implement lucky scheduling because of the simplicity of its implementation along with the flexibility when including/removing threads in the system. The current implementation of lucky scheduling uses a list data structure to keep threads updated with their current number of tickets and a global variable to track the sum of threads' tickets. The random number generator implemented in C++ standard library is used to select the winning ticket/thread.</p><p>Since the number of core types is small and fixed, the algorithm complexity is O(m) where m is the number of threads, because it is dominated by searching for a thread with winning ticket. For future many-core systems with hundreds or thousands of cores, a more efficient implementation using balanced tree or heap structures could reduce the complexity to O(log m) <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Preliminary results</head><p>We evaluate the performance and energy consumption of lucky scheduling against the heterogeneous-aware fair <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>: Improvements of lucky scheduling over bias scheduling and big core fair policy share policy <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref> and bias scheduling <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref> using a mix of thread workloads. The fair share algorithm allocates the big core among threads in a round robin fashion. For the bias scheduling, we compute bias k = LLCMS i,k / MIPS i,k for each thread k running on a core of type i. Threads with the lowest bias are mapped to the available big cores, whereas the highest bias are mapped to small cores.</p><p>Binding threads to cores of the same type is done via sched setaffinity system call. The Linux scheduler thus makes scheduling decisions respecting this affinity. The reassignment interval is set up to 200ms which approximately corresponds to the Linux load balancing granularity, responsible for migrating threads among cores to maximize system utilization <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref>. We found this interval suitable to capture thread phase changes while helping mitigate thread migration overhead and cold-cache effect.</p><p>The SPEC 2006 benchmark suite was used as the workload on the system. Each SPEC benchmark program is considered a thread in the system and the number of threads is equal to the sum of cores <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>. The benchmarks were selected to test a variety of CPU and memory requirements which are composed of 4-threads mixture varying from compute-intensive (4CI) to memory-intensive (4MI) workloads <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref>. The workload 4P represent benchmarks that exhibit different phases and workloads 4R1, and 4R2 are random combinations of threads.</p><p>The experiment ends when each thread has run at least once; that is, until the longest thread finishes, also known as makespan in the literature. While the longest thread is not finished, the other threads restart their executions as soon as they are finished. We measure the execution time (wall clock) of a workload by calling Linux gettimeofday system call at the start and end of the workload execution. We estimate the energy consumption of the running threads in a workload using the formula from Section 3.2. We multiply the sum of estimated energy consumption of all threads executed in the system by the workload execution time to derive the energy delay product (EDP). <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref> shows an experiment to demonstrate that inherently unfair thread scheduling leads to more performance loss than improvement for the given mixed set of workloads. When considering all workloads executions, a simple big core fair policy provides EDP gains of 16% over bias scheduling. Beyond that, lucky scheduling outperforms big core fair policy in EDP by 12% (avg.) and 20% (max.). This indicates that energy-efficient proportional-share brings higher performance/energy improvements rather than simply providing equally fair sharing of the big core among all threads. Lucky scheduling achieved better EDP when compared to bias scheduling over all workloads executions (avg. 39% and max. 51%).</p><p>The big core fair policy outperformed lucky scheduling in EDP by 4% in the workload 3CI-1MI and 12% in the workload 4MI. This highlights that more biased/unfair decisions can negatively affect the energy and performance for some workloads. Nevertheless, we show that lucky scheduling was able to provide adequate balance between fairness and core execution bias/efficiency in most cases. Although these results are encouraging, further experiments are required to broaden our understanding of such bias/fairness trade-off decisions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusions &amp; future directions</head><p>Energy-efficient heterogeneous multi-core systems pose challenging scheduling problems. In this paper we advocated a proportional-share scheduling strategy based on lottery/ticket mechanisms that optimizes for combined performance and energy savings. We proposed a simple and effective way to determine ticket/thread assignment by estimating thread performance and energy efficiency between core types in the system. Lucky scheduling has shown energy savings and performance improvements over state-of-theart thread assignment schemes designed for heterogeneous multi-core systems.</p><p>Adapting lucky scheduling to support multi-threaded benchmarks and addressing other types of core heterogeneity (e.g., micro-architectural differences) are interesting research directions. To help minimize migration overhead and preserve cache affinity, we may exploit ticket inflation to allocate additional tickets to the threads that are already running on a big core, giving more chances to keep those threads running on the same type of core. Sensitivity analysis is needed to determine the best parameter for the ticket inflation and which workloads would benefit from such a scheduling adjustment.</p><p>Migrating specific threads between cores with different processing capabilities can also cause performance variability due to contention in the shared resources (lastlevel cache, memory controller/bus) <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref>. Extending lucky scheduling to incorporate resource contention awareness to cater to both computational and memory measures in the ticket estimate/assignment is an interesting avenue for future work.</p><p>Exploring thread consolidation may provide additional energy-savings by maximizing the utilization of a set of active cores and quickly powering down idle cores, bringing them up when thread workloads increase. This would require a better prediction model that incorporates the performance degradation of co-running threads in the system to make effective thread allocation decisions. This would be important when deciding where to allocate a given set of threads that would provide optimized energy efficiency and incur the least performance slowdown.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Performance comparison between bias scheduling and big core fair sharing</figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic thread assignment on heterogeneous multiprocessor architectures</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Becchi</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Crowley</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Computing frontiers</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">User-level scheduling on numa multicore systems under linux</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Blagodurov</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fedorova</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Linux Symposium</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Power-aware microarchitecture: Design and modeling challenges for next-generation microprocessors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brooks</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Al</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Micro</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="26" to="44" />
			<date type="published" when="2000-11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">QuickIA: Exploring heterogeneous architectures on real prototypes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chitlur</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Al</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">12</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Maximizing power efficiency with asymmetric multicore systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fedorova</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Saez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Shelepov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prieto</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Commun. ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009-12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Greenhalgh</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Big</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">LITTLE processing with ARM CortexTM-A15 and Cortex-A7. White Paper</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bias scheduling in heterogeneous multi-core architectures</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Koufaty</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Reddy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hahn</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EuroSys&apos;10</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Single-ISA heterogeneous multi-core architectures: The potential for processor power reduction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kumar</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Farkas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Jouppi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Ranganathan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tullsen</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page">36</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A study on linux kernel scheduler version 2.6.32</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.scribd.com/thangmle/d/24111564-Project-Linux-Scheduler-2-6-32" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Contention aware execution: online contention detection and response</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mars</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Vachharajani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Hundt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Soffa</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CGO &apos;10</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Web search using mobile cores: quantifying and mitigating the price of efficiency</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Reddi</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Al</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ISCA &apos;10</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Leveraging workload diversity through os scheduling to maximize performance on single-isa heterogeneous multicore systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Saez</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Shelepov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Fedorova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prieto</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Parallel Distrib. Comput</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="114" to="131" />
			<date type="published" when="2011-01" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">HASS: a scheduler for heterogeneous multicore systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shelepov</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Saez Alcaide</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffery</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Fedorova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Perez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Blagodurov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kumar</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">SIGOPS Oper. Syst. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009-04" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient interaction between os and architecture in heterogeneous platforms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Srinivasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Illikkal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>And Iyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">SIGOPS Oper. Syst. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lottery scheduling: flexible proportional-share resource management</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Waldspurger</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Weihl</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">OSDI &apos;94</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
