<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/atharsefid/Desktop/grobid-0.5.3/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.3" ident="GROBID" when="2020-09-29T02:56+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Openly Addressable Device Tiers</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>05/18/2017</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>Seagate, LLC.</roleName><forename type="first">Andy</forename><surname>Kowles</surname></persName>
							<email>andrew.kowles@seagate.com</email>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Openly Addressable Device Tiers</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published">05/18/2017</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>Hot Storage 2017 WACI Session</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 1: Shadow Addressing and Capacity</head><p>Using the simple shadow addressing, device vendors expose their investments in nonvolatile media tiers which might include a Disk Cache or NVM/SCM. Competitive advantage can be gained by device consumers by accessing these device tiers in more efficient ways specific to their unique operational profiles. In <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>, a batch of metadata updates can be send to the disk cache. After the velocity of metadata updates slows, the most recent copy is addressed to the Main Store (MS).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 2: Using OATs to Reduce System Metadata Effects on HDD bandwidth</head><p>In this use case example, a system NAND tier is less necessary because the HDDs can absorb and service metadata IOs faster, with less total disk bandwidth and work amplification. Also note that the MC is not subject to durability issues. The final write(s) to MS cause the MC space to be freed and available for reuse.</p><p>Significantly, in another use case example, file systems (or other software) gain rollback capability of one revision for any block which is addressed to Media Cache. Also significantly, the overprovisioned disk media may be located at the OD of the disk for maximum data rate and minimum access time, or at any other radius, for example in the highest reliability area. Can low level storage software take advantage of a small but fast and reliable area of the disk or a collection of disks? Can an application be loaded more quickly from disk if it's pre-cached in MC?</p><p>Many more details and options for such open addressing, including several more use cases for DM-SMR and HA-SMR will be explored during the presentation and in subsequent work.</p></div>		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl/>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
