<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/atharsefid/Desktop/grobid-0.5.3/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.3" ident="GROBID" when="2020-09-29T03:03+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">HotRestore: A Fast Restore System for Virtual Machine Cluster HotRestore: A Fast Restore System for Virtual Machine Cluster</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lei</forename><surname>Cui</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">State Key Laboratory of Software Development Environment Beihang University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beihang University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jianxin</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">State Key Laboratory of Software Development Environment Beihang University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beihang University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tianyu</forename><surname>Wo</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">State Key Laboratory of Software Development Environment Beihang University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beihang University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bo</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">State Key Laboratory of Software Development Environment Beihang University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beihang University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Renyu</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">State Key Laboratory of Software Development Environment Beihang University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beihang University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yingjie</forename><surname>Cao</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">State Key Laboratory of Software Development Environment Beihang University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beihang University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jinpeng</forename><surname>Huai</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">State Key Laboratory of Software Development Environment Beihang University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beihang University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lei</forename><surname>Cui</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">State Key Laboratory of Software Development Environment Beihang University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beihang University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jianxin</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">State Key Laboratory of Software Development Environment Beihang University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beihang University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tianyu</forename><surname>Wo</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">State Key Laboratory of Software Development Environment Beihang University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beihang University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bo</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">State Key Laboratory of Software Development Environment Beihang University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beihang University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Renyu</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">State Key Laboratory of Software Development Environment Beihang University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beihang University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yingjie</forename><surname>Cao</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">State Key Laboratory of Software Development Environment Beihang University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beihang University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jinpeng</forename><surname>Huai</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">State Key Laboratory of Software Development Environment Beihang University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beihang University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">HotRestore: A Fast Restore System for Virtual Machine Cluster HotRestore: A Fast Restore System for Virtual Machine Cluster</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">USENIX Association 28th Large Installation System Administration Conference</title>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
							<biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>This paper is included in the Proceedings of the 28th Large Installation System Administration Conference (LISA14). November 9-14, 2014 • Seattle, WA Open access to the Proceedings of the 28th Large Installation System Administration Conference (LISA14) is sponsored by USENIX</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>A common way for virtual machine cluster (VMC) to tolerate failures is to create distributed snapshot and then restore from the snapshot upon failure. However, restoring the whole VMC suffers from long restore latency due to large snapshot files. Besides, different latencies would lead to discrepancies in start time among the virtual machines. The prior started virtual machine (VM) thus cannot communicate with the VM that is still restoring, consequently leading to the TCP backoff problem. In this paper, we present a novel restore approach called HotRestore, which restores the VMC rapidly without compromising performance. Firstly, HotRestore restores a single VM through an elastic working set which prefetches the working set in a scalable window size, thereby reducing the restore latency. Second, HotRe-store constructs the communication-induced restore dependency graph, and then schedules the restore line to mitigate the TCP backoff problem. Lastly, a restore protocol is proposed to minimize the backoff duration. In addition, a prototype has been implemented on QE-MU/KVM. The experimental results demonstrate that HotRestore can restore the VMC within a few seconds whilst reducing the TCP backoff duration to merely dozens of milliseconds.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Machine virtualization is now widely used in datacenters and this has led to lots of changes to distributed applications within virtualized environments. In particular, the distributed applications are now encapsulated into virtual machine cluster (VMC) which provides an isolated and scaled computing paradigm <ref type="bibr">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">24,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">22]</ref>. However, failures increasingly become the norm rather than the exception in large scale data centers <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[17,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">35]</ref>. The variety of unpredictable failures might cause VM crash or network interruption, and further lead to the unavailability of applications running inside the VMC. There are many approaches for reliability enhancement in virtualized environment. Snapshot/restore <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[25,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">39,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">40,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">37]</ref> is the most widely used one among them. It saves the running state of the applications periodically during the failure-free execution. Upon a failure, the system can restore the computation from a recorded intermediate state rather than the initial state, thereby significantly reducing the amount of lost computation. This feature enables the system administrators to recover the system and immediately regain the full capacity in the face of failures.</p><p>In the past decades, several methods have been proposed to create distributed snapshot of VMC, and most of them aim to guarantee the global consistency whilst reducing the overhead such as downtime, snapshot size, duration, etc <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">25,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">14]</ref>. However, restoring the VM-C has received less attention probably because restoration is only required upon failures. As a matter of fact, due to the frequently occurring failures in large scale data centers, restoration becomes frequent events accordingly <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[35]</ref>. Worse still, just one VM crash would lead to the entire VMC's restoration with the consistency guarantee taken into account. The frequent restoration of multiple virtual machines cause non-negligible overheads such as restore latency and performance penalty. Here, restore latency is referred to the time to load saved states from the persistent storage until the VM execution is resumed.</p><p>There are a few well-studied works on improving VM restoration. Working set restore <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[39,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">40]</ref> is one solution proposed recently, and it restores a single VM by prefetching the working set. Since the working set reflects the access locality, this method reduces the restore latency without compromising performance. It seems that the VMC restore could be simply accomplished by restoring the VMs individually with working set restore <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[19]</ref>. Unfortunately, several practical drawbacks are still far from settled.</p><p>First, the restore latency with working set restore is still long. In fact, the latency is proportional to the work- VM1 after start sends packet1 to VM2, and this packet will be lost because VM2 which is restoring is currently suspended. VM1 would resend this packet once retransmission timeout (RTO) is reached. Packets 2, 3, 4 are retransmitted items of packet1. If packet1 is a SYN to connect VM2, the TCP handshake would fail if the retransmission duration exceeds TCP connection timeout. If packet1 is a heartbeat packet, the timeout may cause VM2 be falsely reported as fail which would result in misbehaviour.</p><p>ing set size which is directly related to the workload activity. For memory intensive tasks, the working set might be the entire memory, so that the working set restore degrades to eager restore <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[37]</ref> which starts the VM after all state is loaded. Second, due to the heterogeneity of virtual machines cooperated in the VMC as well as the variety of workloads, the working set sizes of various VMs may be different. This difference results in diverse restore latencies and hence causes VMs being launched at different times. As a result, if the prior started VM sends a packet to a restoring one, it will not receive any reply within a while. This might lead to temporary backoff of active TCP connections as illustrated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>.</p><p>Therefore, in the cluster, the practical VM disruption time not only involves the restore latency but is determined by the TCP backoff duration as well. The backoff duration directly depends on the degree of discrepancy among VMs' restore completion times, i.e., start times. What's more, due to the complexity of workloads, these VMs may differ greatly in working set sizes, making TCP backoff duration the dominant factor in disruption.</p><p>In this paper, we propose HotRestore, which is capable of restoring the saved state of VMC swiftly and efficiently. Unlike prior VMC restore tools, HotRestore could resume the applications' execution within a few seconds and the applications can regain their full capacity rapidly. Moreover, the distributed applications only suffer transient network interruption during the restoration. Consequently, HotRestore can be naturally adopted in scenarios with high availability requirement, where fast recovery is essentially critical to provide reliable services to end users.</p><p>HotRestore proposes two key ideas to achieve these objectives. On one hand, it traces the memory access during post-snapshot, and records the traced pages in a first-access-first-load (FAFL) queue, which finally constitutes an elastic working set. The motivation behind is that when a VM is restored, it will be roll-backed to the snapshot point. If the execution is deterministic, the VM will re-execute in the same way as that of postsnapshot. As a result, the traced memory pages during post-snapshot will be touched again and thus can be regarded as working set pages. By only loading the working set pages upon restoration, the restore latency decreases with a lot.</p><p>On the other hand, restore line which depicts the start times of VMs is designed in order to reduce the TCP backoff duration. The basic idea is that for a packet sent from one VM, the associated destination VM must have been started to receive the packet for preventing potential backoff. The restore line derives from defacto restore order and causal restore order. The former one is revealed by the calculated working set sizes of VMs while the latter is communication-induced. Since the semantics of the two orders might conflict, HotRestore revises the working set sizes to make defacto order be consistent with causal order, and thereafter computes the restore line. Moreover, a restore protocol is designed to guarantee that the VMs can start as indicated by the restore line, thereby significantly minimizing the backoff duration.</p><p>Our contribution is three-fold. First, we introduce elastic working set, which is a subset of active memory pages in any desired size, in order to restore a single VM rapidly. Second, we propose restore line for virtual machines that cooperate into a cluster, schedule the VMs' start times to minimize the TCP backoff duration. Third, we have implemented HotRestore on our previous work called HotSnap <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[14]</ref> which creates distributed snapshots of the VMC, and conducted several experiments to justify its effectiveness.</p><p>The rest of the paper is organized as follows. The next section gives a brief overview of previous work on HotSnap. Section 3 presents the concepts and implementation of elastic working set. Section 4 introduces the algorithm to compute the restore line and describes the restore protocol. Section 5 introduces several implementation details on QEMU/KVM platform followed by the experimental results in Section 6. Finally we present the previous work related to HotRestore in section 7 and conclude our work in Section 8 and 9.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">A Brief Overview of HotSnap</head><p>HotSnap creates a global consistent state among the VMs' snapshots. It proposes a two stage VM snapshot cre-ation approach consisting of transient snapshot and full snapshot. In transient snapshot, HotSnap suspends the VM, records the CPU and devices' state, sets guest memory pages to be write-protected, and then starts the VM. After that, full snapshot starts up. HotSnap will save the guest pages in a copy-on-write manner. Specifically, upon a page fault triggered by touching the write-protected page, HotSnap will save the page into snapshot file, remove the write-protect flag and then resume the VM. The recorded snapshot is actually the instantaneous state in transient snapshot; therefore full snapshot is actually a part of post-snapshot stage.</p><p>In HotSnap, we tailor the classical message coloring method to suit to virtualized platforms. In the coloring method, the packet color is divided into pre-snapshot and post-snapshot, so is the VM color. HotSnap intercepts the packet sent and received by the simulated tap device on QEMU/KVM. For a packet to be sent, HotSnap piggybacks the packet with the immediate VM color. For a received packet, if the packet color is post-snapshot while the VM color is pre-snapshot, the packet will be temporarily dropped to avoid inconsistency; otherwise, the packet will be forwarded to the virtual machine and be finally handled.</p><p>The consistency of global state is guaranteed during snapshot creation by HotSnap. Therefore, HotRestore makes no attempt to ensure consistency upon restoration, which is different to previous works that focus on consistency as well as avoiding domino effect <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[16,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">34,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">36]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Elastic Working Set</head><p>This section first presents the estimation method of elastic working set, and then describes how to create snapshot and restore the VM when working set is employed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Working Set Estimation</head><p>An elastic working set should satisfy three requirements. Firstly, the restore latency is as short as possible without comprising application performance. Secondly, high hit rate and high accuracy are achieved after VM starts. High hit rate implies most of the accessed pages hit in the working set, while high accuracy means most of the working set pages will be touched within a short while after VM starts. Thirdly, the working set size could scale up or scale down without the decrement of hit rate, accuracy and performance. In this manner, the size can be revised on-demand upon VMC restoration. To estimate one such working set, we need to determine: i) which pages should be filled into the working set, and ii) how many pages should be loaded on restoration (or namely the working set size).  <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>: Elastic working set with the FAFL queue.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.1">Working Set Pages</head><p>Upon restoration, the VM will be roll-backed to the saved snapshot point and continue to execute. Ideally, if the execution is deterministic, the VM after restoration will re-execute the same instructions and touch the same memory area as that of post-snapshot. This insight inspires us to trace these memory access during post-snapshot and regard the traced pages as candidate working set pages for producing the final working set. Optimal selection from the candidate pages has been well studied. LRU and CLOCK are two classical and widely-used page replacement algorithms <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[23,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">41]</ref>. However, we argue that the FIFO manner could be better in the mentioned scenario within the paper. The reason is as follows. If the execution is deterministic, the page access order after restoration remains the same as that of post-snapshot. This implies that the first accessed page during post-snapshot will be firstly accessed after restoration. As a result, HotRestore adopts a first-accessfirst-load (FAFL) manner to determine the working set pages. Specifically, HotRestore saves the traced pages in the FAFL queue during post-snapshot, and loads the pages dequeued from the queue upon restoration. <ref type="figure">Figure  2</ref> illustrates the overview of the FAFL queue. The traced pages, i.e., A-F, have been stored in the queue in access order, and the working set can be simply produced by dequeuing the pages from the queue.</p><p>Elasticity is another crucial feature of the FAFL queue. The queue depicts the order of pages which are touched by guest kernel or applications during post-snapshot. On tone hand, given that the VM execution is deterministic, loading more or fewer pages into the working set upon restoration will not influence the hit rate or accuracy seriously. Consequently, it enables the working set to scale up/down efficiently. On the other hand, the background load thread after VM is launched could still fetch the pages in the FAFL manner rather than loading the pages blindly. In this way, the probability of page fault could be effectively reduced. This is essentially important to maintain the application performance without severe degradation when the working set size decreases.</p><p>The external inputs events or time change make the VM execution be non-deterministic invariably in real world scenarios. Despite this, our experimental results 1 show that elastic working set could achieve high hit rate and accuracy. Meanwhile, it could scale up and scale down without compromising performance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.2">Working Set Size</head><p>The working set size plays an important role when rolling back. Although a small size reduces the restore latency, it incurs numerous page faults, and thus aggravating the decreased performance after restoration. On the other hand, a large size could avoid severe performance penalty incurred by more loaded memory pages, but at the cost of long latency.</p><p>Statistical sampling approach described in ESX Server <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[38]</ref> is frequently used to predict the working set size. However, it lacks the ability to respond to the phase changes of workload in real time which is critical in restoration. Since the working set size upon restoration should capture the size of workload activity in a timely manner, we propose a hybrid working set size estimation method. First, we adopt a statistical sampling approach to calculate the working set size during normal execution. The size depicts the average workload activity in a long period, and is referred to as W SS sample . Secondly, we count the touched pages during post-snapshot. The page count reflects timely workload activity in part, and is referred to as W SS snapshot . The expected working set size is the weighted sum of these two sizes and is determined by:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">W SS = α * W SS sample + β * W SS snapshot</formula><p>In most programs, W SS remains nearly constant within a phase and then changes alternately. Since the workload always keeps steady for quite a while <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[41]</ref>, we empirically set α to be larger in HotRestore, i.e., α is 0.7 and β is 0.3. In addition, due to the well scalability of the FAFL queue, we adopt W SS/2 rather than W SS as the actual working set size upon restoration. The remaining pages will be loaded by the background thread from the FAFL queue or by demand-paging. The experimental results in §6.1.3 demonstrate that the size shrink only incurs negligible performance overhead.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Snapshot and Restore</head><p>This section describes the VM snapshot and restore when elastic working set is employed.</p><p>Snapshot. Unlike HotSnap which only traces the memory write operations, HotRestore traces all access-1 §6.1 will explain the results. es and records them in the FAFL queue to estimate the working set. Therefore, HotRestore adopts a snapshot approach that consists of copy-on-write and record-onaccess. In detail, HotRestore sets the guest memory pages to be non-present to trace all accesses. For write operation, HotRestore records the page frame number into the FAFL queue, saves the page content into persistent storage, and then removes the non-present flag to allow the page to be read or written without fault later on. For read operation, HotRestore only records the page frame number but does not save the page content. This is because read operations occur much more frequently than write operations, and saving the page content would lead to serious performance degradation. Therefore, HotRestore removes the read-protect flag but reserves the writeprotect flag. The page content will be saved either in copy-on-write manner once it is required to be written or by the background copy thread.</p><p>Restore. Upon restoration, HotRestore firstly loads the CPU state and devices' state, and then fetches the working set pages into the guest memory. Afterwards, it sets the page table entries of unrestored pages to be nonpresent before starting the VM. The unrestored pages will be loaded by i) on-demand paging due to touching the non-present page after VM starts, or ii) background load thread running concurrently which ensures that restore finishes in a reasonable period of time.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Restore of Virtual Machine Cluster</head><p>The key of VMC restore is to mitigate the TCP backoff problem. In TCP, after sending a packet, the sender will wait for the ack from the receiver. It would resend the packet once timeout occurs to ensure that the packet is successfully received. Motivated by this, the basic idea to avoid TCP backoff is to ensure the receiver start before the sender.</p><p>This section presents our solution to VMC restore. We start by describing the communication-induced restore dependency graph (RDG). Based on RDG, we compute the causal restore order 2 of VMs, and then schedule the restore line by revising the working set sizes of VMs. Finally, we introduce the restore protocol which ensures the VMs start as indicated by the restore line.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Restore Dependency Graph</head><formula xml:id="formula_1">We define "V M i depends on V M j " or V M i →V M j if V M i sends a packet to V M j .</formula><p>If V M i sends a packet to V M j during snapshot, it will resend the packet after it is restored to the saved snapshot point. Therefore, the dependency can be reserved upon restoration (we guarantee the dependency by deterministic communication in §5.1). This motivates us to construct the RDG via the dependency among VMs. In RDG, each node represents one VM, and a directed edge is drawn from V M i to V M j if V M i depends on V M j . The name "restore dependency graph" comes from the observation that if there is an edge from V M i to V M j and V M i is to be restored, then V M j must be restored no later than V M i to be ready to receive the packet and make the reply. Restore here means the "restore end" or "VM start", rather than "restore start". The dependency in RDG is transitive, i.e., if <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 3</ref>(b) demonstrates a RDG yielded by the timespace diagram in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 3</ref>(a). RDG only depicts the dependency between different VMs, i.e., space, but has no concept of time whether it is physical time or global virtual time. This is because the packet order and send/receive time may change after restoration due to non-deterministic execution. The lack of time semantics allows the existence of dependency ring, e.g., VM1, VM2 and VM3 in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 3</ref>(b) form a ring. We define V M i ↔ V M j if V M i and V M j are in a ring. VM5 is an orphan node; it neither depends on any VM, nor is depended by other VMs. The orphan node reflects the case that there is no packet sent or received associated with the node.</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">V M i →V M j and V M j →V M k , then V M i →V M k .</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Restore Line Calculation</head><p>Restore line depicts the desired start times of VMs while guaranteeing the causal restore order of VMs. The causal restore order can be calculated from the restore dependency graph: if V M i → V M j in RDG, then V M j should be ahead of V M i in causal restore order. Moreover, the VM start time (or restore latency) is related to the working set size. The different working set sizes of VMs form the defacto restore order. This motivates us to compute the restore line by the causal restore order as well as the defacto restore order.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.1">Causal Restore Order</head><p>The causal restore order is the semantics of logical start time; each dependency edge represents one elapsed clock. It is insufficient to obtain a unique causal restore order solely on RDG. First, the RDG is not necessarily a complete graph, e.g., there is no path between VM2 and VM4, implying VM2 and VM4 can be restored independently after VM3. Second, the existence of the dependency ring and orphan node make a lot of choices on the order. As a result, rather than compute a unique order, we instead give the following rules to construct one feasible causal restore order through RDG.</p><p>Rule 1. The VM, which doesn't depend on other VMs but is depended, is prioritized in causal restore order.</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">Rule 2. V M i should restore after V M j , if V M i depends on V M j while V M j does not depend on V M i .</formula><p>Rule 3. The VM that depends on several VMs will not restore until all the depended VMs are restored.</p><p>Rule 4. The VMs can restore independently if no dependency exists between them.</p><p>Rule 5. The VMs in the ring restore at the same time, i.e., they are placed together in causal restore order.</p><p>Rule 6. An orphan node may execute independently and therefore will be free in causal restore order.</p><p>Rule 1 seeks the VMs that should be restored first. Once found, the VMs that depend on prior restored VMs will join in the causal restore order by Rules 2 and 3. Rule 4 implies that the VMs can restore independently if there is neither direct nor transitive dependency between them. Based on these rules, we can reach two conclusions. First, after the completion of loading the working set, the VM can start if it satisfies any one of Rules 1, 4, 5, and 6. Second, after one VM is started, the VM can start accordingly if it depends on this started VM and satisfies Rule 2 or Rule 3 as well.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.2">Defacto Restore Order</head><p>The previously calculated working set sizes of VMs are always different due to the phase changes of workload, varieties of workloads or VM heterogeneity. These different sizes lead to different restore latencies and further form the defacto restore order which can be regarded as the semantics of physical start time.</p><p>The problem here is that the VM that is prior in causal restore order may have a larger working set size and thus starts later than the latter VM, making the defacto restore order inconsistent with the causal restore order. The inconsistency results in the TCP backoff problem as mentioned above. As a result, revising the working set sizes to match the two semantics becomes one crux of the problem in restoring the VMC. First, the defacto restore order after revision should be consistent with the causal restore order, to avoid TCP backoff. Second, the revised working set size should not impose significant effects on latency or performance for a single VM, i.e., minimum change on previous working set size.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.3">Working Set Size Revision</head><p>The basic idea of revision is simple. Given that a case that V M i →V M j , but the working set size of V M j , i.e., S j , is larger than S i , we can decrease S j or increase S i , or change the two both to achieve the matching.</p><p>System Model. We consider network intensive applications which is common in nowadays large scale data centers, such as distributed database, scientific computing, web services <ref type="bibr">[1]</ref>, etc. Their characteristic lies in that the communicating VMs send and receive packets frequently. We transfer the RDG to weighted RDG with the assignment to node value and edge weight, as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 4</ref>(a).</p><p>In weighted RDG, the node value S i is referred to as the previous calculated working set size (W SS) of V M i . The edge weight W i, j denotes the number of the captured packets sent from V M i to V M j during snapshot. Here, W i, j has no practical meaning, it is just used to ensure that the revised S i , i.e., S * i , be larger than S * j if V M i depends on V M j . We denote this relation by</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">S * i 񮽙 S * j +W i, j . Moreover, this inequation implies that if V M i → V M j and V M j → V M k , then S * i 񮽙 S * k + W i, j + W j,k . W i, j is minor compared to S * i or S * j</formula><p>, hence it causes no significant effect on the revised size. The dependency ring is particular, because the virtual machines in the ring should be provided with equivalent size to start at the same time. Therefore, for V M i ↔ V M j , we determine the sizes by: <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 4</ref>(b) demonstrates an inconsistent graph yielded by the weighted RDG in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 4</ref>(a). The horizontal line shows the defacto restore order, and the arrow depicts the causal restore order. The defacto restore order is [VM2, VM4, VM3, VM5, VM1], while there exist several candidates for causal restore order, e.g., <ref type="bibr">[</ref>  <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>: Restore protocol. We assume that B depends on A, so that B starts later.</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">S * i − S * j = 0.</formula><p>line with the least movement, to guarantee consistency between the causal order and the revised defacto order, such as the example shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 4</ref>(c). Problem Formulation. We assume that the previous calculated working set size is optimal. This is reasonable since the previous size achieves well tradeoff between restore latency and performance loss for a single VM, as demonstrated in the experimental results in §6.1.3. Given n VMs, let S = {S 1 , S 2 , ..., S n } be the previous working set sizes of VMs and W = {W i, j |V M i → V M j } be the set of edge weight of each two communicating VMs. We aim to find a minimum revised working set size S * to guarantee the consistency between the revised defacto restore order and causal restore order. The formulation is denoted by:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">min ∑ n i=0 | S * i − S i | s.t. S * i − S * j 񮽙 W i, j (W i, j ∈ W ) S * i − S * j = 0 (V M i ↔ V M j )</formula><p>We use the classical Linear Programming approach <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[26]</ref> to solve this optimization problem. Consequently, the desired restore line is computed through arranging the VMs in ascending order of the revised working set sizes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Restore Protocol</head><p>The purpose of restore protocol is to ensure that the virtual machines start as indicated by the restore line. The restore protocol is entirely software based and does not depend on any specialized hardware. We make the following assumptions about the distributed VMC system. First, the VMs, the underlying physical servers as well as the network devices are failure-free during restoring. This is reasonable since the restoration procedure lasts for a short time compared to the mean time to failure (MTTF) of hardware or software. Second, the network latency is minor, i.e., the messages can be received within a relatively short period. Otherwise, the restore latency would be directly related to the network latency on waiting for the messages of protocol. This assumption is satisfied in nowadays data center networks which always utilize 1Gbps or even 10Gbps Ethernet. There exist two roles in restore protocol, Coordinator and Cohort, as shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>. Each virtual machine is associated with one Cohort, and only one VM is regarded as the Coordinator. The roles of Coordinator consist of constructing the restore dependency graph, scheduling the restore line, broadcasting the working set sizes of VMs and notifying Cohorts to load the working set or start to execute. Besides, the Coordinator employs Checker to determine whether the associated VM can start after receiving the LOAD FIN reply from the Cohort, and which VMs can start correspondingly once receiving the START FIN reply from one Cohort, as described in §4.2.1. The Cohort restores the VM through three steps: i) load the working set pages after receiving the LOAD command and then reply LOAD FIN, ii) load the pages in background until receiving the START command, and iii) start the VM after receiving the S-TART command, reply the START FIN command, and then load the remaining pages through on-demand paging along with background loading.</p><p>Disruption will disappear after all the VMs are started, meanwhile the hot restoration is completed. The whole restoration procedure will not finish until all the VMs reply RESTORE FIN after completion of loading the remaining memory pages from the snapshot file.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Implementation Issues</head><p>HotRestore is implemented on qemu-kvm-0.12.5 <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[28]</ref> in Linux kernel 2.6.32.5-amd64, it does not require the modification of guest OS. HotRestore utilizes HotSnap to guarantee global consistency of snapshot state. Some optimizations such as compression of zero pages are provided by HotSnap and are also employed in HotRestore. Since the page saved in background belongs to the working set if it is accessed during snapshot procedure, HotRestore stores the working set pages in the snapshot file instead of a separate file. Besides, it creates a FAFL file to store the guest frame number for indexing these pages. The FAFL file makes it convenient to fetch working set pages in any desired size. The rest of this section describes the sub-level parts and optimizations in detail.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Packets Used to Construct RDG</head><p>In reliable communication, the receiver will reply ack to the sender. The capture of data/ack packets makes sender and receiver depend on each other and further form a ring in RDG. The dependency from receiver to sender is compelled, therefore it should be removed when constructing the RDG. One possible approach is to identify the roles by analyzing the packets, however it is extremely complicated and is impractical. Therefore, we resort to the on-the-fly packets, which cannot be received by the destination VM during transient snapshot. It cannot be received due to two reasons: i) the receiver VM is suspended to create transient snapshot or ii) the packet violates the global consistency, i.e., it is sent from a post-snapshot VM to a pre-snapshot VM. HotRestore logs on-the-fly packets on the receiver side, and constructs the RDG through these packets. Logging these packets brings two benefits. First, the on-the-fly packet will not be received or handled, and hence avoiding two-way dependency for one transmission. Second, replaying these packets after restoration can ensure deterministic communication, and hence the dependency is preserved.</p><p>UDP packets are also preserved. Although UDP is unreliable, the applications may support the reliability themselves through retransmission. This reliability guarantee would lead to the interruption of network communication if UDP packets are lost upon restoration. In conclusion, on constructing the RDG, we employ TCP as well as UDP packets whose source and destination are both the VMs within the VMC.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Optimizations on Restore</head><p>HotRestore adopts several optimizations to reduce the restore latency as well as performance overhead.</p><p>Sequential loading of working set pages. In HotRestore, the working set pages scatter here and there in the snapshot file and are mixed with the pages saved in background. Upon restoration, HotRestore dequeues the guest frame number (gfn) from the FAFL queue to index the working set page. However, the gfn order in the FAFL queue is not consistent with that in the snapshot file. For example, page A is firstly saved in background, and then page B is saved and recorded due to memory write operation, finally A is recorded due to memory read. In this case, A is stored in front of B in the snapshot file, but is behind B in the FAFL queue. Fetching the working set pages in FAFL order would seek the pages back and forth in the disk file, thereby incurring longer latency. To solve this problem, we rearrange the working set pages by their file offset once the revised size S * is known, so that the pages can be loaded sequentially from the snapshot file. Besides, the pages that are neighboring in the snapshot file can be loaded together to further reduce the amount of file read operations.</p><p>DMA cluster. DMA pages are touched frequently for IO intensive workloads, e.g., we observe about 280,000 DMA access in 30 seconds execution under Gzip for a VM configured with 2GB RAM. DMA page access exhibits two characteristics: First, the page will be accessed repeatedly (may be hundreds or even thousands times), therefore the amount of touched pages is actually only a few hundreds or thousands. Second, the accessed pages are always neighboring. These observations inspire us to load multiple neighboring pages (HotResotre loads 4 pages) for each on-demand DMA paging to reduce the occurrence of demand-loading, thereby avoiding significant performance degradation incurred by page faults.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Real World I/O Bandwidth</head><p>In real world scenarios, the restore latency is related to not only the working set size, but also the available I/O bandwidth. The snapshot procedures may contend for I/O bandwidth, making the latencies various even if the file sizes are identical. As a result, the practical start times may be not as indicated in the restore line. In our test environments, the working set size is small while the bandwidth is sufficient, so that the restore latency is less affected. However, we believe that this problem will get worse for memory intensive workloads, especially in I/O intensive data centers. VM placement <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[30]</ref> and I/O schedule layer <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[32]</ref> are alternative approaches to mitigate this problem, and we leave this as our future work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4">Non-deterministic Events</head><p>There exist many events that lead to non-deterministic system execution, they fall into two categories: external input and time <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[13]</ref>. The external input involves the data sent from another entity, such as the network packets from the web server, or user operations (e.g., booting a new application). Time refers to the point in the execution stream where the internal or external event takes place, for example, the receiving time of network packets. The combination of the two influences the results of several strategies resides in CPU scheduler, IO scheduler, and TCP/IP stack, so that the system execution is diverged even the system is restored from the same snapshot point. Fortunately, compared to the individual desktop which involves multiple tasks and continual interactive operations, the distributed applications running in the virtual machine cluster are always monotonous and involves less user interaction, making the execution of the virtual machine be always deterministic.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Evaluation</head><p>We conduct the experiments on eight physical servers, each configured with 8-way quad-core Intel Xeon 2.4GHz processors, 48GB DDR memory and Intel 82576 Gbps Ethernet card. The servers are connected via switched Gbps Ethernet. We configure 2GB memory for the VMs. The operating system on physical server and virtual machine is debian6.0 with 2.6.32-5-amd64 kernel. We save the snapshot files in local disk, and then restore the virtual machines from snapshot files to evaluate HotRestore.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">Elastic Working Set</head><p>We evaluate the elastic working set in terms of hit rate, accuracy, working set size and scalability, under several applications. The applications include: 1) Compilation, a development workload which involves memory and disk I/O operations. We compile the Linux 2.6.32-5 kernel.</p><p>2) Gzip is a compression utility, we compress the /home directory whose size is 1.4GB. 3) Mummer is a bioinformatics program for sequence alignment, it is CPU and memory intensive <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[5]</ref>. We align two genome fragments obtained from NCBI <ref type="bibr">[2]</ref>. 4) Pi calculation, a CPU intensive scientific program. 5) MPlayer is a movie player. It prefetches a large fraction of movie file into buffer for performance requirements. 6) MySQL is a database management system <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[6]</ref>, we employ SysBench tool <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[9]</ref> to read (write) data from (to) the database. We conduct the experiments ten times and report the average as well as the standard deviation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1.1">Hit Rate and Accuracy</head><p>We first measure the hit rate and accuracy under different working set sizes. We start the VM after the working set in the specified size is loaded, and disable the background load thread to trace all memory accesses. If the traced page is in the working set, then a hit occurs, and the hit count increases by 1. The traced page will not be traced again, since multiple hits on the same page would increase the hit rate and accuracy. Once the count of the traced pages reaches the given size, we calculate the hit rate by the ratio of hit count to the given size. The accuracy calculation is a little different. We observe that most of the untouched working set pages will be touched within a short period. Therefore, we trace an extra 1/5 size, and calculate the accuracy by the ratio of hit count to 1.2 times given size.  is 94.4% while it is 85.7% with LRU and 86.8% with CLOCK. The improvement is mainly contributed to the FAFL queue which captures the access order of VM execution more accurately. An interesting result is that the hit rate decreases as the size grows, e.g., the hit rate with FAFL decreases from 94.4% to 88.9% while the size increases from 15K to 20K. We suspect that this is because the execution suffers from larger deviation after longer execution time. Despite this, the hit rate is still high. Besides, the accuracy of the three manners exceeds 95% in most cases. This fact proves that the memory tracing method during post-snapshot could capture the memory accesses accurately.</p><p>We also measure the hit rate and accuracy under other workloads. <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 2</ref> illustrates the results when the calculated working set size is applied upon restoration. We can see that the hit rate under Gzip workload is low, this is because Gzip is I/O intensive and involves large amounts of DMA operations which always diverge after the VM is restored. For MySQL, Mummer and MPlayer workloads, the hit rate and accuracy is high due to two reasons: i) these workloads consist of a large amount of pages that hit the buffer cache which facilitate working set estimation and ii) their executions are almost deterministic. The high rate under Pi workload is poor, e.g., it is 62.8% with FAFL, this is due to the dynamic memory allocation during execution. Fortunately, the associated working set size is small, it is less than 1K pages, so that the performance loss is insignificant after the VM is restored. These three methods all achieve high accuracy, this means that most of the loaded working set pages will be touched by the applications after the VM is restored. The accuracy under Pi workload is low, we guess that this is due to the non-deterministic execution of Pi. On average, FAFL increases the hit rate by 15.3% and 4.92% respectively compared to LRU and CLOCK.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1.2">Working Set Size</head><p>Here, the working set size is referred to as the total amount of loaded state including the CPU state, devices' state, page content and extra information such as page address. Zero page compression used in most snapshot technologies may achieve 50% reduction of snapshot size <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[21]</ref>; however, the reduction is specific to workload and relates to application execution time. As a result, this optimization is disabled in this experiment. Table 3 compares HotRestore with working set restore <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[39]</ref> which calculates the working set size through the statistical sampling approach.</p><p>As expected, HotRestore loads less pages upon restoration. Compared to working set restore, HotRestore reduces the working set size by 50.95% on average, therefore the restore latency is supposed to be halved accordingly. Although restoring a VM requires extra time to sort the working set pages and set protection flags, the extra time is minor. Compared to the default restore method in QEMU/KVM which takes about 60 seconds to load a 2G snapshot file, HotRestore can restore the VM within 3 seconds for most workloads.  <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: Comparison of working set sizes (MB). STDEV is also reported</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1.3">Scalability</head><p>The results in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 1</ref> have shown that the hit rate and accuracy remain high regardless of the working set sizes, they therefore prove that the elastic working set can scale up or scale down without compromising the hit rate or accuracy.</p><p>On the other hand, however, scaling down the size would bring more page faults due to demand-paging and thus imposes performance overhead. Therefore, the performance loss or the count of page faults should be measured and reported. We trace the page faults after restoration and record the count in 100ms interval. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 6</ref> shows the count on different working set sizes: the calculated W SS and its two variants, 0.5W SS and 0.7W SS. W SS is 18327 pages in this experiment. As we can see, the decrease of the working set size indeed incurs more page faults. Specifically, the numbers are 2046, 3539 and 5690 for W SS, 0.7W SS and 0.5W SS respectively during the 7 seconds tracing period. Intuitively, the increased count of page faults should be equivalent to or approximate the saved page count upon restoration. However, our results show that it is not. For example, 0.7W SS loads 5498 less pages upon restoration but incurs only 1493 more page faults compared to W SS. This is mainly because the pages stored in the FAFL queue depict the page access order. If the W SS applied upon restoration is less than the calculated W SS, the remaining working set pages tend to be dequeued and loaded by the background load thread. The FAFL method effectively reduces the count of page faults compared to the approach which loads pages blindly.</p><p>The result for 2W SS is also given, as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Fig- ure 6(d)</ref>. It can be seen that the count of page faults can be further reduced due to the increase of W SS, specifically, it decreases to 958. However, we believe that the reduction is insignificant. This is because that one page fault incurs about 200us interruption which involves the time to exit to VMM, load the page from local disk, remove protection flag and resume the VM. Therefore, the overall overhead for handling thousands of page faults is negligible compared to the gain of 50% reduction on the working set size or namely the restore latency.</p><p>These results show that the working set can scale up/down without significant performance loss. This gives us a hint that slight working set size revision is al- lowable when restoring the VMC. The results under other workloads are similar, so that they are ignored due to space constraints.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Restoration of VMC</head><p>In this section, we evaluate HotRestore in the VMC and discuss the restore latency as well as the TCP backoff duration. The native restore method of QEMU/KVM incurs dozens of seconds disruption, so the result is neglected here. We conduct the experiments with three restore mechanisms: Working Set Restore. It reduces the restore latency by prefetching the working set for a single VM.</p><p>HotRestore without Restore Line (HotRestore w/o RL). It reduces the restore latency through elastic working set, but does no further work on VMC restore.</p><p>HotRestore with Restore Line (HotRestore w/ RL). It exploits the elastic working set and utilizes restore line to reduce the TCP backoff duration.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2.1">Detailed View of Disruption</head><p>We first illustrate the disruption duration consisting of restore latency and TCP backoff duration in detail. We setup the VMC with 8 VMs, and apply two representative network applications: i) Distcc <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[3]</ref> which is a com- HotRestore w/ RL pilation tool that adopts client/server architecture to distribute the tasks across the nodes, and ii) Elasticsearch <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[4]</ref> which is a distributed, de-centralized search server used to search documents. The nodes play equivalent role in Elasticsearch. The practical TCP backoff duration is hard to depict unless modifying the guest OS, therefore, we approximate the value by the difference between start times of communicating VMs. If the VM is communicating with multiple VMs, the maximum time difference will be adopted as the duration. We use NTP to synchronize the times of physical server, so that the difference among physical times of servers is within only a few milliseconds. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 7</ref> compares the detailed disruption duration of VMs of HotRestore to that of Working Set Restore. The gray bar illustrates the restore latency, while the red bar depicts the TCP backoff duration. It can be seen that the restore latencies of VMs are various and thus cause the backoff problem. Take Distcc as an example, the latencies of VM2 and VM6 are 5.21 seconds and 6.13 seconds respectively. Since VM2 depends on VM6, hence the backoff duration of VM2 is 0.92 seconds. It can be seen that the restore latencies of VMs with Working Set Restore are much longer than that with HotRestore methods. The HotRestore w/o RL method reduces the restore latency by employing a smaller working set size, so that the backoff duration decreases accordingly. The results in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 7(a)</ref> show that the HotRestore w/o RL reduces the disruption by 54.1% on average compared to Working Set Restore. The HotRestore w/ RL method reduces the disruption further. Although there is no significant decrease on restore latency compared to HotRestore w/o RL, the backoff is eliminated as a result of the restore line. Generally, it achieves a 56.7% reduction on disruption duration compared to Working Set Restore under Distcc workload.</p><p>The disruption under Elasticsearch workload shows similar results. Compared to Working Set Restore, HotRestore w/o RL reduces the average disruption duration by 48.6%. It is worth noting that the TCP backoff appears in HotRestore w/ RL, e.g., the backoff duration of VM5 and VM7 are 0.1 and 0.12 seconds respectively. This is because VM4, VM5 and VM7 form a dependency ring and are given identical working set size to be started simultaneously. However, due to the fluctuation of disk IO speed, the practical start times of VMs are different. In this experiment, VM5 and VM7 start earlier than VM4, as a result, they suffer from TCP backoff problem. On average, HotRestore w/ RL reduces the disruption by 53.6% compared to Working Set Restore.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2.2">Details on TCP Backoff Duration</head><p>The above experiments present an overview of backoff duration. We can see that some VMs do not experience TCP backoff, while others suffer from long backoff duration, e.g., the duration of VM5 is 4.49 seconds under Elasticsearch. In this section, we will exhibit the details on backoff duration, especially for the complicated network topology as the VMC scales out. We evaluate HotRestore for a VMC configured with 8, 12, 16 VMs under Elasticsearch workload, and reports the details on VMC backoff duration. There is no direct metric to measure the backoff duration for the whole VMC, therefore, we calculate all the backoff duration between each two communicating VMs, and report the maximum, minimum, average and median value. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 8</ref> demonstrates the results on backoff duration. As expected, HotRestore w/ RL achieves the least duration. Compared to Working Set Restore which incurs 2.66 seconds backoff duration on average, HotRestore w/ RL reduces the average duration to less than 0.07 seconds. As explained earlier, the duration with HotRestore is mainly due to the existence of dependency ring as well as the difference of VMs' start times. Besides, we can see that the maximum backoff duration with Working Set Restore exceeds 10.1 seconds in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 8</ref>(b). The long duration may make the application inside the VM experience a long freeze stage even if the VM actually has already started. HotRestore solves the problem through the restore line. As we can see, even the maximum duration is less than 0.14 seconds in HotRestore. As a result, the VM after restoration is able to execute without perceivable interruption.</p><p>These results demonstrate that HotRestore w/ RL reduces the TCP backoff duration to milliseconds and scales well for larger scale VMC. Besides, for low latency network where the proposed restore protocol is not suitable, the HotRestore w/o RL approach can still work and bound the duration in a few seconds.</p><p>It is worth noting that the TCP backoff duration here is simply calculated by the difference between the start times of communicating VMs. In practice, however, the backoff duration increases twofold for each timeout, making the practical backoff duration of the Working Set Restore be much larger than the value shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 8</ref>. In other words, HotResotre would performs much better than Working Set Restore in practical scenarios.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3">Performance Overhead</head><p>This part will measure the incurred performance overhead of HotRestore. The overhead mainly comes from two aspects. One is the overhead on snapshot. Compared to traditional snapshot that only traces write operations, HotRestore traces both read and write operations, so that it incurs extra overhead. Another one is the overhead after restoration. The demand-paging will trigger page faults, making the VM exit to VMM for loading the desired page from disk file.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3.1">Overhead during Snapshot</head><p>We measure the overhead in terms of the count of traced pages during snapshot.    million micro-blogs and launch ten threads to query concurrently. Each query requests different keywords and acquires 40 micro-blogs. The average response time for each query is about 0.192s during normal execution. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 9</ref> demonstrates the average response time of ten threads for continuous queries. As we can see, the response time with Working Set Restore is long after restoration. Specifically, the latency of the first query is 0.36 seconds, which is about twice the latency of normal execution. The reason is as follows: The Elasticsearch node will handle the query after the associated VM starts. However, some other nodes are still suspended to load the working set, thereby causing the backoff among these nodes. As a result, the requested node cannot reply as fast as that in normal execution with fewer peers, especially for concurrent queries from ten threads. The response time decreases for the subsequent queries, due to the coordination with peers that are resumed recently. HotRestore shows no significant performance loss. The requested node can coordinate with peers within a short period after restoration due to the short backoff duration. In practice, the average response time with HotRestore is 0.215 seconds for the first six queries, only a little higher than that of normal execution.</p><p>The response time with HotRestore returns to the normal value from the 7th cycle, while it keeps high until the 16th cycle with the Working Set Restore approach. This implies that HotRestore halves the time for Elasticsearch to regain the full capacity. Although the working set sizes of some certain VMs are revised to be smaller and thus degrade the performance for the single VM, the overall performance of entire VMC is improved due to the elimination of the network interruption.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Related Work</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.1">VM Restoration</head><p>The idea of fast restore is not new, several approaches have been proposed to fast restore (or start) the processes and the operating systems. Recovery Oriented Computing (ROC) <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[33]</ref> achieves fast recovery of process upon failures by fine grained partitioning and recursive restart. Li et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[29]</ref> track the pages touched by applications during post-checkpoint, and use these touched pages to restart the processes fast. Windows adopts SuperFetch <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[8]</ref> and ReadyBoost <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[7]</ref> to accelerate the application and OS launch times respectively by monitoring and adapting the usage patterns and prefetching the frequently used files and data into memory so that they can be accessed quickly when needed. HotRestore is fundamentally different from these works in that it focuses on the restore latency of virtual machines, rather than processes or operating systems.</p><p>There is not much work on improving VM restore. The most simple approach is eager restore, which starts the virtual machine after all the state including device state and memory state are loaded <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[37]</ref>. This approach, obviously, incurs long latency for VMs equipped with large size memory. Lazy restore <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[18]</ref> reduces the latency to milliseconds through starting the VM after CPU state and device state are loaded and loading the memory state in an on-demand way. It however incurs serious performance loss due to large amounts of demand-paging after restore, especially in the beginning execution after the VM is rollbacked. Working set restore <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[39]</ref> addresses the performance issue by prefetching the working set upon restore, at the cost of only a few seconds downtime. Our work on a single VM restore shares a similar philology to working set restore. The difference is, their method employs working set to reduce the time-to-responsiveness metric, yet we propose an elastic working set for restoring the virtual machine cluster.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.2">VMC Restoration</head><p>There have been amounts of work about restoring a distributed system, and the key of them is to guarantee the consistency of the saved state. Several work create the global consistent state through coordinated snapshotting approach, so that the system can be rolled back directly from the saved state <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[27,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">20,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">12]</ref>. Another field assumes that the nodes create snapshots independently, therefore they focus on guaranteeing the global consistency among snapshots upon restore and avoiding domino effect <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[16,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">36,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">34]</ref>. Several recently proposed snapshot systems for virtual machine cluster create the consistent global state <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[25,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">19]</ref> when snapshotting, but make no improvement on restoration. We guarantee the consistency while the snapshots are being created by our prior work called HotSnap <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[14]</ref>, and our concern within the paper is to reduce the restore latency as well as the TCP backoff duration.</p><p>Besides, the TCP backoff problem incurred during snapshot has received attention recently. VNSnap <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[25]</ref> saves the memory state in a temporary memory region and then flushes into disk asynchronously, thereby reducing the discrepancy of snapshot completion times to reduce the backoff duration. Emulab <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[11]</ref> addresses this issue by synchronizing clocks across the nodes to suspend all nodes for snapshot simultaneously. Our work emphasizes on backoff duration upon restoration. By exploiting the network causal order, we propose a restore line method to minimize the backoff duration.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.3">Working Set</head><p>Working set captures the notion about memory access locality. Denning describes which pages should be swapped in and out of the working set <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[15]</ref>. LRU <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[31]</ref>, CLOCK <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[23]</ref> and CAR <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[10]</ref> are improved methods to identify which pages should be replaced into the working set. HotRestore adopts the FAFL queue to record the traced pages as candidate working set pages, and then produces the working set according to the desired size. Besides, several systems adopt the working set to achieve fast restoration of process <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[29]</ref> or VM <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[39]</ref>. They employ memory tracing to capture the working set pages and leverage the sampling approach <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[38]</ref> to estimate the working set size. HotRestore is different in that it figures out a hybrid size based on sampling during normal execution as well as statistic during snapshot, and then halves the size as the expected working set size. The size shrink does not impose significant performance loss due to the well scalability of the elastic working set.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8">Limitations and Future Work</head><p>There still exist several limitations in HotRestore. First, the proposed elastic working set would perform poor for non-deterministic applications, especially for applications in SMP virtual machines due to the variable vCPU scheduling. Other non-deterministic events, as described in §5.4, will also lead to the divergence of VM execution after restoration. As a result, the on-demand paging would occur frequently, and further imposes significant performance loss. Second, for some applications, e.g., long running scientific programs, where fast restore is inessential, HotRestore may incur unnecessary overhead due to extra read traces during snapshot, given that the VMC snapshot is frequently created. Therefore, our ongoing work contain two directions. The first is to analyze the memory traces for nondeterministic applications in SMP (Symmetric MultiProcessing) VM for seeking a suitable page replacement algorithm to build an accurate working set, with the aim to reduce the amount of page faults as well as eliminating performance degradation. What's more, given that snapshot is required more frequently than restore, we plan to make a holistic study on performance overhead with multiple snapshots along with one restore operations in real world scenarios, with the aim to find an adaptive snapshot/restore policy to minimize the overall overhead for long running applications.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="9">Conclusions</head><p>In this paper, we present HotRestore, a restore system which enables fast restore of the virtual machine cluster without perceivable disruption. HotRestore employs an elastic working set to reduce the restore latency without compromising the application performance, and proposes restore line to reduce the TCP backoff duration. The key insight in restore line is that the start times of VMs can be revised to match the network causal order of VMs. We have implemented HotRestore on QEMU/KVM platform. Our evaluation results show that the whole VM-C can be restored within a few seconds, what's more, the applications can regain the full capacity rapidly after restoration benefiting from the elimination of TCP backoff. We believe that HotRestore will help improve system reliability and performance after failure recovery, especially in the scenarios where failures and restoration are requied frequently.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: A TCP transmission case during restoration. VM1 after start sends packet1 to VM2, and this packet will be lost because VM2 which is restoring is currently suspended. VM1 would resend this packet once retransmission timeout (RTO) is reached. Packets 2, 3, 4 are retransmitted items of packet1. If packet1 is a SYN to connect VM2, the TCP handshake would fail if the retransmission duration exceeds TCP connection timeout. If packet1 is a heartbeat packet, the timeout may cause VM2 be falsely reported as fail which would result in misbehaviour.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Communication-induced RDG.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: The revision of working set sizes. (a) is derived from Figure 3, while the dependency between VM1 and VM3 is removed.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Figure 6: Comparison of page fault count after restore.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Figure 7: Comparison of disruption time in the VMC.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 8 :</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Figure 8: Comparison of TCP backoff duration.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 9 :</head><label>9</label><figDesc>Figure 9: Comparison of response time.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 1 demonstratesis 17K. STDEV is minor and thus is removed.</head><label>1</label><figDesc>the hit rate and accuracy of FAFL compared to LRU and CLOCK under Linux kernel compilation. It can be seen that the hit rate with FAFL is higher, e.g., for a 15K size, the hit rate with FAFL</figDesc><table>Hit Rate 
Accuracy 

Size 
FAFL 
LRU 
CLOCK 
FAFL 
LRU 
CLOCK 

5K 
0.816 
0.778 
0.814 
0.859 
0.817 
0.838 
10K 
0.845 
0.875 
0.749 
0.945 
0.918 
0.926 
15K 
0.944 
0.857 
0.868 
0.952 
0.954 
0.952 
17K 
0.912 
0.918 
0.822 
0.958 
0.955 
0.955 
20K 
0.889 
0.888 
0.828 
0.963 
0.962 
0.923 
25K 
0.870 
0.861 
0.869 
0.962 
0.963 
0.970 

Table 1: Hit rate and accuracy for working set with various sizes. Here, the size refers to page count, the calculated 
W SS Hit Rate 
Accuracy 

Workloads 
FAFL 
LRU 
CLOCK 
FAFL 
LRU 
CLOCK 

Gzip 
0.806 
0.768 
0.883 
0.974 
0.979 
0.966 
MySQL 
0.947 
0.655 
0.912 
1 
0.998 
1 
Mummer 
0.931 
0.835 
0.812 
1 
0.971 
0.909 
Pi 
0.628 
0.562 
0.589 
0.702 
0.682 
0.793 
MPlayer 
0.890 
0.825 
0.862 
0.926 
0.923 
0.892 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Hit rate and accuracy under various workloads. STDEV is minor and thus is removed.</figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>10 28th Large Installation System Administration Conference (LISA14) USENIX Association</head><label>10</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Modes 
Compilation 
Gzip 
Mummer 
Pi 
MPlayer 
MySQL 

HotRestore 
72.0(2.88) 
60.9(15.3) 
347.5(30.7) 
1.5(0.09) 37.2(6.4) 42.4(8.9) 
Working Set Restore 
153.0(7.92) 
113.5(21.2) 836.3(117.9) 2.76(0.17) 75.3(9.4) 87.8(11.4) 

Reduction 
52.94% 
46.34% 
58.45% 
45.65% 
50.6% 
51.71% 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>Table 4 compares</head><label>4</label><figDesc>the results of HotSnap (as the baseline shows) and HotRestore. It can be seen that the increase incurred by HotRestore ranges from 11.3% to 124%. Upon a page fault triggered by access tracing, the VM- M suspends the VM and handles the page fault. The overhead to handle the fault mainly consists of two part- s. First, the VM exits to VMM which removes the read/write protect flag and then resumes the VM. The exit and entry of VM to VMM takes 38us in our platfor- m. Second, the VMM saves the traced page into storage for memory write operation. Saving one page (4K) takes about 150us on average. Fortunately, tracing the memo- ry read operations in HotRestore does not require saving the page. As a result, the extra time during snapshot cre- ation incurred by tracing read operations is minor. Ta- ble 5 compares the snapshot creation time under various workloads. As an example, the total time to save the VM state in HotRestore increases by 1.3 seconds compared to that of Baseline under Compilation workload.</figDesc><table>Modes 
Compile Gzip Pi MPlayer MySQL 

Baseline 
25933 53447 1523 21510 
12825 
HotRestore 34348 59466 3413 30217 
17598 

Increase 
32.4% 11.3% 124% 40.4% 37.2% 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" validated="true"><head>Table 4 : Comparison of traced page count.</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Modes 
Compile Gzip Pi MPlayer MySQL 

Baseline 
85.3 
79.5 54.2 
72.5 
77.3 
HotRestore 86.6 
81.1 54.4 
74.2 
78.2 

Increase 
1.3 
1.6 
0.2 
1.7 
0.9 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7" validated="false"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Comparison of snapshot duration (seconds). 

6.3.2 Overhead after Restoration 

We setup Elasticsearch in the VMC configured with 8 
VMs. We measure the performance loss in terms of the 
response time. Specifically, we fill Elasticsearch with 1 </table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> 28th Large Installation System Administration Conference (LISA14) USENIX Association</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> The restore order here describes the order of completion times of the working set restore, or namely VM start times, rather than restore start times.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>We would like to thank our shepherd Theophilus Benson and the anonymous reviewers for their valuable comments and help in improving this paper. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>References</head><p>[1] Amazon ec2. Http:// aws.amazon.com/ec2/.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Distcc</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://code.google.com/p/distcc/" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Elasticsearch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.elasticsearch.org/" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mummer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://mummer.sourceforge.net/" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mysql</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.mysql.com/" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Readyboost</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ReadyBoost" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Superfetch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WindowsVistaI/Otechnologies" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Sysbench</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://sysbench.sourceforge.net/" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Car: Clock with adaptive replacement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bansal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Modha</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of USENIX FAST</title>
		<meeting>USENIX FAST</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="187" to="200" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Transparent checkpoints of closed distributed systems in emulab</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Burtsev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Radhakrishnan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hibler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lepreau</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EuroSys</title>
		<meeting>EuroSys</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="173" to="186" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distributed snapshots: Determining global states of distributed systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Chandy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Lamport</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Transactions on Computer Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="63" to="75" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When virtual is better than real</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Noble</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the HotOS</title>
		<meeting>the HotOS</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="133" to="138" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>operating system relocation to virtual machines</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hotsnap: A hot distributed snapshot system for virtual machine cluster</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Cui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of USENIX LISA</title>
		<meeting>USENIX LISA</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="59" to="73" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The working set model for program behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Denning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Communications of the ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="323" to="333" />
			<date type="published" when="1968" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A survey of rollback-recovery protocols in message-passing systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Elnozahy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Alvisi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y.-M</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Comput. Surv</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="375" to="408" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Availability in globally distributed storage systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Labelle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Popovici</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Stokely</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V.-A</forename><surname>Truong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Barroso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Grimes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Quinlan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of OSDI</title>
		<meeting>OSDI</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="14" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A generic checkpoint-restart mechanism for virtual machines</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Garg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Sodha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Cooperman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>CoRR abs/1212.1787</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Checkpoint-restart for a network of virtual machines</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Garg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Sodha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Jin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Cooperman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IEEE International Conference on Cluster Computing</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Restoring consistent global states of distributed computations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Goldberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gopal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Lowry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Strom</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACM/ONR workshop on Parallel and distributed debugging (PADD)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="144" to="154" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Difference engine: harnessing memory redundancy in virtual machines</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Vrable</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Savage</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Snoeren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Varghese</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Voelker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Vahdat</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Communications of ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="85" to="93" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Largescale virtualization in the emulab network testbed</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hibler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ricci</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Stoller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Duerig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Guruprasad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Stack</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Webb</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lepreau</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">USENIX Annual Technical Conference</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="113" to="128" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Clock-pro: An effective improvement of the clock replacement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ATC</title>
		<meeting>ATC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="323" to="336" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Violin: Virtual internetworking on overlay infrastructure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Parallel and Distributed Processing and Applications</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="937" to="946" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Vnsnap: Taking snapshots of virtual networked environments with minimmal downtime</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kangarlou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Eugster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of DSN</title>
		<meeting>DSN</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="87" to="98" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A new polynomial-time algorithm for linear programming</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Karmarkar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of STOC</title>
		<meeting>STOC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="302" to="311" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An efficient protocol for checkpointing recovery in distributed systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Parallel and Distributed Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="955" to="960" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Kvm: the linux virtual machine monitor</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kivity</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Kamay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Laor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Lublin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computer and Information Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="225" to="230" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A fast restart mechanism for checkpoint/recovery protocols in networked environments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Lan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of DSN</title>
		<meeting>DSN</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="217" to="226" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving the scalability of data center networks with trafficaware virtual machine placement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Meng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Pappas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of INFOCOM</title>
		<meeting>INFOCOM</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="9" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The lru-k page replacement algorithm for database disk buffering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>O&amp;apos;neil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>O&amp;apos;neil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Weikum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACM SIGMOD</title>
		<meeting>the ACM SIGMOD</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="297" to="306" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scheduling io in virtual machine monitors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ongaro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Cox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Rixner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of VEE</title>
		<meeting>VEE</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Recovery-oriented computing (roc): Motivation, definition, techniques, and case studies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Patterson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Broadwell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>UCB//CSD-02-1175</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>UC Berkeley Computer Science</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical Report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">State restoration in systems of communicating processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Russell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Software Engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="183" to="194" />
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding failures in petascale computers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Schroeder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Gibson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Physics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">78</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="11" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimistic recovery in distributed systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Strom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Yemini</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Transations on Computer Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="204" to="226" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scott. Checkpoint/restart of virtual machines based on xen</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Vallee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Naughton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Ong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of HAPCW</title>
		<meeting>HAPCW</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Memory resource management in vmware esx server</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Waldspurger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of USENIX OSDI</title>
		<meeting>USENIX OSDI</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="181" to="194" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fast restore of checkpointed memory using working set estimation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Garthwaite</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Baskakov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Barr</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of VEE</title>
		<meeting>VEE</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="534" to="533" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimizing vm checkpointing for restore performance in vmware esxi</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Denniston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Baskakov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Garthwaite</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of USENIX ATC</title>
		<meeting>USENIX ATC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Low cost working set size tracking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Jin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Luo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of USENIX ATC</title>
		<meeting>USENIX ATC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="22" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
