<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/atharsefid/Desktop/grobid-0.5.3/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.3" ident="GROBID" when="2020-09-29T03:03+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Compiling Abstract Specifications into Concrete Systems-Bringing Order to the Cloud Compiling Abstract Specifications into Concrete Systems -Bringing Order to the Cloud</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ian</forename><surname>Unruh</surname></persName>
							<email>iunruh@ksu.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit4">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit5">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit6">Kansas State University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexandru</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Bardas</surname></persName>
							<email>bardasag@ksu.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit4">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit5">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit6">Kansas State University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rui</forename><surname>Zhuang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit4">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit5">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit6">Kansas State University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xinming</forename><surname>Ou</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit4">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit5">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit6">Kansas State University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Scott</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Deloach</surname></persName>
							<email>sdeloach@ksu.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit4">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit5">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit6">Kansas State University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ian</forename><surname>Unruh</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit4">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit5">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit6">Kansas State University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexandru</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Bardas</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit4">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit5">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit6">Kansas State University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rui</forename><surname>Zhuang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit4">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit5">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit6">Kansas State University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xinming</forename><surname>Ou</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit4">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit5">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit6">Kansas State University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Scott</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Deloach</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit4">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit5">Kansas State University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit6">Kansas State University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Compiling Abstract Specifications into Concrete Systems-Bringing Order to the Cloud Compiling Abstract Specifications into Concrete Systems -Bringing Order to the Cloud</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>This paper is included in the Proceedings of the 28th Large Installation System Administration Conference (LISA14). November 9-14, 2014 • Seattle, WA Open access to the Proceedings of the 28th Large Installation System Administration Conference (LISA14) is sponsored by USENIX</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Currently, there are important limitations in the abstractions that support creating and managing services in a cloud-based IT system. As a result, cloud users must choose between managing the low-level details of their cloud services directly (as in IaaS), which is time-consuming and error-prone, and turning over significant parts of this management to their cloud provider (in SaaS or PaaS), which is less flexible and more difficult to tailor to user needs. To alleviate this situation we propose a high-level abstraction called the requirement model for defining cloud-based IT systems. It captures important aspects of a system&apos;s structure, such as service dependencies, without introducing low-level details such as operating systems or application configurations. The requirement model separates the cloud customer&apos;s concern of what the system does, from the system engineer&apos;s concern of how to implement it. In addition, we present a &quot;compilation&quot; process that automatically translates a requirement model into a concrete system based on pre-defined and reusable knowledge units. When combined, the requirement model and the compilation process enable repeatable deployment of cloud-based systems, more reliable system management, and the ability to implement the same requirement in different ways and on multiple cloud platforms. We demonstrate the practicality of this approach in the ANCOR (Automated eNterprise network COmpileR) framework, which generates concrete, cloud-based systems based on a specific requirement model. Our current implementation 1 targets OpenStack and uses Puppet to configure the cloud instances, although the framework will also support other cloud platforms and configuration management solutions.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Cloud computing is revolutionizing industry and reshaping the way IT systems are designed, deployed and utilized <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. However, every revolution has its own challenges. Already, companies that have moved resources into the cloud are using terms like "virtual sprawl" to describe the mess they have created <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">[38]</ref>. Cloud services are currently offered in several models: Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS), Platform as a Service (PaaS), and Software as a Service (SaaS). While these options allow customers to decide how much management they want to perform for their cloud-based systems, they do not provide good abstractions for effectively managing those systems or addressing diverse user needs.</p><p>IaaS solutions such as Amazon Web Services (AWS) and OpenStack allow cloud users to access the raw resources (compute, storage, bandwidth, etc.); however, it forces users to manage the software stack in their cloud instances at a low level. While this approach gives users tremendous flexibility, it also allows the users to create badly configured or misconfigured systems, raising significant concerns (especially related to security) <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">7]</ref>. Moreover, offering automatic scalability and failover is challenging for cloud providers because replication and state management procedures are applicationdependent <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. On the other hand, SaaS (also known as "on-demand software") provides pre-configured applications to cloud users (e.g., SalesForce and Google Apps). Users typically choose from a set of predefined templates, which makes it difficult to adequately address the range of user needs. PaaS (e.g., Google App Engine, Heroku, and Windows Azure) is somewhere in the middle, offering computing platforms with various preinstalled operating systems as well as services and allowing users to deploy their own applications as well.</p><p>As PaaS is a compromise between IaaS and SaaS, it also inherits the limitations of both to various degrees. For example, users can be easily "locked in" to a PaaS vendor, like in SaaS, and the configuration of applications is still on the users' shoulders, like in IaaS.</p><p>We observe that existing cloud service models suffer from the lack of an appropriate higher-level abstraction capable of capturing objectives and functionality of the complete IT system. Such an abstraction, if designed well, can help both the creation and the longterm maintenance of the system. While there have been attempts at providing abstractions at various levels of cloud-based services, none have provided an abstraction that both separates user requirements from low-level platform/system details and provides a global view of the system. This has limited the usefulness of those solutions when it comes to long-term maintenance, multi-platform support, and migration from one cloud provider to another. We believe to be effective, the abstraction should exhibit the following properties.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">It must be capable of representing what a user needs</head><p>instead of low-level details on how to implement those needs. A major motivation for using cloud infrastructures is to outsource IT management to a more specialized workforce (called system engineers hereafter). Communicating needs from users to engineers is better served using higher-level abstractions as opposed to low-level system details.</p><p>2. It must support automatic compilation into valid concrete systems on different cloud infrastructures. Such compilation should use well-defined knowledge units built by the system engineers and be capable of translating a specification based on the abstraction (i.e., an abstract specification) into different concrete systems based on low-level implementation/platform choices.</p><p>3. It should facilitate the long-term maintenance of the system, including scaling the system up/down, automatic fail over, application update, and other general changes to the system. It should also support orchestrating those changes in a secure and reliable manner and aid in fault analysis and diagnosis.</p><p>We believe such an abstraction will benefit all three existing cloud service models. For IaaS, an abstract specification will act as a common language for cloud users and system engineers to define the system, while the compilation/maintenance process becomes a tool that enables system engineers to be more efficient in their jobs. Re-using the compilation knowledge units will also spread the labor costs of creating those units across a large number of customers. In the SaaS model the system engineers will belong to the cloud provider so the abstract specification and the compilation/maintenance process will help them provide better service at a lower cost. In the PaaS model we foresee using the abstraction and compilation process to stand up a PaaS more quickly than can be done today. This could even foster the convergence to a common set of PaaS APIs across PaaS vendors to support easier maintenance and migration between PaaS clouds.</p><p>There are multiple challenges in achieving this vision. The most critical is whether it is feasible to design the abstraction so that it can capture appropriate system attributes in a way that is meaningful to users and system engineers while being amenable to an automated compilation process that generates valid concrete systems.</p><p>The contributions of our work are:</p><p>• We design an abstract specification for cloudbased IT systems that separates user requirements from system implementation details, is platformindependent, and can capture the important aspects of a system's structure at a high level.</p><p>• We design a compilation process that (1) translates the high-level specification into the low-level details required for a particular choice of cloud platform and set of applications, and (2) leverages a mature configuration management solution to deploy the resulting system to a cloud.</p><p>• We show that maintaining an abstract specification at an appropriate level enables users to address automatic scaling and failover even though these processes are highly application-dependent, and supports a more reliable and error-free orchestration of changes in the system's long-term maintenance.</p><p>To demonstrate the efficacy of our approach, we implemented and evaluated a fully-functional prototype of our system, called ANCOR (Automated eNterprise network COmpileR). The current implementation of AN-COR targets OpenStack <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">[45]</ref> and uses Puppet <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[20]</ref> as the configuration management tool (CMT); however, the framework can also be targeted at other cloud platforms such as AWS, and use other CMT solutions such as Chef <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[34]</ref>.</p><p>The rest of the paper is organized as follows. Section 2 explains the limitations of current solutions as well as the enabling technologies used in this work. Section 3 presents an overview of the framework, including the proposed abstraction and the compilation workflow. Section 4 describes the implementation of the ANCOR framework and its evaluation. We discuss some other relevant features of the approach and future work in Section 5, followed by related work and conclusion.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Background</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Limitations of Available Automation and Abstraction Technologies</head><p>Recent years have seen a proliferation of cloud management automation technologies. Some of these solutions (e.g., AWS OpsWorks) tend to focus on automation as opposed to abstraction. They include scripts that automatically create virtual machines, install software applications, and manage the machine/software lifecycle. Some are even able to dynamically scale the computing capacity <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[36,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">38,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">39]</ref>. Unfortunately, none of these solutions provide a way to explicitly document the dependencies between the deployed applications. Instead, dependencies are inferred using solution-specific methods for provider-specific platforms. Not only is this unreliable (e.g., applications may have non-standard dependencies in some deployments), but it lacks the capability to maintain the dependency after the system is generated. Ubuntu Juju <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[41]</ref> is a special case that is described and discussed in Section 6 (Related Work). Recent years have also seen a general movement towards more abstractions at various levels of cloud services, especially in PaaS. Examples include Windows Azure Service Definition Schema (.csdef) <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">[57]</ref> and Google AppEngine (GAE) YAML-based specification language <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[16]</ref>. These abstractions are focused on a particular PaaS, thus they have no need to separate the platform from user requirements. Rather, they simply abstract away some details to make it easier for users to use the particular platform to deploy their apps. The abstractions only capture applications under the users' control and do not include platform service structures. As a result the abstractions cannot support compiling abstract specifications to different cloud platforms 2 .</p><p>Systems like Maestro <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[22]</ref>, Maestro-NG <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[23]</ref>, Deis <ref type="bibr">[9]</ref>, and Flynn <ref type="bibr">[15]</ref> are based on the Linux Containers <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[21]</ref> virtualization approach (specifically the Docker open-source engine <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[10]</ref>). Some of the description languages in these systems (specifically Maestro and MaestroNG) can capture dependencies among the containers (applications) through named channels. However, these specifications abstract instances (virtual machines), as opposed to the whole system. There is no formal model to define a globally consistent view of the system, and as a result once a system is deployed it is challenging to perform reliable configuration updates. Current Dockerbased solutions are primarily focused on the initial configuration/deployment; maintenance is usually not addressed or they resort to a re-deployment process.</p><p>The lack of a consistent high-level abstraction describ-ing the complete IT system creates a number of challenges in configuring cloud-based systems: network deployments and changes cannot be automatically validated, automated solutions are error-prone, incremental changes are challenging (if not impossible) to automate, and configuration definitions are unique to specific cloud providers and are not easily ported to other providers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Enabling Technologies</head><p>Several new technologies have facilitated the development of our current prototype. In particular, there have been several advancements in the configuration management tools (CMT) that help streamline the configuration management process. This is especially beneficial to our work, since those technologies are the perfect building blocks for our compilation process. To help the reader better understand our approach, we present a basic background on the state-of-the-art CMTs. Two popular configuration management solutions are Chef <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[34]</ref> and Puppet <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[20]</ref>. We use Puppet but similar concepts exist in Chef as well. Puppet works by installing an agent on the host to be managed, which communicates with a controller (called the master) to receive configuration directives. Directives are written in a declarative language called Puppet manifests, which define the desired configuration state of the host (e.g., installed packages, configuration files, running services, etc.). If the host's current state is different than the manifest received by the Puppet agent, the agent will issue appropriate commands to bring the system into the specified state.</p><p>In Puppet, manifests can be reused by extracting the directives and placing them in classes. Puppet classes use parameters to separate the configuration data (e.g., IP addresses, port numbers, version numbers, etc.) from the configuration logic. Classes can be packaged together in a Puppet module for reuse. Typically, classes are bound to nodes in a master manifest known as the site manifest. Puppet can also be configured to use an external program such as External Node Classifier (ENC) <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[18]</ref> or Hiera <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[35]</ref> to provide specific configuration data to the classes that will be assigned to a node.</p><p>In the current prototype we use Hiera <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[35]</ref>, which is a key/value look-up tool for configuration data. Hiera stores site-specific data and acts as a site-wide configuration file, thus separating the specific configuration information from the Puppet modules. Puppet classes can be populated with configuration data directly from Hiera, which makes it easier to re-use public Puppet modules "as is" by simply customizing the data in Hiera. Moreover, users can publish their own modules without worrying about exposing sensitive environment-specific data or clashing variable names. Hiera also supports module  <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> is an example of a Puppet class for a worker queue based on Redis <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">[47]</ref>. Puppet classes can be reused in different scenarios without hard-coding parameters: in this particular example there is only one parameter, port. The concrete value of this parameter ($exports <ref type="bibr">["redis"]</ref>["port"]) is derived from Hiera <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 2</ref>), which is shown as 6379 but can be computed automatically by a program at runtime. This allows us to calculate parameters based on the up-to-date system model, as opposed to hardcoding them. We use this technology in the compilation process described later.</p><p>We should also emphasize that while our current prototype uses Puppet, ANCOR can work with many mature CMT solutions such as Chef, SaltStack <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">[49]</ref>, Bcfg2 <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[43]</ref>, or CFEngine <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[44]</ref>. Two important properties are required for a CMT to be useable by ANCOR. First, the directives an agent receives dictates a desired state as opposed to commands for state changes, which allows configuration changes to be handled in the same way as the initial configuration. Second, there is a mechanism for reusable configuration modules (e.g., Puppet classes) that become the building blocks, or the "instruction set," into which ANCOR can compile the abstract requirement model. Depending on the specific CMT features, an orchestrator component might also be needed (especially in case the CMT employs only a pull-configuration model). An orchestrator component can be used on the CMT master node to trigger different actions on the CMT agents (achieve a push-configuration model). The key idea behind our approach is to abstract the functionality and structure of IT services into a model that is used to generate and manage concrete systems. We call this abstraction the requirement model. We also maintain the details of the concrete system in the system model. The two constitute the Operations Model. When ANCOR compiles a requirement model into a concrete, cloud-based system, the system model is populated with the details of the cloud instances and their correspondence to the requirement model. When the system changes, the system model is updated to ensure it has a consistent and accurate view of the deployment. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Fig- ure 14</ref>, part of the Appendix, shows the complete entityrelation diagram for the operations model. The Compiler references the requirement model to make implementation decisions necessary to satisfy the abstract requirements and to instruct the conductor to orchestrate the provisioning and configuration of the instances. It can also instruct the conductor to perform user-requested configuration changes while ensuring the concrete system always satisfies the requirement model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">The ANCOR Framework</head><p>The Conductor consists of two sub-components, Provisioning and Configuring, which are responsible for interacting with the cloud-provider API, the CMT and orchestration tools (shown below the dashed line).</p><p>The ANCOR framework manages the relationships and dependencies between instances as well as instance clustering. Such management involves creating and deleting instances, adding/removing instances to/from clusters, and keeping dependent instances/clusters aware of configuration updates. The ANCOR framework simplifies network management as system dependencies are formalized and automatically maintained. Moreover, tra-  ditional failures can also be addressed, thus increasing network resiliency. Next, we explain the requirement model, the way it is compiled into a concrete system, and how it is used to better manage that system.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Requirement Model</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.1">The ARML language</head><p>We specify the requirement model in a domain-specific language called the ANCOR Requirement Modeling Language (ARML). ARML's concrete syntax is based on YAML <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[12]</ref>, which is a language that supports specification of arbitrary key-value pairs. The abstract syntax of ARML is described in the Appendix ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 13</ref>). <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4</ref> shows an example ARML specification for an eCommerce website in <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>. The example is a scalable and highly available eCommerce website on a cloud infrastructure, which adopts a multiple-layer architecture with the various clusters of services shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>: web load balancer (Varnish <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">[55]</ref>), web application (Ruby on Rails <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">[48]</ref> ) with Unicorn <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[30]</ref>, HAProxy <ref type="bibr">[17]</ref> and Nginx <ref type="bibr">[29]</ref>), database (MySQL <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[26]</ref>), worker application (Sidekiq <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[40]</ref>), and messaging queue (Redis <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">[47]</ref>). Arrows indicate dependency between the clusters. Each cluster consists of mul-  <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>: eCommerce Website tiple instances that offer the same services. Clustering supports scaling via cluster expansion (adding more instances to the cluster) or contraction (removing instances from the cluster). The clustering strategies employed by these applications fall into two main categories: homogeneous and master-slave. In a homogeneous cluster all cluster members have the same configuration. If one of the instances stops working, another instance takes over. In master-slave, the master and slave instances have different configurations and perform different functions (e.g., write versus read). If the master fails, a slave is promoted to be the master. In this example system, the web load balancer, web application, and the worker application employ the homogeneous clustering while the database employs master-slave (thus MySQL master and MySQL slaves form one cluster). Redis is used as a messaging queue. The clustering approach, mainly replication, supported by Redis is not suited for high-throughput queues.</p><p>A requirement model contains the specifications of system goals and roles. A goal is a high-level business goal (e.g., blog website, eCommerce website, etc.) whose purpose is to organize the IT capabilities (roles) around business objectives. In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4</ref> there is a single system goal ecommerce that is supported by six roles.</p><p>A role defines a logical unit of configuration. Examples include a database role, a web application role, a message broker role, and so on. In essence, a role represents a group of similarly configured instances that provide the same functionality. In our model we use a single role to represent all the instances that achieve that functionality. For example, the web application instances in <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref> are configured identically (except for network addresses) and multiple load balancers dispatch incoming web requests to the instances in the web application cluster. We have a single role webapp for all the web application instances, and a weblb role for all the load balancer instances. The role-to-instance mapping is maintained in the system model.</p><p>A role may depend on other roles. A role uses a channel to interact with other roles. A channel is an interface exported (provided) by a role and possibly imported (consumed) by other roles. Channels could include a single network port or a range of ports. For instance, the webapp role exports an http channel, which is a TCP port (e.g., 80). The weblb role imports the http channel from the webapp role. A role is a "black box" to other roles, and only the exported channels are visible interfaces. Using these interfaces the requirement model captures the dependencies between the roles.</p><p>The webapp role also imports three channels from various other roles: querying from db master, querying from db slave, and redis from work queue.</p><p>This means the webapp role depends upon three other roles: db master, db slave, and work queue. The min field indicates the minimum number of instances that should be deployed to play the role. If min is not specified it's default value is 1. In the current prototype implementation the count of the instances will be equal to min. The requirement model addresses instance clustering naturally by requiring multiple instances to play a role. For homogeneous clusters this is easy to understand. For master-slave clusters, at least two roles are involved in the cluster, the master and the slave. The dependency information captured in the export/import relationship is sufficient to support calculating configuration changes when, for example, the master is removed from the cluster and a new node is promoted to be the master. So far we have not found any real-world clustering strategies that require explicitly modeling the cluster structure beyond the dependency relationship between the roles that form the cluster. If more general clustering strategies are needed, we will extend our requirement model to support this.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.2">Role Implementation</head><p>Role names are system-specific and are chosen by the user or system engineers to convey a notion of the role's purpose in the system; there are no pre-defined role names in ARML. However, to automatically compile and maintain concrete systems, system engineers must provide the semantics of each role, which is specified in the role specification's implementation field. The implementation field defines how each instance must be configured to play the role. The conductor then uses this implementation information to properly configure and deploy the concrete instances. The value of the implementation field is thus dependent on the CMT being used. This process is similar to traditional programming language compilers where abstract code constructs are compiled down to machine code. The compiler must contain the semantics of each code construct in terms of machine instructions for a specific architecture. The analogy between our AN-COR compiler and a programming language compiler naturally begs the question: "what is the architectureequivalent of a cloud-based IT system?" In other words, is there an interface to a "cloud runtime" into which we can compile an abstract specification?</p><p>It turns out that a well-defined interface between the requirement model and the "cloud runtime" is well within reach if we leverage existing CMT technologies. As explained in Section 2.2, there has been a general movement in CMT towards encapsulating commonlyused configuration directives into reusable, parameterized modules. Thus, one can use both community and custom modules to implement roles and populate those reusable knowledge units with parameters derived from our high-level requirement model. Potential role implementations must be specified in a role's "implementations" field (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4)</ref>. A role may have multiple implementations since there could be more than one way to achieve its functionality. The compiler then selects an appropriate role implementation from those that satisfy all constraints levied by existing role implementations in the system. (The current prototype simply selects the first role implementation in the "implementations" field; we leave the constraint specification and implementation selection problems for future work.)</p><p>An important challenge was structuring the knowledge units so that they could be easily reused in different requirement models. Failing to have a proper role implementation design model would lead to rewriting every single role implementation from scratch. We adopted an approach similar to that used by Dunn <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[11]</ref>. We name role implementations based on their functionality and/or properties (e.g., weblb) and use "profiles" to integrate individual components to embody a logical software stack. The software stack is constructed using community and custom modules as lower-level components <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">3</ref> .</p><p>For instance, in case of the load balancer: The weblb role is assigned the default implementation in the ARML specification (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4)</ref>. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 6</ref> is a Puppet class that shows the implementation that was defined as default for the weblb. <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref> pictures a sample of possible parameters that Puppet is getting through Hiera from the compiler for configuring one of the weblb instances. There are two parts in each role implementation (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 6</ref>). The code before "---" imports operations model values from Hiera (e.g., see <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref>). The statements hiera("exports") and hiera("imports") query Hiera to find all the channels the web balancer will consume (imports) and the channels that it will make available to other roles (exports). These channels will be stored in two variables, <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">3</ref> All default role implementations used with ANCOR are available on GitHub: https://github.com/arguslab/ancor-puppet { "exports": { "http": { "port": 80, "protocol": "tcp" } }, "imports": { "webapp": { "webapp-ce66a264": { "ip_address": "10.118.117.16", "stage": "undefined", "planned_stage": "deploy", "http": { "port": 42683, "protocol": "tcp" } }, "webapp-84407edd": { "ip_address": "10.118.117.19", "stage": "undefined", "planned_stage": "deploy", "http": { "port": 23311, "protocol": "tcp" } }, "webapp-1ce1ce46": { "ip_address": "10.118.117.22", "stage": "undefined", "planned_stage": "deploy", "http": { "port": 10894, "protocol": "tcp" } } } }, "classes": [ "role::weblb::default" ] } <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref>: Specific weblb Paramaters Sample Exposed to Hiera by ANCOR "exports" and "imports". The web balancer will be instructed to expose an http channel on the particular port (in this case port 80, see "exports" in <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref>), and will be configured to use all instances that are assigned to play the role webapp, from which it imports the http channel.</p><p>The default weblb implementation is based on the reusable Puppet "Varnish profile" (profile::varnish -see <ref type="figure">Figure 8</ref>).</p><p>The profile::varnish Puppet class uses the necessary specified parameters to customize the Varnish installation.</p><p>The parameters in profile::varnish (e.g., $listen address, $listen port, etc.) are initialized with default values. These values will be overwritten in case they are specified in role::weblb::default. In the current example, $listen port is the only parameter that will be overwritten (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 6</ref>), the other parameters will keep their default values defined in  Thus, a role implementation definition specifies a concrete way to implement the intended functionality embodied by a role by describing the invocation of predefined configuration modules with concrete parameters computed from the operations model. These role implementations are not only useful when generating the system, but also for modifying the system as it changes over time. For example, if a new instance is deployed to play the webapp role, the dependency structure in the operations model allows ANCOR to automatically find all the other roles that may be impacted (those depending on the webapp role) and use their role implementation to direct the CMT to reconfigure them so that they are consistent with the updated operations model. ANCOR leverages existing CMT to define the role implementations, to minimize additional work that has to be done by the system engineers. For example, only information in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 6</ref> is what one needs to write for AN-COR; <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref> is generated automatically by ANCOR; <ref type="figure">Figure 8</ref>, 9, and 10 are what one would have to specify anyway using Puppet.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">The ANCOR Workflow</head><p>There are four main phases involved in creating and managing cloud-based systems using ANCOR.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Requirements model specification 2. Compilation choices specification 3. Compilation/Deployment 4. Maintenance</head><p>The first two phases result in the creation of the requirement model while the next two phases perform the actual deployment and maintenance of the cloud-based system.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.1">Requirement Model Specification</head><p>In this phase, the user and system engineers work together to define the goals of the system, which may require significant input from various stakeholders. Next, they determine the roles required to achieve each goal and the dependencies among the roles. This task could be handled by the system engineers alone or in consultation with the user. The high-level requirement language ARML provides an abstract, common language for this communication.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.2">Compilation Choices Specification</head><p>In this phase, system engineers define role semantics using pre-defined CMT modules. In our current prototype this is accomplished by defining the role implementations that invoke Puppet classes as described in Section 3.1.2. If no appropriate CMT modules exist, system engineers must define new profiles and place them into the repository for future use. In general, system engineers could specify multiple implementation choices for each role to provide the ANCOR compiler flexibility in choosing the appropriate implementation at runtime. One of the options available to system engineers is the specification of the desired operating system for each instance. Here again, different operating systems may be used for each implementation of a role. With a wide variety of choices available to systems engineers, a constraint language is needed to specify the compatibility among the various implementation choices; we leave this for future research.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.3">Compilation/Deployment</head><p>Once the requirement model has been defined, the framework can automatically compile the requirements into a working system on the cloud provider's infrastructure. This process has seven key steps:</p><p>1. The framework signals the compiler to deploy a specific requirement model. The provisioning module uses a package such as cloud-init to initialize each cloud instance, including installing the CMT and orchestration tool agents (e.g., the Puppet agent and MCollective <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[19]</ref> agent). 5. Once an instance is live, the message orchestrator (e.g., MCollective) prepares the instance for configuration by distributing its authentication key to the CMT master (e.g., Puppet master). 6. The configuration is pushed to the authenticated instances using the CMT agent and, if needed, the orchestrator (e.g., Puppet agent and MCollective). 7. System engineers may check deployed services by using system monitoring applications such as Sensu <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">[50]</ref> or Opsview <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[46]</ref> , or by directly accessing the instances.</p><p>In step 6, configuration is carried out via the Hiera component while configuration directives (node manifests) are computed on the fly using ANCOR's operations model. This ensures that the parameters used to instantiate the Puppet modules always reflect the up-todate system dependency information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.4">Maintenance</head><p>Once the system is deployed in the cloud, system engineers can modify the system. If the change does not affect the high-level requirement model, the maintenance is straightforward. The compiler will track the impacted instances using the operations model and reconfigure them using the up-to-date system information. A good example for this type of change is cluster expansion/contraction.</p><p>Cluster expansion is used to increase the number of instances in a cluster (e.g., to serve more requests or for high-availability purposes).</p><p>1. System engineers instruct the compiler to add instances to a specific role. In future work we also would like to allow monitoring modules to make expansion decisions as well. 2. The compiler triggers the conductor component to create new instances, which automatically updates the ANCOR system model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">The compiler calculates the instances that depend</head><p>on the role and instructs the configuration manager to re-configure the dependent instances based on the up-to-date ANCOR system model.</p><p>Cluster contraction is the opposite of cluster expansion. The main goal of cluster contraction is to reduce the number of instances in a cluster (e.g., to lower cost).</p><p>1. System engineers instruct the compiler to mark a portion of a role's instances for removal. 2. The compiler calculates the instances that depend on the role and instructs the configuration manager to re-configure the dependent instances based on the up-to-date ANCOR system model. 3. The compiler triggers the conductor component to remove the marked instances.</p><p>If the change involves major modifications in the requirement model (e.g., adding/removing a role), ANCOR will need to re-compile the requirement model. How to perform "incremental recompilation" that involve major structural changes without undue disruption will be a topic for future research.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Prototype Implementation</head><p>We built a prototype <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(Figure 3</ref>) in Ruby (using Rails, Sidekiq and Redis) to implement the ANCOR framework using OpenStack as the target cloud platform. The operations model is stored in MongoDB collections using Rails. ANCOR employs straight-forward type-checking to ensure that the requirement model is well-formed (e.g., allowing a role to import a channel from another role only if the channel is exported by that role). The compiler references the MongoDB document collections that store the operations model and interacts with the conductor using a Redis messaging queue and Sidekiq, a worker application used for background processing. The conductor interacts with the OpenStack API through Fog (a cloud services library for Ruby) to provision the network, subnets and instances indicated by the compiler. Once an instance is live, the configuration module uses Puppet and MCollective to configure it using the manifest computed on the fly based on the operations model. The conductor also interacts with the system model and updates the provided system model database every time it performs a task (provisioning or configuration). Therefore, the system model stored in the MongoDB datastore will always have an updated picture of the system. Obviously, the different role implementation choices (e.g., Sidekiq, Redis or Rails) used to build the eCommerce website example scenario ( <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>) are independent from the components that leverage Sidekiq, Redis and Ruby on Rails in the ANCOR framework prototype <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(Figure 3)</ref> In the current implementation we are using a workflow model that is based on chained and parallel tasks processing. Once the ARML specification is entered by the user, the specification will be parsed and the requirement model will be encountered. Next, the compiler steps in and based on the requirement model it chooses the number of instances that play a role, the role implementations, the IP addresses, the channels (port number and/or sockets that will be consumed or exposed), etc. Then the compiler populates the system model and creates various tasks that it passes to the worker queue. A task can be viewed as an assignment that is passed to a background (worker) process. In ANCOR, Sidekiq is used for background processing. Tasks are stored in the database and have several attributes (e.g., type, arguments, state, context) A task can be related to provisioning (e.g., using Fog) or to configuring an instance (e.g., push configuration from Puppet master to Puppet agent). In case other tasks (e.g., deploy instance) depend on the execution of the current task (e.g., create network) a wait handle is created. Wait handles can be viewed as the mechanism used by the tasks to signal dependent tasks when they finished execution. A task creates a wait handle object that stores the ids of the tasks that wait for it to execute. Once the task finished the wait handle triggers all the dependent tasks to execute. The purpose of a wait handle is to start, resume or suspend the dependent tasks. Using this approach we can resume or suspend a task several times including tasks related to the orchestration tool (MCollective) and the CMT (Puppet). Independent tasks (e.g., two different deploy instance tasks) will be executed in parallel employing locks on certain shared resources. The ANCOR prototype code, detailed instructions on how to deploy/run it and a detailed document containing specific implementation details are available online at https://github.com/arguslab/ancor.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Using ANCOR</head><p>The current framework implementation exposes a REST API <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[14]</ref> to it's clients. The current clients include a Command-Line Interface (CLI), a web-browser dashboard and also the Puppet master (specifically the Hiera module). Through the REST API, Hiera is obtaining the specific configuration details (e.g., imported and exported channels -$exports and $imports arrays, see <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>) from the compiler in order to customize the Puppet modules that are part of the chosen role implementation (e.g., see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2</ref>). The CLI and the dashboard are used to deploy, manage, visualize (in case of the dashboard) and delete ANCOR deployments.</p><p>One can use the CLI to deploy, manage and delete the eCommerce website example using several key commands:</p><p>1. ancor environment plan eCommerce.yamlplans the deployment (eCommerce.yaml is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4</ref>) 2. ancor role list -lists the current set of roles 3. ancor instance list -lists the current set of instances 4. ancor environment commit -deploys the environment on the cloud infrastructure 5. ancor task list -displays the current progress of the deployment 6. ancor instance add webapp -used to add another instance for the webapp role after all tasks are completed 7. ancor environment list -used to unlock the environment after all tasks are completed 8. ancor environment remove production -deletes the current deployment More options and instructions on using the ANCOR CLI and the dashboard are available on the framework website.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Prototype Evaluation</head><p>The objective of our evaluation is to measure the dynamics of change management. This implies measuring how much the performance of a deployed IT system is influenced when adding and removing instances using AN-COR. Throughput and latency values are highly dependent on the applications' configurations and on the underlying cloud infrastructure. Thus, we are not focused on the throughput and latency themselves but on the difference between the baseline measurements and the measurements during system changes. We evaluated our prototype using two IT system setups: a basic blogging website ( <ref type="figure">Figure 11</ref>) and the eCommerce website scenario ( <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>). These scenarios are also available online. As we add other scenarios into the repository and integrate ANCOR with different cloud infrastructures (AWS will likely be the next infrastructure supported), we plan to expand this evaluation.</p><p>The current testing scenarios were deployed on a private cloud testbed in the Argus CyberSecurity Laboratory at Kansas State University. The cloud testbed consists of fifteen Dell PowerEdge R620 servers, each of which is equipped with 2 x Intel Xeon E-2660 v2 Processor@2.20GHz, 128GB of RAM, 4 x 1TB 7.2K HDD running in RAID0 (Stripe) and an Intel dual port 10GbE DA/SFP+ network card. Moreover, each server is connected to the main switch (Dell Force10 -S4810P switch) using two bounded 10GbE ports.</p><p>We deployed an OpenStack Havana infrastructure on these machines using Mirantis' open-source framework Fuel <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[24]</ref>. The infrastructure consists of one controller node and fourteen compute nodes.  <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">[58]</ref>, an HTTP benchmarking tool, was used to test the system's availability and performance while managing various clusters (i.e., adding/removing instances to/from a cluster). We ran the benchmarking tool on the initially deployed scenarios and established a baseline for every component in our measurements. wrk was launched from client machines that are able to access the websites (i.e., connect to the load balancer). We targeted various links that ran operations we implemented to specifically test the various system components (e.g., read/write from/to the database ). After establishing the baseline, we started adding and removing instances to and from different clusters while targeting operations that involve the deepest cluster in the stack (database slave for the eCommerce setup). In case of the blogging website scenario we focused on the web application. The performance in the three cases are very close since we only added and removed one instance in the experiments. All caching features at the application level were disabled in both scenarios. Having caching features enabled would have prevented us from consistently reaching the targeted components; however the performance would be greatly improved. For instance, <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> exposes the baseline results for accessing a WordPress <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">[56]</ref> posts from the blogging website setup <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 12</ref>) with caching enabled.      </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.1">Blogging Website Scenario</head><p>The basic blogging website is pictured in <ref type="figure">Figure 11</ref>. When adding instances to the WordPress web application cluster, latency and throughput improve <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">(Table 3)</ref>, which is as expected. When instances are removed from the cluster the performance is slightly worse than the addinstance case, due to the decreased number of instances in the cluster. But it is still slightly better than the baseline, which has the less number of instances.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.2">eCommerce Website Scenario</head><p>When adding instances to the MySQL slaves cluster, latency slightly increases but throughput is improved (Table 6). When instances are removed from the cluster both performance metrics were negatively affected ( <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">Table 7)</ref>.</p><p>These results show that 1) the ANCOR system is reliable in generating a concrete IT system in the cloud from a high-level requirement model specification; and 2) the formal models in ANCOR help facilitate orchestrating changes in the cloud-based IT system such as scaling.</p><p>It is important not to disregard the fact that all benchmarking results were influenced by the way applications were configured (e.g., disabled caching functionality and "hot-swap" feature). The "hot-swap" feature loads an updated configuration without restarting a service (e.g., Unicorn), which could further improve performance if one further tunes these applications.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Discussion and Future Work</head><p>Our requirements specification approach and the implemented ANCOR framework offer system engineers the same flexibility as in a typical IaaS model. This means that engineers can keep their workflow using their preferred configuration management tools (e.g., Puppet and Chef) and orchestration tools (e.g., MCollective). They have the option to do everything in their preferred ways up to the point where they connect the components (services) together. For example, system engineers have the option of using predefined configuration modules and of leveraging the contributions from the CMT community. Or they can write their own manifests or class definitions to customize the system in their own ways. ANCOR can leverage all of these and does not force the system engineers to use particular low-level tools or languages; rather it provides the ability to manage the whole system based on a high-level abstraction.</p><p>The high-level requirement model we developed could also facilitate tasks like failure diagnosis and system analysis to identify design weaknesses such as single point of failures or performance bottlenecks. The system dependency information specified in the requirement model and maintained in the operations model allows for more reliable and streamlined system updates such as service patching. It also allows for more finegrained firewall setup (i.e., only allows network access that is consistent with the system dependency), and enables porting systems to different cloud providers in a more organized manner (e.g., one can take the up-to-date requirement model and compile it to a different cloud provider's infrastructure, and then synchronize data from the old one to the new one).</p><p>One of our future work directions is to construct a proactive change mechanism as part of the compiler. This mechanism would randomly select specific aspects of the configuration to change (e.g., replacing a portion of the instances with freshly created ones with different IP addresses, application ports, software versions, etc.); the changes would be automatically carried out by the conductor component. Moreover, changes can be scheduled based on security monitoring tools (e.g., Snort <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">[51]</ref>, Suricata <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">[52]</ref>, SnIPS <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">[59]</ref>, etc.) or on component behavior and interaction reports (using an approach similar to <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>). Our goal in this is to analyze the possible security benefits as well as to measure and analyze the performance, robustness, and resilience of the system under such disturbance. We are also considering adding SLA (Service Level Agreement) related primitives to the requirement model. Furthermore, we are looking into adding other CMT modules to support the use of multiple configuration management tools such as Chef. In addition, we are planning on developing built-in Docker support modules and switching to the OpenStack AWS compatible API that will enable us to use the same provider module on different cloud platforms.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Related Work</head><p>There has been a general trend towards creating more abstractions at various levels of cloud service offerings. Some of the solutions even use similar terminologies and features as those in ANCOR. For example, some solutions also use the term "role" in a similar way to ours <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">57]</ref>, and others have adopted named channels to describe dependencies in configuration files <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[22,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">23,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">57]</ref>. Thus it is important to describe the fundamental differences between the abstraction used in ANCOR and those in the other solutions, so that one does not get confused by the superficial similarities between them.</p><p>Abstractions used in the various PaaS solutions such as the Windows Azure service definition schema <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">[57]</ref> and Google AppEngine YAML-based specifications <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[16]</ref> allow users to define their cloud-based applications. These abstractions, while useful for helping users to use the specific PaaS platform more easily, do not serve the same purpose as ARML. In particular, they only define user-provided applications and not the complete IT system in the cloud, since the important platform components are not modeled. Thus these abstractions cannot be used to compile into different implementation choices or platforms. They are tied to the specific PaaS platform and thus will never separate the user requirements from the platform details. Using these abstractions will lock the users in to the specific PaaS vendor, while ANCOR will give users complete flexibility as to implementation choices at all levels, including platforms.</p><p>Docker container-based solutions such as Maestro <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[22]</ref>, Maestro-NG <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[23]</ref>, Deis <ref type="bibr">[9]</ref>, and Flynn <ref type="bibr">[15]</ref> provide management aid for deploying cloud instances using the Linux Containers virtualization approach. Some of them (Maestro and Maestro-NG) also have environment descriptions (in YAML) for the Docker instances that include named channels to capture dependencies. These solutions can automate initial deployment of cloud instances and make it easier to stand up a PaaS, but again they take a different approach and do not provide the same level of abstraction that supports the vision outlined in Section 1. Specifically, the abstractions provided by their environment descriptions are focused on instances as opposed to the complete IT system, the container is the unit of configuration, and maintenance tasks are done by progressing through containers. It is not clear how much the container-based solutions can help alleviate the longterm maintenance problem of cloud-based IT systems. Moreover, the container-based solutions are tied to Linux environments and Docker, which is still under heavy development and not ready for production use. We also summarized a few other features to differentiate ANCOR from the other solutions in <ref type="table" target="#tab_12">Table 8</ref>. ANCOR can be used to deploy systems using other orchestration tools such as Flynn and Deis in conjunction with traditional IT systems. As shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_12">Table 8</ref>, ANCOR is currently the most general and flexible management solution available.</p><p>Several companies are developing cloud migration technologies. While some appear to internally use abstractions to support migration <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">13]</ref>, no details are available for independent evaluation. Our approach is more fundamental in the sense that we build systems using the abstraction and, smoother and more reliable migration could be a future product of our approach. Rather than creating technology specifically to replicate existing systems, we aim to fundamentally change the way cloud-based systems are built and managed, which includes enabling dynamic and adaptive system changes, reducing human errors, and supporting more holistic security control and analysis.</p><p>Often, solutions like AWS CloudFormation <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref>, OpenStack Heat <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[31]</ref> or Terraform [53] may be, mistakenly, viewed as being at the same level of abstraction with AN-COR. These solutions are primarily focused on building and managing the infrastructure (cloud resources) by allowing the details of an infrastructure to be captured into a configuration file. CloudFormation and Heat manage AWS/OpenStack resources using templates (e.g., Wordpress template <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[33]</ref>, MySQL template <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[32]</ref>, etc.), and they do not separate user requirements from system implementation details. The templates have the potential to integrate well with configuration management tools but there is no model of the structure and dependencies of the system. Thus, it cannot achieve one main objective of ANCOR which is to use the operations model to maintain the system, e.g., updating dependencies automatically while replacing instances. Terraform similarly uses configuration files to describe the infrastructure setup, but it goes even further by being cloud-agnostic and by enabling multiple providers and services to be combined and composed <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">[54]</ref>.</p><p>Juju <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[41]</ref> is a system for managing services and works at a similar level as ANCOR. It resides above the CMT technologies and has a way of capturing the dependencies between software applications (services). It can also interact with a wide choice of cloud services or bare metal servers. The Juju client works on multiple operating systems (Ubuntu, OS X, and Windows) but Jujumanaged services run primarily on Ubuntu servers, although support for CentOS and a number of Windowsbased systems will be available in the near future <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[42]</ref>. While we were aware of the existence of Juju at the time of this paper's writing, the lack of formal documentation on how Juju actually works, the services running only on Ubuntu, and the major changes in the Juju project (e.g., code base was completely rewritten in Go) kept us away from this project. We recently reevaluated Juju and discovered fundamental similarities between ANCOR and Juju. Even so, there are subtle differences that make the two approaches work better in different environments. For instance, the ANCOR approach adopts a more "centralized" management scheme in terms of deciding the configuration parameters of dependent services, while Juju adopts a negotiation scheme between dependent services (called relations in Juju) to reach a consistent configuration state across those services. Depending on the need for change in the system, the ANCOR approach may be more advantageous when it comes to a highly dynamic system with proactive changing (e.g., in a moving target defense system).</p><p>Our approach has benefited from the recent development in the CMT technologies that have provided the building blocks (or "instruction sets") for our compiler. The general good practice in defining reusable configuration modules such as those advocated by <ref type="bibr">Dunn [11]</ref> is aligned very well with the way we structure the requirement model. Thus our approach can be easily integrated with those CMT technologies.</p><p>Sapuntzakis et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[37]</ref> proposed the configuration language CVL and the Collective system to support the creation, publication, execution, and update of virtual appliances. CVL allows for defining a network with multiple appliances and passing configuration parameters to each appliance instance through key-value pairs. The decade since the paper was published has seen dramatic improvement in configuration management tools such as Puppet <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[20]</ref> and Chef <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[34]</ref>, which has taken care of specifying/managing the configuration of individual machines. Our work leverages these mature CMTs and uses an abstraction on a higher level. In particular, ARML specifies the dependency among roles through explicit "import" and "export" statements with the channel parameters, which are translated automatically to concrete protocol and port numbers by the integration of operations model and the CMT. While CVL does specify dependency among appliances through the "provides" and "requires" variables, they are string identifiers and not tied to configuration variables of the relevant appliances (e.g., the "DNS host" configuration parameter of an LDAP server). In the CVL specification of the virtual appliance network, the programmer would need to take care in passing the correct configuration parameters (consistent with the dependency) to the relevant appliances. In ANCOR this is done automatically by the coordination between the CMT and the operations model (compiled from the high-level ARML specification). This also allows for easy adaptation of the system (e.g., cluster expansion and contraction).</p><p>Begnum  virtual machine network. Like ANCOR, MLN uses offthe-shelf configuration management solutions instead of reinventing the wheel. A major difference between AN-COR and MLN is that ANCOR captures the instance dependency in the requirement model, which facilitates automating configuration of a complete IT system and its dynamic adaptation. ANCOR achieves this by compiling the abstract specification to the operations model, which is integrated with the CMT used to deploy/manage the instances.</p><p>Plush <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref> is an application management infrastructure that provides a set of abstractions for specifying, deploying, and monitoring distributed applications (e.g., peerto-peer services, web search engines, social sites, etc.). While Plush's architecture is flexible, it is not targeted towards cloud-based enterprise systems and it is unclear whether system dependencies can be specified and maintained throughout the system lifecycle.</p><p>Narain pioneered the idea of using high-level specifications for network infrastructure configuration management in the ConfigAssure <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[27,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">28]</ref> project. ConfigAssure takes formally specified network configuration constraints and automatically finds acceptable concrete configuration parameter values using a Boolean satisfiability (SAT) solver. While we adopt Narain's philosophy of using formal models to facilitate system management, the cloud problem domain is different from that of network infrastructure, thus requiring new models and methodologies.</p><p>Use of higher-level abstractions to improve system management has also been investigated in the context of Software-Defined Networking (SDN). Monsanto et al. introduced abstractions for building applications from independent modules that jointly manage network traffic <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[25]</ref>. Their Pyretic language and system supports specification of abstract network policies, policy composition, and execution on abstract network topologies. Our AN-COR language and system adopts a similar philosophy for cloud-based deployment and management.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusion</head><p>Separating user requirements from the implementation details has the potential of changing the way IT systems are deployed and managed in the cloud. To capture user requirements, we developed a high-level abstraction called the requirement model for defining cloud-based IT systems. Once users define their desired system in the specification, it is automatically compiled into a concrete cloud-based system that meets the specified user requirements. We demonstrate the practicality of this approach in the ANCOR framework. Preliminary benchmarking results show that ANCOR can improve manageability and maintainability of a cloud-based system and enable dynamic configuration changes of a deployed system with negligible performance overhead.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8">Acknowledgments</head><p>This work was supported by the Air Force Office of Scientific Research award FA9550-12-1-0106 and U.S. National Science Foundation awards 1038366 and 1018703. Any opinions, findings and conclusions or recommendations expressed herein are those of the authors and do not necessarily reflect the views of the above agencies.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A Appendix</head><p>The abstract syntax of ARML is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 13</ref>. We use A ⇒ B to represent the key-value pairs (written as "A : B." in YAML). Upper-case identifiers represent nonterminal symbols, lower-case identifiers represent terminal symbols, and ARML keywords are distinguished by bold font. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 14</ref> shows the complete entity-relation diagram for the operations model. The arrows indicate the direction of references in the implementation (one-way or two-way references) and the associated multiplicity (1-to-1, 1-to-n, or n-to-n ). For instance, one role may support multiple goals, and multiple roles could support one goal. Thus the multiplicity between goal and role is n-ton.  The system model is a local reflection of the cloudbased IT system and, as previously mentioned, it is used for bookkeeping. This enables the user to track instances in terms of roles. Furthermore, the system model bridges the gap between the more abstract requirement model and the many different concrete systems that can implement it. The requirement model is considered read-only by the rest of the framework. On the other hand, the system model can be updated by every component in the framework.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>USENIX Association</head><p>An instance is a virtual machine that is assigned to play a role. A role can be played by more than one instance but an instance currently can play only one role. A role can have one or more ways of being implemented. This aspect is captured in RoleImplementation. RoleImplementation is equivalent to Scenario in the current prototype code. A NIC stores the MAC address(es) that belong to an instance and a Network stores the network(s) that an instance is connected to. Moreover, an instance has access to the ports that a role consumes or exposes (channels) through ChannelSelection. A Channel can be a single port or a range of ports. The cloud provider firewall configuration (known as "security groups" in OpenStack) is captured in SecurityGroup. One SecurityGroup can have multiple configuration entries, SecurityRules. ProviderEndpoint captures the cloud platform specific API. This component makes it easier to integrate AN-COR with different cloud providers. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Puppet Worker Queue Class classes: -role::work_queue::default exports: redis: { port: 6379 } Figure 2: Hiera Configuration Data customization by enabling the configuration of default data with multiple levels of overrides. Figure 1 is an example of a Puppet class for a worker queue based on Redis [47]. Puppet classes can be reused in different scenarios without hard-coding parameters: in this particular example there is only one parameter, port. The concrete value of this parameter ($exports["redis"]["port"]) is derived from Hiera (Figure 2), which is shown as 6379 but can be computed automatically by a program at runtime. This allows us to calculate parameters based on the up-to-date system model, as opposed to hardcoding them. We use this technology in the compilation process described later. We should also emphasize that while our current prototype uses Puppet, ANCOR can work with many mature CMT solutions such as Chef, SaltStack [49], Bcfg2 [43], or CFEngine [44]. Two important properties are required for a CMT to be useable by ANCOR. First, the directives an agent receives dictates a desired state as opposed to commands for state changes, which allows configuration changes to be handled in the same way as the initial configuration. Second, there is a mechanism for reusable configuration modules (e.g., Puppet classes) that become the building blocks, or the "instruction set," into which ANCOR can compile the abstract requirement model. Depending on the specific CMT features, an orchestrator component might also be needed (especially in case the CMT employs only a pull-configuration model). An orchestrator component can be used on the CMT master node to trigger different actions on the CMT agents (achieve a push-configuration model).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 3 shows</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3 shows the three major components of the AN-COR framework: the Operations Model, the Compiler, and the Conductor. The arrows denote information flow. The key idea behind our approach is to abstract the functionality and structure of IT services into a model that is used to generate and manage concrete systems.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: ANCOR Framework</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: eCommerce Website Requirements Specification</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Figure 6: Web Load Balancer Role Implementation</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>#</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 8: Web Load Balancer Role Profile</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 9 :Figure 10 :</head><label>910</label><figDesc>Figure 9: Web Load Balancer, Varnish, Initialization Script: default.erb (used in profile::varnish)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>The compiler makes several implementation deci- sions including the number of instances used for each role and the flavors, operating systems, and role implementations used. 3. The compiler signals the conductor component to begin deployment. 4. The conductor interacts with the OpenStack API to provision instances and create the necessary secu- rity rules (configure the cloud's internal firewall).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>ReqModel</head><label></label><figDesc>::= goals ⇒ GoalSpec + roles ⇒ RoleSpec + GoalSpec ::= goalID ⇒ [name ⇒ string] roles ⇒ roleID + RoleSpec ::= roleID ⇒ [name ⇒ string] [min ⇒ integer] [exports ⇒ ChannelSpec + ] [imports ⇒ ImportSpec + ] implementations ⇒ ImplementationSpec + ChannelSpec ::= chanelID ⇒ (type ⇒ channelTypeID, ChannelAttr * ) ChannelAttr ::= attributeID ⇒ value ImportSpec ::= roleID ⇒ channelID + ImplementationSpec ::= implementationID ⇒ value goalID, roleID, channelID, attributeID, channelTypeID, strategyID, implementationID, clusterID, tag are symbols. integer and string are defined in the usual way.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Figure 13 :</head><label>13</label><figDesc>Figure 13: ARML Grammar</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Figure 14 :</head><label>14</label><figDesc>Figure 14: Operations Model</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Benchmarking -Blogging Website Scenario -
webapp cluster (baseline) 

4 threads and 40 connections 
Avg 
Stdev 
Max 
+/-Stdev 
Latency 
418.76ms 
268.63ms 
1.88s 
78.65% 
96.63 requests/sec, 28989 requests in 5 min 
Timeouts: 0 
Errors (non-2xx or 3xx HTTP responses): 0 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Benchmarking -Blogging Website Scenario -
webapp cluster (adding one instance) 

4 threads and 40 connections 
Avg 
Stdev 
Max 
+/-Stdev 
Latency 
456.13ms 
325.94ms 
1.34s 
73.53% 
89.49 requests/sec, 26849 requests in 5 min 
Timeouts: 0 
Errors (non-2xx or 3xx HTTP responses): 0 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" validated="false"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Benchmarking -Blogging Website Scenario -
webapp cluster (removing an instance) 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7" validated="false"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Benchmarking -db slave cluster (baseline) 

4 threads and 40 connections 
Avg 
Stdev 
Max 
+/-Stdev 
Latency 
17.21ms 
20.22ms 
161.34ms 
93.13% 
771.71 requests/sec, 231563 requests in 5 min 
Timeouts: 4292 
Errors (non-2xx or 3xx HTTP responses): 0 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8" validated="false"><head>Table 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Benchmarking -db slave cluster (adding one 
instance) 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10" validated="false"><head>Table 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Benchmarking -db slave cluster (removing 
one instance) </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_12" validated="false"><head>Table 8 : Current Solutions Comparison</head><label>8</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Current ANCOR implementation is available and is distributed under the GNU (version 3) General Public License terms on: https: //arguslab.github.io/ancor/ Tags: cloud, modeling networking configuration, configuration management, deployment automation</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> Indeed, it appears that these abstractions will likely make it harder for users to move to other cloud providers as they are platform-specific.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A query language for understanding component interactions in production systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Oliner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Aiken</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 24th ACM International Conference on Supercomputing (ICS)</title>
		<meeting>the 24th ACM International Conference on Supercomputing (ICS)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="201" to="210" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distributed Application Configuration, Management, and Visualization with Plush</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Albrecht</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Tuttle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Braud</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Dao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Topilski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Snoeren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Vahdat</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">In ACM Transactions on Internet Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">11</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A View of Cloud Computing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Armbust</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Fox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Griffith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Joseph</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Katz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Konwinski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Patterson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Rabkin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Stoica</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Zaharia</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Communications of the ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="50" to="58" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aws</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://aws.amazon.com/cloudformation/" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Security Analysis of Amazon&apos;s Elastic Compute Cloud Service</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Balduzzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zaddach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Balzarotti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Kirda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Loureiro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 27th Annual ACM Symposium on Applied Computing (SAC)</title>
		<meeting>the 27th Annual ACM Symposium on Applied Computing (SAC)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1427" to="1434" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Managing Large Networks of Virtual Machines</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Begnum</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">LISA</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 20th USENIX conference on Large Installation System Administration</title>
		<meeting>the 20th USENIX conference on Large Installation System Administration</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">AmazonIA: When Elasticity Snaps Back</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bugiel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Nürnberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Pöppelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sadeghi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Schneider</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 18th ACM conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS)</title>
		<meeting>the 18th ACM conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="389" to="400" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">One hybrid cloud software</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Cloudvelocity</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<publisher>CloudVelocity Software</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Learn What Docker Is All About -accessed 1</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Docker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.docker.io/learnmore/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Designing Puppet: Roles and Profiles -accessed 10</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Craig</forename><surname>Dunn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.craigdunn.org/2012/05/239/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://yaml.org/" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Run any app on any cloud&apos; is CliQr&apos;s bold claim. 451 Research</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Fellows</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://cdn1.hubspot.com/hub/194983/Runanyapponanycloud.pdf" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013-01" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Architectural Styles and the Design of Networkbased Software Architectures</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Fielding</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<pubPlace>Irvine</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of California</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">PhD thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<ptr target="https://developers.google.com/appengine/docs/python/config/appconfig" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Google Developers -accessed</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">External Node Classifiers -accessed 9</title>
		<ptr target="http://docs.puppetlabs.com/guides/externalnodes.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Puppet Labs</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">What is MCollective and what does it allow you to do? -accessed 9</title>
		<ptr target="http://puppetlabs.com/mcollective" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Puppet Labs</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">What is Puppet? -accessed 9</title>
		<ptr target="http://puppetlabs.com/puppet/what-is-puppet" />
		<imprint/>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Puppet Labs</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lxc -Linux</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://linuxcontainers.org/" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Maestro Github repository -accessed 1</title>
		<ptr target="https://github.com/toscanini/maestro" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">-Ng</forename><surname>Maestro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Github</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://github.com/signalfuse/maestro-ng" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mirantis Software Website</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://software.mirantis.com/" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Composing Software-Defined Networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Monsanto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Reich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Foster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rexford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 10th USENIX conference on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI)</title>
		<meeting>the 10th USENIX conference on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="14" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">MySQL website -accessed 9</title>
		<ptr target="http://www.mysql.com/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Declarative infrastructure configuration synthesis and debugging</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sanjai</forename><surname>Narain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gary</forename><surname>Levin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sharad</forename><surname>Malik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vikram</forename><surname>Kaul</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Network and Systems Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="235" to="258" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards eliminating configuration errors in cyber infrastructure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sharad</forename><surname>Sanjai Narain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ehab</forename><surname>Malik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Al-Shaer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of 4th IEEE Symposium on Configuration Analytics and Automation (SafeConfig)</title>
		<meeting>4th IEEE Symposium on Configuration Analytics and Automation (SafeConfig)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="2" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<ptr target="https://github.com/defunkt/unicorn" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Unicorn! Repository on GitHub. What it is</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Openstack</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://wiki.openstack.org/wiki/Heat" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Heat/CloudFormation MySQL Template -accessed 5</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Openstack</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://github.com/openstack/heat-templates/blob/master/cfn/F17/MySQLSingleInstance.template" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Heat/CloudFormation Wordpress Templateaccessed 5</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Openstack</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://github.com/openstack/heat-templates/blob/master/cfn/F17/WordPressWithLB.template" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Opscode</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.opscode.com/chef/" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<ptr target="http://docs.puppetlabs.com/hiera/1/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PuppetLabs Docs -accessed</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">White Paper -Quantifying the Benefits of the RightScale Cloud Management Platform -accessed</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Rightscale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Virtual Appliances for Deploying and Maintaining Software</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Sapuntzakis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Brumley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Chandra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Zeldovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Chow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Lam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rosenblum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 17th USENIX conference on Large Installation System Administration (LISA)</title>
		<meeting>the 17th USENIX conference on Large Installation System Administration (LISA)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="181" to="194" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">White Paper -Managing the Cloud as an Incremental Step Forward -accessed 8</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">-</forename><surname>Service</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.techrepublic.com/resource-library/whitepapers/managing-the-cloud-as-an-incremental-step-forward/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<ptr target="http://aws.amazon.com/opsworks/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amazon Web Services. AWS OpsWorks</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Sidekiq Repository on GitHub -accessed 2</title>
		<ptr target="https://github.com/mperham/sidekiq" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ubuntu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://juju.ubuntu.com/" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Steven</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Vaughan-Nichols</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<ptr target="http://www.zdnet.com/canonical-juju-devops-tool-coming-to-centos-and-windows-7000029418/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Canonical Juju DevOps Tool Coming to CentOS and Windows</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">What is Bcfg2? -accessed 4</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Bcfg2 Website</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://docs.bcfg2.org/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">What is CFEngine</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cfengine</forename><surname>Website</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://cfengine.com/what-is-cfengine" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Openstack</forename><surname>Website</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.openstack.org/" />
		<title level="m">Open Source Software for Building Private and Public Clouds -accessed 4</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Opsview</forename><surname>Website</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.opsview.com/" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Redis -accessed 4</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Redis</forename><surname>Website</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://redis.io/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Ruby is</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruby</forename><surname>Website</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.ruby-lang.org/en/" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">What is SaltStack? -accessed 4</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Saltstack</forename><surname>Website</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://saltstack.com/community.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sensu</forename><surname>Website</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://sensuapp.org/" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">What is Snort? -accessed 4</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Snort Website</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.snort.org/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Suricata</forename><surname>Website</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://suricata-ids.org/" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Terraform -accessed 9</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Terraform</forename><surname>Website</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.terraform.io/intro/index.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Terraform</forename><surname>Website</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.terraform.io/intro/vs/cloudformation.html" />
		<title level="m">Terraform vs. Other Software -accessed 9</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Varnish Cache Website</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.varnish-cache.org/about" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">WordPress -accessed 4</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wordpress</forename><surname>Website</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://wordpress.org/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<ptr target="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/windowsazure/ee758711.aspx" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Windows Azure Service Definition Schema (.csdef</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Github</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://github.com/wg/wrk" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Prioritizing intrusion analysis using DempsterShafer theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zomlot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Chandran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Sundaramurthy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Luo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Ou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Rajagopalan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 4th ACM workshop on Security and artificial intelligence (AISec)</title>
		<meeting>the 4th ACM workshop on Security and artificial intelligence (AISec)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="59" to="70" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
