<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/atharsefid/Desktop/grobid-0.5.3/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.3" ident="GROBID" when="2020-10-16T20:09+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">LINA: Identifying Comparable Documents from Wikipedia</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="2015-07-30">July 30, 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Emmanuel</forename><surname>Morin</surname></persName>
							<email>emmanuel.morin@univ-nantes.fr</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="laboratory">LINA -UMR CNRS 6241</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Université de Nantes</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amir</forename><surname>Hazem</surname></persName>
							<email>amir.hazem@lium.univ-lemans.fr</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elizaveta</forename><surname>Loginova-Clouet</surname></persName>
							<email>elizaveta.loginova@univ-nantes.fr</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="laboratory">LINA -UMR CNRS 6241</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Université de Nantes</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Florian</forename><surname>Boudin</surname></persName>
							<email>florian.boudin@univ-nantes.fr</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="laboratory">LINA -UMR CNRS 6241</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Université de Nantes</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">LIUM -EA 4023</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Université du Maine</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">LINA: Identifying Comparable Documents from Wikipedia</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the Eighth Workshop on Building and Using Comparable Corpora</title>
						<meeting>the Eighth Workshop on Building and Using Comparable Corpora <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="88" to="91"/>
							<date type="published" when="2015-07-30">July 30, 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>This paper describes the LINA system for the BUCC 2015 shared track. Following (Enright and Kondrak, 2007), our system identify comparable documents by collecting counts of hapax words. We extend this method by filtering out document pairs sharing target documents using pigeonhole reasoning and cross-lingual information .</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Parallel corpora, that is, collections of documents that are mutual translations, are used in many natural language processing applications, particularly for statistical machine translation. Building such resources is however exceedingly expensive, requiring highly skilled annotators or professional translators <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Preiss, 2012)</ref>. Comparable corpora, that are sets of texts in two or more languages without being translations of each other, are often considered as a solution for the lack of parallel corpora, and many techniques have been proposed to extract parallel sentences ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Munteanu et al., 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Abdul-Rauf and Schwenk, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Smith et al., 2010)</ref>, or mine word translations <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Fung, 1995;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Rapp, 1999;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Chiao and Zweigenbaum, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Morin et al., 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Vuli´cVuli´c and Moens, 2012)</ref>.</p><p>Identifying comparable resources in a large amount of multilingual data remains a very challenging task. The purpose of the Building and Using Comparable Corpora (BUCC) 2015 shared task 1 is to provide the first evaluation of existing approaches for identifying comparable resources. More precisely, given a large collection of Wikipedia pages in several languages, the task is to identify the most similar pages across languages.</p><p>1 https://comparable.limsi.fr/bucc2015/ In this paper, we describe the system that we developed for the BUCC 2015 shared track and show that a language agnostic approach can achieve promising results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Proposed Method</head><p>The method we propose is based on <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Enright and Kondrak, 2007)</ref>'s approach to parallel document identification. Documents are treated as bags of words, in which only blank separated strings that are at least four characters long and that appear only once in the document (hapax words) are indexed. Given a document in language A, the document in language B that share the largest number of these words is considered as parallel.</p><p>Although very simple, this approach was shown to perform very well in detecting parallel documents in Wikipedia (Patry and Langlais, 2011). The reason for this is that most hapax words are in practice proper nouns or numerical entities, which are often cognates. An example of hapax words extracted from a document is given in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. We purposely keep urls and special characters, as these are useful clues for identifying translated Wikipedia pages.</p><p>website major gaston links flutist marcel debost states sources college crunelle conservatoire principal rampal united currently recorded chastain competitions music http://www.oberlin.edu/faculty/mdebost/ under international flutists jean-pierre profile moyse french repertoire amazon lives external *http://www.amazon.com/micheldebost/dp/b000s9zsk0 known teaches conservatory school professor studied kathleen orchestre replaced michel <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Example of indexed document as bag of hapax words (en-bacde.txt).</p><p>Here, we experiment with this approach for detecting near-parallel (comparable) documents. Following (Patry and Langlais, 2011), we first search for the potential source-target document pairs. To do so, we select for each document in the source language, the N = 20 documents in the target language that share the largest number of hapax words (hereafter baseline).</p><p>Scoring each pair of documents independently of other candidate pairs leads to several source documents being paired to a same target document. As indicated in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 2</ref>, the percentage of English articles that are paired with multiple source documents is high (57.3% for French and 60.4% for German). To address this problem, we remove potential multiple source documents by keeping the document pairs with the highest number of shared words (hereafter pigeonhole). This strategy greatly reduces the number of multiply assigned source documents from roughly 60% to 10%. This in turn removes needlessly paired documents and greatly improves the effectiveness of the method.  In an attempt to break the remaining score ties between document pairs, we further extend our model to exploit cross-lingual information. When multiple source documents are paired to a given English document with the same score, we use the paired documents in a third language to order them (hereafter cross-lingual). Here we make two assumptions that are valid for the BUCC 2015 shared Task: (1) we have access to comparable documents in a third language, and (2) source documents should be paired 1-to-1 with target documents.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Strategy</head><p>An example of two French documents (doc fr 1 and doc fr 2) being paired to the same English document (doc en ) is given in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1</ref>. We use the German document (doc de ) paired with doc en and select the French document that shares the largest number of hapax words, which for this example is doc fr 2. This strategy further reduces the number of multiply assigned source documents from 10% to less than 4%. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Experiments</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Experimental settings</head><p>The BUCC 2015 shared task consists in returning for each Wikipedia page in a source language, up to five ranked suggestions to its linked page in English. Inter-language links, that is, links from a page in one language to an equivalent page in another language, are used to evaluate the effectiveness of the systems. Here, we only focus on the French-English and German-English pairs. Following the task guidelines, we use the following evaluation measures investigate the effectiveness of our method:</p><p>• Mean Average Precision (MAP). Average of precisions computed at the point of each correctly paired document in the ranked list of paired documents.</p><p>• Success (Succ.). Precision computed on the first returned paired document.</p><p>• Precision at 5 (P@5). Precision computed on the 5 topmost paired documents.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Results</head><p>Results are presented in <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>. Overall, we observe that the two strategies that filter out multiply assigned source documents improve the performance of the method. The largest part of the improvement comes from using pigeonhole reasoning.  <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: Performance in terms of MAP, success (Succ.) and precision at 5 (P@5) of our model. break ties between the remaining multiply assigned source documents only gives a small improvement. We assume that the limited number of potential source-target document pairs we use in our experiments (N = 20) is a reason for this.</p><p>Interestingly, results are consistent across languages and datasets (test and train). Our best configuration, that is, with pigeonhole and crosslingual, achieves nearly 60% of success for the first returned pair. Here we show that a simple and straightforward approach that requires no language-specific resources still yields some interesting results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Discussion</head><p>In this paper we described the LINA system for the BUCC 2015 shared track. We proposed to extend <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Enright and Kondrak, 2007)</ref>'s approach to parallel document identification by filtering out document pairs sharing target documents using pigeonhole reasoning and cross-lingual information. Experimental results show that our system identifies comparable documents with a precision of about 60%.</p><p>Scoring document pairs using the number of shared hapax words was first intended to be a baseline for comparison purposes. We tried a finer grained scoring approach relying on bilingual dictionaries and information retrieval weighting schemes. For reasonable computation time, we were unable to include low-frequency words in our system. Partial results were very low and we are still in the process of investigating the reasons for this.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Example of the use of cross-lingual information to order multiple documents that received the same scores. The number of shared words are labelled on the edges.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Percentage of English articles that are 
paired with multiple French or German articles on 
the training data. 

</table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This work is supported by the French National Research Agency under grant ANR-12-CORD-0020.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the use of comparable corpora to improve SMT performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sadaf</forename><surname>Abdul-Rauf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Holger</forename><surname>Schwenk</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 12th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 12th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Athens, Greece</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="16" to="23" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Looking for candidate translational equivalents in specialized, comparable corpora</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yun-Chuang</forename><surname>Chiao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pierre</forename><surname>Zweigenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 19th International Conference on Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="5" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>COLING &apos;02. Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A fast method for parallel document identification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jessica</forename><surname>Enright</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Grzegorz</forename><surname>Kondrak</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Human Language Technologies 2007: The Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (NAACL&apos;07)</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Rochester, New York, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="29" to="32" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Compiling bilingual lexicon entries from a non-parallel english-chinese corpus</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pascale</forename><surname>Fung</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 3rd Annual Workshop on Very Large Corpora (VLC&apos;95)</title>
		<meeting>the 3rd Annual Workshop on Very Large Corpora (VLC&apos;95)<address><addrLine>Cambridge, MA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="173" to="183" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bilingual terminology mining -using brain, not brawn comparable corpora</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Emmanuel</forename><surname>Morin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Béatrice</forename><surname>Daille</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Koichi</forename><surname>Takeuchi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kyo</forename><surname>Kageura</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 45th Annual Meeting of the Association of Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 45th Annual Meeting of the Association of Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Prague, Czech Republic</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="664" to="671" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improved machine translation performance via parallel sentence extraction from comparable corpora</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Dragos Stefan Munteanu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Fraser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Marcu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">HLT-NAACL 2004: Main Proceedings</title>
		<editor>Daniel Marcu Susan Dumais and Salim Roukos</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Boston, Massachusetts, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2004-05-02" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="265" to="272" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identifying parallel documents from a large bilingual collection of texts: Application to parallel article extraction in wikipedia</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexandre</forename><surname>Patry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philippe</forename><surname>Langlais</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 4th Workshop on Building and Using Comparable Corpora (BUCC&apos;11)</title>
		<meeting>the 4th Workshop on Building and Using Comparable Corpora (BUCC&apos;11)<address><addrLine>Portland, Oregon, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="87" to="95" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identifying comparable corpora using lda</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Judita</forename><surname>Preiss</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2012 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>the 2012 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies<address><addrLine>Montréal, Canada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="558" to="562" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic Identification of Word Translations from Unrelated English and German Corpora</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Reinhard</forename><surname>Rapp</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 37th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL&apos;99)</title>
		<meeting>the 37th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL&apos;99)<address><addrLine>College Park, MD, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="519" to="526" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extracting parallel sentences from comparable corpora using document level alignment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Quirk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kristina</forename><surname>Toutanova</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Human Language Technologies: The 2010 Annual Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Los Angeles, California</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="403" to="411" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Detecting highly confident word translations from comparable corpora without any prior knowledge</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ivan</forename><surname>Vuli´cvuli´c</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marie-Francine</forename><surname>Moens</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 13th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 13th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Avignon, France</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012-04" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="449" to="459" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
