<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/atharsefid/Desktop/grobid-0.5.3/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.3" ident="GROBID" when="2020-09-29T04:00+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">From Patching Delays to Infection Symptoms: Using Risk Profiles for an Early Discovery of Vulnerabilities Exploited in the Wild From Patching Delays to Infection Symptoms: Using Risk Profiles for an Early Discovery of Vulnerabilities Exploited in the Wild</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>August 15-17. 2018</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chaowei</forename><surname>Xiao</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Armin</forename><surname>Sarabi</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Santa</forename><surname>Cruz</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>UIUC</roleName><forename type="first">Bo</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mingyan</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chaowei</forename><surname>Xiao</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Armin</forename><surname>Sarabi</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bo</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mingyan</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tudor</forename><surname>Dumitras</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Michigan</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Harvard University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country>UC</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Tudor Dumitras</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Michigan</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Maryland</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>College Park</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Michigan</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Michigan</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Harvard University / UC</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Santa Cruz</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">UIUC</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Michigan</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">University of Maryland</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>College Park</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">From Patching Delays to Infection Symptoms: Using Risk Profiles for an Early Discovery of Vulnerabilities Exploited in the Wild From Patching Delays to Infection Symptoms: Using Risk Profiles for an Early Discovery of Vulnerabilities Exploited in the Wild</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 27th USENIX Security Symposium</title>
						<meeting>the 27th USENIX Security Symposium <address><addrLine>Baltimore, MD, USA</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published">August 15-17. 2018</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>Open access to the Proceedings of the 27th USENIX Security Symposium is sponsored by USENIX. This paper is included in the</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>At any given time there exist a large number of software vulnerabilities in our computing systems, but only a fraction of them are ultimately exploited in the wild. Advanced knowledge of which vulnerabilities are being or likely to be exploited would allow system administrators to prioritize patch deployments, enterprises to assess their security risk more precisely, and security companies to develop intrusion protection for those vulnerabil-ities. In this paper, we present a novel method based on the notion of community detection for early discovery of vulnerability exploits. Specifically, on one hand, we use symptomatic botnet data (in the form of a set of spam blacklists) to discover a community structure which reveals how similar Internet entities behave in terms of their malicious activities. On the other hand, we analyze the risk behavior of end-hosts through a set of patch deployment measurements that allow us to assess their risk to different vulnerabilities. The latter is then compared to the former to quantify whether the underlying risks are consistent with the observed global symptomatic community structure, which then allows us to statistically determine whether a given vulnerability is being actively exploited in the wild. Our results show that by observing up to 10 days&apos; worth of data, we can successfully detect vulnerability exploitation with a true positive rate of 90% and a false positive rate of 10%. Our detection is shown to be much earlier than the standard discovery time records for most vulnerabilities. Experiments also demonstrate that our community based detection algorithm is robust against strategic adversaries.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Most software contains bugs, and an increased focus on improving software security has contributed to a growing number of vulnerabilities that are discovered each year <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[12]</ref>. Vulnerability disclosures are followed by fixes, either in the form of patches or new version releases. However, the installation/deployment of software patches on millions of vulnerable hosts worldwide are in a race with the development of vulnerability exploits. Owing to the sheer volume of vulnerability disclosures, it is hard for system administrators to keep up with this process. The severity of problem was highlighted in 2017 by the the WannaCry and NotPetya outbreaks, as well as the Equifax data breach exposing sensitive data of more than 143 million consumers; in all three cases the underlying vulnerability had been patched (but not deployed) months before the incident <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">[46,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">47,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">20]</ref>. Prior research suggests that, on median, at most 14% of the vulnerable hosts are patched when exploits are released publicly <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[30]</ref>.</p><p>On the other hand, many vulnerabilities are never exploited. For instance, Nayak et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[32]</ref> found that only 15% of known vulnerabilities are exploited in the wild. In an ideal world, all vulnerabilities should be patched as soon as they are identified regardless of their possibility of eventual exploitation. However, in reality, we live in a resource-constrained world where risk management and patch prioritization become important decisions. Even though patches may be released before or shortly after the public disclosure of a software vulnerability, many enterprises do not patch their systems in a timely manner, sometimes caused by the need or desire to test patches before deploying them on their respective machines <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref>. Within this context, the ability to detect critical vulnerabilities prior to incidents would be highly desirable, as it enables enterprises to prioritize patch testing and deployment. Furthermore, identifying actively exploited-inthe-wild vulnerabilities that have not yet been addressed by the software vendor can also guide them in prioritizing patch development.</p><p>However, determining critical software vulnerabilities is non-trivial. For example, intrinsic attributes of vulnerabilities, such as the CVSS score <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[28]</ref>, are not strong predictors of eventual exploitation <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[36]</ref>, underlining the Early detection in this study refers to the ability to detect after t C , i.e., post-disclosure, but much earlier than t E , the current state of the art.</p><p>need for detection techniques based on field measurements. In this paper, we ask the question: How early can we determine that a specific vulnerability is actively being exploited in the wild? To put this on the appropriate time scale, we illustrate the sequence of events associated with a vulnerability in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>: its introduction at t A with application installation, disclosure at t C , patching at t F ; and for those eventually exploited in the wild, detection at t E . However, real exploitations may occur much earlier, shown at t D (post-disclosure) and sometimes t B (pre-disclosure). In this study, by early detection we refer to the ability to detect exploits after t C (post-disclosure) but before t E (before the current state of the art). We show that this early detection can be well accomplished by using two datasets: end-host software patching behavior and a set of reputation blacklists (RBLs) capturing IP level malicious (spam) activities. Specifically, when viewed at an aggregate level (e.g., an ISP), the patching delays for a given vulnerability constitute a risk profile for that ISP. If a symptom that often follows exploitation (e.g., increased spam or malicious download activities) occurs in a group of ISPs that share a certain risk profile, then it is likely that the vulnerabilities associated with that risk profile are being exploited in the wild. We show that there is strong empirical evidence of a strong correlation between risk profiles and infection symptoms, which enables early detection of exploited vulnerabilities, even in cases where the exploit was not yet discovered and where causal connection between exploitation and the symptom is not known.</p><p>By observing these signals up to 10 days after vulnerability disclosure (t C ), we can detect exploits with true and false positive rates of 90% and 10%, respectively. Note that intrinsic attributes of a vulnerability (e.g., remote exploitability) are available immediately after disclosure, however, we show that features extracted from 10 days of post-disclosure data can significantly improve the accuracy of detecting active exploitation. Moreover, the median time between vulnerability disclosure and reports of exploitation in our dataset is 35 days, with 80% of reported exploits appearing beyond 10 days after the public disclosure of the underlying vulnerability. This indicates that our proposed method can improve detection times for active exploits. Note that compared to other techniques such as detection of exploits from social media posts (which usually appear around the time exploits are discovered) <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[36]</ref>, we base our detection on statistical evidence of exploitation from real-world measurements, which can capture much weaker indications of exploits shortly after the public disclosure of a vulnerability.</p><p>Our main contributions are summarized as follows:</p><p>1. We use a community detection <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">[51]</ref> method for correlating and extracting features from user patching data and IP level malicious activities. We show that the resulting features can detect active exploitation, validated using a ground-truth set of vulnerabilities known to be exploited in the wild.</p><p>2. Using these features, combined with other intrinsic features of a given vulnerability, we show that accurate detection can be achieved within 10 days of vulnerability disclosure. This is much earlier than the state-of-the-art on average, and thus provides significant time advantage in patch development and deployment. We also evaluate retrospective analysis of pre-disclosure data on the disclosure date to detect and promptly respond to zero-day exploits.</p><p>3. The community structure generated during feature extraction can also be used to identify groups of hosts at risk to specific vulnerabilities currently being exploited, adding to our ability to strengthen preventative and protective measures.</p><p>4. We evaluate the robustness of our technique against strategic adversaries, observing graciously degrading performance even when the adversary can control a significant number of hosts within many ISPs.</p><p>The rest of paper is organized as follows. In Section 2 we outline the conceptual idea behind our methodology and how community detection is used as a feature extraction tool. We describe our datasets and data processing in Sections 3 and 4. Section 5 details the community detection technique. Section 6 presents our classifier design, detection performance, and comparison with a number of alternatives. In Section 7 we present case studies of our system's output, evaluate the robustness of our technique against strategic adversaries, and discuss how our proposed methodology could be used in practice. Section 8 summarizes related work and Section 9 concludes the paper. Figure 2: Detecting active viral strain by comparing population symptom pattern and risk behavior pattern. There are two strains of viruses: those exposed to air contamination are more at risk/susceptible to strain 1, while those exposed to water contamination are more at risk/susceptible to strain 2. By comparing the symptom group to the risk groups we can infer which strain is likely to be the underlying cause of the infection.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Overview of Concept and Methodology</head><p>Our study is premised on a simple observation, that vulnerability exploitation leads to host infection, which then leads to manifestation of symptoms such as malicious activities. However, using the latter to detect the former is far from trivial: observed signs of infection do not reveal which vulnerability is the underlying culprit. This led us to consider a more verifiable hypothesis: entities (to be precisely defined shortly) that exhibit similar patching behavior in a particular vulnerability (and thus their vulnerability state) might also exhibit similar patterns of infection associated with that vulnerability if it is being actively exploited; on the other hand, the same similarity association should not exist if the vulnerability is not being actively exploited. If this hypothesis holds, then it follows that one should be able to assess the strengths of association between patching behavior and infection symptoms and use it to detect whether a vulnerability is likely being actively exploited.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Main idea</head><p>We illustrate the above idea using an analogy shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>. Suppose in any given year multiple strains of a virus may be active in a particular region. Each strain works through a different susceptibility: some through contaminated air, some through contaminated water, shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 2b</ref> and 2c respectively. When infected, regardless of the active strain, the outward symptoms are indistinguishable. However, if we know the infected population, then by identifying the underlying risk pattern it becomes possible to infer which strain may be active. Comparing <ref type="figure">Figure 2b</ref> to 2a and then 2c to 2a, we see a large overlap between the symptom group and the group at risk to strain 1 (through air contamination), indicating a likelihood that stain 1 is active; by contrast, the symptom group and those at risk to strain 2 (through water contamination) are largely disjoint, suggesting that strain 2 is likely not active.</p><p>To apply this analogy in our context, the symptom pattern refers to malicious activities while risk behavior refers to host patching. More specifically, infected population maps to hosts showing explicit signs of botnet activities, and exposure to active (non-active) viral strains maps to having vulnerabilities that are (not) being actively exploited.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Challenges</head><p>This example illustrates the conceptual idea behind our methodology, though it is a gross simplification as we elaborate below. In particular, we face two challenges. First, the telemetry that many security vendors collect on end-hosts is often anonymized, for user privacy reasons, and omits attributes that may identify the host, such as its IP address. This makes it impossible to correlate the risky behaviors (reflected in this telemetry) with symptoms (reflected in RBLs) at the host or IP level. Yet since we are correlating behavioral and symptomatic data, it is essential that both are associated with the same entity. To resolve this, we use aggregation to assess this idea at a higher level. Specifically, while the patching data does not contain IP addresses, it shows ISP information associated with each host. This allows us to aggregate patching behavior at the ISP level. On the RBL side, we use a separate IP intelligence database to aggregate malicious behavior at the ISP level by using IP to ISP mappings. In other words, each unit in the population shown in the above example now maps to an ISP. With this aggregation, the above hypothesis essentially states that ISPs behaving similarly in patching a certain vulnerability (risk patterns) are most likely to show similar infection symptoms if that vulnerability is being exploited. This technique can be adapted for a more fine-grained aggregation, such as autonomous systems (ASs), or not using any aggregation when both risk behavior and symptoms are available at the host level. However, as is evident from our results in Section 6.2, aggregation at the ISP level is not too coarse so as to impede our technique from detecting actively exploited vulnerabilities.</p><p>Our second challenge is in determining the right metric to use to capture "similarity" both in the patching behavior and in the symptoms. Unlike what is shown in the example, in our context neither the symptoms (spam activities from an ISP) nor the risk behaviors (patching records of end-hosts in an ISP) are binary, or even necessarily countable as they are extracted from time series data. This makes identifying either pattern within the population much less straightforward. One natural first step is to compute pairwise correlation for each pair of ISPs' time series. This results in two similarity matrices, one from the patching behavior data for a specific vulnerability, one from the symptomatic infection data (collected following that vulnerability's disclosure from spam lists). It is the second-order similarity comparison between these two matrices that is hypothesized to be able to tell apart exploited vulnerabilities from nonexploited ones. To this end, we present the use of community detection <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">51]</ref> over the symptom similarity matrix to identify groups of similar ISPs; this is then followed by quantifying the consistency between the risk behavior similarity matrix and the detected community structure. Our results show that indeed for vulnerabilities with known exploits, this match is much stronger than that for those without known exploits.</p><p>We then use the consistency measures as features, along with a number of other intrinsic features, to train a classifier aimed at detecting exploitations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Threat model</head><p>One type of adversaries implicit in this work are those actively exploiting software vulnerabilities. One basic assumption we adopt is that such exploitation can occur as soon as the vulnerabilities are introduced (with new version releases, etc.), though our detection framework is triggered by the official vulnerability disclosure, as indicated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>. We assume such an adversary can potentially develop and actively pursue exploits for any existing vulnerability.</p><p>A second type of adversaries we consider are those who not only seek exploitation but also have the ability to control a significant number of end-hosts so as to manipulate the patching signals we use in our detection framework. In other words, this is a type of attack (or evasion attempt) against our specific detection methodology which uses patching signals as one of the inputs. The manipulation is intended to interfere with the way we measure similarity between networks; in Section 7.2 we examine the robustness of our detection method against this type of attack. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> summarizes the datasets used in this study. Since we need time-aligned measurements to compare behaviors between patching and malicious activity signals, only the overlapping time period, 01/2013-07/2014, is used in our analysis.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Datasets</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">End-host patching</head><p>Our study draws from a number of data sources that collectively characterize the users' patching behavior, allowing us to assess their susceptibility to known vulnerabilities and exploits at any point in time. This set will also be referred to as the risk/behavioral data. These include the host patching data <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[14]</ref>, the National Vulnerability Database (NVD) <ref type="bibr">[33]</ref>, and release notes from software vendors of the products examined in our study.</p><p>Patch deployment measurements This data source allows us to observe users' patching behavior to assess their susceptibility to known vulnerabilities. We use patch deployment measurements collected by Nappa et al. on end-hosts <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[30]</ref>. This corpus records installation of subsequent versions of different applications along with each event's timestamp, by mapping records of binary executables on user machines to their corresponding application versions. This data is derived from the WINE dataset provided by Symantec <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[14]</ref>, and includes observations on hosts worldwide between 02/2008 and 07/2014. In addition, we extract the security flaws affecting each application version from the National Vulnerability database (NVD), where each vulnerability is denoted by its Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures Identifier (CVE-ID).</p><p>For each host and CVE-ID, we follow the methodology described in <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[38]</ref> to collect the periods of time where a host is susceptible to disclosed but unpatched vulnerabilities, through the presence of vulnerable application versions on their machines. This method involves finding the state of a host, i.e., the set of applications installed on the machine, for any point throughout the observation period, and extracting the set of disclosed vulnerabilities corresponding to those application versions from NVD. Note that a user might also install different product lines of the same application, e.g., Flash Player 10 and 11, at the same time. We will elaborate on this in Section 4.1.</p><p>For this study, we analyze user patching behavior over 7 applications with the best host coverage in our dataset, namely Google Chrome, Mozilla Firefox, Mozilla Thunderbird, Safari, Opera, Adobe Acrobat Reader, and Adobe Flash Player; we ignore hosts that have recorded less than 10 events for all of these applications. Re- Vulnerability exploits As noted earlier, only a small fraction of disclosed vulnerabilities have known exploits; some exploits may remain undiscovered, but a large number of vulnerabilities are never exploited. We identify the set of vulnerabilities exploited in the real world from two sources. The first is the corpus of exploited vulnerabilities collected by Carl et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[36]</ref>. These are extracted from public descriptions of Symantec's anti-virus signatures <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[42]</ref>, and intrusion-protection signatures (IPS) <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. Limiting the vulnerabilities included in our study to the above 7 products between 01/2013 to 07/2014, we curate a dataset containing 18 vulnerabilities. The second source of exploits is the SecurityFocus vulnerability database <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[40]</ref> from Symantec. We query all CVE-IDs extracted from NVD included in our study and obtain 44 exploited-in-the-wild (EIW) vulnerabilities. Combining all curated datasets we obtain 56 exploited-in-the-wild (EIW) and 300 not-exploited-in-the-wild (NEIW) vulnerabilities.</p><p>Software release notes To find whether a host is susceptible to a vulnerability and to address the issue of parallel product lines, we utilize the release date of each application version included in our study. For Thunderbird, Firefox, Chrome, Opera, Adobe Acrobat Reader and Adobe Flash Player, we crawl the release history logs from the official vendor's websites or a third party. However, there sometimes exist sub-versions that are not included in these sources. Thus, we also use release dates from Nappa et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[30]</ref> who automatically extract software release dates by selecting the first date when the version appears in the patch deployment dataset <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[14]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Malicious activities</head><p>Our second main category of data consists of IP level spam activities and will refer to this as symptomatic data since malicious activities are ostensible signs that end-hosts have been infected, possibly through the use of an exploited vulnerability present on the host. This dataset is sourced from well-established monitoring systems such as spam traps in the form of various reputation blacklists (RBLs) <ref type="bibr">[9,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">39,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">41,</ref><ref type="bibr">45,</ref><ref type="bibr">48]</ref>. In this study, we use 5 common daily IP address based RBLs from January 2013 to July 2014 which overlap with the patch deployment measurements.</p><p>Note that the use of spam data is only a proxy for host infection caused by vulnerability exploits and an imperfect one at that. For instance, not all spam are caused by exploits; some spamming botnets are distributed through malicious attachments. Similarly, it is also common for cyber-criminals to rent pay-per-install services to install bots. In both cases, the resulting spam activities are not correlated with host patching patterns. This raises the question whether these other types of operations may render our approach ineffective. Our results show the opposite; the detection performance we are able to achieve suggests that spam is a very good proxy for this purpose despite the existence of non-vulnerability related spamming bot distributions.</p><p>Note that hosts in our patch deployment dataset are anonymized, but can be aggregated at the Internet Service Provider (ISP) level. Hence, we also use the Maxmind GeoIP2ISP service <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[29]</ref> (identifying 3.5 million IPv4 address blocks belonging to 68,605 ISPs) to aggregate malicious activity indicators at the ISP level. We then align the resulting time series data with aggregated patching signals for evaluating our methodology.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Data Processing and Preliminaries</head><p>In this section we further elaborate on how time series data are aggregated at the ISP level and how we define similarity measures between ISPs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Aggregating at the ISP level</head><p>The mapping from hosts to ISPs is not unique; as devices move it may be associated with different IP addresses and possibly different ISPs. This is the case with both the patching data and the RBLs and our aggregation takes this into account by similarly mapping the same host to multiple ISPs whenever this is indicated in the data.</p><p>Aggregating the RBL signals at the ISP level is relatively straightforward. Each RBL provides a daily list of malicious IP addresses, from which we count the total number of unique IPs belonging to any ISP. Formally, let R n (t) denote the total number of unique IPs listed on these RBLs on day t that belong to ISP n (by mapping the IPs to prefixes associated with this ISP). This is then normalized by the size of ISP n; this normalization step is essential as pairwise comparisons between ISPs can be severely skewed when there is a large difference in their respective sizes. The normalized time series r n (t) will also be referred to as the symptom signal of ISP n.</p><p>Aggregating the patching data at an ISP level is significantly more involved. This is because the measurements are in the form of a sequence of application versions installed on a host with their corresponding timestamps. To quantify the risk of a given host, we first extract known vulnerabilities affecting each application version from NVD using the Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures Identifier (CVE-ID) of the vulnerability. Each vulnerability will also be referred to as a CVE throughout this paper. However, this extraction is complicated by the fact that there may be multiple product lines present on a host, or when a user downgrades to an earlier release. Moreover, multiple product lines of a software are sometimes developed in parallel by a vendor, all of which could be affected by the same CVE, e.g,. Flash Player 10 and 11. It follows that if a host has both versions, then updating one but not the other will still leave the host vulnerable. In this study, we use the release notes described in Section 3.1 as an additional data source to distinguish between parallel product lines, by assuming that application versions belonging to the same line follow a chronological order of release dates, while multiple parallel lines can be developed in parallel by the vendor. This heuristic allows us to discern different product lines of each application and users that have installed multiple product lines on their respective machines at any point in time, leading to a more accurate estimate of their states.</p><p>We quantify the vulnerability of a single host h to CVE j on day t by counting how many versions present on the host on day t are subject to this CVE. Denoted by W j h (t), in most cases this is a binary indicator (i.e., whether there exists a single version subject to this CVE), but occasionally this can be an integer &gt; 1 due to the presence of parallel product lines mentioned above. This quantity is then summed over all hosts belonging to an ISP n, resulting in a total count of unpatched vulnerabilities present in this ISP. We again normalize this quantity by the ISP's size and denote the normalized signal by w j n (t). We have now obtained two types of time series for each ISP n: r n (t) denoting the normalized malicious activities (also referred to as the symptom signal), and w j n (t), j ∈ V , denoting the normalized risk with respect to CVE j; the latter is a set of time series, one for each CVE in the set V (also referred to as the risk signal).</p><p>Note that r n (t) is not CVE-specific; however, a given CVE determines the time period in which this signal is examined as we show next.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Similarity in symptoms and in risk</head><p>As described in the introduction and highlighted in <ref type="figure">Fig- ure 2</ref>, our basic methodology relies on identifying the similarity structure using symptom data and quantifying how strongly the risk patterns are associated with the symptom similarity structure. This is done for each CVE separately. Note that our aggregated malicious activity signal r n (t) for ISP n is agnostic to the choice of CVE, since the observed malicious activities from a single host can be attributed to a variety of reasons including various CVEs the host is vulnerable to. However, our analysis on a given CVE determines the time window from which we examine this signal. Specifically, consider the following definition of correlation between two vectors u[0 : d] and v <ref type="bibr">[0 : d]</ref>, which tries to find similarity between the two vectors by allowing time shifts/delays between the two:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">S u,v (k) = ∑ d t=k u(t) · v(t − k) ∑ d−k t=0 v(t) · v(t) · ∑ d−k t=0 u(t + k) · u(t + k) ,<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where k = 0, · · · , d denotes all possible time shifts. The above equation keeps v fixed and slides u one element at a time and generates a sequence of correlations over increasingly shorter vectors. Similarly, we can keep u fixed and slide v one element at a time, which gives us S v,u (k) for k = 0, · · · , d. Our pairwise similarity measure is defined by the maximum of these correlations subject to a lower bound on how long the vector should be:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">S u,v = max( max 0≤k≤d−a (S u,v (k)), max 0≤k≤d−a (S v,u (k)),<label>(2)</label></formula><p>where a is a lower bound to guarantee the correlation is computed over vectors of length at least d − a to prevent artificially high values. In our numerical experiment a is set to d 4 . With the above definition, the pairwise symptom similarity between a pair of ISPs n and m for CVE j can now be formally stated. Assume t j o to be the day of disclosure for CVE j. We will focus on the time period from disclosure to d days after that, as we aim to see whether by examining this period we can detect the presence of an exploit. <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">1</ref> For simplicity of presentation, we shift t j o to origin, which gives us two symptom signals of length d + 1: r n [0 : d] and r m <ref type="bibr">[0 : d]</ref>, and a pairwise symptom similarity measure S j r n ,r m using Equations (1) and (2). We can similarly define the pairwise risk similarity between this pair of ISPs, given by S j w n ,w m . <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 3</ref>: Visualization of community structure of malicious ISPs; each color denotes a single community.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Comparing Symptom Similarity to Risk Similarity</head><p>In this section, we first use community detection methods <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">51]</ref> to identify the underlying communities in the pairwise symptom similarities. We then detail our technique for quantifying the strength of association between symptoms and risk behavior for specific CVEs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Community detection over symptom similarity</head><p>The set of pairwise similarity measures S j r n ,r m constitute a similarity matrix denoted by S j [n, m], ∀n, m ∈ I where I denotes the set of all ISPs included in the following analysis. This matrix is equivalently represented as a weighted (and undirected) graph, where I is the set of vertices (each vertex being an ISP) and the pairwise similarity S j r n ,r m is the edge weight between vertices n and m (note each edge weight is a number between 0 and 1). A community detection algorithm can then be run over this graph to identify hidden structures.</p><p>The general goal of community detection is to uncover hidden structures in a graph; a typical example is the identification of clusters (e.g., social groups) that are strongly connected (in terms of degree), whereby nodes within the same cluster have a much higher number of in-cluster edges than edges connecting to nodes outside the cluster. This has been an extensive area of research within the signal processing and machine learning community and has found diverse applications including biological systems <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[18,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">43,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">52]</ref>, social networks <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[23,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">51,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">52]</ref>, influence and citations <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[31,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">51,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">52]</ref>, among others.</p><p>In our context, the similarity matrix S j [n, m] induces a weighted and fully-connected graph. The result of com-  munity detection over such a graph is a collection of clusters, each of which represents ISPs that share very similar symptoms. We use two state-of-the-art community detection algorithms, both of which detect overlapping communities, i.e., a node may belong to multiple clusters. The first one is BigClam (Cluster Affiliation Model for Big Networks) <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">[52]</ref>; this is a model-based community detection algorithm that finds densely overlapping, hierarchically nested, as well as non-overlapping communities. The second is DEMON (Democratic Estimate of the Modular Organization of a Network) <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[10]</ref>, which discovers communities by using local properties.  <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[24]</ref> provided by <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>; different colors encode different communities identified by the algorithm. In this example, an original graph of 8,742 nodes was reduced to one with 1,112 nodes and 10 detected communities. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2</ref> To convey a sense of what the notion of community captures, we further plot the spam signals of groups of ISPs each belonging to one of two communities in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4</ref>; as can be seen, those in the same community exhibit similar temporal signals.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Measuring the strength of association between risk and symptoms</head><p>We now verify the hypothesis stated in the introduction; that is, if a CVE is being actively exploited, then ISPs showing similar vulnerabilities to this CVE are also likely to exhibit similar infection symptoms, while on the other hand if a CVE is not actively exploited, then the similarity in vulnerabilities may not be associated with similarity in symptoms. Toward this end, we note that there isn't a unique way to measure the strength of association in these two types of similarities. One could, for instance, try to directly compare the two similarity matrices S j [r n , r m ] and S j [w n , w m ]; we shall use one ver-   sion of this whereby we perform row-by-row correlation between the two matrices as one of the benchmark comparisons presented in Section 6. Below we will consider a more intuitive measure. We first use the communities detected by symptom similarity to sort pairwise risk similarity values into two distinct groups: inter-cluster similarity and intra-cluster similarity. Specifically, denote the set of clusters identified by community detection over matrix S j [r n , r m ] as C . Then if we can find a cluster C ∈ C such that both n, m ∈ C, then S j w n ,w m is sorted into the intra-cluster group; otherwise it is sorted into the inter-cluster group. This is repeated for all pairs n, m ∈ I . <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 5</ref> shows the distribution of these values within each group for two distinct CVEs, one is known to have an exploit in the wild (detected by Symantec 20 days post-disclosure), and the other has no known exploits in the wild.</p><p>The difference between the two is both evident and revealing: for the CVE without a known exploit, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 5a</ref> shows virtually no difference between the two distributions, indicating that the risk similarity values are not differentiated by the symptom patterns. On the other hand, for the exploited CVE (though only known after the analyzed observation time period), <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 5b</ref> shows a very distinct difference (p value of Kolmogorov-Smirnov test &lt; 0.01) between the two groups. In particular, the intracluster group contains much higher risk similarity values. This suggests that high risk similarity coincides with high symptom similarity (which is what determined the community structure). Also worthy of note is the fact that for the exploited CVE, the earliest date of exploit observation on record is 20 days post-disclosure (disclosure on 01/15/2014, observation in the wild on 02/05/2014), whereas this analysis is feasible within 10 days of the disclosure (01/15-01/25/2014). This suggests that exploits occur much sooner than commonly reported, and that early detection is possible.</p><p>We sum up the values in each group and take the difference between the intra-cluster and inter-cluster sum and denote it by D j . This allows us to quantify the strength of association between risk and symptoms for any arbitrary CVE; a high D j indicates that there is a statistically significant difference between intra-cluster and inter-cluster risk similarities, which in turn provides evidence for active exploitation. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 6a</ref> shows the distribution of D j over two CVE subsets: one with known exploits (with observation dates at least 10 days postdisclosure) and one without known exploits. We see that for the group of exploited CVEs, the intra-cluster risk similarities are decidedly higher, suggesting a consistency with communities detected using symptoms. By contrast, for non-exploited CVEs, there is no appreciable difference between the two groups; indeed the distribution looks very similar to that obtained using random partitions of the ISP shown as a reference in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 6b</ref>.</p><p>We also plot for each CVE its time to earliest detection on record against the above similarity difference measure in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 7</ref>; the curve highlights the mean of D j in each delay bin. We observe a general downward trend in the mean, i.e., for exploits spotted earlier their inter-cluster and intra-cluster similarity difference is also more pro-  nounced. This is consistent with our belief that the similarity difference D j is fundamentally a sign of active exploitation, which coincides with being detected earlier; for those detected much later on, it is more likely that exploitation occurred later and therefore could not be observed during the early days.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Early Detection of Exploits in the Wild</head><p>Our results in the previous section shows that the intraand inter-cluster risk similarity distributions as well as the difference D j are statistically meaningful in separating one group of CVEs (exploited) from another (not exploited). This suggests that these can be used as features in building a classifier aiming at exploits detection.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">Features and labels</head><p>Each CVE in our sample set is labeled as either exploited or un-exploited, which constitutes the label. As described in Section 3.1, our ground-truth comes from three sources, public descriptions of Symantec's antivirus signature, intrusion-protection signatures and exploit data from SecurityFocus. Each CVE also comes with a set of features. In addition to the spam/symptom data and patching/risk data we analyzed rigorously in the previous section, we will also use intrinsic attributes associated with each CVE extracted from NVD. Specifically, CVE summary information offers basic descriptions about its category, the process to exploit it, and whether it requires remote access, etc. These are important static features for characterizing the properties of a CVE. We apply bag of words to retrieve features from the summaries after punctuation and stemming processes. In total we obtained 3,037 keywords from our dataset. We then select 16 features with the highest mutual information with labels; these are shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref>. We observe that keywords such as attack, exploit, server, and allow, have higher mutual information with labels of exploited, which is consistent with common understanding of what might motivate exploits.</p><p>Below we summarize the complete set of features used in this study (each family is given a category name), some of which are introduced for comparison purposes as we describe in detail next.</p><p>• <ref type="bibr">[Community]</ref>: The difference in distribution (intra-cluster minus inter-cluster similarity) shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 5</ref>, in the form of histograms with 20 bins.</p><p>• <ref type="bibr">[Direct]</ref>: The distribution of row-by-row correlation between the two similarity matrices S j [r n , r m ] and S j [w n , w m ], in the form of 20-bin histograms.</p><p>• <ref type="bibr">[Raw]</ref>: The two similarity matrices S j [r n , r m ] and S j [w n , r m ].</p><p>• <ref type="bibr">[Intrinsic]</ref>: The top 20 intrinsic features using bag of words as shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref>.</p><p>• [CVSS] CVSS <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[28]</ref> metrics and scores. For each CVE, we use three metrics: AcessVecotr, AccesComplexity, and Authentication, which measure the exploit range, required attack complexity and the level of authentication needed for successful exploitation, respectively</p><p>We can also categorize these sets of features as graphbased ( <ref type="bibr">[Community]</ref>, <ref type="bibr">[Direct]</ref>, <ref type="bibr">[Raw]</ref>) and intrinsic ( <ref type="bibr">[In- trinsic]</ref>, <ref type="bibr">[CVSS]</ref>) features. The intrinsic features describe what is known about a vulnerability at the time of disclosure, e.g., whether it can be used to gain remote control of the host. Intuitively, these features can affect the likelihood of a CVE being targeted by cyber-criminals. On the other hand, graph-based features can detect the onset of active exploitation, by associating similar patching behavior with similarity in infection patterns. Our results in the following section demonstrate that while intrinsic features alone are poor predictors of eventual exploitation of a CVE, combining intrinsic attributes with graph-based features enables early and accurate detection of EIW vulnerabilities.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Detection performance</head><p>We now compare the detection performance by training classifiers using different subsets of the features listed above. In training the classifiers, we note there is an imbalance between our EIW (56) and NEIW (300) classes of CVEs. For this reason, the training and testing are conducted using 20 rounds of random sub-sampling from the NEIW set to match its size with the EIW set; for each round, we apply 5-fold cross validation to split the dataset into training and test sets. We train Random Forests <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[34]</ref> for classification, and average our results over all 20 rounds; our results are reported below. When using <ref type="bibr">[Community]</ref> features, we observed similar performance for BigClam and DEMON. BigClam has linear time complexity, so for simplicity of exposition below we only report our results using BigClam.</p><p>Also for comparison, we will directly use the two similarity matrices (the <ref type="bibr">[Raw]</ref> features) to train a classifier. The dimensionality of the matrix is equal to the number of valid ISPs, 3050 by 3050. This is much higher in dimension than the number of instances we have, leading to severe overfitting if used directly. We thus apply a common univariate feature selection method <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[37]</ref> provide by <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[34]</ref> to obtain K = 150 features with the highest values based on the chi-squared test <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">3</ref> . Three standard machine learning methods are then used to train a classifier: SVM, Random Forest and a fully-connected neural network with three hidden layers and 30 neurons for each hidden layer. We observe similar performance for all examined models, and thus we only report our results using Random Forest classifiers. We depict the ROC (Receiver Operating Characteristic) curves and report the AUC (Area Under the Curve) score as performance measures. We train and compare multiple classifiers on different sets of features:</p><p>• "All features": This is a classifier trained with all features using 10 days of data post-disclosure.</p><p>• "Community features": A set of classifiers trained using only <ref type="bibr">[Community]</ref> and on 10 days of observational data post-disclosure (for both symptoms and risk). Only CVEs whose known detection dates are beyond 10 days are used for testing these classifiers.</p><p>• "Direct features": Trained based on the <ref type="bibr">[Direct]</ref> features alone on 10 days of data post-disclosure.</p><p>• "Raw features": Trained with [Raw] features on 10 days of observational data post-disclosure. <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">3</ref> We did not use PCA for dimensionality reduction in order to retain interpretability of the features used.</p><p>• "Day x": A set of classifiers trained using only <ref type="bibr">[Community]</ref> and on x days of observational data post-disclosure (for both symptoms and risk). Only CVEs whose known detection dates are beyond day x are used for testing these classifiers.</p><p>• "Back x": A set of classifiers trained using only <ref type="bibr">[Community]</ref> and on 10 days of observational data starting from x days before disclosure (for both symptoms and risk).</p><p>• "Intrinsic features": Trained using <ref type="bibr">[Intrinsic]</ref> and <ref type="bibr">[CVSS]</ref> families of features.</p><p>• "Community+Intrinsic": This is a classifier trained with <ref type="bibr">[Intrinsic]</ref> and <ref type="bibr">[Community]</ref> features on 10 days of observational data post-disclosure.</p><p>• "Direct+Raw+Intrinsic": This is a classifier trained with <ref type="bibr">[Intrinsic]</ref>, <ref type="bibr">[Direct]</ref>, and <ref type="bibr">[Raw]</ref> features on 10 days of observational data post-disclosure.</p><p>The main comparison is given in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">Figure 8a</ref>. We see a remarkable improvement in detection performance when we combine the community features with CVE intrinsic features. We see that even though both community and direct features are extracted from the raw features, they both perform much better than directly using raw features. In particular, the community detection based method is shown to perform the best among these three. The reason why extracted features perform better than raw features is because with the latter a lot of the temporal information embedded in the time series data is underutilized (e.g., in decision tree type of classifiers, time series data are taken as multiple individual inputs), whereas the features we extract (either in the form of community comparison or in the form of row-by-row correlation) attempt to preserve this temporal information.</p><p>Additionally, we see that combining community features with intrinsic features achieves very good detection performance, almost similar to the concatenation of all features; this suggests that when combined with intrinsic features, community features can effectively replace the use of raw and direct features. Finally, the overall attainable performance is very promising: 96% AUC, and 90% and 10% true and false positive rates. The same set of results are re-plotted in terms of precision and recall in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">Figure 8b</ref>.</p><p>As mentioned earlier and observed here, the intrinsic features by themselves are not particularly strong predictors, and weaker than the community features when used alone, as measured by AUC (69%). This is because the intrinsic features are a priori characterizations of a vulnerability (thus the use of which amounts to prediction), whereas community features are a posteriori signs of exploitation, allowing us to perform detection. It is thus not surprising that the latter is a more powerful metric. It is however promising to see that the two sets of features complement each other well by providing orthogonal attributes for predicting/detecting exploitation, resulting in much higher performance when combined.</p><p>It should be noted that this level of performance still falls short of what could be attained in a typical intrusion detection systems (IDS) or spam filters, and there are a few reasons for this. Firstly, as mentioned earlier our labeling of vulnerabilities as exploited and non-exploited may be noisy: some exploited vulnerabilities may have remained unidentified and unreported. Secondly, in an IDS type of detection system there are typically very specific signatures one looks for, whereas in our setting the analysis is done over large populations where such signatures become very weak or non-existent; e.g., we can only observe if a host is sending out spam without any visibility into how or why. Accordingly, a performance gap is expected if comparing to IDS type of detection systems. It is however worth noting that in our setting a false positive is not nearly as costly as one in an IDS; ours would merely suggest that an as-yet unexploited CVE should be prioritized for patch development/deployment, which arguably would have to be done at some point regardless of our detection result.</p><p>If multiple CVEs are simultaneously exploited, our detection can still work as long as the hosts have nonidentical patching behavior for these CVEs. This is because the risk behavior would be different even if the infection groups are the same, as we showed in <ref type="figure">Figure 2c</ref>. If the host population also exhibit the same patching behavior toward these CVEs, then the resulting ambiguity will cause our algorithm to "detect" all of these CVEs, only one/some of which are the culprit. This would be another type of false positive; the consequence however is again limited -all these CVEs will be suggested as high priority even though one or some of them could have waited.</p><p>Note that the accuracies presented here are obtained in spite of multiple sources of noise that can appear in our datasets or imperfections in our methodology. For instance the one-to-multiple mapping from symptoms of malicious behavior (indicated by RBLs) to vulnerabilities, especially when multiple vulnerabilities appear in the same time window, and hosts appearing in a blacklist for reasons other than exploitation of software vulnerabilities, can introduce noise in the measured symptoms (malicious activities). Furthermore, aggregation at a coarse level can lead to only observing the averages of behavior that could otherwise be utilized to detect exploitation. However, the ground-truth for testing the performance of our technique is independent of the aforementioned sources of noise, and the observed performance shows that our method is, to a large extent, robust to these imperfections.</p><p>We next examine the impact of the length of the observational period when using community detection, by comparing the ROCs of classifiers trained using different number of days, immediately following disclosure, as well as starting from a few days before disclosure. This is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">Figure 8c</ref>. We see that as we increase the observation period post-disclosure the predictive power of the similarity comparison improves. This is to be expected as longer periods are more likely to capture symptoms of infection especially during the early days as vulnerabilities are just starting to be exploited. Interestingly, starting the observation even before disclosure also seems to be picking up information, an indication that some exploits do start earlier than official disclosure as mentioned in the introduction. Among the examined set the "Day 4" version is the worst-performing; this is due to a very short window of observation, only 4 days post-disclosure. This short window affects the effectiveness of time series data analysis but also is more likely to miss information that is just emerging post-disclosure.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Case Studies and Discussion</head><p>In this section we present a few examples of our system's output for (potentially) zero-day EIW vulnerabilities, and discuss the robustness of our technique against strategic attackers, and its practical utility for building real-world monitoring of software vulnerabilities. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">Figure 8c</ref> suggests that by performing a retrospective analysis on the disclosure date, our technique can also detect zero-day exploits. We now discuss two such examples below, both of which were detected by the "Back 10" classifier with an operating point (corresponding to a threshold of 0.7) of 80.6% true positive and 20% false positive rate.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.1">Case studies</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CVE-2013-0640</head><p>This vulnerability affects Adobe Acrobat Reader and was disclosed on 02/13/2013 <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. It allows remote attackers to execute arbitrary code via a crafted PDF document. Our system detected this vulnerability on the same day as disclosure using data from the preceding 10 days. Interestingly, we also found proof of zero-day exploits for this vulnerability <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CVE-2013-5330</head><p>This vulnerability affects several versions of Adobe Flash Player and was disclosed on 11/12/2013. It allows attackers to execute arbitrary code or cause a denial of service (memory corruption) via unspecified vectors. Again, our system detected that this vulnerability on the disclosure day using data from the preceding 10 days. While this vulnerability has been reported as exploited in the wild, the earliest report was on 01/28/2014 <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[11]</ref>; our results suggest that this CVE might have been exploited months before this date.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.2">Robustness against strategic attacks</head><p>In security applications, strategic adversaries always have incentive to manipulate instances they have control over to evade detection <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[44,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">50,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">49,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16]</ref>. During such manipulations, the attacker usually needs to mimic normal user behavior as well as preserving their original malicious functionality without making arbitrarily large changes. Since our detection method relies on models trained using measurement data, it is potentially vulnerable to attempts of data manipulation. An adversary of the second type mentioned in Section 2.3 is such an example: we assume it has the ability to alter the patching information (as it is collected) from a significant number of hosts, so as to alter the aggregate signals and skew the similarity analysis. Below we examine how robust our detection system is against such evasion attempts.</p><p>We will simulate this data manipulation by altering the risk signals for a group of ISPs. Specifically, we randomly select a set of N ISPs from the total population I and revise their risk signals as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">w j n (t) ←− ∑ i∈N w j i (t) N ± γ · w j n (t), n ∈ N,<label>(3)</label></formula><p>where the first term is the average value among this controlled group of ISPs, and γ is randomly drawn from the set (0.1, 0.2, 0.3) for each n (similarly, ± is determined by a random coin flip) to serve as a small perturbation around the average. The intention of this manipulation is to make these N values very similar to each other, each a small perturbed version of the common average; this revision also preserves the original average so as to minimize the likelihood detection by a simple statistical test.</p><p>For each selection N we perform 20 random trials of the detection algorithm, each over different random perturbations shown above. The average AUC is reported in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">Figure 9</ref> as we increase the size of N, from 10% to 45% as a fraction of the overall ISP population I . As can be seen, our method is fairly robust against this type of evasion attacks with gracefully degrading performance. It should be noted that for examining the robustness of our method we have assumed a powerful (and not very realistic) adversary; even at 10% this would have been an extremely costly attack as it indicates the control of hosts within hundreds of ISPs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.3">Practical use</head><p>We next discuss how the proposed methodology could be used in practice, in real time, and by whom. Any software or AV vendor, as well a security company would perform such a task; they typically have access to data similar in nature to WINE. The RBLs and NVD are publicly available, so is IP intelligence data (usually at a cost). Since we rely on CVE information to perform user patching data aggregation (risk with respect to specific vulnerabilities) and on intrinsic features of a vulnerability, the detection process is triggered by a CVE disclosure. Following the disclosure, malicious activity data and user patching data can be processed on a daily basis. On each day following the disclosure we have two signals of length: risk signal w(t) and symptom signal r(t) for each ISP. Community detection, feature extraction, and detection then follow as we described earlier. In addition, the community structure can be updated in an online fashion, so the information can be obtained and maintained in a computationally efficient manner <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[27]</ref>. How our detection system can enhance security in practice lies in the primary motivation of this study: <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[38]</ref> has measured the portion of the vulnerability window (time from disclosure to patch installation) that is incurred by user negligence for four of the products included in this paper, the largest is roughly 60% for Chrome and Flash Player; suggesting delays may exist in patch development. The ability to detect active exploits early would allow a software vendor to better prioritize patch development and more judiciously allocate its resources. A secondary use of the system is to allow a network (e.g., an ISP) to identify its most at-risk host populations that have not patched a vulnerability with detected exploits, and encourage prompt actions by these hosts. This system is not meant to alter individual enduser patching behavior, but would allow users through silent updates to get patches sooner for vulnerabilities most at risk of being exploited.</p><p>Furthermore, <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[30]</ref> suggests that in the timeline of evolution of software patches, patch development happens soon after vulnerability disclosure, yet there is a gap prior to patch deployment, as, e.g., enterprises want to test patches before they deploy them. In this landscape, early detection can also be utilized by enterprises to prioritize patch deployment of vulnerabilities that are being actively exploited. Our community detection method can be used to complement intrinsic attributes of a CVE, such as the CVSS score, to detect critical vulnerabilities with more precision. Additionally, the ability to detect machines with critical software vulnerabilities helps thirdparties better assess a firm's cyber-risk, e.g., to design cyber-insurance policies and incentivize firms to improve their state of security <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[25,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">26]</ref>.</p><p>Note that our proposed technique relies on observing spam activity to detect compromised hosts, therefore our methodology fails to recognize exploits that do not result in any spam activity. However, once a machine is compromised, it is up to the attacker how they use the infected host, e.g., for ransomware, or to send spam. Even though a vulnerability might be used mainly for non-spam activities, one can detect exploitation as long as a portion of infected devices are used for sending spam. Nevertheless, infected hosts discovered by alternative bot detection techniques (e.g., scanning activity extracted from network telescope data and/or honeypots <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>) can be appended to the proposed symptomatic data, in order to build a more robust system.</p><p>Finally, while our technique is evaluated over measurements that are 3-4 years old (due to unavailability of the WINE dataset), the updating mechanism employed by the software examined herein have remained largely the same. In particular, except for Adobe Acrobat Reader, all of the software included in this study were using silent updates to automatically deliver patches to users, at the start of our observation windows <ref type="bibr">(1/2013)</ref>. This supports our claim that the same dynamics apply to more recent vulnerabilities, where even though patches are developed and disseminated by vendors through automated mechanisms, users and enterprises often opt out of keeping their software up to date, leading to eventual exploitation, and then followed by observation of symptoms. <ref type="bibr">WannaCry and NotPetya outbreaks (exploiting CVE-2017-0144)</ref>, and the Equifax data breach (caused by CVE-2017-5638) are all recent examples of this phenomena, where patches for the underlying vulnerabilities had been disseminated by software vendors months before each incident, but had not yet been deployed on the compromised machines <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">[46,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">47,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">20]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8">Related Work</head><p>Bozorgi et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref> used linear support vector to predict the development of proof-of-concept (POC) exploits by leveraging exploit metadata. Our interest in this study is solely on exploits in the wild and their early detection. In <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[36]</ref> social media was used to predict official vulnerability disclosure and it was shown that accurate prediction can be made to gain a few days in advance of disclosure announcements as an effective means of mitigating zeroday attacks. The focus of this study by contrast is the detection of exploits post-disclosure by using two distinct datasets, one capturing end-host patching behavior, the other IP level malicious activities. Allodi <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref> conducts an empirical study on the economics of vulnerability exploitation, by analyzing data collected from an underground cybercrime market.</p><p>Prior studies on end-host patching behavior heavily focus on understanding the patching behavior itself and its implication on user vulnerability and how it decays/evolves over time; these include e.g., observing patching patterns at different stages <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">[35]</ref>, the decay rate <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">53]</ref>, patching behavior across different update mechanisms <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[13,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">19]</ref>, vulnerability decay and threat by shared libraries <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[30]</ref>, among others. To the best our knowledge, ours is the first study that attempts to to detect active exploitation by correlating patching behavior and vulnerability data with host infection data inferred from a set of spam blacklists.</p><p>Detection of community structures in graphs or networks is an increasingly active field in graph mining and has seen extensive work, see e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17]</ref>. It has found wide applications in sociology <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[23,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">51,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">52]</ref>, biology <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[18,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">43,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">52]</ref>, computer science <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[31,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">51,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">52]</ref>, and many other disciplines, where data is often modeled as a graph, using community detection as a tool for visualization, to reduce graph size, and to find hidden patterns. As an example, the notion of similarity graphs is a commonly used technique to represent data. For in-stance, Holm et al. built similarity protein graphs where nodes represent protein structures and edges represent structural alignments for efficient search in the protein structure databases <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22]</ref>. Similarly, to find disjoint subsets of data, E. Hartuv et al. created similarity graphs on pairs of elements, where similarity is determined by the set of features for each element, and then perform clustering on them <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[21]</ref>. In this study, we build similarity graphs among ISPs by measuring the similarity between their time series data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="9">Conclusion</head><p>In this paper we presented a novel method based on the notion of community detection to perform early detection of vulnerability exploitation. We used symptomatic botnet data to discover a community structure revealing how similar network entities behave in terms of their malicious activities. We then analyzed the risk behavior of end-hosts through a set of patching data that allows us to assess their risk to different vulnerabilities. The latter was then compared to the former to quantify whether the underlying risks are consistent with the observed global symptomatic community structure, which then allowed us to statistically determine whether a given vulnerability is being actively exploited. Our results show that by observing up to 10 days worth of data post-disclosure, we can successfully detect the presence of exploits at 90% accuracy. This is much earlier than the recorded times of detection for most vulnerabilities. This early detection capability provides significant time advantage in patch development and deployment, among other preventative and protective measures. The community structure generated during the feature extraction can also be used to identify groups of hosts at risk to specific vulnerabilities currently being exploited, adding to our ability to strengthen preventative and protective measures.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Vulnerability disclosure, exploits and detection time line. Early detection in this study refers to the ability to detect after t C , i.e., post-disclosure, but much earlier than t E , the current state of the art.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Aggregate malicious signals of selected ISPs belonging to either green or pink community in Fig. 3.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 3 visualizes</head><label>3</label><figDesc>the communities discovered from the symptom similarity matrix corresponding to CVE- 2013-2729 from 2013/05/16 to 2013/05/26 using the Force Atlas layout</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5: Intra-and inter-cluster risk similarity on different types of CVEs based on community detection.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Figure 6: Distinguishing between EIW and NEIW CVEs.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Figure 7: Time to recorded detection (x-axis) vs the difference measure (D j ) calculated within 10 days post disclosure (y-axis); the red curve is the mean difference within each delay bin. Different categories of CVEs are color-coded, with ties broken randomly when a CVE belong to multiple categories.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Figure 8 :</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Figure 8: ROC and AUC comparison (left), precision and recall comparison (center), and comparison between different observation windows post-and pre-disclosure (right).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Figure 9 :</head><label>9</label><figDesc>Figure 9: Robustness of performance against an adversary controlling hosts within a percentage of all ISPs (x-axis).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>The top 16 intrinsic features, and their mutual 
information with both sources of ground-truth data. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> In Section 6 we also examine whether signs of infection can be detected before the official disclosure; in that case this window starts d 1 days before the disclosure and ends d 2 days after.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> The reduction in number of nodes is due to deletion of all edges to some nodes when all their edge weights are below a certain threshold.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We thank Xueru Zhang, Parinaz Naghizadeh, Pin-Yu Chen, and Ziyun Zhu for their valuable discussions on this work. This work was supported by the NSF under grants CNS-1422211, CNS-1616575, CNS-1739517, and CNS-1464163, and by the DHS via contract number FA8750-18-2-0011.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Security advisory for Adobe Reader and Acrobat</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adobe</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.adobe.com/support/security/advisories/apsa13-02.html" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Economic factors of vulnerability trade and exploitation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Allodi</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACM SIGSAC Conference on Computer and Communications Security</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1483" to="1499" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding the Mirai botnet</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Antonakakis</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">April</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Bailey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Bernhard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Bursztein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Cochran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Durumeric</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Halderman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Inv-Ernizzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Kallitsis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Al</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">USENIX Security Symposium</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
				<ptr target="http://bit.ly/1hCw1TL" />
		<title level="m">Symantec attack signatures</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gephi: An open source software for exploring and manipulating networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bastian</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Heymann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Jacomy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Al</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ICWSM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="361" to="362" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Patching is hard</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bellovin</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.cs.columbia.edu/~smb/blog/2017-05/2017-05-12.html" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">It&apos;s a kind of magic</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bennett</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Beyond heuristics: Learning to classify vulnerabilities and predict exploits</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bozorgi</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Saul</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Savage</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Voelker</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="114" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">DEMON: A local-first discovery method for overlapping communities</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Coscia</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rossetti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Giannotti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pedreschi</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="615" to="623" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Flash) in an unknown exploit kit fed by high rank websites</title>
		<idno>CVE-2013-5330</idno>
		<ptr target="http://malware.dontneedcoffee.com/2014/02/cve-2013-5330-flash-in-unknown-exploit.html" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cve</forename><surname>Id Syntax Change</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://cve.mitre.org/cve/identifiers/syntaxchange.html" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Web browser security update effectiveness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Duebendorfer</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Frei</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Workshop on Critical Information Infrastructures Security</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="124" to="137" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Toward a standard benchmark for computer security research: The Worldwide Intelligence Network Environment (WINE)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">,</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Dumitras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shou</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">Workshop on Building Analysis Datasets and Gathering Experience Returns for Security</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="89" to="96" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The matter of Heartbleed</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Durumeric</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Kasten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adrian</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Halderman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Bailey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Weaver</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Amann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Beekman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Payer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Al</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Internet Measurement Conference</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="475" to="488" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Robust physicalworld attacks on deep learning visual classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eykholt</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Evtimov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Fernandes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Rahmati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Xiao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Prakash</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kohno</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Song</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1625" to="1634" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Community detection in graphs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fortunato</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Physics Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">486</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="75" to="174" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Community structure in social and biological networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Girvan</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Newman</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">99</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7821" to="7826" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Planet scale software updates</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gkantsidis</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Karagiannis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Ro-Driguez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vojnovic</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">In ACM SIGCOMM Computer Communication Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Failure to patch two-monthold bug led to massive Equifax breach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Goodin</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2017/09/massive-equifax-breach-caused-by-failure-to-patch-two-month-old-bug" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A clustering algorithm based on graph connectivity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hartuv</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shamir</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Information Processing Letters</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="175" to="181" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Searching protein structure databases with DaliLite v. 3</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Holm</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K ¨ A ¨ Ari¨ainenari¨</forename><surname>Ari¨ainen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Rosenstr¨omrosenstr¨ Rosenstr¨om</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Schenkel</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bioinformatics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2780" to="2781" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distributed community detection in delay tolerant networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hui</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Yoneki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Chan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Crowcroft</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACM/IEEE International Workshop on Mobility in the Evolving Internet Architecture</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page">7</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">ForceAtlas2, a continuous graph layout algorithm for handy network visualization designed for the Gephi software</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jacomy</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Venturini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Heymann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bastian</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PloS one</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">98679</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Designing cyber insurance policies: Mitigating moral hazard through security pre-screening</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Khalili</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Naghizadeh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liu</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Conference on Game Theory for Networks</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="63" to="73" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Designing cyber insurance policies: The role of pre-screening and security interdependence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Khalili</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Naghizadeh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liu</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Information Forensics and Security</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2226" to="2239" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Community detection algorithms: A comparative analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lancichinetti</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fortunato</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Physical Review E</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">56117</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Common vulnerability scoring system version 2 calculator</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lin</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Yeh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Tutorial</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>PAKDD</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Maxmind</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.maxmind.com/" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The attack of the clones: A study of the impact of shared code on vulnerability patching</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nappa</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bilge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Ca-Ballero</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>And Dumitras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Community detection in content-sharing social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Natarajan</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Sen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chaoji</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IEEE/ACM International Conference on Advances in Social Networks Analysis and Mining</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="82" to="89" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Some vulnerabilities are different than others: Studying vulnerabilities and attack surfaces in the wild</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nayak</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Marino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Efstathopoulos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>And Dumitras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Symposium on Research in Attacks, Intrusions and Defenses</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-09" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scikit-learn: Machine learning in Python</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pedregosa</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Varoquaux</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Gramfort</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Michel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Thirion</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Grisel</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Blondel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Prettenhofer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Weiss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Dubourg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Al</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2825" to="2830" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The laws of vulnerabilities</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ramos</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">RSA Conference</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Vulnerability disclosure in the age of social media: Exploiting Twitter for predicting real-world exploits</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sabottke</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Suciu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>And Dumitras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">USENIX Security Symposium</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A review of feature selection techniques in bioinformatics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Saeys</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Inza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>And Larra˜nagalarra˜ Larra˜naga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bioinformatics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2507" to="2517" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Patch me if you can: A study on the effects of individual user behavior on the end-host vulnerability state</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sarabi</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Xiao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>And Dumitras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Conference on Passive and Active Network Measurement</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="113" to="125" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xbl</forename><surname>Sbl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pbl</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zen</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.spamhaus.org" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Symantec security focus community</title>
		<ptr target="http://www.securityfocus.com" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<monogr>
				<ptr target="http://www.spamcop.net" />
		<title level="m">SpamCop blocking list</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Symantec threat explorer</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Symantec</forename><surname>Corporation</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.symantec.com/security_response/threatexplorer/azlisting.jsp" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Community detection in biological networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thakur</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Applied Statistics for Network Biology: Methods in Systems Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="299" to="327" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Feature conservation in adversarial classifier evasion: A case study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tong</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Hajaj</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vorob-Eychik</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1708.08327</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Indicators associated with WannaCry ransomware</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Us-Cert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.us-cert" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Us-Cert</forename><surname>Petya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.us-cert.gov/ncas/alerts/TA17-181A" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Generating adversarial examples with adversarial networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiao</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J.-Y</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Song</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1801.02610</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiao</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J.-Y</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Song</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1801.02612</idno>
		<title level="m">Spatially transformed adversarial examples</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overlapping community detection at scale: A nonnegative matrix factorization approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Leskovec</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACM International Conference on Web Search and Data Mining</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="587" to="596" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Community detection in networks with node attributes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Mcauley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Leskovec</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IEEE International Conference on Data Mining</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1151" to="1156" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When private keys are public: Results from the 2008 Debian OpenSSL vulnerability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yilek</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Rescorla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Shacham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>En-Right</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Savage</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Internet Measurement Conference</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="15" to="27" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
