<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/atharsefid/Desktop/grobid-0.5.3/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.3" ident="GROBID" when="2020-09-29T04:05+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Open access to the Proceedings of the 29th USENIX Security Symposium is sponsored by USENIX. Hall Spoofing: A Non-Invasive DoS Attack on Grid-Tied Solar Inverter Hall Spoofing: A Noninvasive DoS Attack on Grid-Tied Solar Inverter</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>August 12-14, 2020</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anomadarshi</forename><surname>Barua</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">UC Irvine</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Irvine</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mohammad</forename><surname>Abdullah</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">UC Irvine</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Irvine</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Al</forename><surname>Faruque</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">UC Irvine</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Irvine</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anomadarshi</forename><surname>Barua</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">UC Irvine</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Irvine</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mohammad</forename><surname>Abdullah</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">UC Irvine</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Irvine</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Al</forename><surname>Faruque</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">UC Irvine</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Irvine</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Open access to the Proceedings of the 29th USENIX Security Symposium is sponsored by USENIX. Hall Spoofing: A Non-Invasive DoS Attack on Grid-Tied Solar Inverter Hall Spoofing: A Noninvasive DoS Attack on Grid-Tied Solar Inverter</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 29th USENIX Security Symposium</title>
						<meeting>the 29th USENIX Security Symposium						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published">August 12-14, 2020</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>This paper is included in the 978-1-939133-17-5</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Grid-tied solar inverters continue to proliferate rapidly to tackle the growing environmental challenges. Nowadays, different smart sensors and transducers are tightly integrated with the grid-tied inverter. This integration opens the &quot;Pan-dora&apos;s Box&quot; of unknown threats that could come from very unconventional ways. This paper demonstrates a noninvasive attack that could come by spoofing the Hall sensor of an in-verter in a stealthy way by using an external magnetic field. We demonstrate how an attacker can camouflage his/her attack tool and place it near a target inverter. In doing so, he/she can intentionally perturb grid voltage and frequency and can inject false real and reactive power to the grid. We also show the consequences of the attack on a scaled-down testbed of a power grid with a commercial 140 W grid-tied inverter from Texas Instruments. We are able to achieve a 31.52% change in output voltage, 3.16x (-6dB to-11dB) increase in low-frequency harmonics power, and 3.44x increase in real power. Moreover, we introduce a duty-cycle variation approach for a noninvasive adversarial control that can change the inverter voltage up to 34% and real power up to 38%. We discuss the feasibility of using a 100 kW inverter through discussion. This provides insights behind the generalization of the attack model. In addition, the commercial power system simulation tool Etap 19.0.1 is used to simulate the impact of the attack on a 2.3 MW power grid. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first methodology that highlights the possibility of such an attack that might lead to grid blackout in a weak grid.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Cyber-physical systems (CPSs) in power grids comprise sophisticated control mechanisms. These mechanisms may produce multidisciplinary security issues capable of compromising the Availability and Integrity <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">3]</ref> of the power grids. Examples of such attacks on power CPSs include cyberattacks on the Ukrainian power grid <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref>, DoS attacks on anonymous western utilities in the U.S. power sector <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>, the Slammer worm attack on Ohio's Davis-Besse nuclear power plant <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref>, the Stuxnet malware attack on Iran's nuclear facilities <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>, etc. The results of these attacks are very serious, including region-wise blackouts affecting more than 230,000 residents <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref> and monetary losses <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref>.</p><p>Nowadays, distributed energy sources are proliferating rapidly and a substantial portion of these sources are highly efficient grid-tied solar inverters 1 <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">11]</ref> equipped with Hall sensors. These Hall sensors, however, can be cleverly spoofed to orchestrate a noninvasive attack on the grid. The attack in question can perturb the normal operation of a power system and may cause grid failures in a weak grid. It is important to note that a strong grid gradually becomes weak due to the continuous integration of distributed energy sources <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref>. Strong grids may also behave as weak grids at a particular time of a day (e.g., peak hours). Moreover, micro-grids <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref> also behave as weak grids when connected over long cables to a utility grid. A detailed background of strong and weak grids is provided in Section 3.1.</p><p>This paper shows that a smart attacker can inject measurement errors into the Hall sensors of an inverter using a noninvasive magnetic spoofing technique with adversarial control. The injected errors can propagate from the compromised Hall sensor to the internal controllers of the inverter and eventually compromise the inverter itself. The compromised inverter can hamper the grid stability and may cause grid failures in a weak grid scenario. This method is similar to the false data injection approach. But in this case, the injection is coming from the physical domain by exploiting the physics of the Hall sensor. We show that the attacker can intelligently control the false data injection by applying distinct types of external magnetic fields, such as constant, sinusoidal, and square pulsating magnetic fields, on the Hall sensors. This may perturb the inverter output voltage, frequency, real and reactive power. This perturbation can propagate through the cyber domain and finally impact the physical domain. Hence, this can be termed as an attack from Physical-to-Cyber-to-Physical (P-2-C-2-P) domain <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref>. In power CPSs, this type of cross-domain attack is yet to be explored in depth by the security community.</p><p>Technical Contributions: Our technical contributions are listed as follows that are elaborated in the following sections:</p><p>i. A new attack model (Section 4) that describes how the availability of the grid-tied inverter is stealthily breached.</p><p>ii. Algorithms and a potential design for the relevant attack tool (i.e., Embedded Hall Spoofing Controller) and mathematical models of an inverter's control blocks (Section 5).</p><p>iii. A testbed (Section 6) with a scaled-down model of a power grid, on which the attack model is validated and adversarial control is demonstrated (Section 7).</p><p>iv. The attack model is further evaluated (Section 8) using an industry-standard commercially used Electrical Power System Analysis Software (Etap 19.0.1) on a medium-sized 2.3 MW (equivalent to approx. ∼ 150 houses) grid.</p><p>v. Defense (Section 9.1) is proposed and justified, and limitations (Section 9.2) of this attack are noted.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>We discuss here different attacks on analog sensors, inertial sensors, and on power systems that exist in the literature.</p><p>Attacks on Analog Sensors: Kune et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref> spoofed sensors by electromagnetic interference (EMI) to induce defibrillation shocks on implantable cardiac devices. Park et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref> used infrared to trigger a medical infusion pump to deliver overdose to patients. Davidson et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17]</ref> reported how spoofing optical sensors of an unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) can compromise complete control of the lateral movement. Yan et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[18]</ref> published a contact-less attack on self-driving cars using ultrasound and EMI. Shin et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19]</ref> showed a spoofing attack on LiDar to create illusions of objects appearing closer in automotive systems. Zhang et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref> injected inaudible commands into a microphone using ultrasonic carriers. Lastly, Shoukry et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[21]</ref> used an external magnetic field to spoof the Antilock Braking System (ABS) to change the wheel speed of a vehicle. There are a few fundamental differences between our work and <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[21]</ref>. First, the attacker requires access to place the electromagnetic actuator near the ABS wheel speed sensor and must strongly secure the attack object ABS Hacker to the vehicle body, likely with a nut and bolt. Second, the original magnetic field of the vehicle must be shielded before spoofing.</p><p>The space to place this extra shield near the ABS sensor is critical. Third, the ABS Hacker comprises expensive heterogeneous processors. Fourth, the adaptive controller of <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[21]</ref> requires complex tuning of its closed-loop poles and zeros. In contrast to <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[21]</ref>, our attack can be noninvasively executed on a cheap Arduino board and does not require strong physical mounting or extra shielding.</p><p>Attacks on Inertial Sensors: Son et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22]</ref> used high power sound noise to compromise the gyroscope of a drone to make it uncontrollable. <ref type="bibr">Wang et al. [23]</ref> used a sonic gun to demonstrate acoustic attacks on different inertial sensors. Trippel et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[24]</ref> showed fine-grained adversarial control over MEMS accelerometers using acoustic signals to damage digital integrity. <ref type="bibr">Tu et al. [25]</ref> also demonstrated adversarial control over embedded inertial sensors to trigger the actuation of different control systems. In contrast to their methods (e.g., biasing attack, sample rate drifts, etc.), our paper introduces a duty-cycle variation approach for adversarial control that is novel in our attack model in the power CPSs.</p><p>Attacks on Modern Power Systems: There are quite a lot of works on traditional Cyber-to-Physical domain (C-2-P) attacks in the literature, such as malicious false data injection <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[26]</ref>, flooding <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[27]</ref>, arbitrary command injection <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[28]</ref>, timedelay input attack <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[29]</ref>, load distribution attack <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[30]</ref>. Ilge Akkaya et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[31]</ref> used GPS spoofing on Phase Measurement Units (PMUs) to lead a substation to an erroneous state. In contrast to these works, our work demonstrates an unconventional P-2-C-2-P attack in the power CPSs.</p><p>Our work shows how an attacker can cause damage (e.g., blackout) to the connected power grid by intelligently applying constant, sinusoidal, and square pulsating magnetic fields. Moreover, in contrast to the prior works, this paper models the vulnerable blocks of the controller of an inverter and mathematically proves the underlying principle of propagation of attack from sensors to the internal controllers. Our attack impact is more realistic, has more economically damaging effect, and can impact a large region.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Background</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Strong and Weak Grid in the Power CPSs</head><p>The grid where voltage and frequency are stable and do not vary during load connection/disconnection is known as a strong grid. Historically, rotational generators are present in the power systems. Rotational generators have prime movers to convert rotational kinetic energy into electrical energy. Rotational energy stored in the prime mover of these generators acts as an inertia against any sudden change of load in the system; therefore, the voltage/frequency does not vary abruptly within a limit in the grid when a small load is disconnected from the grid. It is important to note that a strong grid is not ideally strong all the time. The voltage/frequency of a strong grid may vary abruptly if the change of the load is large compared to the generation capacity, or if the rotational energy stored in the prime mover is not sufficient to compensate for the sudden change in the grid. Hence, a strong grid can behave as a weak grid. A weak grid refers to a grid wherein its voltage is highly sensitive to any variation in the load <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[32]</ref>.</p><p>Due to the continuous integration of distributed solar/wind inverters, the modern grid is shifting from centralized to distributed generation resulting in poor control and lack of inertia (i.e., rotational turbines). This causes grid weakening over time <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref>, which is already a concern in the community. In this scenario, an attacker can perturb the grid voltage/frequency using an inverter and this perturbation may disrupt the entire system. Moreover, low generation, long transmission lines, etc., can also contribute to weak grids. We can also find weak grids in isolated places like Baja, Mexico; parts of Alaska; or under-developed areas between strong grids.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Real Power, Reactive Power and Phase</head><p>An inverter can inject real power and reactive power into the grid. Real power is related to grid frequency and reactive power is related to grid voltage <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[33]</ref>. If the generation of real power is lower than the real power demand, the grid frequency may fall. Whereas, if the generation of reactive power is lower than the required, the grid voltage may fall. Real power is the amount of power in watts (W) being dissipated, and reactive power results from inductive/capacitive loads measured in volt-ampere reactive (VAR) <ref type="bibr">(Appendix 11.2)</ref>. The phase is the position of a point of a wave in a time instant. Three-phase voltages are 120 o phase apart from each other.  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 1</ref> shows the working principle of a typical Hall sensor. It comprises a Hall element, which is made of a thin piece of p-type semiconductor material (e.g. Gallium Arsenide, etc.). Let us assume that a bias current I bias is flowing in +ve Y direction (terminal 1, 3) of the Hall element having thickness d. This Hall element is placed within an applied magnetic field B whose direction is -ve Z-axis. The charge carriers inside the Hall sensors feel a force along +ve X-axis. This force is known as the Lorentz force F. Due to this Lorentz force, the charge carriers will be deflected along the +ve Xaxis and a voltage V Hall will be generated across the Hall element. The generated voltage V Hall may be expressed as:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Working Principle of a Hall Sensor</head><formula xml:id="formula_0">V Hall = k( I bias d × B)<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where k is the hall coefficient, which depends upon the properties of the hall element. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Why is a Hall Sensor Used in an Inverter?</head><p>Inverters measure grid voltage, current, and their phase angles for important control applications. Four methods <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">[34]</ref> are mainly used to measure voltage/current: i) Resistive drop/-divider method, ii) Magneto-resistance method, iii) A voltage/current transformer, and iv) A Hall effect sensor. A resistive drop/divider is not suitable for high voltage/current measurement because of the following reasons: high power loss in the resistor itself, inability to measure small DC current in the presence of large AC current, and absence of proper isolation. A magneto-resistive material is nonlinear and temperature-dependent, therefore, it is not suitable for accurate high current measurement. A voltage/current transformer is not suitable for simultaneous AC/DC measurement and is bulky. It also requires an external resistance to convert current into voltage and has a low efficiency for core loss. In contrast, the Hall effect sensor has excellent accuracy, high efficiency, very good linearity, low thermal drift, and low response time. It is lightweight, compact, and suitable for simultaneous large AC/DC voltage/current measurement with galvanic isolation. Therefore, Hall sensors are pervasive in high power inverter applications <ref type="bibr">(Appendix 11.4)</ref>.</p><p>To show the prevalence of Hall sensors in inverters, we investigate six industry-designed inverters (small to medium range) and a large 100 kW inverter. All these inverters <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">(Table 1</ref> and Section 8) have similar functional blocks, and Hall effect sensors are present in the measurement unit. This is because inverters are optimized for efficiency and accuracy, but not for security from this type of unconventional spoofing attack.  Attacker's Intent: The attacker wants to disrupt the normal operation of a power system by spoofing an inverter noninvasively and wants to cause grid failures in a weak grid.</p><p>Attacker's Capabilities: The attacker can surreptitiously place a small box near the target inverter. This box contains a powerful electromagnet integrated with an electronic spoofing controller (i.e., Embedded Hall Spoofing Controller). This box is small enough to be camouflaged within a small container, such as flower vase, coffee cup. Placing the camouflaged attack tool near the inverter requires a brief one-time access. The box has wireless controls allowing for remote communication. Therefore, the attacker can remotely control the timing of the attack and can pick a vulnerable time (e.g., at peak hour, etc.) to impact the connected power grid. The authorities of the target inverter may not be aware of this attack model and would possibly neglect the security implications of any small camouflaged box placed near an inverter.</p><p>Attacker's Access Level: The access near the inverter needed for the attack can be possible in at least three scenarios. First (most likely), a malicious employee or a guest, who has access near the inverter, may place the camouflaged attack tool near the inverter. An incident similar to this has </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Physical Domain</head><p>Figure 2: Brief overview of the Hall spoofing attack methodology. already been reported in past news <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[41]</ref>. A disgruntled exemployee of an electric utility in Texas posted a note in a hacker journal indicating that his insider knowledge of the system could be used to shut down that region's power grid. Moreover, solar plants are usually located in an isolated place with less security <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[42]</ref>. Getting a brief one-time access near the isolated solar plants may not be difficult. <ref type="bibr">Staggs et al.</ref> [42] demonstrated how easily an attacker can access a wind plant in the middle of a remote field and can invasively place an attack tool inside of the wind turbine. Our attack model is stronger compared to <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[42]</ref> because of its noninvasive nature. Second, the manufacturer may introduce the malicious electromagnet with controllers inside of the solar inverter. Third is interdiction, which has been rumored to be used in the past <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">[43,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">44,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">45,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">46]</ref> and has been recently proven to be feasible <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">[47]</ref>. During interdiction, a competitor can intercept the inverter during delivery or installation and may modify the inverter by placing an electronic device inside and then proceed with delivery or installation to the customer.</p><p>Stealthy Nature: The attacker can remotely perturb the inverter by camouflaging the tiny attack tool and can choose the timing of the attack to remain unidentified to maximize the impact. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig. 3</ref> is an example that shows how the attacker can place the camouflaged attack tool near the target inverter. Outcome of this Attack: The attacker may cause grid failures if the power grid is weak. And for weakly protected systems, the attacker can fry the internal circuitry of the inverter itself. By spoofing the Hall sensor, the attacker can give a false impression that the conditions required for synchronization of the inverter with the grid have been achieved when they have not. This improper grid synchronization may shut down the inverter (Section 7.1). A micro-grid is a group of interconnected loads and distributed energy resources, which can operate in both grid-connected or island mode <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref>. The attacker can disconnect the micro-grid from the utility grid at a random time or can prevent it from disconnecting even when it is supposed to disconnect (e.g., in the case of an outage). The attacker can choose the timing of the attack and can remotely shut down the inverter in peak hours to create a shortage of real/reactive power with no prior notice to the authority. This scenario can be significant in a weak grid and a micro-grid. As the timing of the attack can be remotely controlled, the attacker can cause a security breach by randomly shutting down the local solar power supply of any important organization, remote airport, army base, etc. The attacker can prevent the inverter from starting and can cause a repetitive shutdown. Simply pressing the restart button of the inverter may not solve the problem until the attack tool is removed. As this attack is stealthy, it can remain unidentified. This trick, which may cause grid instability, can be used to ask for ransom or to blackmail the utility.</p><p>Attacker's Safety: As inverters handle high voltage, it is unsafe for the attacker to invasively manipulate them. In this sense, our attack model is safe for the attacker as it enables the attacker to control the operation of the inverter noninvasively.</p><p>Attacker's Resources: We assume that the attacker has domain knowledge of the inverter controllers with some high school knowledge of electromagnetism.</p><p>Cost: The design cost of the Embedded Hall Spoofing Controller and the electromagnet is less than $50. The electronic parts are readily available from Amazon and Digikey.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Attack Model Design</head><p>This section explains how an attacker can design the attack tool (i.e., Embedded Hall Spoofing Controller). This section also mathematically models important basic blocks of an inverter irrespective of the inverter size.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Embedded Hall Spoofing Controller</head><p>The Embedded Hall Spoofing Controller consists of an electromagnet, an Arduino Uno, few MOSFETs, a Zigbee RF module, an Ultrasonic Sensor, and Energizer A23 Batteries. A small (height 3.8 cm, radius 3.5 cm) but powerful electromagnet (WF-P80/38) is used as a source of magnetic field. An electromagnet can also be built by winding wires around a strong neodymium (NIB) magnet, which is easily found in a computer hard disk <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">[48]</ref>. An ultrasonic sensor (HC-SR04) is interfaced with the Arduino board to measure the distance between the electromagnet and the inverter shield. This distance helps to calculate the required strength of the Magneto-Motive Force (MMF) to influence the Hall sensors and stops oversupply of power to extend the battery lifetime. MMF measures technique. This PWM helps to generate variable-frequency electromagnetic flux and controls the power input to the electromagnet depending upon the attacker's need and intention. To protect the MOSFET from an inductive surge (due to the switching of the large electromagnet), a free-wheeling diode (U1620G) is connected across the electromagnet.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Controller Compromising Algorithm</head><p>The algorithm, which compromises the inverter controller, runs on the Arduino Uno (Algorithm 1). It is computationally inexpensive and may run on the Arduino for a long period with the battery pack mentioned in Section 5.1. It controls the ultrasonic sensor, Zigbee modules, and ADC, PWM, RX-TX peripherals of the Arduino Uno. After initializing the necessary modules and peripherals, the algorithm first checks for battery voltage level to see whether it is above the threshold. Otherwise, it returns ErrorCode after informing the attacker about this issue through Zigbee. Then the distance from the inverter is calculated using the ultrasonic module. If it is outside of the range, it notifies the attacker (ErrorCode) through Zigbee. Otherwise, it activates the MOSFET switching block and generates PWM frequency depending upon the attacker's need and intention for different attack scenarios. The attacker can also enable adversarial control and provide duty-cycle to the attack tool through the Zigbee. Depending upon the provided duty-cycle (see Section 7.4), the PowerController supplies the required amount of power to the electromagnet. This algorithm also checks for MagnetCurrent, which is flowing through the electromagnet. If it is less than the required amount, the algorithm also notifies the attacker.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Modelling Grid-Tied Inverters</head><p>This section mathematically models the basic blocks of the inverter controller. A grid-tied solar inverter can be singlephase or three-phase. <ref type="figure">Fig. 5</ref> shows the basic blocks of a threephase inverter. Let us denote the balanced abc-phase (phase a, b, c) grid voltages by e a , e b , and e c , which are 120 0 phase apart. These abc-phase grid voltages may be represented by a </p><formula xml:id="formula_1">񮽙 S abc (t) =   e a e b e c   =   E cos ωt E cos(ωt − 120 0 ) E cos(ωt + 120 0 )   (2)</formula><p>where E is the amplitude and ω is the angular frequency of the grid voltage. Terms e a , e b , and e c are sensed by three Hall effect voltage sensors (we name these as grid sensors) and then are sampled by the Digital Signal Processing (DSP) unit.</p><p>The abc-to-dq Transformation Block: This block transforms abc-phase grid voltage 񮽙 S abc into direct-quadrature (dq) axis components, which are direct current (DC) quantities. This transformation facilitates the designing of a simple controller, such as the Proportional-Integral (PI) controller, in DC domain <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">[49]</ref>. We know the axis of the rotor flux of a rotating machine is known as direct <ref type="formula">(d)</ref>  A loop filter with inductance L is present between 񮽙 S abc and 񮽙 U abc for signal smoothing. The relation between 񮽙 S abc and 񮽙 U abc can be simplified using their dq axis components (e d , e q and u d , u q ) and finally can be expressed as (Appendix 11.6):</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">u d = e d + L di d dt − ω Li q (4) u q = L di q dt + ω Li d<label>(5)</label></formula><p>Generation of Reference Currents (i * d , i * q ): Two reference points, which are i * d and i * q , control the real and reactive power set points of the inverter. The solar panel output voltage V T and current I T are sensed by two separate Hall voltage and current sensors (we name these as solar panel sensors). V T and I T are given as inputs to a Maximum Power Point Tracking (MPPT) block that generates reference point i * d to track the maximum available real power from the panel. The other reference point i * q is generated from the reference reactive power Q * , which is provided by the facility's energy management systems using a Wide/Local Area Network <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">[50]</ref>.</p><p>Proportional </p><formula xml:id="formula_3">u p d = K p (i * d − i d ) + K i (i * d − i d )<label>(6)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_4">u p q = K p (i * q − i q ) + K i (i * q − i q )<label>(7)</label></formula><p>where K p and K i are the proportional and integral constants of the PI controllers. The term i * d is related with real power and i * q is related with reactive power. By tracking these two quantities, PI controllers control the correct injection of real and reactive power into the grid (Eqn. 6, 7).</p><p>Space </p><formula xml:id="formula_5">u * d = e d + u p d − ω Li q<label>(8)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_6">u * q = u p q + ω Li d<label>(9)</label></formula><p>Note that, the reference voltages u * d and u * q depend on reference currents i * d and i * q , dq components of grid currents i d and i q , angular frequency ω, and filter inductance L.</p><p>Phase Locked Loop (PLL) Block: PLL synchronizes the inverter output frequency with the grid frequency by implementing the following equation <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">[51]</ref>:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">e d e q = cos θ * sin θ * − sin θ * cos θ * eα e β = k cos(θ − θ * ) sin(θ − θ * )<label>(10)</label></formula><p>where k is a constant, θ and θ * are the instantaneous phase angles (i.e., frequency) of the grid and inverter output voltage, respectively. The PI controller of the PLL tries to equal e q with e * q . Therefore, if the reference value e * q is set to 0 (generated internally), e q in Eqn. 10 will be also close to 0. This causes sin(θ − θ * ) = 0 (i.e., θ = θ * ) in Eqn. 10. This results in gridsynchronization, because the inverter output voltage 񮽙 U abc has the same phase (i.e., θ = θ * ) as the grid voltage 񮽙 S abc . Single Phase Grid Controllers: A single-phase grid-tied inverter has similar blocks as the three-phase, except it does not have Clarke matrix transformation, but it uses Phase Shifters. As it has a similar controller, an adversary can similarly affect it using the same attack methodology.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Experimental Setup 6.1 A Scaled-Down Testbed of a Power Grid</head><p>To avoid safety concerns related to high voltage and high power experiments, we have created a scaled-down version of a real grid in our lab <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">(Fig. 6)</ref> to validate our attack model. A 140 W grid-tied inverter kit (part# = TMDSOLARUIN-VKIT) from Texas Instruments Inc. is used. This is a scaleddown version of a practical solar inverter. This inverter has a Piccolo-B control card (C2000 microcontroller) that implements all the controller blocks (e.g., PLL, Park &amp; Clarke transformations, PI controllers, MPPT, SVPWM, etc.). The supported software kit is downloaded from ControlSUITE, then compiled using Code Composer Studio 9.1.0 IDE, and then flashed into the solar inverter kit. The Solar panel is emulated by a DC Power source (Part# = PSB 2400L2). An isolated and stable grid is created using another inverter (Part# = BESTEK) with a 300 W load. The 140 W target solar inverter is connected with this stable grid to emulate a weak grid. Oscilloscopes (Part# = Tektronix TDS2022C) with differential probes (Part# = Yokogawa 700924 Probe 1400V / 100 MHz) and multimeters are used to measure the inverter output voltage, current, and power before and after the attack. In order to assist the understanding for readers, attack demonstration and results are shown in a video in the following link: https: //sites.google.com/view/usenix-spoofing/home </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Feasibility Analysis of the Attack</head><p>The feasibility of this attack methodology depends upon the following three key factors: (i) The location of the Hall sensors, (ii) The barrier and EM shielding around the inverter, and (iii) The amount of MMF required to overcome the barrier and influence the Hall sensors. As Hall sensors measure the voltage/current, they normally are placed nearby where the solar panel and the grid voltage cables enter the inverter board. Therefore, the PV Connection side and the Grid Connection side are two suitable locations to place the camouflaged attack tool near the inverter <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">(Fig. 7)</ref>. The Hall sensors are within 4 cm from the board edge for our experimental inverter. This information regarding the location of the Hall sensors is essential to optimal placement of the attack tool and thus maximizing the attack's impact.</p><p>The generated MMF by the electromagnet should be strong enough to overcome the following two barriers: (i) The air gap between the body of the inverter and the electromagnet, and (ii) The metallic shield around the inverter.</p><p>Most of the generated MMF is used to overcome the air gap barrier because air has a very high magnetic reluctance. The more the air gap (the distance between the inverter and the electromagnet) is, the more MMF is required to overcome the distance. After penetrating the air, the remaining MMF is used to penetrate the shield around the solar inverter. If the shield is non-magnetic (e.g., aluminum, tin, brass, stainless steel, etc.) or non-metallic (e.g., plastic, polycarbonate, etc.), the remaining MMF can easily penetrate the shield. If the shield is made of ferromagnets (e.g., steel, etc.), the remaining MMF should be strong enough to saturate the ferromagnetic shield, so that its magnetic shielding property gets diminished <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">[52]</ref>. For example, 0.6 Tesla magnetic flux density is sufficient to saturate steel shield <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">[53]</ref>.</p><p>Is it possible to generate that much MMF by our Embedded Hall Spoofing Controller? We discuss some comparative numbers here to answer this question. It is possible to make a 0.1 Tesla to 2 Tesla powerful lab magnet with 500-9000 turns on an iron core <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">[54]</ref>. A coin-sized neodymium magnet has 0.5-1.25 Tesla <ref type="bibr">[55]</ref> and a typical loudspeaker magnet has 1-2.4 Tesla [56] magnetic strength. Our experimental electromagnet has approx. ∼4000 turns that can generate up to 0.8 Tesla with the mentioned battery pack. This is sufficient to spoof the Hall sensors of an inverter from at most 10 cm distance. Here we consider a steel shield around the inverter. By investing more money (&gt;$50) on the magnetic core (e.g., neodymium-iron-boron (Nd 2 Fe 14 B) rare earth magnet <ref type="bibr">[55]</ref>), we can shrink the size of the electromagnet and make it stronger to spoof from 10+ cm distance. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>DC + Hall sensors</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Attack Model Validation</head><p>In this section we validate our proposed attack model, which is explained in Section 4, in our lab testbed for 5 different scenarios. We also explain how the attack propagates from the sensor to the inverter controller by using suitable equations. It is clear from Section 5.3 that grid voltage 񮽙 S abc can control the inverter output voltage 񮽙 U abc (Eqn. 8, 9) and phase angle θ (Eqn. 10); inverter output voltage 񮽙 U abc and real power P depend on output current 񮽙 I abc (Eqn. 8, 9), solar panel voltage V T , and current C T ; and inverter reactive power Q depends on output current 񮽙 I abc and reference i * q . The above dependency information is important from the attacker's perspective and can be formulated mathematically as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">θ = f ( 񮽙 S abc ); 񮽙 U abc = f ( 񮽙 S abc , 񮽙 I abc ,V T , I T ) P = f ( 񮽙 I abc ,V T , I T ); Q = f ( 񮽙 I abc , i * q )<label>(11)</label></formula><p>where f (.) is the function notation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.1">Attacking Grid Synchronization</head><p>Two conditions must be satisfied to synchronize the inverter with the grid <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[33]</ref>: (i) inverter output voltage 񮽙 U abc must be slightly higher than the grid voltage 񮽙 S abc , and (ii) inverter voltage phase θ must be same as the grid voltage phase. Scenario 1: Let us assume the attacker spoofs only the grid voltage ( 񮽙 S abc ) sensors with a constant ±MMF (aligning and opposing polarity). Therefore, the attacker considers injecting magnetic field ±∆B into the Hall grid voltage sensors. The term +∆B means that the applied +MMF aligns vertically in the same direction of the Hall sensor measurement axis, and −∆B means that the applied -MMF aligns vertically in the opposite direction of the Hall sensor measurement axis <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">(Fig.  8</ref>). An injection of ±∆B results in a false Hall voltage V f Hall ; therefore Eqn. 1 may be expressed as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">V f Hall = k{ I bias d × (B ± ∆B)}<label>(12)</label></formula><p>V f Hall causes injection of false voltages, which include ±∆E a , ±∆E b , and ±∆E c (± for ±MMF), into grid voltage vector 񮽙 S abc . Therefore, Eqn. 2 is changed as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">񮽙 S f alse abc (t) =   e a ± ∆E a e b ± ∆E b e c ± ∆E c  <label>(13)</label></formula><p>where ±∆E a , ±∆E b , and ±∆E c may be different from each other. The low-pass filter of the DSP unit cannot filter out these false voltages. So, 񮽙 S f alse abc propagates to the following abcto-dq transformation block. This affects Eqn. 3 as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">񮽙 S f alse dq = e d e q = 񮽙 3 2 E 0 ± PM × ∆eα ∆e β<label>(14)</label></formula><p>where  <ref type="figure">Figure 9</ref>: Spoofing grid-tied inverter output voltage. the DSP unit cannot filter out this false signal. This propagates to the following abc-to-dq transformation block and creates a false current 񮽙 I f alse dq . This affects Eqn. 6 and 7 as follows: The attack Scenario 2 is demonstrated in our testbed by spoofing a grid current sensor using 0.8 Tesla from a 7.8 cm distance <ref type="figure">(Fig. 9)</ref>. The attacker causes an increase in the inverter output voltage from -125 V to -85.6 V (∆V = + 31.52%) by +MMF spoofing and causes a decrease from +125 V to +85.6 V (∆V = -31.52%) by -MMF spoofing. This creates a sudden mismatch between the inverter output voltage and the grid voltage. This mismatch forces the inverter to shut down.  has different phase angles and amplitudes than 񮽙 S abc . The low-pass filter of the DSP unit cannot filter out this injected low frequency (&lt; 2Hz) error, and the error propagates to the following PLL block of the controller. Hence, the R.H.S of the Eqn. 10 is given by:</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">u f d = K p (i * d − i f alse d ) + K i (i * d − i f alse d )<label>(15)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_13">u f q = K p (i * q − i f alse q ) + K i (i * q − i f</formula><formula xml:id="formula_14">abc (t) =   e a + ∆E a (t) e b + ∆E b (t) e c + ∆E c (t   =    E f 1a cos(ωt + θ f a ) E f 2a cos(ωt + θ f b ) E f 3a cos(ωt + θ f c )   <label>(17</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_15">e d e q = cos θ * sin θ * − sin θ * cos θ * e f α e f β = k cos(θ f − θ * ) sin(θ f − θ * )<label>(18)</label></formula><p>where e f α and e f β are propagated errors that cause false phase angle θ f of the grid voltage. The PLL of the inverter tries to lock with the attacker provided phase angle θ f (i.e., θ * = θ f ). This causes a frequency mismatch between the grid and the inverter voltage. This frequency mismatch causes frequency oscillations and may cause grid failures in weak grids.</p><p>The attack Scenario 3 is demonstrated in our testbed and the outcome is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 10</ref>. The attacker injects 0.8 Tesla magnetic pulse (1Hz) from a 7.8 cm distance into the grid voltage sensors. This causes the inverter output frequency to go out of phase. The output voltage shape is completely distorted when the attack tool is placed within 1 cm of the inverter (extreme scenario). <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 11</ref> shows the Fast Fourier Transform (FFT) analysis of the inverter output voltage. The frequency spectrum reveals the strong presence of low-frequency components (&lt;10Hz) and indicates that low frequency (1Hz) power is 3.16x (-6dB to -11dB) more than the fundamental frequency (60Hz) power during the attack. This distorted output wave shuts down the inverter, and blackout occurs in the testbed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.2">False Real/Reactive Power Injection</head><p>The attacker can attack 񮽙 I abc , V T , or I T sensor depending upon his resources to perturb the real power or reactive power injection (Eqn. 11). Note that, three current sensors are placed in the AC section of the inverter to measure 񮽙 I abc , and one voltage sensor and one current sensor are placed in the DC section of the inverter (note that we name these as solar panel sensors) to measure the solar voltage V T or the current I T .</p><p>Scenario 4: Let us assume the attacker wants to perform a real power injection attack; therefore, the attacker considers attacking either V T or I T sensor by spoofing with a constant </p><formula xml:id="formula_16">= K p (i * f d − i d ) + K i (i * f d − i d )<label>(20)</label></formula><p>u f d can change the input reference voltage of the SVPWM (Eqn. 8, 9) causing more or less injection of real power than required into the grid. This phenomenon may alter the demand response of the grid and can be critical in a weak grid. The results of this scenario are discussed in detail in Section 7.3.</p><p>Scenario 5: Let us assume the attacker wants to perform a reactive power injection attack; therefore, the attacker considers attacking the 񮽙 I abc sensors (Eqn. 11). The attacker can use pulsating square (⊓) MMF (as a square wave generation is easier than the sine wave generation) to spoof the 񮽙 I abc sensors. It creates pulsating perturbation ∆I ⊓ (t) with frequency ω ⊓ , which may be expressed as: ∆I ⊓ (t) = sgn(sin(ω ⊓ t)), where sgn is the signum function. The pulsating error ∆I ⊓ (t) may cause pulsating voltage V f ⊓ Hall (t) (Eqn. 12). This false V f ⊓ Hall (t) results in an injection of pulsating ∆I a⊓ (t), ∆I b⊓ (t), ∆I c⊓ (t) measurement errors into 񮽙 I abc as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">񮽙 I f alse abc (t) =   I cos ωt + sgn(sin(ω ⊓ t)) I cos(ωt − 120 0 ) + sgn(sin(ω ⊓ t)) I cos(ωt + 120 0 ) + sgn(sin(ω ⊓ t))  <label>(21)</label></formula><p>The pulsating false current 񮽙 I f alse abc (t) creates a pulsating qaxis current i ⊓ q after the abc-to-dq transformation (Section 5). PI current controller cannot properly track the i * q due to the pulsating nature of i ⊓ q . As a result, a pulsating error voltage is produced (Eqn. 7) that causes a pulsating push of reactive power into the grid. This may cause fluctuation in the grid voltage. And for a weak grid scenario, this fluctuation for a long time may be detrimental for the grid health. As our setup does not have reactive power injection capability, we have shown the impacts of this scenario via simulation using a commercially used software Etap (Section 8.2). For scenarios 2 and 3, 40.17% output voltage variation and 26.3% Total Harmonic Distortion (THD) in output frequency are noted, respectively, for 7.5 cm of spoofing-distance. The THD value refers to the magnitude of harmonics (i.e., due to injected errors) present in the frequency. The inverter is shut down if the spoofing-distance is less than 7 cm for scenarios 2 and 3. This is shown as a flat line (100% variation) in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig.  12</ref>. For attack scenario 4, real power injection increases from 45 W to 155 W (240% increase) for +MMF spoofing, and the inverter is shut down for -MMF spoofing for 1cm spoofingdistance. The attack impact prevails up to 10 cm for scenarios 2, 3 and up to 8 cm for scenario 4 in our experimental setup. Note that MMF follows the inverse square law with distance (MMF ∝ 1/distance 2 ). However, inverter power, voltage, and frequency may not change by following the inverse square law. The reason for this is that the relevant controllers are nonlinear and they may add higher order poles and zeros. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 12</ref> supports this claim. It shows that real power, voltage, and frequency change in inverse of higher order (greater than inverse square) with distance. Moreover, voltage and frequency vary significantly compared to power. This indicates that voltage and frequency are more sensitive than power to distance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.3">Attack-Impact with Spoofing-Distance</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.4">Controlling Inverter Voltage and Power</head><p>The generated MMF from the electromagnet depends upon power, and this power is supplied by the battery pack. The attacker can remotely send adversarial commands (i.e., dutycycle) using the Zigbee to control the input power to the electromagnet (i.e., spoofing-power). The Embedded Hall Spoofing Controller can vary the spoofing-power according to the received adversarial command. This results in varying MMF exerted to the inverter. As our attack model is noninvasive, the direct feedback from the compromised Hall sensor to the Embedded Hall spoofing Controller is absent. Rather, the ultrasonic sensor provides specific information about the distance between the inverter and the attack tool. This information acts as a weak feedback to control the spoofing-power and this can be utilized to control the inverter voltage and power from a specific distance.</p><p>Duty-Cycle Variation: The spoofing-power can be controlled from a specific distance by using a PWM technique. PWM is used to vary the duty-cycle (i.e., active/on-time) of the relevant MOSFET. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 13</ref> shows that by varying the dutycycle of a signal of 100Hz from 0% to 100%, the attacker can change the power input to the electromagnet from 0 W to 50 W and can control the output voltage and the real power of the inverter <ref type="bibr">(Eqn. 12, 15, 16, and 20</ref> give more insights). This experiment is conducted by placing the electromagnet 5 cm away from the sensors. When the magnetic field is applied to grid sensors, the output voltage of the inverter changes in sublinear fashion from 0% to 34%, up to 32 W of input power to the electromagnet. The inverter stops working after this point, and this is shown as a flat line (100% variation). When the magnetic field is applied to solar panel sensors, the real power output of the inverter changes in sub-linear fashion from 0% to 38%, up to 50 W of input power to the electromagnet. The battery pack can provide this amount of power as this power is required only for a few seconds. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 13</ref> shows that the 35 W power applied to grid sensors may turn off the inverter, but the same power applied to solar panel sensors may not do the same. This indicates that the inverter is more sensitive to its grid voltage variation than its real power variation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Inverter Stopped after +MMF spoofing on grid sensor</head><p>Adversarial control over output voltage using electromagnetic power Adversarial control over output real power using electromagnetic power </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8">Attack Evaluation in a Practical Grid</head><p>In Section 7, different attack scenarios are demonstrated using a 140 W inverter in our testbed. However, in this section, an industry used software, the Electrical Power System Analysis &amp; Operation Software Etap 19.0.1, is used to show the impacts and the consequences of the previously explained attack scenarios in the context of a large grid. The IEEE 13 bus test grid is used to model a medium-sized isolated grid with 2.3 MW and 1.536 MVar distributed loads (typical size of a substation/micro-grid representing approx. ∼ 150 houses) to demonstrate the attack consequences <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Fig. 14)</ref>. The test grid has five distributed generators and a lumped solar inverter. The generators and the inverter have ranges of 1000 MW, 500 kW, and 100 kW generation rating. Let us assume that the attacker has chosen the comparatively small 100 kW inverter (Gen 5) to show how attacking a small generation could eventually collapse the entire grid. It is important to note that a single inverter can bring down the entire network if the grid is weak, the inverter size is large compared to other <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 14</ref>: IEEE 13 bus model simulation in Etap to demonstrate the attack impacts in a large system. generators, or the grid does not have the inertia to compensate for the sudden load change. Usually, residential inverters (0.1 kW-10 kW) are too small to bring down the entire network. Rather, in this section, we address the impact of compromising a larger inverter (e.g., 100 kW) in detail.  Feasibility Analysis of using a 100 kW Inverter: Large inverters (e.g., 100 kW) normally exist as the central inverter in solar/industrial plants or shopping malls. To the best of our knowledge <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">[58,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">59,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b57">60]</ref>, the inverters have abc-to-dq transformation blocks, PI controllers, PLLs, MPPT, SVPWM in common, irrespective of their sizes (see Section 5.3). These high power central inverters are normally connected with high voltage DC (&gt; 600V) and AC (∼480V) lines, and overall good efficiency (&gt;98%) is a critical requirement of these inverters. To increase efficiency, they are designed as an iron-core transformerless system. However, this way of design increases the injection of DC voltage/current and circulating current into the grid. These injections of unwanted signals can cause overloading in the distribution transformer. Therefore, tight control is necessary to overcome these shortcomings, and accurate measurement is the key to obtaining this control. Thus, designers commonly use Hall sensors because of their lower measurement error, better linearity, higher efficiency, and better galvanic isolation. Hall sensors are used to find DC current injection and measure ground leakage current and circulating current in the inverter's power stage [58] <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">[61]</ref>. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 15</ref> is a teardown of a 100 kW inverter, which is obtained by contacting the designers of the relevant inverter <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">[58]</ref>. This figure clearly shows the presence of Hall voltage and current sensors inside of it and gives a strong insight of using a 100 kW inverter in our simulation. The PV and grid voltage sensors are LV 25-P, and the leakage current sensors are CT 0.4-P, the circulating current sensors are HO-6P, and the grid current sensors are LA 100-TP. These sensors are present within 4.2 cm from the edge, therefore, these sensors are within the attack range. The enclosures of these inverters are made of steel, aluminum, or non-metallic poly-carbonate. Metallic enclosures often get hot due to sunlight, and it is detrimental for the inverter. Therefore, manufacturers prefer non-metallic poly-carbonate <ref type="bibr">[62]</ref> as an enclosure, which is heat-resistant but more fragile to our attack model. As we can't access a high voltage inverter for safety reasons, our experiments use the miniature inverter having core functionalities similar to an industry-standard inverter. It is clear from <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 1</ref> and the above discussion that highly efficient small, medium, and large grid-tied inverters have Hall sensors. This gives a strong intuition behind the generalization of our attack model. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8.1">Grid Synchronization Attack Evaluation</head><p>Inverters are typically connected with the power grid using protective relays at the point-of-interface (POI). These protective relays have under/over frequency, rate of change of frequency , under/over voltage detection schemes. If the frequency/voltage changes fast or goes beyond the threshold set by the standard (e.g., <ref type="bibr">IEEE 1547</ref><ref type="bibr">, IEEE 2030</ref>, the relays trip out the corresponding inverters/loads from the POI.</p><p>The attacker can perturb output voltage, phase, and frequency of the 100 kW (Gen 5) target inverter by using our attack model (Scenario 1, 2, 3 of Section 7). This can lead to any of the following consequences: the inverter can be damaged, it can be shut down, or connected protective relays can trip it out from the connected grid. Any of these consequences can result in a sudden loss of 100 kW power from the grid.</p><p>Explanation of Cascading Grid Collapse <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">[63]</ref>: The grid power generation should be equal to the sum of power consumption and loss. This balance needs to be maintained for a stable grid health. As the 100 kW inverter stops working without prior notice, anticipation, or preparation, it will shift its 100 kW load to nearby generators. Those nearby generators will be overloaded and will shift their loads onto other generators in a cascading manner in a very short time, eventually causing grid collapse. This effect can be extreme during peak hours when the generators are already running at maximum capacity and may be unable to compensate for this 100 kW sudden mismatch between generation and demand. Moreover, when the 100 kW inverter stops working, the adjacent generator's governor set point is also changed to push kinetic energy into the grid to catch up with this power disparity. When generators adjust their governors, power system frequency falls and blackout is required in the affected part to preserve the power system. Due to the grid weakening, this frequency fluctuation is an important issue, and the attacker can leverage this vulnerability by using our attack model. This is demonstrated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 16</ref> by simulating in Etap 19.0.1. The simulation is run for a 10-second window. The attacker attacks the inverter at t = 2 second. After this point, the grid voltage and frequency start continuously decaying and fall to 97% of the rated values within 8 sec. IEEE 1547 standard <ref type="bibr" target="#b60">[64]</ref> indicates that the grid will shut down as the grid frequency is out of this range: 59.3 Hz &lt; frequency &lt; 60.5 Hz. This may result in a blackout in the region.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Grid voltage level falls to 15% of the rated voltage</head><p>Grid frequency level falls to 68% of the rated frequency</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Attack happens</head><p>Figure 17: Impact of false real and reactive power injection.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8.2">Real and Reactive Power Injection Attack</head><p>Section 7.4 explains that the attacker can force the inverter to inject more or less real/reactive power into the grid by duty-cycle variation. Let us consider a scenario where the grid is balanced (i.e., generation = consumption) and the 100 kW inverter (Gen 5) is running in under-rated condition (i.e., sending less power into the grid than the rated maximum amount). Suddenly, the inverter (Gen 5) is compromised and pushes excess real/reactive power into the grid because of +MMF spoofing. This sudden push of power (i.e., adversarial control) forces the other nearby generators to regulate their own governor set-points to absorb the excess power. As frequency and voltage depend on the set-points of the governors, the sudden swing of the governors can cause temporary grid voltage and frequency dip. This scenario is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 17</ref>. The adversary attacks the inverter at t = 2 second by injecting real/reactive power. This injection causes frequency to fall to 68% and voltage to fall to 15% of the rated value. The attacker can also force the inverter to push less power than the inverter set-point by -MMF spoofing (Section 7). If the attacker keeps injecting more/less power into the grid in a periodic fashion (Scenario 5), the nearby generators will continuously change their governor set-points and this may create oscillations in grid voltage and frequency. This can cause transient instability and may result in a blackout in the region because of the reasons already described in Section 8.1. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8.3">Attacking Utility Connected Micro-Grid</head><p>Section 8.1 and Section 8.2 show the impacts of our attack on an isolated grid. Let us consider a scenario where this isolated grid is connected with the utility grid forming a mediumsized micro-grid. Normally, a utility grid having rotational generators is considered as a strong grid, and any grid (i.e., the micro-grid) connected with this strong grid is also considered as strong. A small amount of power and frequency fluctuation in the micro-grid can be absorbed by the connected strong utility grid. However, a micro-grid becomes weaker as its distance from the utility grid increases. A long transmission line acts as a large impedance between the micro-grid and the utility grid. Voltage/frequency fluctuation in the micro-grid cannot ride through to the utility grid because of this large impedance. As a result, disparities in the micro-grid may not be absorbed by the connected strong utility grid. In large countries like the U.S.A. or China, this far away micro-grid can be easily found (e.g., Borrego Springs, 90 miles east of San-Diego <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">[65]</ref>; 6.8 GW Gansu province wind farm project, 1000 miles from the industrial east coast in China <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">[66]</ref>; Blue Lake Rancheria, 300 miles north of San Francisco <ref type="bibr" target="#b63">[67]</ref>, etc.).</p><p>Etap 19.0.1 simulation in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 18</ref> shows that if the transmission line length between the utility and the micro-grid increases, the micro-grid becomes weaker. Scenario 1, 2, 3, 4 can cause the grid frequency to drop in our IEEE 13 Bus model if the transmission line length is more than 100 km (i.e., micro-grid is 100 km away from the utility grid). If the distance is less, the micro-grid remains strong and a negligible frequency fluctuation can be present after the attack.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="9">Defense and Limitations</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="9.1">Defense</head><p>The defense against this type of unconventional attack should consider the following four practices together:</p><p>Sensing Presence of External Magnetic Field: The first practice is to put a magnetic flux sensor as a guard near the Hall voltage/current sensor device to measure the presence of an external magnetic field. This idea is similar to the presence of a temperature sensor near a MOSFET to shut it down at a higher temperature. Most high power devices use this method to protect a MOSFET from over temperature. Sensing of a high external magnetic field by the guard magnetic sensor can be used to relay the information to the operator about the possible attack situation. It is noteworthy that this guard sensor has a very low chance of getting influenced by the external magnetic field generated by a nearby current-carrying conductor as this magnetic field is very low. For example, a 500 A current-carrying conductor in the power system can generate only 1 mT at 10 cm distance <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">[68]</ref>, and the attacker's external magnetic field is much greater (&gt; 0.8 T) than this. Therefore, the additional magnetic sensor can safely separate the attacker's high spoofing magnetic field from the magnetic field usually present in the power grid.</p><p>Secured Surrounding Environment: The second practice is to prevent any visitor or unauthorized personnel from going near the grid-tied solar inverter. Any unauthorized object found near the inverter should be considered as a security breach. Furthermore, any authorized electronic device, which has magnetic capabilities placed near the inverter, should be carefully examined. However, this countermeasure alone may fail in a few scenarios that involve large countries where solar plants are usually found in an isolated place with less security. <ref type="bibr">Staggs et al. [42]</ref> demonstrated how easily this countermeasure can be defeated and an attacker can access a wind plant in the middle of a remote field.</p><p>Shielding: Shields redirect the magnetic fields from sensitive devices. Presence of multiple lamination layers in the shield can increase the robustness against the strong magnetic field. High saturation magnetic flux density material (HB), non-magnetic material (NM) and amorphous alloy material (AM) can be used as lamination layers of the shield <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">[69]</ref>. Aluminum and poly-carbonates are not good for shielding and should never be used. The thickness of the shields also matters. We have increased the thickness of the shield from 2mm to 4 mm and the impact of the attack is reduced by approx. 40%. The thickness of the shield can also increase the weight making it more inconvenient. Alloys, such as CO-NETIC-AA, NETIC S3-6, and MuMETAL, can be used as shields <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">[70]</ref> but they are costlier. However, we must remember that having only a good shield is not enough, as any shield can be compromised with a stronger magnetic field.</p><p>Robust Sensors: Differential Hall effect sensors can be used because they are robust to external common-mode magnetic interference. The differential Hall effect sensor has two Hall elements, which are closely placed together to cancel out common-mode noises <ref type="bibr">[71]</ref>. Sensor-shielding can be added to the Hall sensor to make it insensitive to a small external magnetic field (&lt; ∼ 30mT) <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">[72]</ref>. Moreover, a field concentrator can be added to a Hall sensor to make it robust to an external magnetic field. However, a field concentrator causes magnetic hysteresis, which introduces an additional source of error in the measurement <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">[72]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="9.2">Limitations</head><p>In this paper, the introduced adversarial control does not offer fine-grained control compared to <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[24,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">25]</ref>. The reason for this is that the direct feedback from the compromised Hall sensor to the attacker is absent. However, the attack is strong enough to perturb the connected power grid. Our adversarial attack offers limited control over the inverter voltage within a limited range (Section 7.4) and exceeding this range can result in a DoS attack as the inverter is very sensitive to output voltage variation. Moreover, close access near the inverter, short-attacking range, finding the weak grid scenario, and the prior knowledge on the timing of the attack (i.e., peak hours) are also the limitations. Furthermore, the attacker can not inject high frequency (&gt;2Hz) pulsating MMF, because the inductive property of the electromagnet filters it out.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="10">Conclusion</head><p>We have proposed and presented a noninvasive attack using the magnetic field on the grid-tied solar inverter. The presence of the Hall sensors in the inverters leaves them vulnerable to be spoofed from the outside. We have illustrated the integrity and availability risks of an inverter by proper mathematical modeling of the basic blocks of the inverter controller. This shows how the false data injection into a Hall sensor can compromise the inverter controller. We have identified five attack scenarios by which the attacker can compromise the inverter and also the connected grid. Moreover, we have introduced a duty-cycle variation approach for adversarial control that can alter the inverter voltage and real power noninvasively. We have tested the attack scenarios in our scaled-down testbed of the power grid and demonstrated our proof of concept. We discuss the feasibility of using a 100 kW inverter and this gives insights behind the generalization of our attack model. We have used industry-standard software Etap 19.0.1 to show the consequences of our attack in a large power grid. This attack can lead to a grid blackout in a weak grid. Our work is an example of a noninvasive attack that originates in the physical domain following some physical laws, compromises the cyber domain, and again finally impacts the physical domain. This can cause financial loss to the power companies. Hence, this attack is novel in power CPSs and it can draw attention to the security community for further research.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="11">Appendix 11.1 Grid Synchronization</head><p>Grid-tied solar inverters need to synchronize itself with the power grid to work in unison. Therefore, The inverter output frequency should be equal to the connected grid frequency (e.g., 60 Hz). Moreover, the inverter voltage should have the same phase angle and slightly higher magnitude than the grid voltage to push power into the grid. There are a few methods for the grid synchronization. The most common synchronization method is Phase-Locked-Loop (PLL). Any wrong synchronization of frequency, voltage, and phase angle may bring the grid down. Moreover, the damage could get worse for large inverters like the central one, because these inverters have a higher influence on the connected power grid.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="11.2">Real Power and Reactive Power</head><p>The concept of real and reactive power is important in a power grid. Real power is the energy required to rotate a motor, illuminate a house, heat a room, etc. The real power generation should be equal to the power demand. If the power generation surpasses the demand, it will increase the grid frequency that may damage the connected loads. If the power generation is less than the demand, this scenario will reduce the grid frequency and may cause blackout. Therefore, the frequency variation is critical for the grid health and this should be within the acceptable limit (e.g., IEEE 1547 standard: 59.3 Hz &lt; f requency &lt; 60.5 Hz) for stable grid operation.</p><p>On the other hand, reactive power is used to regulate grid voltage. It is used to control the voltage level and this is essential for the active power to do real work. If the reactive power generation is less than the demand, the voltage level will drop and if the generation is higher, the voltage level will rise compared to the nominal value. This variation should be within 1% of the nominal voltage for healthy grid operation. Nowadays, the distributed energy resources (DERs) like solar/wind inverters can push real and reactive power into the grid and facility's energy management system control this amount depending upon the actual demand.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="11.3">Generators in a Strong and a Weak Grid</head><p>A strong grid consists of rotational generators because the rotational generators provide inertia that can compensate for any sudden change of loads in the power system. The rotational generator has a governor-control mechanism that controls the prime-mover of the generator during load variation. In a strong grid, the majority of the power comes from the centralized rotational generators. On the other hand, in a weak grid, the majority of the power may not come from the centralized rotational generators, but comes from many distributed energy sources, such as solar/wind turbines, battery energy storage. Due to the continuous integration of distributed energy sources, the modern grid is experiencing poor control and lack of inertia causing grid weakening over time. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 19</ref> is a teardown <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[39]</ref> of Sunny Boy series inverter from SMA Solar Technology. This figure indicates the presence of Hall sensors. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Fig. 20</ref> is a block diagram <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[36]</ref> of a threephase grid-tied inverter from Texas Instruments Inc. This figure also clearly indicates the presence of Hall sensors. Both inverters also require &gt;800 V DC source and that is why they are not safe to test in the lab set-up. Page 6 of <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[37]</ref> also indicates the presence of Hall sensors in the inverter made by STMicroelectronics. Page 15 of <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[38]</ref> indicates the presence of Hall sensors in the inverter made by Microchip. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="11.4">Presence of Hall Sensors in Inverters</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="11.5">񮽙 S abc to 񮽙 S dq Transformation</head><p>The Clarke Matrix (CM) and the Park Matrix (PM) are expressed as follows <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[73]</ref>:</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Working principle of a typical Hall sensor.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Fig. 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig. 2 depicts our proposed attack model, which can affect the availability of an inverter by spoofing Hall sensors. The components of our attack model are described as follows: Attacker's Intent: The attacker wants to disrupt the normal operation of a power system by spoofing an inverter noninvasively and wants to cause grid failures in a weak grid. Attacker's Capabilities: The attacker can surreptitiously place a small box near the target inverter. This box contains a powerful electromagnet integrated with an electronic spoofing controller (i.e., Embedded Hall Spoofing Controller). This box is small enough to be camouflaged within a small container, such as flower vase, coffee cup. Placing the camouflaged attack tool near the inverter requires a brief one-time access. The box has wireless controls allowing for remote communication. Therefore, the attacker can remotely control the timing of the attack and can pick a vulnerable time (e.g., at peak hour, etc.) to impact the connected power grid. The authorities of the target inverter may not be aware of this attack model and would possibly neglect the security implications of any small camouflaged box placed near an inverter. Attacker's Access Level: The access near the inverter needed for the attack can be possible in at least three scenarios. First (most likely), a malicious employee or a guest, who has access near the inverter, may place the camouflaged attack tool near the inverter. An incident similar to this has</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Demonstration of access near a typical inverter. Outcome of this Attack: The attacker may cause grid failures if the power grid is weak. And for weakly protected systems, the attacker can fry the internal circuitry of the inverter itself. By spoofing the Hall sensor, the attacker can give a false impression that the conditions required for synchronization of the inverter with the grid have been achieved when they have not. This improper grid synchronization may shut down the inverter (Section 7.1). A micro-grid is a group of interconnected loads and distributed energy resources, which can operate in both grid-connected or island mode [13]. The attacker can disconnect the micro-grid from the utility grid at a random time or can prevent it from disconnecting even when it is supposed to disconnect (e.g., in the case of an out-</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: The Embedded Hall Spoofing Controller. the strength of the generated magnetic flux. A Metal Oxide Semiconductor Field Effect Transistor (MOSFET), P7N20E is used to toggle the electromagnet ON and OFF with variable frequencies using a Pulse Width Modulation (PWM) technique. This PWM helps to generate variable-frequency electromagnetic flux and controls the power input to the electromagnet depending upon the attacker's need and intention. To protect the MOSFET from an inductive surge (due to the switching of the large electromagnet), a free-wheeling diode (U1620G) is connected across the electromagnet.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Camouflaged attack tool placed 8cm away from the inverter Grid-tied solar inverter with a steel shield Solar panel emulator Power inverter for grid emulation Small-scaled grid loadFigure 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Figure 6: A scaled-down testbed of a power grid.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Figure 7: Typical locations of Hall sensors inside an inverter.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 8 :</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Figure 8: Aligning and opposing spoofing into Hall sensors. Scenario 1: Let us assume the attacker spoofs only the grid voltage ( 񮽙 S abc ) sensors with a constant ±MMF (aligning and opposing polarity). Therefore, the attacker considers injecting magnetic field ±∆B into the Hall grid voltage sensors. The term +∆B means that the applied +MMF aligns vertically in the same direction of the Hall sensor measurement axis, and −∆B means that the applied -MMF aligns vertically in the opposite direction of the Hall sensor measurement axis (Fig. 8). An injection of ±∆B results in a false Hall voltage V</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 10 :</head><label>10</label><figDesc>Figure 10: Spoofing grid-tied inverter output frequency. Scenario 3: Let us assume the attacker spoofs only the grid voltage ( 񮽙 S abc ) sensors with a sinusoidal MMF (note that the last two scenarios are for constant MMF). An injection of a sinusoidal MMF results in a false Hall voltage V f Hall (t), which causes an injection of ∆E a (t), ∆E b (t), ∆E c (t) measurement errors into 񮽙 S abc . Therefore, Eqn. 2 is changed as follows: 񮽙 S f alse</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Injected Low frequency (1Hz) harmonics power is 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 11: The frequency spectrum of the inverter output voltage before and after the attack Scenario 3.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Fig. 12 40.17% change in the output voltage after +MMF spoofing on grid sensor 26 .3% THD after +MMF spoofing on grid sensor 240% Increase of Power than the reference setpoint after +MMF spoofing on solar panel sensor Inverter Stopped after -MMF spoofing on solar panel sensor Inverter Stopped after +MMF spoofing on grid sensor Figure 12 :</head><label>1226sensor12</label><figDesc>Fig. 12 shows the impact of the attack scenarios for different spoofing-distances for 0.8 Tesla magnetic field. Here, spoofing-distance means the distance between the electromagnet and the sensor. Note that attack scenarios 1, 2, 3 are created by spoofing the grid voltage/current sensors, and scenario 4</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Figure 13 :</head><label>13</label><figDesc>Figure 13: Attack effects with different spoofing-power.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head>Figure 15 :</head><label>15</label><figDesc>Figure 15: Feasibility analysis of using a 100 kW inverter. Feasibility Analysis of using a 100 kW Inverter: Large inverters (e.g., 100 kW) normally exist as the central inverter in solar/industrial plants or shopping malls. To the best of our knowledge [58, 59, 60], the inverters have abc-to-dq transformation blocks, PI controllers, PLLs, MPPT, SVPWM in common, irrespective of their sizes (see Section 5.3). These high power central inverters are normally connected with high voltage DC (&gt; 600V) and AC (∼480V) lines, and overall good efficiency (&gt;98%) is a critical requirement of these inverters. To increase efficiency, they are designed as an iron-core transformerless system. However, this way of design increases the injection of DC voltage/current and circulating current into the grid. These injections of unwanted signals can cause overloading in the distribution transformer. Therefore, tight control is necessary to overcome these shortcomings, and accurate measurement is the key to obtaining this control. Thus, designers commonly use Hall sensors because of their lower measurement error, better linearity, higher efficiency, and better galvanic isolation. Hall sensors are used to find DC current injection and measure ground leakage current and circulating current in the inverter's power stage [58] [61]. Fig. 15 is a teardown of a 100 kW inverter, which is obtained by contacting the designers of the relevant inverter [58]. This figure clearly shows the presence of Hall voltage and current sensors inside of it and gives a strong insight of using a 100 kW inverter in our simulation. The PV and grid voltage sensors are LV 25-P, and the leakage current sensors are CT 0.4-P, the circulating</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head>Figure 16 :</head><label>16</label><figDesc>Figure 16: Grid voltage and frequency instability in IEEE 13 bus model after the grid synchronization attack.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_14"><head>Transmission line length is 50 km Transmission line length is 80 km Transmission line length is 100 Figure 18 :</head><label>10018</label><figDesc>Figure 18: Frequency instability in a weak micro-grid.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_15"><head>Figure 19 :</head><label>19</label><figDesc>Figure 19: SMA Solar Technology Sunny Boy inverter [39].</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>If d, I bias , and k are constant, V Hall depends only on applied B. This B is proportional</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table>to the cur-
rent/voltage to be measured. Any external perturbation of 
B can change V Hall . And this change can give a false sense 
of voltage/current measurement that can propagate to the 
inverter controller and hamper its normal operation. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="true"><head>Table 1 : Presence of Hall sensors in different inverters.</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Manufacturer 
Inverter Series 
Sensor Power 
Texas Instr. [35] TMDSOLARUINVKIT 
Hall 
0.14 kW 
Texas Instr.[36] 
TIDA-01606 
Hall 
10 kW 
STMicro. [37] 
STEVAL-ISV003V1 
Hall 
0.25 kW 
Microchip [38] 
Grid Connected Inverter 
Hall 
0.215 kW 
SMA[39] 
Sunny Boy 
Hall 
5 kW 
SOLAX [40] 
SL-TL5000T 
Hall 
3 kW 

4 Attack Model 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Algorithm 1 : Solar Inverter Controller Compromising Algorithm. Input: Control variables: {Attack_level, Adversarial_control, Duty_cycle} Output: Pulse Width Modulation Frequency: PW M f req 1 n ←: Timesteps 2 ADC_arduino, PW M_arduino, RX_T X_arduino ← Initialize 3 Zigbee_module,Ultrasound_module ← Initialize 4 for i ← 1 to n do 5 batteryVoltage ← ADC_Channel_1 6 if batteryVoltage &lt; VoltageT hreshold then9 else 10 Inform_attacker (battery_voltage_sufficient) 11 ultrasound_setup ← Activate 12 Distance ← Ultrasound_Measurements 13 if Distance &gt; Distance_threshold then 14 Inform_attacker (distance_threshold_exceed) 15 return ErrorCode_DistanceT hresholdExceed 16 PowerController ← (Duty_cycle = 100%) 17 if Attack_Level = Constant_MMF then 18 Mos f etGate ← PulledU p 19 else if Attack_Level = Pulsating_MMF_1Hz then 20 Mos f etGate ← PulledU p 21 PW M f req ← 1 22 else if Attack_Level = Pulsating_MMF_2Hz then 23 Mos f etGate ← PulledU p 24 PW M f req ← 2 25 else 26 Mos f etGate ← PulledDown 27 if Adversarial_control = Enable then 28 PowerController ← (Duty_cycle, Distance) 29 Inform_attacker (adversarial_control_enabled) 30 else 31 PowerController ← (Duty_cycle = 100%) 32 Inform_attacker (adversarial_control_disabled) 33 MagnetCurrent ← ADC_Channel_2 34 if MagnetCurrent &lt; CurrentT hreshold then 35 Inform_attacker (battery_Charge_low) 36 return ErrorCode_BatteryChargeLow grid voltage space vector 񮽙 S abc as follows:</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>7 

Inform_attacker (battery_voltage_low) 

8 

return ErrorCode_BatteryVoltageLow 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>axis, and the quadrature (q) axis lags d axis by 90 o . The abc-to-dq transformation is done in two steps: a Clarke Matrix (CM) transforms 񮽙 S abc into alpha-beta component vector 񮽙 S αβ (eα and e β ), and a Park Matrix (PM) transforms 񮽙 S αβ into dq component vector 񮽙 S dq (e d and e q ). The term 񮽙 S dq can be given by (Appendix 11.5):and e q are the d and q axis components of the abc, u b , u c ] and output currents [i a , i b , i c ] as vectors 񮽙 U abc and 񮽙 I abc , respectively. The inverter output current 񮽙 I abc is similarly sensed and sampled by three Hall effect current sensors (we name these as grid sensors) and the DSP unit, respectively. 񮽙 U abc and 񮽙 I abc vectors are also sinusoidal quantities, and they are converted into their dq axis components using a Clarke and a Park matrix. Let us denote 񮽙 U dq and 񮽙 I dq as the dq transformations of 񮽙 U abc and 񮽙 I abc , respectively. The term 񮽙 U dq comprises u d and u q where u d and u q are the d and q axis components of 񮽙 U abc . The term 񮽙 I dq similarly comprises i d and i q where i d and i q are the d and q axis components of 񮽙 I abc .</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table>USENIX Association 
29th USENIX Security Symposium 1277 

񮽙 S dq = 

e d 
e q 

= 
񮽙 

3 

2 E 
0 

(3) 

where e d -
phase grid voltages, respectively and they are DC quantities. 
Please note that e q = 0 for balanced grid voltage. 
Let us denote the three-phase inverter output voltages 
[u a </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>-Integral (PI) Current Controllers: Two sep- arate PI current controllers force the dq axis components i d and i q to track the reference set points i * d and i * q . This tracking generates fractional DC voltages u p d and u p q as follows:</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" validated="false"><head>Vector Pulse Width Modulation (SVPWM) Block: The SVPWM block, which generates appropriate pulse width PWM Invertersignals, controls the MOSFET switches and gener- ates appropriate 3-phase inverter output voltages u a , u b , and u c . The SVPWM block uses two reference signals u * d and u * q ,</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Solar 
Panel 

MPPT 
Block 

V 

A 

I T 

V T V 

A 

I T 

V T 

+ -
+ -

PI 
Controller 

i d 

+ -
+ -

PI 
Controller 

i q 
i q 

* 

Hall 
Voltage 
Sensors 

+ -
+ -

e d 

+ 

u d 

p 

ꙍLiq 

+ + 
+ + 

u q 

p 

ꙍLiq 

u q 

* 

u d 

* 

V T 

I T 

i d 

* 

AC 

a 

Grid 

i a i b i c 

A 
A 
A 

abc 
to 
αβ 

αβ 

to 
dq 

i d 

i q 

i α 

iβ 

abc 
to 
αβ 

αβ 

to 
dq 

e d 

e q 

e α 

e β 
i a 
i b 
i c 

e a 
e b 
e c 

e a 
e b 
e c 

+ -
e q 

* 

PI 
Controller 

ϴ 

ϴ 

u a 

u b 
u c 

Hall Current 
Sensors 

PV Hall Sensors 

L 
L 
L 

PLL 

abc-to-dq 
transformation 
block 

0 

Figure 5: Typical controllers inside of a 3-phase inverter. 
modulated which are generated by putting Eqn. 6, 7 into Eqn. 4, 5: 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7" validated="false"><head>and e q change with time (i.e., e q 񮽙 = 0). This influences the Right-Hand Side (R.H.S) of Eqn. 8 and 9. As a result, reference voltages u * d and u * q are perturbed.abc than the grid voltage 񮽙 S abc can cause high transient current to be pushed into the grid. If 񮽙 U f alse abc is smaller than 񮽙 S abc , the񮽙 I abc ) sensors with a constant ±MMF. An injection of ±MMF results in a false Hall voltage V f Hall , which causes an injection of ±∆I a , ±∆I b , ±∆I c measurement errors into 񮽙 I abc . This causes a false output current 񮽙 I f alse abc . The low-pass filter of</head><label></label><figDesc>inverter acts as a load and current flows into the inverter from the grid. Both cases can shut down the inverter or may damage the inverter by frying the electronics. Scenario 2: Let us assume the attacker spoofs only the grid current (</figDesc><table>PM × 

∆eα 
∆e β 

is a time-varying quantity. Terms ∆eα 

and ∆e β are the errors propagating from the Clarke matrix 

transformation block. Therefore, 񮽙 S 

f alse 
dq 

is no longer stable, 
and as a result, e d This will 
force SVPWM to create a false inverter output voltage vector 
񮽙 
U 

f alse 

abc . It is possible to generate a larger or smaller 񮽙 
U 

f alse 

abc than 
allowed. A larger 񮽙 
U 

f alse 

∆ V= + 39.4 V 

for spoofing 
with +mmf 

∆ V= -39.4 V 

for spoofing 
with -mmf 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8" validated="false"><head>result, reference voltages u * d and u * q are</head><label></label><figDesc>perturbed. This will force SVPWM to create false inverter output voltage vector 񮽙 U f alse abc . Similar to the consequences in Scenario 1, this may shut down the inverter.</figDesc><table>alse 

q 

) 
(16) 

Generated false voltages u 

f 

d and u 

f 

q influence the R.H.S of 
Eqn. 8 and 9. As a </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9" validated="false"><head>) where E f 1a , E f 2a , E f 3a and θ f a , θ f b , θ f c are false amplitudes and phase angles, respectively. Thus 񮽙 S f alse abc</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> In this paper, grid-tied solar inverter are used interchangeably with inverter.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors would like to thank the anonymous reviewers, our shepherd Prof. Xiali Hei and colleagues Nathan, Kelvin, Anthony, Arnav and Luke for their valuable comments that greatly helped to improve this paper. This paper is based upon work partially supported by the University of California, Office of the President under Grant No. LFR-18-548175 and the Broadcom Fellowship.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="11.7">Attack Scenario 3</head><p>After injecting ∆E a (t), ∆E b (t), ∆E c (t) measurement errors into 񮽙 S abc , Eqn. 2 changes as follows:</p><p>񮽙 </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="11.8">Attack Scenario 5</head><p>Let us assume the attacker uses pulsating square (⊓) MMF (as square wave generation is easier than the sine wave generation) for spoofing 񮽙 I abc sensors. It creates pulsating perturbation ∆I ⊓ (t) with frequency ω ⊓ . This may be expressed as:  </p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Challenges for securing cyber physical systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alvaro</forename><surname>Cardenas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Saurabh</forename><surname>Amin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bruno</forename><surname>Sinopoli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Annarita</forename><surname>Giani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adrian</forename><surname>Perrig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shankar</forename><surname>Sastry</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Workshop on future directions in cyber-physical systems security</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Citeseer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information availability: An insight into the most important attribute of information security</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Suhail</forename><surname>Qadir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Smk</forename><surname>Quadri</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Information Security</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">03</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">185</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A survey on the security of cyberphysical systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guangyu</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Control Theory and Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2" to="10" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cyber security in the energy world</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ang</forename><surname>Chee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kiong</forename><surname>Gary</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Utomo Nugroho</forename><surname>Prananto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2017 Asian Conference on Energy, Power and Transportation Electrification (ACEPT)</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="5" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Experts assess damage after first cyberattack on U.S. grid</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Blake</forename><surname>Sobczak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.eenews.net/stories/1060281821" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019-05-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="14" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Slammer worm crashed Ohio nuke plant net. The Register</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Poulsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">W32. stuxnet dossier. White paper, Symantec Corp</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nicolas</forename><surname>Falliere</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liam</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Murchu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Chien</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Security Response</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">29</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Inside the cunning, unprecedented hack of ukraine&apos;s power grid. Wired</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kim</forename><surname>Zetter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The value of supply security: The costs of power outages to Austrian households, firms and the public sector</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Johannes</forename><surname>Reichl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Schmidthaler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Friedrich</forename><surname>Schneider</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Energy Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="256" to="261" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">US solar photovoltaic manufacturing: Industry trends, global competition, federal support. Library of Congress</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Michaela</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Platzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Congressional Research Service</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">European Union wind and solar electricity policies: overview and considerations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Phillip</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Control of a grid connected converter during weak grid conditions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><forename type="middle">Buus</forename><surname>Søren Lund Lorenzen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lorand</forename><surname>Nielsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Bede</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2016 IEEE 7th International Symposium on Power Electronics for Distributed Generation Systems (PEDG)</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="6" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Microgrid: A conceptual solution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Robert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paolo</forename><surname>Lasseter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Piagi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IEEE Power Electronics Specialists Conference</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Citeseer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4285" to="4291" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Taxonomy for description of cross-domain attacks on CPS</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Yampolskiy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Horvath</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Xenofon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuan</forename><surname>Koutsoukos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Janos</forename><surname>Xue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Sztipanovits</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2nd ACM international conference on High confidence networked systems</title>
		<meeting>the 2nd ACM international conference on High confidence networked systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="135" to="142" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ghost talk: Mitigating EMI signal injection attacks against analog sensors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Denis Foo Kune</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Backes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Shane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Kramer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Reynolds</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yongdae</forename><surname>Fu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wenyuan</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2013 IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="145" to="159" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">This ain&apos;t your dose: Sensor spoofing attack on medical infusion pump</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Youngseok</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yunmok</forename><surname>Son</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hocheol</forename><surname>Shin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dohyun</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yongdae</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">10th {USENIX} Workshop on Offensive Technologies ({WOOT} 16)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Controlling UAVs with sensor input spoofing attacks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Drew</forename><surname>Davidson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hao</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rob</forename><surname>Jellinek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vikas</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Ristenpart</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">10th {USENIX} Workshop on Offensive Technologies ({WOOT} 16)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Can you trust autonomous vehicles: Contactless attacks against sensors of self-driving vehicle</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chen</forename><surname>Yan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wenyuan</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jianhao</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">DEF CON</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">109</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Illusion and dazzle: Adversarial optical channel exploits against lidars for automotive applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hocheol</forename><surname>Shin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dohyun</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yujin</forename><surname>Kwon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yongdae</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Conference on Cryptographic Hardware and Embedded Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="445" to="467" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dolphinattack: Inaudible voice commands</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guoming</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chen</forename><surname>Yan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaoyu</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tianchen</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Taimin</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wenyuan</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2017 ACM SIGSAC Conference on Computer and Communications Security</title>
		<meeting>the 2017 ACM SIGSAC Conference on Computer and Communications Security</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="103" to="117" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Non-invasive spoofing attacks for anti-lock braking systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yasser</forename><surname>Shoukry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paulo</forename><surname>Tabuada</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mani</forename><surname>Srivastava</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Workshop on Cryptographic Hardware and Embedded Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="55" to="72" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rocking drones with intentional sound noise on gyroscopic sensors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yunmok</forename><surname>Son</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dongkwan</forename><surname>Shin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Youngseok</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Juhwan</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kibum</forename><surname>Noh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jungwoo</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yongdae</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">24th {USENIX} Security Symposium ({USENIX} Security 15)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="881" to="896" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Sonic gun to smart devices: Your devices lose control under ultrasound/sound</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhengbo</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<pubPlace>BlackHat USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">WALNUT: Waging doubt on the integrity of MEMS accelerometers with acoustic injection attacks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Timothy</forename><surname>Trippel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ofir</forename><surname>Weisse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wenyuan</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Honeyman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Fu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2017 IEEE European Symposium on Security and Privacy (EuroS&amp;P)</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="18" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Injected and delivered: Fabricating implicit control over actuation systems by spoofing inertial sensors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yazhou</forename><surname>Tu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhiqiang</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Insup</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiali</forename><surname>Hei</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">27th {USENIX} Security Symposium ({USENIX} Security 18)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1545" to="1562" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Malicious data attacks on the smart grid</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oliver</forename><surname>Kosut</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liyan</forename><surname>Jia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Robert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lang</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Tong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Smart Grid</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="645" to="658" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Communication security for smart grid distribution networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elias</forename><surname>Bou-Harb</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claude</forename><surname>Fachkha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Makan</forename><surname>Pourzandi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mourad</forename><surname>Debbabi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chadi</forename><surname>Assi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Communications Magazine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="42" to="49" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cyber-physical security of a smart grid infrastructure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yilin</forename><surname>Mo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tiffany Hyun-Jin</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kenneth</forename><surname>Brancik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dona</forename><surname>Dickinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heejo</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adrian</forename><surname>Perrig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bruno</forename><surname>Sinopoli</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the IEEE</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">100</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="195" to="209" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Preventing time-delay switch attack on load frequency control in distributed power systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Arman</forename><surname>Sargolzaei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mohamed</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Kang K Yen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Abdelghani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Smart Grid</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1176" to="1185" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distributed internet-based load altering attacks against smart power grids</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alberto</forename><surname>Amir-Hamed Mohsenian-Rad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Leon-Garcia</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Smart Grid</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="667" to="674" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modelbased evaluation of GPS spoofing attacks on power grid sensors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ilge</forename><surname>Akkaya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patricia</forename><surname>Edward A Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Derler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Workshop on Modeling and Simulation of Cyber-Physical Energy Systems (MSCPES)</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="6" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effect of variable speed wind turbine generator on stability of a weak grid</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eduard</forename><surname>Muljadi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brian</forename><surname>Butterfield</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Abraham</forename><surname>Parsons</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ellis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Energy Conversion</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="29" to="36" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Electric machinery and power system fundamentals</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Stephen J Chapman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Current measurement methods for the smart grid</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Harold</forename><surname>Kirkham</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Power &amp; Energy Society General Meeting</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="7" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Solar Micro Inverter with MPPT Schematic (Rev. A)</title>
		<ptr target="http://www.ti.com/lit/df/tidr767a/tidr767a.pdf.(Accessed" />
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
				<ptr target="http://www.ti.com/lit/pdf/tidue53.(Accessed" />
		<title level="m">10kW 3-Level 3-Phase Grid Tie Inverter Reference Design for Solar String Inverts</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
				<ptr target="https://www.st.com//files/DM00050692.pdf/jcr:content/translations/en.DM00050692.pdf." />
		<title level="m">AN4070: 250 W grid connected microinverter</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Accessed</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">AN1444: Grid-Connected Solar Microinverter Reference Design</title>
		<ptr target="http://ww1.microchip.com/downloads/en/appnotes/01444a.pdf.(Accessed" />
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Teardown: The power inverterfrom sunlight to power grid</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steve</forename><surname>Taranovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.edn.com/teardown-the-power-inverter-from-sunlight-to-power-grid/.(Accessed" />
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Can hackers turn your lights off: The vulnerability of the US power grid to electronic attack. SANS Institute InfoSec Reading Room</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>Stidham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Breaking wind: Adventures in hacking wind farm control networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Staggs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<pubPlace>Black Hat</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inside TAO : documents reveal top NSA hacking unit</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Appelbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Poitras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rosenbach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Stöcker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Schindler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Stark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>0038-7452</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Der Spiegel</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Leaky apps and data shots: Technologies of leakage and insertion in NSAsurveillance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lonneke</forename><surname>Van Der Velden</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Surveillance &amp; Society</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="182" to="196" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Snowden: The NSA planted backdoors in cisco products</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bill</forename><surname>Snyder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page">15</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tool of spies: Leaking your ip by altering the 3d printer compiler</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Sujit Rokka Chhetri</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IEEE Transactions on Dependable and Secure Computing</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interdiction in practice-Hardware Trojan against a high-security USB flash drive</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pawel</forename><surname>Swierczynski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marc</forename><surname>Fyrbiak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Koppe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amir</forename><surname>Moradi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christof</forename><surname>Paar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Cryptographic Engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="199" to="211" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Recycling potential of neodymium: the case of computer hard disk drives. Environmental science &amp; technology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benjamin</forename><surname>Sprecher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rene</forename><surname>Kleijn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gert</forename><forename type="middle">Jan</forename><surname>Kramer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9506" to="9513" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Control in power electronics: selected problems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J David</forename><surname>Irwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<publisher>Elsevier</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cybersecurity for distributed energy resources and smart inverters</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Junjian</forename><surname>Qi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IET Cyber-Physical Systems: Theory &amp; Applications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="28" to="39" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Operation of a phase locked loop system under distorted utility conditions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vikram</forename><surname>Kaura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vladimir</forename><surname>Blasko</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Industry applications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="58" to="63" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chopping of a weak magnetic field by a saturable magnetic shield</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Laurent</forename><surname>Chiesi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Karim</forename><surname>Haroud</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>John A Flanagan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Popovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sensors and Actuators A: Physical</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1-3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="9" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Theory and Calculation of Electric Circuits. The McGraw-Hill Companies, 1.00 edition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Charles</forename><surname>Steinmetz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://books.google.com/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">books?id = z0IOAAAAYAAJ&amp;pg = PA84#v = onepage&amp;q&amp;f = false</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1917" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Inductors</forename><surname>And Transformers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.ece.k-state.edu/people/faculty/gjohnson/files/tcchap4.pdf" />
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Loudspeaker Power Handling Vs</title>
		<ptr target="https://sound-au.com/articles/pwr-vs-eff.htm.(Ac-cessed" />
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Comparative study of maximum power point tracking algorithms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Hohm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>E_ Ropp</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Progress in photovoltaics: Research and Applications</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="47" to="62" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Design and implementation of a 100 kW SiC filter-less PV inverter with 5 kW/kg power density and 99.2% CEC efficiency</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yanjun</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lu</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ren</forename><surname>Xie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hui</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Applied Power Electronics Conference and Exposition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="393" to="398" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overview of control and grid synchronization for distributed power generation systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Frede</forename><surname>Blaabjerg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Remus</forename><surname>Teodorescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marco</forename><surname>Liserre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adrian</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Timbus</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on industrial electronics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1398" to="1409" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Control of single-stage single-phase PV inverter</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mihai</forename><surname>Ciobotaru</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Remus</forename><surname>Teodorescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Frede</forename><surname>Blaabjerg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">EPE Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20" to="26" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A 60-kW 3-kW/kg five-level T-type SiC PV inverter with 99.2% peak efficiency</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yanjun</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lu</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ren</forename><surname>Xie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuxiang</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hui</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Industrial Electronics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9144" to="9154" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using protective relays for microgrid controls</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Edwards</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Scott</forename><surname>Manson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2018 71st Annual Conference for Protective Relay Engineers (CPRE)</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="7" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distributed Generation Photovoltaics and Energy Storage. IEEE standard for interconnection and interoperability of distributed energy resources with associated electric power systems interfaces</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Std</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1547" to="2018" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Blackouts Are a Low-Tech Way to Prevent Fires</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Glanz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brad</forename><surname>Plumer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/10/12/business/power-blackouts-california-microgrids.html" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">a High-Tech State</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overview of current microgrid policies, incentives and barriers in the European Union, United States and China</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amjad</forename><surname>Ali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wuhua</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rashid</forename><surname>Hussain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiangning</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Barry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Abdul</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Hameed Memon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sustainability</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1146</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Blue Lake Rancheria microgrid</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Schatz Energy Research</forename><surname>Center</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://schatzcenter.org/blrmicrogrid/.(Accessed" />
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Magnetic</forename><surname>Field</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Current</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://hyperphysics.phy-astr.gsu.edu/hbase/magnetic/magcur.html" />
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Magnetic shielding material</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Takashi</forename><surname>Sato</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Toshio</forename><surname>Yamada</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masami</forename><surname>Kobayashi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">US Patent</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">637</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1991-09-03" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Protective container for readable cards</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Warren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Osborn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Bryan P Dunford</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">US Patent</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">152</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2007-01-16" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<monogr>
				<ptr target="https://www.allegromicro.com/en/" />
		<title level="m">Insightsand -Innovations / Technical -Documents / HallEffect -Sensor -IC -Publications / ManagingExternal -Magnetic -Field -InterferenceACS71x -Current -Sensor -ICs.aspx. (Accessed</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Managing External Magnetic Field Interference When Using ACS71x Current Sensor ICs</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Grid-connected inverter for wind power generation system</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yong</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yi</forename><surname>Ruan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Huan-Qing</forename><surname>Shen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yan-Yan</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ying</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Shanghai University (English Edition)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="51" to="56" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
