<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/atharsefid/Desktop/grobid-0.5.3/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.3" ident="GROBID" when="2020-09-29T04:09+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Zero-delay Lightweight Defenses against Website Fingerprinting Zero-delay Lightweight Defenses against Website Fingerprinting</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>August 12-14, 2020</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiajun</forename><surname>Gong</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science and Engineering Hong</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Kong University of Science and Technology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tao</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
							<email>taow@cse.ust.hk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science and Engineering Hong</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Kong University of Science and Technology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hong</forename><surname>Kong</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science and Engineering Hong</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Kong University of Science and Technology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiajun</forename><surname>Gong</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science and Engineering Hong</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Kong University of Science and Technology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tao</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science and Engineering Hong</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Kong University of Science and Technology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Zero-delay Lightweight Defenses against Website Fingerprinting Zero-delay Lightweight Defenses against Website Fingerprinting</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 29th USENIX Security Symposium</title>
						<meeting>the 29th USENIX Security Symposium						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published">August 12-14, 2020</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>This paper is included in the Open access to the Proceedings of the 29th USENIX Security Symposium is sponsored by USENIX.</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Website Fingerprinting (WF) attacks threaten user privacy on anonymity networks because they can be used by network surveillants to identify the webpage being visited by extracting features from network traffic. A number of defenses have been put forward to mitigate the threat of WF, but they are flawed: some have been defeated by stronger WF attacks, some are too expensive in overhead, while others are impractical to deploy. In this work, we propose two novel zero-delay lightweight defenses, FRONT and GLUE. We find that WF attacks rely on the feature-rich trace front, so FRONT focuses on obfus-cating the trace front with dummy packets. It also random-izes the number and distribution of dummy packets for trace-to-trace randomness to impede the attacker&apos;s learning process. GLUE adds dummy packets between separate traces so that they appear to the attacker as a long consecutive trace, rendering the attacker unable to find their start or end points, let alone classify them. Our experiments show that with 33% data overhead, FRONT outperforms the best known lightweight defense, WTF-PAD, which has a similar data overhead. With around 22%-44% data overhead, GLUE can lower the accuracy and precision of the best WF attacks to a degree comparable with the best heavyweight defenses. Both defenses have no latency overhead.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>As people increasingly use the Internet for work and entertainment, network surveillance has correspondingly grown to become a pervasive threat against people's privacy. Tor, an anonymity network based on onion routing <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[21]</ref>, has become one of the most popular privacy enhancing technologies by defending web-browsing users from network eavesdroppers. To do so, it forwards user packets across multiple volunteer proxies, so that network surveillants cannot see both the true source and destination of the packets.</p><p>In the last decade, multiple studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">17,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">18,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">20,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">25,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">26,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">29,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">30]</ref> have shown that Tor is vulnerable to Website Fingerprinting (WF), a kind of traffic analysis attack where a local attacker passively eavesdrops on network traffic to find out which webpage a client is visiting. WF attackers succeed by observing packet patterns such as the number of outgoing and incoming packets, packet rates, packet timing, and the ordering of packets. (WF attacks do not need to break encryption.) What makes WF attacks especially threatening is that the local passive eavesdropper (which could be the client's ISP) is virtually impossible to detect.</p><p>To counter WF attacks, a number of defenses <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">6,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">17,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">19,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">27,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">28]</ref> have been proposed over the years, but none have been adopted by Tor or any other privacy enhancing technology. This is because their data overhead may be too high; they may delay packets too much, hurting user experience; they may be too hard to implement realistically, relying on extra infrastructure that cannot be provided; or they may simply be ineffective against the best attacks. A defense against the WF problem grows increasingly urgent as more powerful attacks are found.</p><p>Our work makes the following contributions:</p><p>1. Emphasizing costlessness, practicality and usability, we design two new defenses that can defeat the best WF attacks: FRONT and GLUE. We call them zero-delay lightweight defenses, meaning they do not delay the client's packets and they only add a small number of dummy packets to real traffic.</p><p>• FRONT obfuscates the feature-rich front portion of traces, which is crucial to the attacker's success. It does so using randomized amounts of dummy packets, disrupting the attacker's training process.</p><p>• GLUE adds dummy packets between traces to make it seem as if the client is visiting pages consecutively without pause. This forces the attacker to solve difficult splitting problems, which previous work finds that even the best attacks fail to do <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref>.</p><p>outperform WTF-PAD (the previous best zero-delay defense) with the same data overhead (33%) in terms of attackers' performance as well as information leakage analysis, while GLUE can reduce the TPR and precision of the best WF attacks down to single digits with 22%-44% data overhead (overhead depending on user behavior).</p><p>3. As GLUE relies on the difficulty of the splitting problem, we improve known solutions to splitting with a new framework, CDSB, to evaluate GLUE fairly. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first work that presents the performance of WF attacks when more than two webpages are visited consecutively.</p><p>We organize the rest of the paper as follows. We first discuss the related work in Section 2, and then we give some preliminaries in Section 3. We present FRONT and its evaluation in Sections 4 and 5 respectively, and we present GLUE and its evaluation in Sections 6 and 7 respectively. Finally we summarize our work in Section 8.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>Website Fingerprinting Attacks. WF attacks date back to 2002, when Hintz showed preliminary success in fingerprinting webpages by the number of bytes received in each connection <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref>. Later, more studies successfully applied attacks against single-hop systems (Stunnel, OpenSSH, CiscoVPN and OpenVPN) in the closed-world scenario <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">13]</ref>. (We will define the closed-world scenario and the more realistic open-world scenario in Section 3.) These attacks failed to defeat Tor because of Tor's cell-level padding <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>. In 2011, Panchenko et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17]</ref> showed success against Tor (73% accuracy) with the use of a support vector machine (SVM) using expert features; it was effective in a preliminary open-world scenario as well. Further works <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">18,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">20,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">25]</ref> have been proposed since then that pushed accuracy higher and false positive rate lower.</p><p>We pick four of the best, most recent attacks to evaluate, all of which are highly effective in the open-world scenario:</p><p>• kNN <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[24]</ref>: Proposed by <ref type="bibr">Wang et al. in 2014, this attack</ref> uses a k-nearest neighbors classifier based on automatically learning weights of different features. It is designed to break WF defenses, as it adjusts to defensive feature scrambling by lowering the weights of bad features.</p><p>• CUMUL <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref>: Panchenko et al. proposed this SVM classifier that exploits the "cumulative representation" of a trace in 2016. It is more accurate than kNN, and has an excellent computation time.</p><p>• kFP <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>: In 2016, Hayes and Danezis proposed this attack that jointly uses random forests and k-nearest neighbors.</p><p>It has high precision in the open-world scenario.</p><p>• DF <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref>: DF is a recent attack using a deep Convolutional Neural Network. It outperforms other deep learning attacks <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">18]</ref>, achieving high precision and recall. It is the first attack shown to be effective against WTF-PAD, a lightweight WF defense <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref>.</p><p>Website Fingerprinting Defenses. To defend against local, passive WF attackers, WF defenses can be deployed on an anonymity network to modify how the client talks to the network's proxies. This is generally done by adding dummy packets or delaying real packets according to some strategy; the attacker cannot distinguish between dummy packets and real packets. No modification to the web server is required. Over the years, researchers have put forward a number of defenses to protect privacy-sensitive clients against WF attacks.</p><p>We classify the strategies they use to defeat WF attacks into three categories, roughly in order of overhead: obfuscation, confusion, and regularization.</p><p>Obfuscation defenses seek to obfuscate specific features WF attacks rely on. A number of early defenses obfuscate packet lengths to defeat older WF attacks. These include Traffic Morphing by Wright et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[28]</ref>, which pads and splits packets, and HTTPOS <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref>, which does the same on specific HTTP requests and responses. These two defenses are ineffective on Tor, where packet lengths already leak no information because of constant-size cell-level padding. In 2016, Juarez et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref> introduced WTF-PAD, which uses a sophisticated token system to generate dummy packets and fill up abnormal trace gaps.</p><p>Some defenses aim to achieve confusion: they make it difficult for an attacker to determine which of a certain set of given traces is loaded. Panchenko et al. suggested simply loading a Decoy page for every true page load <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17]</ref>, so the attacker does not know which is the real page. <ref type="bibr">Wang et al.</ref> proposed confusing the attacker by sending two or more traces under a Supersequence <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[24]</ref> that is created by adding dummy packets at the right places and delaying user packets.</p><p>Much work has been done on regularization defenses recently, which restrict how clients can send and receive packets in order to strictly limit the feature space available to the attacker. Some of these defenses enforce a fixed packet rate, with regular sequence end times, on the client: these include BuFLO (Buffered Fixed-Length Obfuscation) by Dyer et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref>, CS-BuFLO (Congestion-Sensitive BuFLO) by Cai et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>, and the overhead-optimized Tamaraw by Cai et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. Fixing the packet rate delays user traffic significantly. In 2017, Wang and Goldberg <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[27]</ref> introduced WalkieTalkie, which forces the browser to communicate in halfduplex mode to limit features. It achieves regularization at a lower overhead if we can assume that the client has some knowledge of webpage sizes.</p><p>Surveying the extensive work done on confusion and regularization defenses, we find that almost all of them have either a high data overhead (requiring many dummy pack- ets) or cause significant delays to user traffic; sometimes both. These factors have stymied the adoption of all of these defenses; Tor developers would not want to harm user experience of their anonymity network. Therefore, to create zero-delay lightweight defenses, we decided to avoid confusion and regularization defenses. Among our new defenses, FRONT is an obfuscation defense, while GLUE is in its own category as it forces the WF attacker to solve a different, much more difficult problem.</p><p>Some other defenses also require extra infrastructure to support, which is detrimental to their deployability. Supersequence and Walkie-Talkie both assume that the client knows some information about the webpage they are about to visit. This is generally impractical. The BuFLO-series of defenses mandate fixed packet rates, which may require some modification to the network stack because otherwise network delays could still reveal information. Walkie-Talkie requires modification to how the browser loads webpages. Our objective is to create defenses that can be deployed as painlessly and quickly as possible against the present threat of network surveillance, so we do not use any extra infrastructure.</p><p>We summarize the above in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>. Our defenses share the category of zero-delay lightweight defenses with only WTF-PAD. Noting that WTF-PAD is defeated by DF <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref>, we compare our work with theirs to show that our defenses are effective against DF.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Preliminaries</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Threat Model</head><p>Like previous works in WF, we consider a passive adversary who is local to the user. <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> illustrates the attack model. The adversary sits between the user and the entry node of the Tor network, eavesdropping on the network traffic over the encrypted channel. The adversary will not delay, modify or drop any packets.</p><p>We aim to deploy our defenses on Tor nodes to protect its clients against WF. There are three nodes in a typical Tor circuit: entry, middle, and exit. The middle node would serve Figure 1: The threat model for WF. The adversary sits between the user and the Tor network. The middle node of Tor network will be a cooperating proxy to deploy our defense.</p><p>as the cooperating proxy enacting the defense with the client. We use the middle node because the entry node is a possible WF attacker. Exit nodes and web servers would be entirely unaffected by our defense, as the middle node would drop dummy packets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Classification</head><p>From the attacker's perspective, WF can be regarded as a classification problem. During webpage loading, a WF attacker records network traffic traces (also known as packet sequences). The attacker visits a certain set of monitored pages in advance and trains a machine learning model on these traces. Each webpage is a class, and a particular trace belonging to this class is called an instance. Then, when observing the client's traces, the attacker predicts which webpage the trace belongs to, based on the trained model. WF attacks may be evaluated in either the closed-world or the open-world scenario. In the closed-world scenario, we assume a user only visits a specific set of webpages, also called monitored webpages. In the open-world scenario, the client can also visit non-monitored webpages, so the attacker must predict whether a trace is a monitored one or a non-monitored one. If it is monitored, the attacker has to further answer which one. The attacker never trains on the same webpage the client visits; therefore, the attacker has zero prior knowledge of the client's behavior. We focus on the more realistic open-world scenario.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>USENIX Association 29th USENIX Security Symposium 719</head><p>While it is more difficult than the closed-world scenario, a large number of attacks have recently shown open-world success <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">17,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">18,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">25,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">30]</ref>.</p><p>In the closed-world scenario, the attacker must achieve high accuracy (true positive rate), while in the open-world scenario, the attacker must achieve both high accuracy and precision. Therefore, to prove the efficacy of our defense against open-world attackers, we need to ensure that the attacker has both low accuracy and low precision. We specifically define precision in open-world WF below.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Precision</head><p>The precision of a classifier is defined as the proportion of positive (i.e. monitored) classifications that are correct. Researchers have pointed out that the base rate (the proportion of monitored webpages visited by the client) has been erroneously ignored in previous WF works when calculating precision <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[23]</ref>. This may lead to the base rate fallacy: an attack that seems to be accurate (high true positive rate) is actually highly imprecise when the base rate is low. If it is imprecise, its classifications are useless to the attacker. The definition of precision is somewhat atypical for WF because it is not a two-class problem, so we explicitly define it as follows:</p><p>Definition 3.1. Positives. If the WF attacker classifies a trace as belonging to a monitored webpage, it is a positive. If the classification is correct, it is a true positive. If the classification is incorrect and the sequence actually belongs to a different monitored webpage, it is a wrong positive. If the classification is incorrect and the sequence actually belongs to a non-monitored webpage, it is a false positive. Definition 3.2. Precision. In an experiment, let N P and N N denote the number of positives and negatives respectively. Let T PR and W PR denote the proportion of true positives and wrong positives to N P . Let FPR denote the proportion of false positives to N N . Then the precision is:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">π = T PR T PR +W PR + r · FPR ,</formula><p>In the above, r is the ratio between how often the client visits non-monitored webpages to how often the client visits monitored webpages. A higher r lowers precision, and makes the open-world classification problem harder; previous attacks have shown success against clients up to r = 1000 <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[23]</ref>. We want to prove that our defense is effective even for low-r clients that visit monitored webpages frequently. Therefore, in our paper, we set r = 10, representing a client that visits one monitored webpage for every ten non-monitored webpages. Hereafter we evaluate precision for such a client.</p><p>We also present the F 1 score, the harmonic mean of TPR and precision, as a single combined metric for comparison between different attacks.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Overhead</head><p>We define the overhead of defending a trace as follows.</p><p>Definition 3.3. Trace. A trace is a sequence of packets collected during a page loading process, denoted as</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">P = (t 1 , L 1 ), (t 2 , L 2 ), · · · , (t |P| , L |P| )</formula><p>where |P| is the total number of cells in the trace. t i is the timestamp of the i-th packet. L i shows the direction and length of the i-th packet. Tor uses its own datagrams called cells which are all padded to the same length. Since Tor cells are of the same length, we simply use L i = +1 to represent a cell coming from the client and −1 to represent a cell coming from the server. (We use packets to refer to both types of datagram.) Definition 3.4. -trace. An -trace comprises traces of consecutive visits to webpages, denoted as P = P 1 ||P 2 || · · · ||P .</p><p>Let P denote the original trace and P denote the trace after implementing some defense D. We define latency and data overhead on this trace as follows, which are the costs of implementing the defense D:</p><p>Definition 3.5. Latency overhead. The latency overhead T (D) of defense D on P is the extra time taken to transmit real packets, divided by the original transmission time. Denote the last real packet in P as t k , then we have:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">T (D) = t k − t |P| t |P| Definition 3.6. Data overhead. The data overhead O(D)</formula><p>of defense D on P is the total amount of dummy data divided by the total amount of real data:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">O(D) = |P | − |P| |P|</formula><p>Generally, latency overhead affects users' browsing experience while data overhead shows the extra burden laid on the network. They should be considered together when evaluating a defense. Following previous works <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">27]</ref>, we define these two metrics to be independent of each other, to simplify the analysis and to more easily highlight how defenses change each overhead. When bandwidth is a concern, for example, increasing the bandwidth overhead will likely delay page loading but will not change the time overhead.</p><p>Note that Definition 3.5 does not include the whole trace P , only the sequence up to the last real packet. That is because the client's page would have fully loaded upon reception of the last real packet; extra dummy packets sent or received after that point have no effect on the client's experience. Our defenses, FRONT and GLUE, have zero latency overhead (zero-delay) and little data overhead (lightweight).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">FRONT</head><p>In this section, we first introduce the high-level idea behind FRONT by pointing out our observations and intuition in Section 4.1. In Section 4.2, we describe its design in detail. Finally, in Section 4.3, we analyze the features of our defense. We will evaluate FRONT in Section 5.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Overview</head><p>Learning from previous failures to implement WF defenses on anonymity technologies like Tor, we believe three properties are necessary to achieve deployability: zero-delay (no latency overhead), lightweight (small data overhead), and easy implementation. This respectively ensures that the defense has no effect on user experience, its extra data can be easily borne by the anonymity network, and its codebase will be easy to understand and maintain. Seeing the failure of confusion and regularization strategies to achieve these properties in previous work, we turn to obfuscation, and create FRONT (Front Randomized Obfuscation of Network Traffic).</p><p>The only known defense that shares these properties with FRONT is WTF-PAD <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref>. In WTF-PAD, the client and server separately maintain two histograms where they sample inter-arrival time to generate dummy packets. To achieve the best performance, they also suggest tuning the parameters by sampling inter-arrival time from the real dataset. However, the tuning process is not user friendly and the construction and maintenance of these histograms are nontrivial. Pulls <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22]</ref> also points out that the token mechanism in WTF-PAD is unnecessary and should be abandoned.</p><p>By contrast, FRONT is much simpler, uses less data overhead, and achieves better performance against the best attacks. It relies on two key intuitions:</p><p>• Obfuscating feature-rich trace fronts. The first few seconds of each trace, which we call the trace front, leaks the most useful features for WF classification. Some of the best attacks explicitly use the trace front for classification <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24]</ref>. We dedicate most of our data budget to obfuscating the trace front, instead of spreading them evenly over the trace.</p><p>• Trace-to-trace randomness. FRONT adds dummy packets in a highly random manner, ensuring different traces of the same webpage look different to each other in total length, packet ordering, and packet directions. To do so, it randomizes the data budget and the region where we inject dummy packets. Since we must allow the attacker to train on defended traces instead of original traces, traceto-trace randomness hurts the attacker's ability to find any meaningful patterns for a webpage class. Most regularization defenses suffer from trace-to-trace consistency. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Defense Design</head><p>There are three steps in using FRONT to defend a trace: sample a number of dummy packets, sample a padding window size and schedule dummy packets. Its parameters are summarized in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>.</p><p>Sample a number of dummy packets N c and N s are two parameters determining the data overhead of FRONT, respectively representing the client's padding budget and the proxy's padding budget. For each trace, the client samples n c from the discretized uniform distribution between 1 and N c , denoted as ¯ U(1, N c ); the proxy samples n s from ¯ U(1, N s ). n c and n s are the actual number of dummy packets they will inject into that trace.</p><p>Sample a padding window FRONT spends most of its budget obfuscating trace fronts. To do so, both client and proxy will first generate a padding window, controlling where most dummy packets are expected to be injected into the original trace. For each trace, the client samples w c from the uniform distribution between W min and W max , denoted as U(W min ,W max ); the proxy samples w s from the same distribution. The reason we set a lower bound W min , instead of 0, is to ensure that the generated padding window size is not too small; if it is too small, the defense may require an extreme bandwidth rate to support.</p><p>Schedule dummy packets After sampling the above variables, the client and proxy generate separate timetables to schedule when their respective n c and n s dummy packets will be sent. They generate the timestamps by sampling n c and n s times from a Rayleigh Distribution. Its probability density function is:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">f (t; w) = t w 2 e −t 2 /2w 2 t ≥ 0 0 t &lt; 0 ,</formula><p>where w is w c for the client and w s for the proxy. True packets will be sent with no delays and dummy packets will be sent according to the timetables. When webpage loading finishes, the client will notify the relay with a packet and any unsent packets left in the timetable are simply dropped.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Defense Analysis</head><p>FRONT makes use of a Rayleigh Distribution. The corresponding PDF f (t; w) is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>. The curve first increases quickly, peaks at w and then gradually decreases. This results in a burst of dummy packets at the start of a trace, in accordance with our first intuition. Though our dummy packet window has a nominal length of w, the window is "soft"; we expect 40% of the dummy packets to lie in the time interval <ref type="bibr">[0, w]</ref>:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">w 0 t w 2 e −t 2 /2w 2 dt ≈ 0.40</formula><p>We sample the number of dummy packets and padding window size so that they are different each time we load a webpage, even if it is the same webpage. This eliminates possible patterns that could be leveraged by an attacker, as suggested by our second intuition.</p><p>In FRONT, the latency overhead is always 0 since it never delays any real packets whereas the data overhead is proportional to N c + N s . The number of dummy packets in each trace will be ¯ U(1, N s ) + ¯ U(1, N c ) (unless they are cut off by the end of a real trace), with a mean of (N s + N c )/2 + 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Evaluation of FRONT</head><p>In this section, we evaluate FRONT in several aspects. After presenting our experimental setup, we evaluate FRONT against the best attacks to show that it is able to defeat them, and do so more efficiently than the state-of-the-art defenses. We follow up with an analysis of our design decisions to show why FRONT succeeds.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Experimental Setup</head><p>To conduct our experiments, we collect a new dataset (denoted as <ref type="bibr">DS-19</ref>) between February and April 2019 with Tor Browser 8.5a7 on Tor 0.4.0.1-alpha, driven by command-line calls to Tor Browser. We visited the homepages of Alexa top 100 websites 100 times each as our monitored webpages and 10000 other webpages as our non-monitored webpages, filtering out pages that did not load (such as those inaccessible through Tor). In doing so, we used a single machine connected to a university network. Since all traces are collected from an automated browser and none of them are from real users, there are no ethical concerns regarding the dataset and the following experiments. We choose two defenses, WTF-PAD <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref> and Tamaraw <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>, as competitors to our defense representing two extremes in design philosophy: WTF-PAD is a lightweight obfuscation defense, while Tamaraw is a heavyweight regularization defense with high latency and data overhead. Other obfuscation defenses have been broken by known attacks, while most confusion and regularization defenses are either more expensive than Tamaraw, or impractical to implement.</p><p>We use kNN <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[24]</ref>, CUMUL <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref>, kFP <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref> and DF <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref> as benchmarks to evaluate the defenses. We use suggested parameters in their papers for kNN, kFP and DF with one exception: for DF, we set the maximum length of the traces to 10000 (instead of 5000 suggested by Sirinam et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref>) to accommodate our dummy packets. CUMUL uses an SVM, which is heavily dependent on choosing the correct parameters, so we first follow the paper to perform parameter tuning on the candidate parameters and find the optimal parameters.</p><p>All the experiments are conducted in open-world setting. For each attack, we apply 10-fold cross validation on the dataset. We count true positives, wrong positives and false positives on each fold and add them up together. Then we calculate their corresponding TPR, WPR, FPR and precision.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Evaluation against Other Defenses</head><p>We start by showing that FRONT dominates WTF-PAD in terms of effectiveness against the best attacks. We also evaluate Tamaraw, a heavyweight defense, for comparison. The overhead of each defense is shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref>. We choose two sets of parameters for FRONT: FT-1 representing a lightweight defense which has similar data overhead as WTF-PAD and FT-2 representing a defense with slightly higher overhead but greater effectiveness. N s + N c determines the data overhead while W min and W max decide the padding window size. We put a more detailed discussion about how to set these parameters in Appendix A. FRONT performance on DS-19 <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 4</ref> shows how well WF attacks perform against our evaluated defenses. We present TPR, precision and F 1 score of each attack under different defenses. When no defense is implemented, all attacks achieve over 89% TPR. kFP and DF become the strongest attacks since F 1 is over 90% for both of them. Even though CUMUL's TPR is quite high (94%), it has the lowest precision (64%), resulting in its low F 1 . All attacks achieve a low F 1 score against Tamaraw, but Tamaraw comes with a very high price in terms of overhead. WTF-PAD is much cheaper at 32% data overhead, and it defends against kNN and CUMUL well. However, kFP and DF remain effective against WTF-PAD, achieving 0.61 and 0.70 F 1 score.</p><p>FT-1 outperforms WTF-PAD in defending against every attack, especially kNN and DF. With nearly the same data overhead as WTF-PAD, kNN performs just as poorly against FT-1 as against Tamaraw, and DF performs half as well as before (by F 1 score). FT-2 further decreases F 1 of the strongest attacks, kFP and DF, with only 48% data overhead.</p><p>We find that FRONT is especially effective against kNN, even approaching Tamaraw's performance. It is also effective at defeating DF, the strongest attack on the undefended dataset: the precision of DF drops significantly against FRONT, more so than kFP.</p><p>To explain why FRONT outperforms WTF-PAD, we evaluate how it embodies our two key intuitions (in Section 4.1) compared to WTF-PAD. First, to show its obfuscation of trace fronts, we calculate how much data budget FRONT and WTF-PAD use in each portion of the trace. WTF-PAD distributes its budget evenly: it spends 24% of its budget in the first quarter of the trace and 49% in the first half. In contrast, FRONT uses 40% of its budget in the first quarter and 69% in the first half. Second, to show trace-to-trace randomness, we evaluate the coefficient of variation of dummy packets injected in each webpage class. We find that FRONT has a median coefficient of variation of 42% compared to 36% for WTF-PAD over our dataset.</p><p>TPR on different websites We further investigate FRONT's webpage-to-webpage performance on DS-19. We equally divide the monitored webpages into 4 groups based on their webpage sizes, denoted as G 1 , G 2 , G 3 and G 4 , where G 1 is the smallest quartile of webpages and G 4 is the largest quartile of webpages. The number of packets of each webpage in those groups is up to 2039, 4368, 6611 and 28199, respectively. We can see that the sizes of webpages vary greatly, especially for G 4 .</p><p>We choose the most precise attack, kFP, and compute the recall. The recall on each group is 24%, 24%, 35% and 54%. The performance of FRONT does not change much on first three groups. The webpages in G 4 are 10 times larger than G 1 , and the recall rate increases by 30%.</p><p>FRONT performance on DS-14 We did a supplementary experiment on Wang's dataset <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[24]</ref> collected in 2014 (denoted as DS-14) which consists of 9000 monitored webpages and 9000 non-monitored ones. The mean number of packets is 2163 in DS-14 and 4444 in DS-19. Therefore, the web pages of DS-14 are significantly smaller. The intent of this experiment is to verify that FRONT works on different websites. With 41% data overhead, FRONT greatly outperforms over WTF-PAD (which has 44% data overhead) in all metrics, no matter which attack is used.</p><p>For the strongest two attacks, kFP and DF, FRONT reduces their F 1 score to 0.30 and 0.41, compared with 0.48 and 0.63 against WTF-PAD. The most significant case is kNN which relies greatly on trace FRONT information. Its F 1 is reduced to only 0.03 while WTF-PAD reduces it to 0.26. We also find that all the attacks perform better on DS-19 than DS-14. The observation that larger websites are easier to identify was also made by Overdorf et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Information Leakage Analysis</head><p>Some recent works <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">12]</ref> have pointed out that empirically evaluating a defense against state-of-art attacks may not show the real security level of such a defense. WeFDE, proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref>, quantifies the amount of information leakage for 3043 features, chosen from those exploited by known state-of-the-art attacks. We use WeFDE to measure the information leaked on undefended traces, WTF-PAD and FRONT. The detailed methodology of WeFDE and the introduction of feature set can be found in <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref>.</p><p>We plot the empirical cumulative distribution function (ECDF) of information leakage for all features in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref>. Generally speaking, the curve for FRONT increases much faster than that for WTF-PAD and undefended Tor, indicating that most features leak less information under FRONT. Specifically, no feature leaks more than 3.6 bits of information on undefended Tor, 3.5 bits for WTF-PAD, 2.3 bits for FT-1 and 2 bits for FT-2.</p><p>The information leakage analysis confirms again that FRONT achieves a higher security level than WTF-PAD. We include the full information leakage result in Appendix D.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4">Choosing Where to Pad</head><p>FRONT is built on the intuition that it helps to obfuscate the trace front for defense effectiveness. We validate this intuition here by delaying all dummy packets from 0 s to 10 s and measure the change in TPR and precision of each attack. We set W min = 1 s, W max = 14 s, N c = 1000 and N s = 1000 based on FT-2. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4</ref> shows the results. The larger the delay, the less we will obfuscate the trace front (the same padding budget is instead spent on the middle or the end).</p><p>We can see that for all attacks, both TPR and precision grow as we increase the delay, thus leaking more of the trace front. All attacks' TPR increase by 5-30%, among which DF always achieves the highest TPR, increasing from 59% to 71%. kFP's TPR nearly doubles from 34% to 62%. In terms of precision, there are some ups and downs due to its sensitivity to false positives. But still, all attacks become 6-15% more precise as we reveal the trace front by shifting dummy packets later. This experiment indicates that trace fronts do leak a lot of information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.5">Impact of Randomness</head><p>In FRONT, the client and proxy will sample the number of dummy packets and the padding window from a range instead of fixing them. We do two experiments to validate the effectiveness of this design decision.</p><p>In the first experiment, we gradually shrink the range of choices for the number of dummy packets and observe the Unlike previous experiments, here we sample n c from ¯ U(β · N c , N c ) and n s from ¯ U(β · N s , N s ). We vary β , which controls the degree of randomization, from 0 to 1 (0 being maximal randomization).</p><p>As β increases, trace-to-trace randomness in the number of dummy packets decreases. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 5</ref> shows the results. We see that increasing β weakens the defense, as all attacks except DF increase in TPR, especially when β &gt; 0.8. As for DF, its TPR remains around 60%: increasing trace-to-trace randomness does not weaken its attack ability. Note that increasing β also increases data overhead linearly, doubling the data overhead at β = 1.</p><p>We perform a similar experiment on randomizing padding window size, using the same settings as the above experiment. We keep W max = 14 s and set W min = β · W max . We gradually increase β from 0 to 1. <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref> shows the results. Just as before, when we decrease the randomness in padding window size, TPR increases, especially for CUMUL and DF.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.6">Evaluation of Data Overhead</head><p>In this part, we want to measure how an increase in the overhead budget affects the attacker's effectiveness. We focus on kFP here because the extensive experiments in Section 5.2 to Section 5.5 show us that kFP is the strongest attack by F 1 score; DF is accurate but imprecise against FRONT, so its F 1 score is lower. Setting W min = 1 s and W max = 14 s, we vary N s + N c from 0 to 7200 packets in intervals of 200 packets. We show TPR and F 1 of kFP in <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref>.</p><p>Without FRONT, kFP can achieve 92% TPR. Its TPR de-  creases quickly as we initially increase the size overhead. With only 25% data overhead, its TPR is already lower than 50%. On the other hand, its F 1 score decreases from 93% to 38% as we increase the data overhead from 0% to 70%.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">GLUE</head><p>Our second proposed defense, GLUE, exploits an entirely new facet of website fingerprinting to achieve even greater success than FRONT against known attacks. We start by presenting the big picture of what GLUE exploits and how it achieves success. Due to the novelty of GLUE, we carefully elaborate our threat model and defense design.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">Overview</head><p>Many WF attacks have been published in recent years, all of them relying on the same assumption: that every trace the attacker must classify corresponds to exactly one webpage. We call these traces singleton traces. This is satisfied if the client dwells on pages for some time before visiting the next page; the attacker will notice the obvious time gap and split the trace at that point. Even a second of inactivity will be enough. Conversely, when the client visits ≥ 2 pages consecutively without an obvious time gap -for example, by clicking a link before the page has fully loaded -all known WF attacks cannot succeed in classifying the -trace thus generated, even if they are properly trained and aware of such a possibility <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">30]</ref>. Since known WF attacks can only classify singleton traces ( = 1), there are two difficult problems the attacker must solve to classify -traces correctly for ≥ 2. First, the attacker must correctly determine ; we call this the split decision problem. Secondly, the attacker must find − 1 points to split the -trace into separate singleton traces; we call this the split finding problem. Then, the classifier can input these singleton traces into a powerful WF attack. There are some works suggesting that the latter problem could be solved for = 2 <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[26,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">29]</ref>, but no solution is known in general; the former problem has never been solved.</p><p>We leverage the difficulty of solving these problems to create a new defense, GLUE. Whenever the client is dwelling on a webpage, GLUE adds dummy packets to make it seem as if the client is visiting new pages consecutively. GLUE will stop sending dummy packets when the client loads a new page, thus hiding the true start of the next page. In other words, GLUE tries to glue together singleton traces intotraces for large values of . Unable to solve either the split decision or finding problem, attacks are very likely to fail if they split traces wrongly. This is especially true if the resultant singleton traces have extra packets in the trace front, which is critical for correct classification.    </p><formula xml:id="formula_6">h Y 0 F F X d d H c F q Z K G X P f b K W x s b m 3 v F H d L e / s H h 0 f l 4 5 O W S T I t s C k S l e h O w A 0 q G W O T J C n s p B p 5 F C h s B + O b u d 9 + Q m 1 k E j / Q J E U / 4 s N Y h l J w s l K H + r 1 b V M T 7 5 Y p b d R d g 6 8 T L S Q V y N P r l r 9 4 g E V m E M Q n F j e l 6 b k r + l G u S Q u G s 1 M s M p l y M + R C 7 l s Y 8 Q u N P F / f O 2 I V V B i x M t K 2 Y 2 E L 9 P T H l k T G T K L C d E a e R W f X m 4 n 9 e N 6 P w 2 p / K O M 0 I Y 7 F c F G a K U c</formula><formula xml:id="formula_7">h Y 0 F F X d d H c F q Z K G X P f b K W x s b m 3 v F H d L e / s H h 0 f l 4 5 O W S T I t s C k S l e h O w A 0 q G W O T J C n s p B p 5 F C h s B + O b u d 9 + Q m 1 k E j / Q J E U / 4 s N Y h l J w s l K H + r 1 b V M T 7 5 Y p b d R d g 6 8 T L S Q V y N P r l r 9 4 g E V m E M Q n F j e l 6 b k r + l G u S Q u G s 1 M s M p l y M + R C 7 l s Y 8 Q u N P F / f O 2 I V V B i x M t K 2 Y 2 E L 9 P T H l k T G T K L C d E a e R W f X m 4 n 9 e N 6 P w 2 p / K O M 0 I Y 7 F c F G a K U c</formula><formula xml:id="formula_8">h Y 0 F F X d d H c F q Z K G X P f b K W x s b m 3 v F H d L e / s H h 0 f l 4 5 O W S T I t s C k S l e h O w A 0 q G W O T J C n s p B p 5 F C h s B + O b u d 9 + Q m 1 k E j / Q J E U / 4 s N Y h l J w s l K H + r 1 b V M T 7 5 Y p b d R d g 6 8 T L S Q V y N P r l r 9 4 g E V m E M Q n F j e l 6 b k r + l G u S Q u G s 1 M s M p l y M + R C 7 l s Y 8 Q u N P F / f O 2 I V V B i x M t K 2 Y 2 E L 9 P T H l k T G T K L C d E a e R W f X m 4 n 9 e N 6 P w 2 p / K O M 0 I Y 7 F c F G a K U c</formula><formula xml:id="formula_9">h Y 0 F F X d d H c F q Z K G X P f b K W x s b m 3 v F H d L e / s H h 0 f l 4 5 O W S T I t s C k S l e h O w A 0 q G W O T J C n s p B p 5 F C h s B + O b u d 9 + Q m 1 k E j / Q J E U / 4 s N Y h l J w s l K H + r 1 b V M T 7 5 Y p b d R d g 6 8 T L S Q V y N P r l r 9 4 g E V m E M Q n F j e l 6 b k r + l G u S Q u G s 1 M s M p l y M + R C 7 l s Y 8 Q u N P F / f O 2 I V V B i x M t K 2 Y 2 E L 9 P T H l k T G T K L C d E a e R W f X m 4 n 9 e N 6 P w 2 p / K O M 0 I Y 7 F c F G a K U c L m z 7 O B 1 C h I T S z h Q k t 7 K x M j</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>r r k g G 1 H J h u C t v r x O W r W q 5 1 a 9 + 1 q l 7 u Z x F O E M z u E S P L i C O t x B A 5 o g Q M E z v M K b 8 + i 8 O O / O x 7 K 1 4 O Q z p / A H z u c P 6 a G P z w = = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt;</head><p>, send request to proxy</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Back Mode</head><p>Click another webpage before time out</p><p>Stop loading glue trace </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Defense Design</head><p>Suppose a client visits webpages in a time period and then stops. GLUE tries to make sure that the attacker will see a seemingly consecutive -trace P = P 1 ||P 2 || · · · ||P . Without GLUE, they may have dwell time gaps between them, allowing the attacker to split them trivially. Denote the dwell time on P i as d i . GLUE pads for a maximum duration d max . For GLUE to create an -trace, let us suppose d i ≤ d max for i = 1, . . . , − 1 and d &gt; d max . While the client dwells on webpages, the client and the proxy will send each other dummy packets. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">Figure 8</ref> gives the state machine of a client, and the proxy's state machine is similar. GLUE also uses FRONT noise to defend the first of -traces.</p><p>Front Mode Starting in Front Mode, our defense waits for the client to visit a webpage. When the client does so, we will add dummy packets according to our FRONT defense, as described in previous sections. We will also sample those inter-arrival times between incoming packets and outgoing packets to obtain some distribution I. After the client finishes visiting the webpage, we sample t ∆ according to I (described below), wait for time t ∆ , then switch to Glue Mode.</p><p>Glue Mode In Glue Mode, the client and proxy send each other dummy packets in such a way that it looks as if the client decided to visit a new, random webpage. (The person behind the client is actually dwelling on the previous webpage.) They will do so for at most time d max . They immediately stop doing so if the client actually decides to visit a webpage before d max has passed: the client will notify the proxy to terminate Glue Mode as well. If the client dwells on the webpage for longer than d max , the algorithm will consider the client inactive and return to Front Mode. Otherwise, it will go to Back Mode. We call the dummy packets added here "glue traces".</p><p>Back Mode In Back Mode, the client is visiting another webpage. This is like Front Mode, except we add zero dummy packets. We still sample packet inter-arrival times and switch back to Glue Mode after waiting for t ∆ .</p><p>GLUE incorporates FRONT in Front Mode, ensuring that the first trace of any -trace will be padded with FRONT. This is because we found that GLUE alone does not protect the first trace well (shown in Section 7.6), but achieves excellent protection of all other traces. We need to add a bit of overhead to protect the first trace.</p><p>In the above, I is the inter-arrival time distribution only with those time gaps between an incoming and an outgoing packet. t ∆ is the sampled inter arrival time. We choose t ∆ ∈ U(I ¯ 20 , I ¯ 80 ) where I ¯ 20 and I ¯ 80 are the 20 percentile and 80 percentile of the inter-arrival time distribution I respectively. We intentionally create such a small gap to simulate a time interval when the client sends out some request after receiving data from the server during a webpage loading. By doing so we connect real traces with glue traces together naturally without any abnormal gaps in between. We also randomize d max by sampling from a uniform distribution so that the attacker could not trivially remove the noise on the tail.</p><p>We illustrate how GLUE works with <ref type="figure" target="#fig_12">Figure 9</ref>. Suppose a client visits three webpages with real traces P 1 , P 2 , and P 3 , then stops, with time gaps d 1 , d 2 &lt; d max after the first two pages respectively. The attacker will collect a 3-trace, P = P 1 ||P 2 ||P 3 . P 1 contains P 1 with FRONT noise, followed by a glue trace of duration d 1 . P 2 contains P 2 followed by a glue trace of duration d 2 . P 3 contains P 3 followed by a glue trace of duration d max . Of course, the attacker cannot know where each trace starts or ends. In fact, the attacker will not even know how many traces there are. If the attacker tries to split the combined trace incorrectly, some or all of the split traces will be contaminated by dummy packets in their beginning or end, which greatly affects WF attack performance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3">Distributing Glue Traces</head><p>To make sure glue traces look like real traces, the client needs to have a database which contains real webpage loads. We propose that the client will retrieve such a database along with the list of Tor nodes at Tor startup from Tor directory servers. Then the client will ask for more after some certain period of time. During Glue Mode, the client instructs the proxy when to send a dummy packet. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " 0 t 7 t E F + 6 e 4 y A j M + R u S V r 5 9 z 8 i A 0 = " &gt; A A A B 6 n i c b V B N S 8 N A E J 3 U r 1 q / q h 6 9 L B b B U 0 l 6 s c e C F 4 8 V 7 Q e 0 o W y 2 k 3 b p Z h N 2 N 0 I J / Q l e P C j i 1 V / k z X / j p s 1 B W x 8 M P N 6 b Y W Z e k A i u j e t + O 6 W t 7 Z 3 d v f J + 5 e D w 6 P i k e n r W 1 X G q G H Z Y L G L V D 6 h G w S V 2 D D c C + 4 l C G g U C e 8 H s N v d 7 T 6 g 0 j + W j m S f o R 3 Q i e c g Z N V Z 6 a I + 8 U b X m 1 t 0 l y C b x C l K D A u 1 R 9 W s 4 j l k a o T R M U K 0 H n p s Y P 6 P K c C Z w U R m m G h P K Z n S C A 0 s l j V D 7 2 f L U B b m y y p i E s b I l D V m q v y c y G m k 9 j w L b G V E z 1 e t e L v 7 n D V I T N v 2 M y y Q 1 K N l q U Z g K Y m K S / 0 3 G X C E z Y m 4 J Z Y r b W w m b U k W Z s e l U b A j e + s u b p N u o e 2 7 d u 2 / U W s 0 i j j J c w C V c g w c 3 0 I I 7 a E M H G E z g G V 7 h z R H O i / P u f K x a S 0 4 x c w 5 / 4 H z + A M s P j W w = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " 0 t 7 t E F + 6 e 4 y A j M + R u S V r 5 9 z 8 i A 0 = " &gt; A A A B 6 n i c b V B N S 8 N A E J 3 U r 1 q / q h 6 9 L B b B U 0 l 6 s c e C F 4 8 V 7 Q e 0 o W y 2 k 3 b p Z h N 2 N 0 I J / Q l e P C j i 1 V / k z X / j p s 1 B W x 8 M P N 6 b Y W Z e k A i u j e t + O 6 W t 7 Z 3 d v f J + 5 e D w 6 P i k e n r W 1 X G q G H Z Y L G L V D 6 h G w S V 2 D D c C + 4 l C G g U C e 8 H s N v d 7 T 6 g 0 j + W j m S f o R 3 Q i e c g Z N V Z 6 a I + 8 U b X m 1 t 0 l y C b x C l K D A u 1 R 9 W s 4 j l k a o T R M U K 0 H n p s Y P 6 P K c C Z w U R m m G h P K Z n S C A 0 s l j V D 7 2 f L U B b m y y p i E s b I l D V m q v y c y G m k 9 j w L b G V E z 1 e t e L v 7 n D V I T N v 2 M y y Q 1 K N l q U Z g K Y m K S / 0 3 G X C E z Y m 4 J Z Y r b W w m b U k W Z s e l U b A j e + s u b p N u o e 2 7 d u 2 / U W s 0 i j j J c w C V c g w c 3 0 I I 7 a E M H G E z g G V 7 h z R H O i / P u f K x a S 0 4 x c w 5 / 4 H z + A M s P j W w = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; P 1 &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " 0 t 7 t E F + 6 e 4 y A j M + R u S V r 5 9 z 8 i A 0 = " &gt; A A A B 6 n i c b V B N S 8 N A E J 3 U r 1 q / q h 6 9 L B b B U 0 l 6 s c e C F 4 8 V 7 Q e 0 o W y 2 k 3 b p Z h N 2 N 0 I J / Q l e P C j i 1 V / k z X / j p s 1 B W x 8 M P N 6 b Y W Z e k A i u j e t + O 6 W t 7 Z 3 d v f J + 5 e D w 6 P i k e n r W 1 X G q G H Z Y L G L V D 6 h G w S V 2 D D c C + 4 l C G g U C e 8 H s N v d 7 T 6 g 0 j + W j m S f o R 3 Q i e c g Z N V Z 6 a I + 8 U b X m 1 t 0 l y C b x C l K D A u 1 R 9 W s 4 j l k a o T R M U K 0 H n p s Y P 6 P K c C Z w U R m m G h P K Z n S C A 0 s l j V D 7 2 f L U B b m y y p i E s b I l D V m q v y c y G m k 9 j w L b G V E z 1 e t e L v 7 n D V I T N v 2 M y y Q 1 K N l q U Z g K Y m K S / 0 3 G X C E z Y m 4 J Z Y r b W w m b U k W Z s e l U b A j e + s u b p N u o e 2 7 d u 2 / U W s 0 i j j J c w C V c g w c 3 0 I I 7 a E M H G E z g G V 7 h z R H O i / P u f K x a S 0 4 x c w 5 / 4 H z + A M s P j W w = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " 0 t 7 t E F + 6 e 4 y A j M + R u S V r 5 9 z 8 i A 0 = " &gt; A A A B 6 n i c b V B N S 8 N A E J 3 U r 1 q / q h 6 9 L B b B U 0 l 6 s c e C F 4 8 V 7 Q e 0 o W y 2 k 3 b p Z h N 2 N 0 I J / Q l e P C j i 1 V / k z X / j p s 1 B W x 8 M P N 6 b Y W Z e k A i u j e t + O 6 W t 7 Z 3 d v f J + 5 e D w 6 P i k e n r W 1 X G q G H Z Y L G L V D 6 h G w S V 2 D D c C + 4 l C G g U C e 8 H s N v d 7 T 6 g 0 j + W j m S f o R 3 Q i e c g Z N V Z 6 a I + 8 U b X m 1 t 0 l y C b x C l K D A u 1 R 9 W s 4 j l k a o T R M U K 0 H n p s Y P 6 P K c C Z w U R m m G h P K Z n S C A 0 s l j V D 7 2 f L U B b m y y p i E s b I l D V m q v y c y G m k 9 j w L b G V E z 1 e t e L v 7 n D V I T N v 2 M y y Q 1 K N l q U Z g K Y m K S / 0 3 G X C E z Y m 4 J Z Y r b W w m b U k W Z s e l U b A j e + s u b p N u o e 2 7 d u 2 / U W s 0 i j j J c w C V c g w c 3 0 I I 7 a E M H G E z g G V 7 h z R H O i / P u f K x a S 0 4 x c w 5 / 4 H z + A M s P j W w = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; P 2 &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " d m N 5 1 v O w a S 6 x l 6 c L w / Q V W 3 c e u 1 0 = " &gt; A A A B 6 n i c b V B N S 8 N A E J 3 U r 1 q / q h 6 9 L B b B U 0 l 6 s c e C F 4 8 V 7 Q e 0 o W y 2 m 3 b p Z h N 2 J 0 I J / Q l e P C j i 1 V / k z X / j p s 1 B W x 8 M P N 6 b Y W Z e k E h h 0 H W / n d L W 9 s 7 u X n m / c n B 4 d H x S P T 3 r m j j V j H d Y L G P d D 6 j h U i j e Q Y G S 9 x P N a R R I 3 g t m t 7 n f e + L a i F g 9 4 j z h f k Q n S o S C U b T S Q 3 v U G F V r b t 1 d g m w S r y A 1 K N A e V b + G 4 5 i l E V f I J D V m 4 L k J + h n V K J j k i 8 o w N T y h b E Y n f G C p o h E 3 f r Y 8 d U G u r D I m Y a x t K S R L 9 f d E R i N j 5 l F g O y O K U 7 P u 5 e J / 3 i D F s O l n Q i U p c s V W i 8 J U E o x J / j c Z C 8 0 Z y r k l l G l h b y V s S j V l a N O p 2 B C 8 9 Z c 3 S b d R 9 9 y 6 d 9 + o t Z p F H G W 4 g E u 4 B g 9 u o A V 3 0 I Y O M J j A M 7 z C m y O d F + f d + V i 1 l p x i 5 h z + w P n 8 A c y T j W 0 = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " d m N 5 1 v O w a S 6 x l 6 c L w / Q V W 3 c e u 1 0 = " &gt; A A A B 6 n i c b V B N S 8 N A E J 3 U r 1 q / q h 6 9 L B b B U 0 l 6 s c e C F 4 8 V 7 Q e 0 o W y 2 m 3 b p Z h N 2 J 0 I J / Q l e P C j i 1 V / k z X / j p s 1 B W x 8 M P N 6 b Y W Z e k E h h 0 H W / n d L W 9 s 7 u X n m / c n B 4 d H x S P T 3 r m j j V j H d Y L G P d D 6 j h U i j e Q Y G S 9 x P N a R R I 3 g t m t 7 n f e + L a i F g 9 4 j z h f k Q n S o S C U b T S Q 3 v U G F V r b t 1 d g m w S r y A 1 K N A e V b + G 4 5 i l E V f I J D V m 4 L k J + h n V K J j k i 8 o w N T y h b E Y n f G C p o h E 3 f r Y 8 d U G u r D I m Y a x t K S R L 9 f d E R i N j 5 l F g O y O K U 7 P u 5 e J / 3 i D F s O l n Q i U p c s V W i 8 J U E o x J / j c Z C 8 0 Z y r k l l G l h b y V s S j V l a N O p 2 B C 8 9 Z c 3 S b d R 9 9 y 6 d 9 + o t Z p F H G W 4 g E u 4 B g 9 u o A V 3 0 I Y O M J j A M 7 z C m y O d F + f d + V i 1 l p x i 5 h z + w P n 8 A c y T j W 0 = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; P 2 &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " d m N 5 1 v O w a S 6 x l 6 c L w / Q V W 3 c e u 1 0 = " &gt; A A A B 6 n i c b V B N S 8 N A E J 3 U r 1 q / q h 6 9 L B b B U 0 l 6 s c e C F 4 8 V 7 Q e 0 o W y 2 m 3 b p Z h N 2 J 0 I J / Q l e P C j i 1 V / k z X / j p s 1 B W x 8 M P N 6 b Y W Z e k E h h 0 H W / n d L W 9 s 7 u X n m / c n B 4 d H x S P T 3 r m j j V j H d Y L G P d D 6 j h U i j e Q Y G S 9 x P N a R R I 3 g t m t 7 n f e + L a i F g 9 4 j z h f k Q n S o S C U b T S Q 3 v U G F V r b t 1 d g m w S r y A 1 K N A e V b + G 4 5 i l E V f I J D V m 4 L k J + h n V K J j k i 8 o w N T y h b E Y n f G C p o h E 3 f r Y 8 d U G u r D I m Y a x t K S R L 9 f d E R i N j 5 l F g O y O K U 7 P u 5 e J / 3 i D F s O l n Q i U p c s V W i 8 J U E o x J / j c Z C 8 0 Z y r k l l G l h b y V s S j V l a N O p 2 B C 8 9 Z c 3 S b d R 9 9 y 6 d 9 + o t Z p F H G W 4 g E u 4 B g 9 u o A V 3 0 I Y O M J j A M 7 z C m y O d F + f d + V i 1 l p x i 5 h z + w P n 8 A c y T j W 0 = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " d m N 5 1 v O w a S 6 x l 6 c L w / Q V W 3 c e u 1 0 = " &gt; A A A B 6 n i c b V B N S 8 N A E J 3 U r 1 q / q h 6 9 L B b B U 0 l 6 s c e C F 4 8 V 7 Q e 0 o W y 2 m 3 b p Z h N 2 J 0 I J / Q l e P C j i 1 V / k z X / j p s 1 B W x 8 M P N 6 b Y W Z e k E h h 0 H W / n d L W 9 s 7 u X n m / c n B 4 d H x S P T 3 r m j j V j H d Y L G P d D 6 j h U i j e Q Y G S 9 x P N a R R I 3 g t m t 7 n f e + L a i F g 9 4 j z h f k Q n S o S C U b T S Q 3 v U G F V r b t 1 d g m w S r y A 1 K N A e V b + G 4 5 i l E V f I J D V m 4 L k J + h n V K J j k i 8 o w N T y h b E Y n f G C p o h E 3 f r Y 8 d U G u r D I m Y a x t K S R L 9 f d E R i N j 5 l F g O y O K U 7 P u 5 e J / 3 i D F s O l n Q i U p c s V W i 8 J U E o x J / j c Z C 8 0 Z y r k l l G l h b y V s S j V l a N O p 2 B C 8 9 Z c 3 S b d R 9 9 y 6 d 9 + o t Z p F H G W 4 g E u 4 B g 9 u o A V 3 0 I Y O M J j A M 7 z C m y O d F + f d + V i 1 l p x i 5 h z + w P n 8 A c y T j W 0 = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; P 3 &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " 6 w 8 S h 4 V Y x x b o 0 a V H 5 7 B T 1 C v s q x Q = " &gt; A A A B 6 n i c b V A 9 S w N B E J 2 L X z F + R S 1 t F o N g F e 5 i k Z Q B G 8 u I 5 g O S I + x t 5 p I l e 3 v H 7 p 4 Q j v w E G w t F b P 1 F d v 4 b N 8 k V m v h g 4 P H e D D P z g k R w b V z 3 2 y l s b e / s 7 h X 3 S w e H R 8 c n 5 d O z j o 5 T x b D N Y h G r X k A 1 C i 6 x b b g R 2 E s U 0 i g Q 2 A 2 m t w u / + 4 R K 8 1 g + m l m C f k T H k o e c U W O l h 9 b w Z l i u u F V 3 C b J J v J x U I E d r W P 4 a j G K W R i g N E 1 T r v u c m x s + o M p w J n J c G q c a E s i k d Y 9 9 S S S P U f r Y 8 d U 6 u r D I i Y a x s S U O W 6 u + J j E Z a z 6 L A d k b U T P S 6 t x D / 8 / q p C R t + x m W S G p R s t S h M B T E x W f x N R l w h M 2 J m C W W K 2 1 s J m 1 B F m b H p l G w I 3 v r L m 6 R T q 3 p u 1 b u v V Z q N P I 4 i X M A l X I M H d W j C H b S g D Q z G 8 A y v 8 O Y I 5 8 V 5 d z 5 W r Q U n n z m H P 3 A + f w D O F 4 1 u &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " 6 w 8 S h 4 V Y x x b o 0 a V H 5 7 B T 1 C v s q x Q = " &gt; A A A B 6 n i c b V A 9 S w N B E J 2 L X z F + R S 1 t F o N g F e 5 i k Z Q B G 8 u I 5 g O S I + x t 5 p I l e 3 v H 7 p 4 Q j v w E G w t F b P 1 F d v 4 b N 8 k V m v h g 4 P H e D D P z g k R w b V z 3 2 y l s b e / s 7 h X 3 S w e H R 8 c n 5 d O z j o 5 T x b D N Y h G r X k A 1 C i 6 x b b g R 2 E s U 0 i g Q 2 A 2 m t w u / + 4 R K 8 1 g + m l m C f k T H k o e c U W O l h 9 b w Z l i u u F V 3 C b J J v J x U I E d r W P 4 a j G K W R i g N E 1 T r v u c m x s + o M p w J n J c G q c a E s i k d Y 9 9 S S S P U f r Y 8 d U 6 u r D I i Y a x s S U O W 6 u + J j E Z a z 6 L A d k b U T P S 6 t x D / 8 / q p C R t + x m W S G p R s t S h M B T E x W f x N R l w h M 2 J m C W W K 2 1 s J m 1 B F m b H p l G w I 3 v r L m 6 R T q 3 p u 1 b u v V Z q N P I 4 i X M A l X I M H d W j C H b S g D Q z G 8 A y v 8 O Y I 5 8 V 5 d z 5 W r Q U n n z m H P 3 A + f w D O F 4 1 u &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; P 3 &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " 6 w 8 S h 4 V Y x x b o 0 a V H 5 7 B T 1 C v s q x Q = " &gt; A A A B 6 n i c b V A 9 S w N B E J 2 L X z F + R S 1 t F o N g F e 5 i k Z Q B G 8 u I 5 g O S I + x t 5 p I l e 3 v H 7 p 4 Q j v w E G w t F b P 1 F d v 4 b N 8 k V m v h g 4 P H e D D P z g k R w b V z 3 2 y l s b e / s 7 h X 3 S w e H R 8 c n 5 d O z j o 5 T x b D N Y h G r X k A 1 C i 6 x b b g R 2 E s U 0 i g Q 2 A 2 m t w u / + 4 R K 8 1 g + m l m C f k T H k o e c U W O l h 9 b w Z l i u u F V 3 C b J J v J x U I E d r W P 4 a j G K W R i g N E 1 T r v u c m x s + o M p w J n J c G q c a E s i k d Y 9 9 S S S P U f r Y 8 d U 6 u r D I i Y a x s S U O W 6 u + J j E Z a z 6 L A d k b U T P S 6 t x D / 8 / q p C R t + x m W S G p R s t S h M B T E x W f x N R l w h M 2 J m C W W K 2 1 s J m 1 B F m b H p l G w I 3 v r L m 6 R T q 3 p u 1 b u v V Z q N P I 4 i X M A l X I M H d W j C H b S g D Q z G 8 A y v 8 O Y I 5 8 V 5 d z 5 W r Q U n n z m H P 3 A + f w D O F 4 1 u &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " 6 w 8 S h 4 V Y x x b o 0 a V H 5 7 B T 1 C v s q x Q = " &gt; A A A B 6 n i c b V A 9 S w N B E J 2 L X z F + R S 1 t F o N g F e 5 i k Z Q B G 8 u I 5 g O S I + x t 5 p I l e 3 v H 7 p 4 Q j v w E G w t F b P 1 F d v 4 b N 8 k V m v h g 4 P H e D D P z g k R w b V z 3 2 y l s b e / s 7 h X 3 S w e H R 8 c n 5 d O z j o 5 T x b D N Y h G r X k A 1 C i 6 x b b g R 2 E s U 0 i g Q 2 A 2 m t w u / + 4 R K 8 1 g + m l m C f k T H k o e c U W O l h 9 b w Z l i u u F V 3 C b J J v J x U I E d r W P 4 a j G K W R i g N E 1 T r v u c m x s + o M p w J n J c G q c a E s i k d Y 9 9 S S S P U f r Y 8 d U 6 u r D I i Y a x s S U O W 6 u + J j E Z a z 6 L A d k b U T P S 6 t x D / 8 / q p C R t + x m W S G p R s t S h M B T E x W f x N R l w h M 2 J m C W W K 2 1 s J m 1 B F m b H p l G w I 3 v r L m 6 R T q 3 p u 1 b u v V Z q N P I 4 i X M A l X I M H d W j C H b S g D Q z G 8 A y v 8 O Y I 5 8 V 5 d z 5 W r Q U n n z m H P 3 A + f w D O F 4 1 u &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; P 0 1 &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " q o m J p T a p + c 8 B D X V i 0 3 2 T m 3 G 3 S F k = " &gt; A A A B 8 X i c b V A 9 S w N B E J 3 z M 8 a v q K X N Y h C s w l 0 a U w Z s L C O Y D 0 z O s L e Z S 5 b s 7 h 2 7 e 0 I I + R c 2 F o r Y + m / s / D d u k i s 0 8 c H A 4 7 0 Z Z u Z F q e D G + v 6 3 t 7 G 5 t b 2 z W 9 g r 7 h 8 c H h 2 X T k 5 b J s k 0 w y Z L R K I 7 E T U o u M K m 5 V Z g J 9 V I Z S S w H Y 1 v 5 n 7 7 C b X h i b q 3 k x R D S Y e K x 5 x R 6 6 S H R j 9 4 7 K W a S + y X y n 7 F X 4 C s k y A n Z c j R 6 J e + e o O E Z R K V Z Y I a 0 w 3 8 1 I Z T q i 1 n A m f F X m Y w p W x M h 9 h 1 V F G J J p w u L p 6 R S 6 c M S J x o V 8 q S h f p 7 Y k q l M R M Z u U 5 J 7 c i s e n P x P 6 + b 2 b g W T r l K M 4 u K L R f F m S A 2 I f P 3 y Y B r Z F Z M H K F M c 3 c r Y S O q K b M u p K I L I V h 9 e Z 2 0 q p X A r w R 3 1 X K 9 l s d R g H O 4 g C s I 4 B r q c A s N a A I D B c / w C m + e 8 V 6 8 d + 9 j 2 b r h 5 T N n 8 A f e 5 w 8 q P J C J &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " q o m J p T a p + c 8 B D X V i 0 3 2 T m 3 G 3 S F k = " &gt; A A A B 8 X i c b V A 9 S w N B E J 3 z M 8 a v q K X N Y h C s w l 0 a U w Z s L C O Y D 0 z O s L e Z S 5 b s 7 h 2 7 e 0 I I + R c 2 F o r Y + m / s / D d u k i s 0 8 c H A 4 7 0 Z Z u Z F q e D G + v 6 3 t 7 G 5 t b 2 z W 9 g r 7 h 8 c H h 2 X T k 5 b J s k 0 w y Z L R K I 7 E T U o u M K m 5 V Z g J 9 V I Z S S w H Y 1 v 5 n 7 7 C b X h i b q 3 k x R D S Y e K x 5 x R 6 6 S H R j 9 4 7 K W a S + y X y n 7 F X 4 C s k y A n Z c j R 6 J e + e o O E Z R K V Z Y I a 0 w 3 8 1 I Z T q i 1 n A m f F X m Y w p W x M h 9 h 1 V F G J J p w u L p 6 R S 6 c M S J x o V 8 q S h f p 7 Y k q l M R M Z u U 5 J 7 c i s e n P x P 6 + b 2 b g W T r l K M 4 u K L R f F m S A 2 I f P 3 y Y B r Z F Z M H K F M c 3 c r Y S O q K b M u p K I L I V h 9 e Z 2 0 q p X A r w R 3 1 X K 9 l s d R g H O 4 g C s I 4 B r q c A s N a A I D B c / w C m + e 8 V 6 8 d + 9 j 2 b r h 5 T N n 8 A f e 5 w 8 q P J C J &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; P 0 1 &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " q o m J p T a p + c 8 B D X V i 0 3 2 T m 3 G 3 S F k = " &gt; A A A B 8 X i c b V A 9 S w N B E J 3 z M 8 a v q K X N Y h C s w l 0 a U w Z s L C O Y D 0 z O s L e Z S 5 b s 7 h 2 7 e 0 I I + R c 2 F o r Y + m / s / D d u k i s 0 8 c H A 4 7 0 Z Z u Z F q e D G + v 6 3 t 7 G 5 t b 2 z W 9 g r 7 h 8 c H h 2 X T k 5 b J s k 0 w y Z L R K I 7 E T U o u M K m 5 V Z g J 9 V I Z S S w H Y 1 v 5 n 7 7 C b X h i b q 3 k x R D S Y e K x 5 x R 6 6 S H R j 9 4 7 K W a S + y X y n 7 F X 4 C s k y A n Z c j R 6 J e + e o O E Z R K V Z Y I a 0 w 3 8 1 I Z T q i 1 n A m f F X m Y w p W x M h 9 h 1 V F G J J p w u L p 6 R S 6 c M S J x o V 8 q S h f p 7 Y k q l M R M Z u U 5 J 7 c i s e n P x P 6 + b 2 b g W T r l K M 4 u K L R f F m S A 2 I f P 3 y Y B r Z F Z M H K F M c 3 c r Y S O q K b M u p K I L I V h 9 e Z 2 0 q p X A r w R 3 1 X K 9 l s d R g H O 4 g C s I 4 B r q c A s N a A I D B c / w C m + e 8 V 6 8 d + 9 j 2 b r h 5 T N n 8 A f e 5 w 8 q P J C J &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " q o m J p T a p + c 8 B D X V i 0 3 2 T m 3 G 3 S F k = " &gt; A A A B 8 X i c b V A 9 S w N B E J 3 z M 8 a v q K X N Y h C s w l 0 a U w Z s L C O Y D 0 z O s L e Z S 5 b s 7 h 2 7 e 0 I I + R c 2 F o r Y + m / s / D d u k i s 0 8 c H A 4 7 0 Z Z u Z F q e D G + v 6 3 t 7 G 5 t b 2 z W 9 g r 7 h 8 c H h 2 X T k 5 b J s k 0 w y Z L R K I 7 E T U o u M K m 5 V Z g J 9 V I Z S S w H Y 1 v 5 n 7 7 C b X h i b q 3 k x R D S Y e K x 5 x R 6 6 S H R j 9 4 7 K W a S + y X y n 7 F X 4 C s k y A n Z c j R 6 J e + e o O E Z R K V Z Y I a 0 w 3 8 1 I Z T q i 1 n A m f F X m Y w p W x M h 9 h 1 V F G J J p w u L p 6 R S 6 c M S J x o V 8 q S h f p 7 Y k q l M R M Z u U 5 J 7 c i s e n P x P 6 + b 2 b g W T r l K M 4 u K L R f F m S A 2 I f P 3 y Y B r Z F Z M H K F M c 3 c r Y S O q K b M u p K I L I V h 9 e Z 2 0 q p X A r w R 3 1 X K 9 l s d R g H O 4 g C s I 4 B r q c A s N a A I D B c / w C m + e 8 V 6 8 d + 9 j 2 b r h 5 T N n 8 A f e 5 w 8 q P J C J &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; P 0 2 &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " k w f h V v Q A 4 T u a h 3 + k l S l x j n V R P R Q = " &gt; A A A B 8 X i c b V A 9 S w N B E J 3 z M 8 a v q K X N Y h C s w l 0 a U w Z s L C O Y D 0 z O s L e Z S 5 b s 7 h 2 7 e 0 I I + R c 2 F o r Y + m / s / D d u k i s 0 8 c H A 4 7 0 Z Z u Z F q e D G + v 6 3 t 7 G 5 t b 2 z W 9 g r 7 h 8 c H h 2 X T k 5 b J s k 0 w y Z L R K I 7 E T U o u M K m 5 V Z g J 9 V I Z S S w H Y 1 v 5 n 7 7 C b X h i b q 3 k x R D S Y e K x 5 x R 6 6 S H R r / 6 2 E s 1 l 9 g v l f 2 K v w B Z J 0 F O y p C j 0 S 9 9 9 Q Y J y y Q q y w Q 1 p h v 4 q Q 2 n V F v O B M 6 K v c x g S t m Y D r H r q K I S T T h d X D w j l 0 4 Z k D j R r p Q l C / X 3 x J R K Y y Y y c p 2 S 2 p F Z 9 e b i f 1 4 3 s 3 E t n H K V Z h Y V W y 6 K M 0 F s Q u b v k w H X y K y Y O E K Z 5 u 5 W w k Z U U 2 Z d S E U X Q r D 6 8 j p p V S u B X w n u q u V 6 L Y + j A O d w A V c Q w D X U 4 R Y a 0 A Q G C p 7 h F d 4 8 4 7 1 4 7 9 7 H s n X D y 2 f O 4 A + 8 z x 8 r x 5 C K &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " k w f h V v Q A 4 T u a h 3 + k l S l x j n V R P R Q = " &gt; A A A B 8 X i c b V A 9 S w N B E J 3 z M 8 a v q K X N Y h C s w l 0 a U w Z s L C O Y D 0 z O s L e Z S 5 b s 7 h 2 7 e 0 I I + R c 2 F o r Y + m / s / D d u k i s 0 8 c H A 4 7 0 Z Z u Z F q e D G + v 6 3 t 7 G 5 t b 2 z W 9 g r 7 h 8 c H h 2 X T k 5 b J s k 0 w y Z L R K I 7 E T U o u M K m 5 V Z g J 9 V I Z S S w H Y 1 v 5 n 7 7 C b X h i b q 3 k x R D S Y e K x 5 x R 6 6 S H R r / 6 2 E s 1 l 9 g v l f 2 K v w B Z J 0 F O y p C j 0 S 9 9 9 Q Y J y y Q q y w Q 1 p h v 4 q Q 2 n V F v O B M 6 K v c x g S t m Y D r H r q K I S T T h d X D w j l 0 4 Z k D j R r p Q l C / X 3 x J R K Y y Y y c p 2 S 2 p F Z 9 e b i f 1 4 3 s 3 E t n H K V Z h Y V W y 6 K M 0 F s Q u b v k w H X y K y Y O E K Z 5 u 5 W w k Z U U 2 Z d S E U X Q r D 6 8 j p p V S u B X w n u q u V 6 L Y + j A O d w A V c Q w D X U 4 R Y a 0 A Q G C p 7 h F d 4 8 4 7 1 4 7 9 7 H s n X D y 2 f O 4 A + 8 z x 8 r x 5 C K &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; P 0 2 &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " k w f h V v Q A 4 T u a h 3 + k l S l x j n V R P R Q = " &gt; A A A B 8 X i c b V A 9 S w N B E J 3 z M 8 a v q K X N Y h C s w l 0 a U w Z s L C O Y D 0 z O s L e Z S 5 b s 7 h 2 7 e 0 I I + R c 2 F o r Y + m / s / D d u k i s 0 8 c H A 4 7 0 Z Z u Z F q e D G + v 6 3 t 7 G 5 t b 2 z W 9 g r 7 h 8 c H h 2 X T k 5 b J s k 0 w y Z L R K I 7 E T U o u M K m 5 V Z g J 9 V I Z S S w H Y 1 v 5 n 7 7 C b X h i b q 3 k x R D S Y e K x 5 x R 6 6 S H R r / 6 2 E s 1 l 9 g v l f 2 K v w B Z J 0 F O y p C j 0 S 9 9 9 Q Y J y y Q q y w Q 1 p h v 4 q Q 2 n V F v O B M 6 K v c x g S t m Y D r H r q K I S T T h d X D w j l 0 4 Z k D j R r p Q l C / X 3 x J R K Y y Y y c p 2 S 2 p F Z 9 e b i f 1 4 3 s 3 E t n H K V Z h Y V W y 6 K M 0 F s Q u b v k w H X y K y Y O E K Z 5 u 5 W w k Z U U 2 Z d S E U X Q r D 6 8 j p p V S u B X w n u q u V 6 L Y + j A O d w A V c Q w D X U 4 R Y a 0 A Q G C p 7 h F d 4 8 4 7 1 4 7 9 7 H s n X D y 2 f O 4 A + 8 z x 8 r x 5 C K &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " k w f h V v Q A 4 T u a h 3 + k l S l x j n V R P R Q = " &gt; A A A B 8 X i c b V A 9 S w N B E J 3 z M 8 a v q K X N Y h C s w l 0 a U w Z s L C O Y D 0 z O s L e Z S 5 b s 7 h 2 7 e 0 I I + R c 2 F o r Y + m / s / D d u k i s 0 8 c H A 4 7 0 Z Z u Z F q e D G + v 6 3 t 7 G 5 t b 2 z W 9 g r 7 h 8 c H h 2 X T k 5 b J s k 0 w y Z L R K I 7 E T U o u M K m 5 V Z g J 9 V I Z S S w H Y 1 v 5 n 7 7 C b X h i b q 3 k x R D S Y e K x 5 x R 6 6 S H R r / 6 2 E s 1 l 9 g v l f 2 K v w B Z J 0 F O y p C j 0 S 9 9 9 Q Y J y y Q q y w Q 1 p h v 4 q Q 2 n V F v O B M 6 K v c x g S t m Y D r H r q K I S T T h d X D w j l 0 4 Z k D j R r p Q l C / X 3 x J R K Y y Y y c p 2 S 2 p F Z 9 e b i f 1 4 3 s 3 E t n H K V Z h Y V W y 6 K M 0 F s Q u b v k w H X y K y Y O E K Z 5 u 5 W w k Z U U 2 Z d S E U X Q r D 6 8 j p p V S u B X w n u q u V 6 L Y + j A O d w A V c Q w D X U 4 R Y a 0 A Q G C p 7 h F d 4 8 4 7 1 4 7 9 7 H s n X D y 2 f O 4 A + 8 z x 8 r x 5 C K &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; P 0 3 &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " i 5 4 L i a w V i a 4 b j I 1 q Y D J N x u n V U / s = " &gt; A A A B 8 X i c b V A 9 S w N B E J 2 L X z F + R S 1 t D o N g F e 5 i Y c q A j W U E 8 4 H J G f Y 2 c 8 m S 3 b 1 j d 0 8 I R / 6 F j Y U i t v 4 b O / + N m + Q K T X w w 8 H h v h p l 5 Y c K Z N p 7 3 7 R Q 2 N r e 2 d 4 q 7 p b 3 9 g 8 O j 8 v F J W 8 e p o t i i M Y 9 V N y Q a O Z P Y M s x w 7 C Y K i Q g 5 d s L J z d z v P K H S L J b 3 Z p p g I M h I s o h R Y q z 0 0 B x c P f Y T x Q Q O y h W v 6 i 3 g r h M / J x X I 0 R y U v / r D m K Y C p a G c a N 3 z v c Q E G V G G U Y 6 z U j / V m B A 6 I S P s W S q J Q B 1 k i 4 t n 7 o V V h m 4 U K 1 v S u A v 1 9 0 R G h N Z T E d p O Q c x Y r 3 p z 8 T + v l 5 q o H m R M J q l B S Z e L o p S 7 J n b n 7 7 t D p p A a P r W E U M X s r S 4 d E 0 W o s S G V b A j + 6 s v r p F 2 r + l 7 V v 6 t V G v U 8 j i K c w T l c g g / X 0 I B b a E I L K E h 4 h l d 4 c 7 T z 4 r w 7 H 8 v W g p P P n M I f O J 8 / L V K Q i w = = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " i 5 4 L i a w V i a 4 b j I 1 q Y D J N x u n V U / s = " &gt; A A A B 8 X i c b V A 9 S w N B E J 2 L X z F + R S 1 t D o N g F e 5 i Y c q A j W U E 8 4 H J G f Y 2 c 8 m S 3 b 1 j d 0 8 I R / 6 F j Y U i t v 4 b O / + N m + Q K T X w w 8 H h v h p l 5 Y c K Z N p 7 3 7 R Q 2 N r e 2 d 4 q 7 p b 3 9 g 8 O j 8 v F J W 8 e p o t i i M Y 9 V N y Q a O Z P Y M s x w 7 C Y K i Q g 5 d s L J z d z v P K H S L J b 3 Z p p g I M h I s o h R Y q z 0 0 B x c P f Y T x Q Q O y h W v 6 i 3 g r h M / J x X I 0 R y U v / r D m K Y C p a G c a N 3 z v c Q E G V G G U Y 6 z U j / V m B A 6 I S P s W S q J Q B 1 k i 4 t n 7 o V V h m 4 U K 1 v S u A v 1 9 0 R G h N Z T E d p O Q c x Y r 3 p z 8 T + v l 5 q o H m R M J q l B S Z e L o p S 7 J n b n 7 7 t D p p A a P r W E U M X s r S 4 d E 0 W o s S G V b A j + 6 s v r p F 2 r + l 7 V v 6 t V G v U 8 j i K c w T l c g g / X 0 I B b a E I L K E h 4 h l d 4 c 7 T z 4 r w 7 H 8 v W g p P P n M I f O J 8 / L V K Q i w = = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; P 0 3 &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " i 5 4 L i a w V i a 4 b j I 1 q Y D J N x u n V U / s = " &gt; A A A B 8 X i c b V A 9 S w N B E J 2 L X z F + R S 1 t D o N g F e 5 i Y c q A j W U E 8 4 H J G f Y 2 c 8 m S 3 b 1 j d 0 8 I R / 6 F j Y U i t v 4 b O / + N m + Q K T X w w 8 H h v h p l 5 Y c K Z N p 7 3 7 R Q 2 N r e 2 d 4 q 7 p b 3 9 g 8 O j 8 v F J W 8 e p o t i i M Y 9 V N y Q a O Z P Y M s x w 7 C Y K i Q g 5 d s L J z d z v P K H S L J b 3 Z p p g I M h I s o h R Y q z 0 0 B x c P f Y T x Q Q O y h W v 6 i 3 g r h M / J x X I 0 R y U v / r D m K Y C p a G c a N 3 z v c Q E G V G G U Y 6 z U j / V m B A 6 I S P s W S q J Q B 1 k i 4 t n 7 o V V h m 4 U K 1 v S u A v 1 9 0 R G h N Z T E d p O Q c x Y r 3 p z 8 T + v l 5 q o H m R M J q l B S Z e L o p S 7 J n b n 7 7 t D p p A a P r W E U M X s r S 4 d E 0 W o s S G V b A j + 6 s v r p F 2 r + l 7 V v 6 t V G v U 8 j i K c w T l c g g / X 0 I B b a E I L K E h 4 h l d 4 c 7 T z 4 r w 7 H 8 v W g p P P n M I f O J 8 / L V K Q i w = = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " i 5 4 L i a w V i a 4 b j I 1 q Y D J N x u n V U / s = " &gt; A A A B 8 X i c b V A 9 S w N B E J 2 L X z F + R S 1 t D o N g F e 5 i Y c q A j W U E 8 4 H J G f Y 2 c 8 m S 3 b 1 j d 0 8 I R / 6 F j Y U i t v 4 b O / + N m + Q K T X w w 8 H h v h p l 5 Y c K Z N p 7 3 7 R Q 2 N r e 2 d 4 q 7 p b 3 9 g 8 O j 8 v F J W 8 e p o t i i M Y 9 V N y Q a O Z P Y M s x w 7 C Y K i Q g 5 d s L J z d z v P K H S L J b 3 Z p p g I M h I s o h R Y q z 0 0 B x c P f Y T x Q Q O y h W v 6 i 3 g r h M / J x X I 0 R y U v / r D m K Y C p a G c a N 3 z v c Q E G V G G U Y 6 z U j / V m B A 6 I S P s W S q J Q B 1 k i 4 t n 7 o V V h m 4 U K 1 v S u A v 1 9 0 R G h N Z T E d p O Q c x Y r 3 p z 8 T + v l 5 q o H m R M J q l B S Z e L o p S 7 J n b n 7 7 t D p p A a P r W E U M X s r S 4 d E 0 W o s S G V b A j + 6 s v r p F 2 r + l 7 V v 6 t V G v U 8 j i K c w T l c g g / X 0 I B b a E I L K E h 4 h l d 4 c 7 T z 4 r w 7 H 8 v W g p P P n M I f O J 8 / L V K Q i w = = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt;</head><p>Original trace P Defended trace P 0 The white boxes are real traces while the grey boxes are glue traces (made with dummy packets). Glue traces remove time gaps between real traces to exploit the difficulty of the split decision and finding problems.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>&lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " K z h e F q + n N 6 V g s E J R 5 n P P / D i T 5 r 8 = " &gt; A A A B 7 3 i c b V D L S g N B E O z 1 G e M r 6 t H L Y B A 8 h d 0 g 6 D H g x W M E 8 4 B k D b O T 3 m T I z O w 6 M y u E k J / w 4 k E R r / 6 O N / / G S b I H T S x o K K q 6 6 e 6 K U s G N 9 f 1 v b 2 1 9 Y 3 N r u 7 B T 3 N 3 b P z g s H R 0 3 T Z J p h g 2 W i E S 3 I 2 p Q c I U N y 6 3 A d q q R y k h g K x r d z P z W E 2 r D E 3 V v x y m G k g 4 U j z m j 1 k n t + k M 3 1 V x i r 1 T 2 K / 4 c Z J U E O S l D j n q v 9 N X t J y y T q C w T 1 J h O 4 K c 2 n F B t O R M 4 L X Y z g y l l I z r A j q O K S j T h Z H 7 v l J w 7 p U / i R L t S l s z V 3 x M T K o 0 Z y 8 h 1 S m q H Z t m b i f 9 5 n c z G 1 + G E q z S z q N h i U Z w J Y h M y e 5 7 0 u U Z m x d g R y j R 3 t x I 2 p J o y 6 y I q u h C C 5 Z d X S b N a C f x K c F c t 1 y 7 z O A p w C m d w A Q F c Q Q 1 u o Q 4 N Y C D g G V 7 h z X v 0 X r x 3 7 2 P R u u b l M y f w B 9 7 n D / / V j + E = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " K z h e F q + n N 6 V g s E J R 5 n P P / D i T 5 r 8 = " &gt; A A A B 7 3 i c b V D L S g N B E O z 1 G e M r 6 t H L Y B A 8 h d 0 g 6 D H g x W M E 8 4 B k D b O T 3 m T I z O w 6 M y u E k J / w 4 k E R r / 6 O N / / G S b I H T S x o K K q 6 6 e 6 K U s G N 9 f 1 v b 2 1 9 Y 3 N r u 7 B T 3 N 3 b P z g s H R 0 3 T Z J p h g 2 W i E S 3 I 2 p Q c I U N y 6 3 A d q q R y k h g K x r d z P z W E 2 r D E 3 V v x y m G k g 4 U j z m j 1 k n t + k M 3 1 V x i r 1 T 2 K / 4 c Z J U E O S l D j n q v 9 N X t J y y T q C w T 1 J h O 4 K c 2 n F B t O R M 4 L X Y z g y l l I z r A j q O K S j T h Z H 7 v l J w 7 p U / i R L t S l s z V 3 x M T K o 0 Z y 8 h 1 S m q H Z t m b i f 9 5 n c z G 1 + G E q z S z q N h i U Z w J Y h M y e 5 7 0 u U Z m x d g R y j R 3 t x I 2 p J o y 6 y I q u h C C 5 Z d X S b N a C f x K c F c t 1 y 7 z O A p w C m d w A Q F c Q Q 1 u o Q 4 N Y C D g G V 7 h z X v 0 X r x 3 7 2 P R u u b l M y f w B 9 7 n D / / V j + E = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; P 0 &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " K z h e F q + n N 6 V g s E J R 5 n P P / D i T 5 r 8 = " &gt; A A A B 7 3 i c b V D L S g N B E O z 1 G e M r 6 t H L Y B A 8 h d 0 g 6 D H g x W M E 8 4 B k D b O T 3 m T I z O w 6 M y u E k J / w 4 k E R r / 6 O N / / G S b I H T S x o K K q 6 6 e 6 K U s G N 9 f 1 v b 2 1 9 Y 3 N r u 7 B T 3 N 3 b P z g s H R 0 3 T Z J p h g 2 W i E S 3 I 2 p Q c I U N y 6 3 A d q q R y k h g K x r d z P z W E 2 r D E 3 V v x y m G k g 4 U j z m j 1 k n t + k M 3 1 V x i r 1 T 2 K / 4 c Z J U E O S l D j n q v 9 N X t J y y T q C w T 1 J h O 4 K c 2 n F B t O R M 4 L X Y z g y l l I z r A j q O K S j T h Z H 7 v l J w 7 p U / i R L t S l s z V 3 x M T K o 0 Z y 8 h 1 S m q H Z t m b i f 9 5 n c z G 1 + G E q z S z q N h i U Z w J Y h M y e 5 7 0 u U Z m x d g R y j R 3 t x I 2 p J o y 6 y I q u h C C 5 Z d X S b N a C f x K c F c t 1 y 7 z O A p w C m d w A Q F c Q Q 1 u o Q 4 N Y C D g G V 7 h z X v 0 X r x 3 7 2 P R u u b l M y f w B 9 7 n D / / V j + E = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " K z h e F q + n N 6 V g s E J R 5 n P P / D i T 5 r 8 = " &gt; A A A B 7 3 i c b V D L S g N B E O z 1 G e M r 6 t H L Y B A 8 h d 0 g 6 D H g x W M E 8 4 B k D b O T 3 m T I z O w 6 M y u E k J / w 4 k E R r / 6 O N / / G S b I H T S x o K K q 6 6 e 6 K U s G N 9 f 1 v b 2 1 9 Y 3 N r u 7 B T 3 N 3 b P z g s H R 0 3 T Z J p h g 2 W i E S 3 I 2 p Q c I U N y 6 3 A d q q R y k h g K x r d z P z W E 2 r D E 3 V v x y m G k g 4 U j z m j 1 k n t + k M 3 1 V x i r 1 T 2 K / 4 c Z J U E O S l D j n q v 9 N X t J y y T q C w T 1 J h O 4 K c 2 n F B t O R M 4 L X Y z g y l l I z r A j q O K S j T h Z H 7 v l J w 7 p U / i R L t S l s z V 3 x M T K o 0 Z y 8 h 1 S m q H Z t m b i f 9 5 n c z G 1 + G E q z S z q N h i U Z w J Y h M y e 5 7 0 u U Z m x d g R y j R 3 t x I 2 p J o y 6 y I q u h C C 5 Z d X S b N a C f x K c F c t 1 y 7 z O A p w C m d w A Q F c Q Q 1 u o Q 4 N Y C D g G V 7 h z X v 0 X r x 3 7 2 P R u u b l M y f w B 9 7 n D / / V j + E = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; d 1 &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " t x h Z e O v u z Z M f 6 d k R i + a l O g h p 0 w 8 = " &gt; A A A B 6 n i c b V B N S 8 N A E J 3 U r 1 q / q h 6 9 L B b B U 0 l 6 s c e C F 4 8 V 7 Q e 0 o W w 2 m 3 b p Z h N 2 J 0 I J / Q l e P C j i 1 V / k z X / j t s 1 B W x 8 M P N 6 b Y W Z e k E p h 0 H W / n d L W 9 s 7 u X n m / c n B 4 d H x S P T 3 r m i T T j H d Y I h P d D 6 j h U i j e Q Y G S 9 1 P N a R x I 3 g u m t w u / 9 8 S 1 E Y l 6 x F n K / Z i O l Y g E o 2 i l h 3 D k j a o 1 t + 4 u Q T a J V 5 A a F G i P q l / D M G F Z z B U y S Y 0 Z e G 6 K f k 4 1 C i b 5 v D L M D E 8 p m 9 I x H 1 i q a M y N n y 9 P n Z M r q 4 Q k S r Q t h W S p / p 7 I a W z M L A 5 s Z 0 x x Y t a 9 h f i f N 8 g w a v q 5 U G m G X L H V o i i T B B O y + J u E Q n O G c m Y J Z V r Y W w m b U E 0 Z 2 n Q q N g R v / e V N 0 m 3 U P b f u 3 T d q r W Y R R x k u 4 B K u w Y M b a M E d t K E D D M b w D K / w 5 k j n x X l 3 P l a t J a e Y O Y c / c D 5 / A O m H j Y A = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " t x h Z e O v u z Z M f 6 d k R i + a l O g h p 0 w 8 = " &gt; A A A B 6 n i c b V B N S 8 N A E J 3 U r 1 q / q h 6 9 L B b B U 0 l 6 s c e C F 4 8 V 7 Q e 0 o W w 2 m 3 b p Z h N 2 J 0 I J / Q l e P C j i 1 V / k z X / j t s 1 B W x 8 M P N 6 b Y W Z e k E p h 0 H W / n d L W 9 s 7 u X n m / c n B 4 d H x S P T 3 r m i T T j H d Y I h P d D 6 j h U i j e Q Y G S 9 1 P N a R x I 3 g u m t w u / 9 8 S 1 E Y l 6 x F n K / Z i O l Y g E o 2 i l h 3 D k j a o 1 t + 4 u Q T a J V 5 A a F G i P q l / D M G F Z z B U y S Y 0 Z e G 6 K f k 4 1 C i b 5 v D L M D E 8 p m 9 I x H 1 i q a M y N n y 9 P n Z M r q 4 Q k S r Q t h W S p / p 7 I a W z M L A 5 s Z 0 x x Y t a 9 h f i f N 8 g w a v q 5 U G m G X L H V o i i T B B O y + J u E Q n O G c m Y J Z V r Y W w m b U E 0 Z 2 n Q q N g R v / e V N 0 m 3 U P b f u 3 T d q r W Y R R x k u 4 B K u w Y M b a M E d t K E D D M b w D K / w 5 k j n x X l 3 P l a t J a e Y O Y c / c D 5 / A O m H j Y A = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; d 1 &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " t x h Z e O v u z Z M f 6 d k R i + a l O g h p 0 w 8 = " &gt; A A A B 6 n i c b V B N S 8 N A E J 3 U r 1 q / q h 6 9 L B b B U 0 l 6 s c e C F 4 8 V 7 Q e 0 o W w 2 m 3 b p Z h N 2 J 0 I J / Q l e P C j i 1 V / k z X / j t s 1 B W x 8 M P N 6 b Y W Z e k E p h 0 H W / n d L W 9 s 7 u X n m / c n B 4 d H x S P T 3 r m i T T j H d Y I h P d D 6 j h U i j e Q Y G S 9 1 P N a R x I 3 g u m t w u / 9 8 S 1 E Y l 6 x F n K / Z i O l Y g E o 2 i l h 3 D k j a o 1 t + 4 u Q T a J V 5 A a F G i P q l / D M G F Z z B U y S Y 0 Z e G 6 K f k 4 1 C i b 5 v D L M D E 8 p m 9 I x H 1 i q a M y N n y 9 P n Z M r q 4 Q k S r Q t h W S p / p 7 I a W z M L A 5 s Z 0 x x Y t a 9 h f i f N 8 g w a v q 5 U G m G X L H V o i i T B B O y + J u E Q n O G c m Y J Z V r Y W w m b U E 0 Z 2 n Q q N g R v / e V N 0 m 3 U P b f u 3 T d q r W Y R R x k u 4 B K u w Y M b a M E d t K E D D M b w D K / w 5 k j n x X l 3 P l a t J a e Y O Y c / c D 5 / A O m H j Y A = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " t x h Z e O v u z Z M f 6 d k R i + a l O g h p 0 w 8 = " &gt; A A A B 6 n i c b V B N S 8 N A E J 3 U r 1 q / q h 6 9 L B b B U 0 l 6 s c e C F 4 8 V 7 Q e 0 o W w 2 m 3 b p Z h N 2 J 0 I J / Q l e P C j i 1 V / k z X / j t s 1 B W x 8 M P N 6 b Y W Z e k E p h 0 H W / n d L W 9 s 7 u X n m / c n B 4 d H x S P T 3 r m i T T j H d Y I h P d D 6 j h U i j e Q Y G S 9 1 P N a R x I 3 g u m t w u / 9 8 S 1 E Y l 6 x F n K / Z i O l Y g E o 2 i l h 3 D k j a o 1 t + 4 u Q T a J V 5 A a F G i P q l / D M G F Z z B U y S Y 0 Z e G 6 K f k 4 1 C i b 5 v D L M D E 8 p m 9 I x H 1 i q a M y N n y 9 P n Z M r q 4 Q k S r Q t h W S p / p 7 I a W z M L A 5 s Z 0 x x Y t a 9 h f i f N 8 g w a v q 5 U G m G X L H V o i i T B B O y + J u E Q n O G c m Y J Z V r Y W w m b U E 0 Z 2 n Q q N g R v / e V N 0 m 3 U P b f u 3 T d q r W Y R R x k u 4 B K u w Y M b a M E d t K E D D M b w D K / w 5 k j n x X l 3 P l a t J a e Y O Y c / c D 5 / A O m H j Y A = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; d 2 &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " 9 F e N 0 j u k u Y i W p m k E S 9 s g V s f E H e M = " &gt; A A A B 6 n i c b V B N S 8 N A E J 3 U r 1 q / q h 6 9 L B b B U 0 l 6 s c e C F 4 8 V 7 Q e 0 o W w 2 k 3 b p Z h N 2 N 0 I J / Q l e P C j i 1 V / k z X / j t s 1 B W x 8 M P N 6 b Y W Z e k A q u j e t + O 6 W t 7 Z 3 d v f J + 5 e D w 6 P i k e n r W 1 U m m G H Z Y I h L V D 6 h G w S V 2 D D c C + 6 l C G g c C e 8 H 0 d u H 3 n l B p n s h H M 0 v R j + l Y 8 o g z a q z 0 E I 4 a o 2 r N r b t L k E 3 i F a Q G B d q j 6 t c w T F g W o z R M U K 0 H n p s a P 6 f K c C Z w X h l m G l P K p n S M A 0 s l j V H 7 + f L U O b m y S k i i R N m S h i z V 3 x M 5 j b W e x Y H t j K m Z 6 H V v I f 7 n D T I T N f 2 c y z Q z K N l q U Z Q J Y h K y + J u E X C E z Y m Y J Z Y r b W w m b U E W Z s e l U b A j e + s u b p N u o e 2 7 d u 2 / U W s 0 i j j J c w C V c g w c 3 0 I I 7 a E M H G I z h G V 7 h z R H O i / P u f K x a S 0 4 x c w 5 / 4 H z + A O s L j Y E = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " 9 F e N 0 j u k u Y i W p m k E S 9 s g V s f E H e M = " &gt; A A A B 6 n i c b V B N S 8 N A E J 3 U r 1 q / q h 6 9 L B b B U 0 l 6 s c e C F 4 8 V 7 Q e 0 o W w 2 k 3 b p Z h N 2 N 0 I J / Q l e P C j i 1 V / k z X / j t s 1 B W x 8 M P N 6 b Y W Z e k A q u j e t + O 6 W t 7 Z 3 d v f J + 5 e D w 6 P i k e n r W 1 U m m G H Z Y I h L V D 6 h G w S V 2 D D c C + 6 l C G g c C e 8 H 0 d u H 3 n l B p n s h H M 0 v R j + l Y 8 o g z a q z 0 E I 4 a o 2 r N r b t L k E 3 i F a Q G B d q j 6 t c w T F g W o z R M U K 0 H n p s a P 6 f K c C Z w X h l m G l P K p n S M A 0 s l j V H 7 + f L U O b m y S k i i R N m S h i z V 3 x M 5 j b W e x Y H t j K m Z 6 H V v I f 7 n D T I T N f 2 c y z Q z K N l q U Z Q J Y h K y + J u E X C E z Y m Y J Z Y r b W w m b U E W Z s e l U b A j e + s u b p N u o e 2 7 d u 2 / U W s 0 i j j J c w C V c g w c 3 0 I I 7 a E M H G I z h G V 7 h z R H O i / P u f K x a S 0 4 x c w 5 / 4 H z + A O s L j Y E = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; d 2 &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " 9 F e N 0 j u k u Y i W p m k E S 9 s g V s f E H e M = " &gt; A A A B 6 n i c b V B N S 8 N A E J 3 U r 1 q / q h 6 9 L B b B U 0 l 6 s c e C F 4 8 V 7 Q e 0 o W w 2 k 3 b p Z h N 2 N 0 I J / Q l e P C j i 1 V / k z X / j t s 1 B W x 8 M P N 6 b Y W Z e k A q u j e t + O 6 W t 7 Z 3 d v f J + 5 e D w 6 P i k e n r W 1 U m m G H Z Y I h L V D 6 h G w S V 2 D D c C + 6 l C G g c C e 8 H 0 d u H 3 n l B p n s h H M 0 v R j + l Y 8 o g z a q z 0 E I 4 a o 2 r N r b t L k E 3 i F a Q G B d q j 6 t c w T F g W o z R M U K 0 H n p s a P 6 f K c C Z w X h l m G l P K p n S M A 0 s l j V H 7 + f L U O b m y S k i i R N m S h i z V 3 x M 5 j b W e x Y H t j K m Z 6 H V v I f 7 n D T I T N f 2 c y z Q z K N l q U Z Q J Y h K y + J u E X C E z Y m Y J Z Y r b W w m b U E W Z s e l U b A j e + s u b p N u o e 2 7 d u 2 / U W s 0 i j j J c w C V c g w c 3 0 I I 7 a E M H G I z h G V 7 h z R H O i / P u f K x a S 0 4 x c w 5 / 4 H z + A O s L j Y E = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " 9 F e N 0 j u k u Y i W p m k E S 9 s g V s f E H e M = " &gt; A A A B 6 n i c b V B N S 8 N A E J 3 U r 1 q / q h 6 9 L B b B U 0 l 6 s c e C F 4 8 V 7 Q e 0 o W w 2 k 3 b p Z h N 2 N 0 I J / Q l e P C j i 1 V / k z X / j t s 1 B W x 8 M P N 6 b Y W Z e k A q u j e t + O 6 W t 7 Z 3 d v f J + 5 e D w 6 P i k e n r W 1 U m m G H Z Y I h L V D 6 h G w S V 2 D D c C + 6 l C G g c C e 8 H 0 d u H 3 n l B p n s h H M 0 v R j + l Y 8 o g z a q z 0 E I 4 a o 2 r N r b t L k E 3 i F a Q G B d q j 6 t c w T F g W o z R M U K 0 H n p s a P 6 f K c C Z w X h l m G l P K p n S M A 0 s l j V H 7 + f L U O b m y S k i i R N m S h i z V 3 x M 5 j b W e x Y H t j K m Z 6 H V v I f 7 n D T I T N f 2 c y z Q z K N l q U Z Q J Y h K y + J u E X C E z Y m Y J Z Y r b W w m b U E W Z s e l U b A j e + s u b p N u o e 2 7 d u 2 / U W s 0 i j j J c w C V c g w c 3 0 I I 7 a E M H G I z h G V 7 h z R H O i / P u f K x a S 0 4 x c w 5 / 4 H z + A O s L j Y E = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt;</head><p>Note that glue traces contain no real data, only timestamps of when dummy packets are sent and received. Therefore, we do not expect the traces to cause much extra data overhead. We estimate the data overhead for distributing glue traces as follows. On average a trace has 4441 packets in our dataset. Therefore, the average web page size is 2.3 MB. Suppose a timestamp takes up 2 bytes, then one glue trace takes up 4441 × 2 = 0.008 MB. Hence, on client side, the data overhead in the long run will be 0.008/2.3 ≈ 0.003 if the number of glue traces downloaded is the same as the number of web pages visited; and it will be 0.03 if the client downloads 10 times more glue traces than actually needed ones.</p><p>On the directory server side, we estimate the distribution cost as follows. Taking statistics from November 2018 to November 2019 1 , we found that the average bandwidth spent on answering directory requests is 172 MB/s and the average number of Tor users is 2.1 million per day. If the average user downloads 200 glue traces per day, the average bandwidth for distributing glue traces is about 39 MB/s. Therefore, the directory server is expected to have about 39/172 ≈ 23% data overhead. To obfuscate user activity, we can require users to download a randomized number of glue traces regularly even if they do not need to, using padding to hide the number of glue traces downloaded from an eavesdropper.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.4">Solving Split Decision and Split Finding</head><p>To break down an -trace, the attacker pursues the following strategy: determine (split decision problem) and then find − 1 points to split the -trace (split finding problem). To the best of our knowledge, there is no prior work on split decision, and only two studies looking into split finding for 2-traces. Wang and Goldberg <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[26]</ref> put forward a split finding algorithm using kNN with a score system. Xu et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[29]</ref> suggested using XGBoost to output the outgoing packet with the highest probability to be the split. They show that their algorithm could achieve better performance than kNN. Neither work considers -traces for ≥ 3.</p><p>Since GLUE relies on these problems being difficult, we want to make a sincere best effort at solving both problems for general so that future work will not be likely to break 1 https://metrics.torproject.org/ GLUE. To do so, we put forward a new framework: CoarseDecided Score-Based (CDSB). CDSB performs better than both previous algorithms for any general .</p><p>Split decision We use a Random Forest classifier with 511 features extracted by expert knowledge to decide how many splits there are. Intuitively, the more webpages we visit, the longer an -trace's transmission time will be. Since splits are time-sensitive, we include rich time information in our feature set. We also exploit volume information such as the number of packets and the number of outgoing packets in our feature set. Refer to Appendix B for a detailed feature list.</p><p>Split finding We extend Xu et al.'s XGBoost to score each outgoing packet in the trace; a higher-scoring packet is more likely to be the true split. However, the algorithm does not simply choose all the highest-scoring packets. Because usually all the packets around a true split score highly, but only one of them is the true split. If we chose all of them, we would have many false positives. Instead, we choose the highest-scoring packet as a split in each round, and we eliminate nearby packets from consideration as splits for future rounds. By this score decoding processing, we generate predicted splits. We put the pseudocode in Appendix C.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Evaluation of GLUE</head><p>In this section, we evaluate the performance of GLUE. We first present the experimental setup. GLUE creates -traces, but the exact value of is determined by client behavior; therefore, we evaluate GLUE on a range of values of , from 2 to 16. Finally, we investigate the overhead of GLUE, which is dependent on how long clients dwell on webpages.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.1">Experimental Setup</head><p>We use DS-19 to evaluate GLUE. We divide it into three parts: ATTACKTRAIN (9000 instances), SPLITTRAIN (2000 instances) and EVALUATION (9000 instances). We use AT-TACKTRAIN to generate training data for WF attacks and split decision; SPLITTRAIN to generate training data for split finding; and EVALUATION to generate test data.</p><p>Due to its novelty, GLUE requires a new methodology to evaluate. The split decision problem is entirely unexplored, and although we make a good-faith attempt to solve it, we want to show that GLUE is still effective even if the attacker "cheats" by being given directly. While -traces are much harder to classify for large , the exact value of is dependent on user behavior. We want to show GLUE is powerful even for the minimal = 2. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2</ref> The split finding problem has been explored more and GLUE relies on its difficulty. Therefore, our evaluation is divided into two cases:</p><p>• -traces without split decision. We evaluate for ∈ <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16]</ref>, and the attacker is told the value of .</p><p>• -traces with split decision. We evaluate for ∈ <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16]</ref>, and the attacker must find .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.2">-traces without Split Decision</head><p>We start with an investigation of -traces without split decision: the client visits pages with a moderately short dwell time between them. We tell the attacker what is, allowing the attacker to cheat by skipping the split decision problem. We use a lightweight setting for FRONT noise (N s = N c = 1100). We sample d max , the maximum duration of glue traces, from U(10 s, 15 s). We assume the client's dwell time between webpages is a uniform distribution between 1 s and 10 s. The client visits ten times more nonmonitored webpages than monitored webpages. We randomly generate 4000 split points and 4000 nonsplit points from SPLITTRAIN as split training data. We randomly generate 9900// -traces for ∈ <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16]</ref> from EVAL-UATION as test data so that we have 900 monitored webpages and 9000 non-monitored webpages in each test dataset.</p><p>The attacker will find −1 split points, split a -trace into singleton traces, and use a standard WF attack on each trace. Alternatively, the attacker could also find 2( − 1) splits and discard all packets between all odd and even splits, thus removing glue traces; however, we found that this strategy performs extremely poorly since it forces the attacker to find more traces accurately, so we do not present this strategy. Note that since the first singleton trace has some FRONT noise, the attacker should train two WF models: one "noisy model" trained on traces with FRONT noise to classify the first singleton trace; the other "clean model" trained without FRONT noise to classify the other singleton traces. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_13">Figure 10</ref> shows the performance of WF attacks after implementing GLUE. Increasing decreases both TPR and precision. In terms of TPR, DF performs the best at first (54% TPR at = 2), but when more and more traces are glued together, it weakens quickly. When = 16, all attacks achieve less than 5% TPR. We can see that despite being told and using our improved split finding procedure, the best WF attacks still cannot defeat GLUE.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.3">-traces with Split Decision</head><p>In this experiment we tackle a more realistic scenario: the attacker does not know how many splits are in an -trace and thus needs to do split decision first. The client and the datasets are the same as in Section 7.2. We also generate 9000 -traces for ∈ <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16]</ref> using ATTACKTRAIN to train for the split decision problem.</p><p>To evaluate the performance of WF attacks correctly, if the attacker guesses more than times for an -trace (due to incorrect split decision), we discard all the extra guesses and use only the first guesses. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_14">Figure 11</ref> shows the results. We can see that with split decision, WF attacks perform even worse, and their performance decreases more drastically with larger . When increases to 16, all WF attacks have less than 1% precision.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.4">Undefended -traces</head><p>To show how attackers' performance are degraded by GLUE, we also test attack performance on the undefended dataset. We find that the best WF attack is kFP and it achieves 96% TPR at = 2 down to 82% TPR at = 16. It achieves 97% precision at = 2 and 82% at = 16. Split finding procedure has nearly no effect on kFP when is small and only a slight effect when is large. This is due to the high accuracy (&gt; 92%) of our split finding algorithm. Even if split decision is required, kFP still achieves 45%-75% TPR and 41%-77% precision. We put the detailed experiment results in Appendix E.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.5">Analysis of Data Overhead</head><p>GLUE's data overhead consists of three parts: O F incurred by FRONT noise, O G incurred by glue traces except the last one and O L incurred by the tail, i.e. the last glue trace. To estimate GLUE's data overhead, let the mean time taken to load a webpage be d P . We take the average over user dwell times that are short enough to be glued, and denote it as d G . The mean time of the tail is d L &gt; d G . (d L is the mean of the distribution from which we sample d max .) For simplicity, we can assume that real and glue traffic have the same uniform packet rate b. Then,</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">O(GLUE) = O F + O G + O L = 1 bd P N s + N c + 2 2 + ( − 1)bd G + bd L = N s + N c + 2 2bd P FRONT noise + ( − 1)d G d P Glue trace + d L d P Tail .</formula><p>We can see that the O(GLUE) increases with users' dwell time and the duration of the tail while it decreases with , the number of pages glued together. Note that we only add FRONT noise for the first trace and the cost for that is shared by all the traces in an -trace, thus O F is inversely proportion to . This is also the case for O L . Since has little impact on O G when it is large, we can reduce GLUE's data overhead with a large . With N s = 1100, N c = 1100, the FRONT noise in our dataset has a mean of 24%. We also calculate the mean time    We apply these settings to our real datasets and show the results in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 12</ref>. The data overhead is 3% to 13% for strict GLUE, 22% to 44% for the normal GLUE, and 35% to 53% for lenient GLUE. The actual value within this range is dependent on , where larger reduces the overhead; we cannot determine because it depends entirely on client behavior. The values we found in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 12</ref> are about 5-10% lower than equation (1) because most glue traces have uneven bandwidth density in reality.</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">O(GLUE) = 0.24 + − 1 27.30 · d G + 1 27.30 · d L .<label>(</label></formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.6">Impact of FRONT Noise</head><p>In our defense design, we introduced some FRONT noise in the beginning. We evaluate FRONT noise separately here to show how it helps GLUE.</p><p>We use the same experiment setting as in Section 7.2 (WF attack on 2-traces to 16-traces without split decision), except that this time we do not add FRONT noise. We calculate TPR for only the first traces of -traces, and plot the results in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 13</ref>. Where there is no FRONT noise, all attacks could achieve 40%-80% TPR on the first traces; with little FRONT noise added, their TPR drops to 20%-60%.</p><p>Our observation is consistent with our discussion in Section 4. Even if the split for the first webpage is wrongly determined, the front portion is clean, leaking useful information to the attacker. Thus, it is necessary to protect the trace front.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8">Conclusion and Future Work</head><p>In this paper, we present two novel zero-delay lightweight defenses that are effective against the best WF attacks and easy to deploy on anonymity networks like Tor.</p><p>The first defense, FRONT, utilizes highly random noise to obfuscate traces. Instead of spreading dummy packets evenly, it focuses on obfuscating trace fronts. We also randomly sample the number of dummy packets and the packet padding window to ensure trace-to-trace randomness. With similar data overhead, it beats the best known lightweight defense, WTF-PAD, using a much simpler scheme.</p><p>We tested FRONT on two datasets collected five years apart, and on subsets defined by page sizes, and found that FRONT's performance was generally not sensitive to either condition except that it performed worse on very large web pages. It could be true, however, that FRONT's performance may be affected if the client has poor network conditions (such that their own network serves as a bottleneck compared to Tor). We did not explore this situation; making FRONT automatically self-adjusting to poor network conditions is a potential future direction in this work.</p><p>The second defense, GLUE, forces WF attacks to confront two difficult problems, split decision and split finding, by gluing singleton traces into -traces. At large enough , GLUE can even outperform heavyweight defenses like Tamaraw. The overhead of GLUE varies, in the range of 3%-53%, depending on client behavior.</p><p>A web-browsing client is able to enlarge by simply increasing the maximum padding time. In fact, with a large enough maximum padding time, the client can consecutively visit webpages non-stop, and all the current best attacks will fail completely. Alternatively, we could implement a timer in the browser UI to remind the client not to dwell too long on a webpage: particularly privacy-sensitive clients could benefit from such a feature.</p><p>We propose that Tor's directory servers should maintain large databases of glue traces, and clients should load glue traces from them when necessary. We think it is a feasible scheme by showing that the extra distribution cost is quite low. It is worth investigating whether the client can generate glue traces "on the fly" that look like real web page traffic to eliminate this extra overhead and to ensure that the attacker cannot see the same traces as the client.</p><p>In this paper, we allow the attacker to know the entire database of glue traces. There are several reasons our attacker currently cannot pursue a strategy of simply identifying glue traces in the client's traffic. First, congestion and latency will perturb the glue trace, so that its instructions on when to send packets will not be exactly realized in the network trace, thwarting a simple matching attack. Second, glue traces are expected to be stopped prematurely by the client. Third, glue traces look like real web page loads, and the directory servers should maintain a large database of them; in other words, glue traces would look like real web page visits. As we cannot prove the impossibility of identifying glue traces in traffic, we leave the question open as future work; better counter-measures against it (such as limiting the attacker's knowledge of glue traces) are also possible.</p><p>Some other defenses can promise a certain level of guaranteed success against any WF attack, even future ones: among the practically deployable ones, Tamaraw has the lowest overhead, though it delays packets by 78% and almost doubles the bandwidth consumed. Considering the seemingly unavoidable overhead required, we did not design our defenses to guarantee future success. For example, we cannot prove that split decision and split finding are unsolvable, difficult as they are even with our improved CDSB. Many other practical defenses also cannot guarantee future success, including WTF-PAD and Tor Browser's randomized pipelining (which has recently been disabled). It remains to be seen whether future developments in the theory of traffic analysis can show what degree of guaranteed success FRONT and GLUE can achieve.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A How to Set FRONT Parameters</head><p>There are four main parameters in FRONT, namely, N c , N s , W min and W max . Obviously, N c + N s determines the data overhead. It is worth considering how to set the ratio between them two, given a fixed data overhead. We also investigate how to set W min and W max in the following.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A.1 Impact of Padding Budget Ratio</head><p>We want to investigate the optimal ratio between N c and N s given a fixed total data overhead. We define a padding budget ratio α = N c / <ref type="figure">(N c + N s )</ref>, which is the proportion of total padding used by the client. We set W min = 1 s,W max = 14 s, and N s + N c = 5000 based on FT-2. This results in a data overhead of 49%. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 14</ref> shows attack performances with different α. In the figure, each line represents an attack. Each attack's performance has an inflection point as we increase α; we mark the optimal α using a black dot, i.e. the value at which each attack is least effective.</p><p>The upper figure shows how TPR changes for the three attacks based on α. The TPR achieved by each attack greatly decreases under FRONT, especially for kNN and CUMUL.    </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A.2 Set the Padding Window Parameters</head><p>In our design, the padding windows for both client and server are sampled from U(W min ,W max ). We introduce W min to ensure that the real padding window is not too small to satisfy the network bandwidth. So how do we set W max ? Intuitively, with a larger W max , the range of possible padding window size is larger, resulting in more randomness. However, this may also cause a "long tail" of Rayleigh distribution -more dummy packets are scheduled to the end of the trace or even dropped due to FRONT design. This may reduce the security level of FRONT, especially for small webpages. We did two experiments to validate this.</p><p>Enlarge W min and W max In this experiment, we try to investigate the impact of enlarging padding window size. We set N s = N c = 2500 based on FT-2. Varying t from 1 s to 11 s, we set W min = t and W max = 13 + t. This means that we are enlarging the expected window size under the same randomness since the maximum change of sampled padding window size is always within W max − W min = 13 s. We use kFP as the attacker since it consistently achieves the best performance against FRONT, as is shown in Section 5. We show TPR on the full dataset as well as on small webpages whose mean loading time is less than 20 s. The small webpages account for 16% in our dataset and the mean loading time on the whole dataset is 27 s. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 15</ref> shows the result. Both lines keep increasing when the expected window size is enlarged. This again validates our intuition that it is better to <ref type="table">Table 5</ref>: Feature set of split decision.</p><p>No.</p><p>Feature <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">description  1  Transmission size  2  Transmission time  3</ref> Number of outgoing packets 4-5</p><p>Mean, std of inter-arrival times 6-105</p><p>Top 100 inter-arrival times 106-107 Mean, std of top 100 inter-arrival times <ref type="bibr">[108]</ref><ref type="bibr">[109]</ref><ref type="bibr">[110]</ref><ref type="bibr">[111]</ref> 25, 50, 75 and 100 percentile of top 100 inter-arrival times have more packet padded in the trace front as well as avoid packet dropping in the trace end.</p><p>Enlarge W max only In the second experiment, we try to find out how to set W max after we decide W min . We fix W min = 1 s but vary W max from 14 s to 36 s. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_21">Figure 16</ref> shows the result. On the full dataset, TPR decreases from 45% to 33% at 15 s and then bounce back to 40%. However, TPR on small webpages keeps increasing from 8% to 30%. This indicates that for small webpages, most dummy packets are left unused in the end since their timestamps are too large, resulting in the increase in TPR. As for other webpages, the randomness accounts for the decrease first while the drop of dummy packets dominates the randomness after W max &gt; 15 s, leading to the increase in TPR. To conclude, we should set W max reasonably large to achieve good randomness. But we can not make W max too large to avoid dropped dummy packets. For simplicity of our design, we set a global W max for all webpages. (Therefore, we set W max = 14 s in our experiments.) But if we are allowed to have some information about webpages, it will be better to have a dynamic W max .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B Split Decision Features</head><p>Features used in split decision. Feature 1 and 3 are volume information while the others are time information of a trace. The first 3 features help us determine how many webpages in an -trace by the length of the trace. Feature 4-111 extract information from large gaps in an -trace. They help determine how many splits are in the trace.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>C Score Decoding Algorithm</head><p>Algorithm 1 shows the pseudocode of score decoding process. The inputs are scores for all outgoing packets, the number of splits to be found and a parameter neighborhood r. We find one split in each round by picking out the highest score while masking all outgoing packets in the "neighborhood". In other words, neighbor packets will not be considered in the following rounds. We set r = 40 in our experiments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Algorithm 1 Score Decoding</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Input:</head><p>A list containing each outgoing packet's location and score; A parameter: Neighborhood r;</p><p>The number of splits n; Output:</p><p>Set of predicted splits L; 1: L ← {}; 2: for i = 1 to n do 3:</p><p>Find the packet p with highest score and add it into L;</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>4:</head><p>Set p.score ← −∞;</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>5:</head><p>for every other packet q do <ref type="bibr">6:</ref> if |q.loc − p.loc| &lt; r then </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>D Information Leakage Analysis Result</head><p>In Section 5.3, we show the ECDF of information leakage. Here we present the detailed result of information leakage analysis. We estimate information leakage for 3043 features on both undefended and defended traces. These features are grouped into 14 different categories and they have covered all the features WF attacks use in the literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref>. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_23">Figure  17</ref> shows the information leakage for each feature on our datasets in the open-world scenario.</p><p>FRONT results in less information leakage in most of the categories compared to WTF-PAD, especially for features like Pkt. Count, Time, NGRAM, Pkt. Distribution and CU-MUL. WTF-PAD outperforms FRONT in category Interval-I, II and III. This result makes sense since WTF-PAD is based on obfuscating time features while FRONT focuses mainly on obfuscating volume features as well as bringing in more randomness.</p><p>E Evaluation on Undefended -traces <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">Figure 18</ref> and 19 shows the attack TPR and precision on undefended -traces, without and with split decision, respectively. When is known (i.e., without split decision), all attacks achieve similar TPR under all the values. But precision varies. kFP has the highest precision all four attacks all the time, ranging from 82% to 97%. When is unknown (i.e., with split decision), TPR and precision of all attacks except kNN drop by 20-30%, but still share the same trend as when without split decision. kNN's performance is greatly affected by split decision when ≥ 9.   </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: PDF of Rayleigh Distribution.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: ECDF of information leakage on different datasets. The 100th percentile points are marked.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Change in performance of WF attacks when all dummy packets are delayed by 1 to 10 seconds.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5: TPR and data overhead while varying β to change the lower bound of padding budget.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 6 :Figure 7 :</head><label>67</label><figDesc>Figure 6: TPR while varying β to change the lower bound of padding window size. Data overhead remains constant.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Figure 8 :</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Figure 8: Client's state machine. Starting from Front Mode, it will switch between Glue Mode and Back Mode until dwell time becomes too long. "Glue traces" are padded in Glue Mode. The client keeps sampling inter-arrival times in both Front and Back Mode.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head>Figure 9 :</head><label>9</label><figDesc>Figure 9: A toy example of what traffic looks like with GLUE. The white boxes are real traces while the grey boxes are glue traces (made with dummy packets). Glue traces remove time gaps between real traces to exploit the difficulty of the split decision and finding problems.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head>Figure 10 :</head><label>10</label><figDesc>Figure 10: WF attack performance without split decision against GLUE on -traces.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_14"><head>Figure 11 :</head><label>11</label><figDesc>Figure 11: WF attack performance with split decision against GLUE on -traces.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_15"><head>Figure 12 :</head><label>12</label><figDesc>Figure 12: Data overhead with respect to different , d G and d L . Data overhead increases when d G and d L are larger.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_16"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>1) We use three different settings to represent different client behaviors: d G = 2.5 s, d L = 5 s as a strict version of GLUE, d G = 5.5 s, d L = 12.5 s as normal GLUE and d G = 10 s, d L = 20 s as lenient GLUE.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_17"><head>Figure 13 :</head><label>13</label><figDesc>Figure 13: TPR on classifying the first page of -traces before and after adding FRONT noise. We use broken lines to show the result with no FRONT noise and full lines with FRONT noise.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_18"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>We found that the optimal α values are 0.32, 0.32, 0.5 and 0.24 in terms of TPR for the three attacks. The lower fig- ure shows the change of precision. Precision curves exhibit greater fluctuation. The optimal α values are still around 0.5 except for kFP. Combining these results, we find that the op- timal α is around 0.25-0.5. This suggests that we should set N s to be equal to or a bit smaller than N c .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_19"><head>Figure 14 :</head><label>14</label><figDesc>Figure 14: Three WF attacks' performances with different α. The upper figure shows attack results in terms of their TPR. The lower figure shows precision. We point out the optimal ratio for our defense using a black dot in each subfigure.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_20"><head>Figure 15 :</head><label>15</label><figDesc>Figure 15: TPR of kFP with different t. The full line shows TPR on the full dataset while the dotted line shows TPR on small webpages with mean loading time less than 20 s.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_21"><head>Figure 16 :</head><label>16</label><figDesc>Figure 16: TPR of kFP with different W max . The full line shows TPR on the full dataset while the dotted line shows TPR on small webpages with loading time less than 20 s.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_23"><head>Figure 17 :</head><label>17</label><figDesc>Figure 17: Information leakage for individual features.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_24"><head>Figure 18 :</head><label>18</label><figDesc>Figure 18: WF attack performance without split decision on clean -traces.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_25"><head>Figure 19 :</head><label>19</label><figDesc>Figure 19: WF attack performance with split decision on clean -traces.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="true"><head>Table 1 : Comparison of known WF defenses. For overhead, Low is a non-zero overhead up to 35%, Medium is roughly 35-70%, High is roughly 70-100%, and Very High is above 100%.</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Category 
Defense 
Latency overhead Data overhead Requires additional infrastructure Defeated by known attacks 

Obfuscation 

Traffic morphing [28] 
None 
Low 
None 
Yes 
HTTPOS [14] 
None 
Low 
None 
Yes 
WTF-PAD [11] 
None 
Low 
None 
Yes 
FRONT (this work) 
None 
Low 
None 
No 

Confusion 

Decoy [17] 
None 
High 
None 
No 
Walkie-talkie [27] 
Medium 
Low 
Knowledge of pages, half-duplex 
No 
Supersequence [24] 
High 
Very High 
Knowledge of pages 
No 

Regularization 

BuFLO [6] 
Very High 
Very High 
Fixed-rate network transfer 
No 
CS-BuFLO [2] 
Very High 
Very High 
Fixed-rate network transfer 
No 
Tamaraw [3] 
High 
High 
Fixed-rate network transfer 
No 
GLUE (this work) 
None 
Low 
None 
No 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="true"><head>Table 2 : Defense parameters and variables in FRONT. De- fense parameters set the overhead and behavior of FRONT, while trace variables are drawn from corresponding defense parameters for each trace separately to ensure trace-to-trace randomness.</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Notation 
Parameter 

Parameters 

N c 
Client's padding budget 
N s 
Proxy's padding budget 
W min 
Minimum padding time 
W max 
Maximum padding time 

Variables 

n c ← ¯ 
U(1, N c ) 
Number of outgoing dummy packets 
n s ← ¯ 
U(1, N s ) 
Number of incoming dummy packets 
w c ← U(W min ,W max ) 
Client's padding window 
w s ← U(W min ,W max ) 
Proxy's padding window 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="true"><head>Table 3 : Defense settings and corresponding overheads.</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Defense 
Parameters 
Overhead (%) 
Latency 
Data 
No defense 
-
0 
0 
Tamaraw [3] 
ρ out = 0.04, ρ in = 0.012, L = 50 
78.43 
162.93 
WTF-PAD [11] 
Normal rcv 
0 
32.71 
FT-1 
N s = N c = 1700,W min = 1 s,W max = 14 s 
0 
33.01 
FT-2 
N s = N c = 2500,W min = 1 s,W max = 14 s 
0 
48.80 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="true"><head>Table 4 : Defense performances on DS-19. A lower F 1 score represents a better defense.</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Defense 
TPR (%) 
Precision (%) 
F 1 
kNN CUMUL 
kFP 
DF 
kNN CUMUL 
kFP 
DF 
kNN CUMUL 
kFP 
DF 
No defense 
89.09 
94.44 
91.85 96.40 83.18 
64.22 
94.38 91.12 
0.86 
0.76 
0.93 0.94 
Tamaraw [3] 
3.41 
3.85 
2.08 
0.58 
2.33 
8.13 
23.16 6.78 
0.028 
0.052 
0.038 0.11 
WTF-PAD [11] 
9.35 
55.55 
52.97 81.99 51.52 
18.53 
70.69 60.92 
0.16 
0.28 
0.61 0.70 
FT-1 (This work) 2.56 
36.08 
43.03 70.82 41.22 
11.97 
71.19 34.88 0.048 
0.18 
0.54 0.47 
FT-2 (This work) 0.83 
26.19 
34.31 58.95 37.22 
8.52 
68.33 30.59 0.016 
0.13 
0.46 0.40 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> For = 1, GLUE simply reduces to FRONT with some extra dummy packets at the end.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This work was partly funded by the Hong Kong Research Grants Council ECS Project Number 26203218.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Availability</head><p>We publish the simulation code used in this paper, including WF attacks we used and WF defenses we propose and evaluate in this paper. We also provide code used in split decision and finding. All the code and datasets are available via https://github.com/websitefingerprinting/ WebsiteFingerprinting/</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fingerprinting Attack on Tor Anonymity Using Deep Learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Abe</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Goto</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Asia-Pacific Advanced Network</title>
		<meeting>the Asia-Pacific Advanced Network</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Congestion Sensitive Website Fingerprinting Defense</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cai</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Nithyanand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Johnson</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Cs-Buflo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 13th Workshop on Privacy in the Electronic Society</title>
		<meeting>the 13th Workshop on Privacy in the Electronic Society</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Systematic Approach to Developing and Evaluating Website Fingerprinting Defenses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cai</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Nithyanand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>And Gold-Berg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 21st ACM SIGSAC Conference on Computer and Communications Security</title>
		<meeting>the 21st ACM SIGSAC Conference on Computer and Communications Security</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Touching from a Distance: Website Fingerprinting Attacks and Defenses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cai</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Joshi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Johnson</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 19th ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security</title>
		<meeting>the 19th ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cherubin</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Bayes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">not Naive: Security Bounds on Website Fingerprinting Defenses. Proceedings on Privacy Enhancing Technologies</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Peek-a-boo, I Still See You: Why Efficient Traffic Analysis Countermeasures Fail</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dyer</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Coull</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Ristenpart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shrimpton</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">33rd IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">k-fingerprinting: A Robust Scalable Website Fingerprinting Technique</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hayes</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Danezis</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">USENIX Security Symposium</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Website Fingerprinting: Attacking Popular Privacy Enhancing Technologies with the Multinomial Na¨ıveNa¨ıve-Bayes Classifier</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Herrmann</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Wendolsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Federrath</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 16th ACM Workshop on Cloud Computing Security</title>
		<meeting>the 16th ACM Workshop on Cloud Computing Security</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fingerprinting Websites Using Traffic Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hintz</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Workshop on Privacy Enhancing Technologies</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Critical Evaluation of Website Fingerprinting Attacks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Juarez</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Afroz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Acar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Diaz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Greenstadt</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 21st ACM SIGSAC Conference on Computer and Communications Security</title>
		<meeting>the 21st ACM SIGSAC Conference on Computer and Communications Security</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Toward an Efficient Website Fingerprinting Defense</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Juarez</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Imani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Perry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Diaz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wright</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">European Symposium on Research in Computer Security</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring Information Leakage in Website Fingerprinting Attacks and Defenses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hopper</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 25th ACM SIGSAC Conference on Computer and Communications Security</title>
		<meeting>the 25th ACM SIGSAC Conference on Computer and Communications Security</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inferring the Source of Encrypted HTTP Connections</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liberatore</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Levine</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 13th ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security</title>
		<meeting>the 13th ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">HTTPOS: Sealing Information Leaks with Browserside Obfuscation of Encrypted Flows</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luo</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Chan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Perdisci</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Network &amp; Distributed System Security Symposium (NDSS</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Citeseer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How Unique is Your. onion?: An Analysis of the Fingerprintability of Tor Onion Services</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Overdorf</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Juarez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Acar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Greenstadt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Diaz</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 24th ACM SIGSAC Conference on Computer and Communications Security</title>
		<meeting>the 24th ACM SIGSAC Conference on Computer and Communications Security</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Website Fingerprinting at Internet Scale</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Panchenko</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Lanze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Pennekamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Engel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Zin-Nen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Henze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wehrle</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Network &amp; Distributed System Security Symposium (NDSS) (2016)</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Citeseer</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Website Fingerprinting in Onion Routing Based Anonymization Networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Panchenko</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Niessen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zinnen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Engel</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 10th Annual ACM Workshop on Privacy in the Electronic Society</title>
		<meeting>the 10th Annual ACM Workshop on Privacy in the Electronic Society</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automated Website Fingerprinting through Deep Learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rimmer</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Preuveneers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Juarez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Van Goethem</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joosen</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Network &amp; Distributed System Security Symposium (NDSS)</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Citeseer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Timing Analysis in Lowlatency Mix Networks: Attacks and Defenses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shmatikov</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wang</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M.-H</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">European Symposium on Research in Computer Security</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deep Fingerprinting: Undermining Website Fingerprinting Defenses with Deep Learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sirinam</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Imani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Juarez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wright</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 25th ACM SIGSAC Conference on Computer and Communications Security</title>
		<meeting>the 25th ACM SIGSAC Conference on Computer and Communications Security</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tor: The Second Generation Onion Router</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Syverson</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Dingledine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mathewson</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">USENIX Security Symposium</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tobias</forename><surname>Pulls</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.cs.kau.se/pulls/hot/thebasketcase-ape/" />
		<title level="m">Adaptive Padding Early (APE</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016-08" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Online; accessed 25</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Optimizing Precision for Open</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wang</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1802.05409</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">World Website Fingerprinting. arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effective Attacks and Provable Defenses for Website Fingerprinting</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wang</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Cai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Nithyanand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>And Gold-Berg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">USENIX Security Symposium</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improved Website Fingerprinting on Tor</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wang</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Goldberg</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 12th ACM Workshop on Privacy in the Electronic Society</title>
		<meeting>the 12th ACM Workshop on Privacy in the Electronic Society</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On Realistically Attacking Tor with Website Fingerprinting</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wang</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Goldberg</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings on Privacy Enhancing Technologies</title>
		<meeting>on Privacy Enhancing Technologies</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An Efficient Defense against Passive Website Fingerprinting Attacks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wang</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Goldberg</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Walkie-Talkie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">USENIX Security Symposium</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Traffic Morphing: An Efficient Defense Against Statistical Traffic Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wright</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Coull</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Monrose</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Network &amp; Distributed System Security Symposium (NDSS</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Citeseer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Multi-tab Website Fingerprinting Attack</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Gong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiang</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 34th Annual Computer Security Applications Conference</title>
		<meeting>the 34th Annual Computer Security Applications Conference</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Website Fingerprinting Attack on Anonymity Networks Based on Profile Hidden Markov Model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhuo</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z.-L</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>And</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhang</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Information Forensics and Security</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
