<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/atharsefid/Desktop/grobid-0.5.3/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.3" ident="GROBID" when="2020-09-29T04:09+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Open access to the Proceedings of the 29th USENIX Security Symposium is sponsored by USENIX. BigMAC: Fine-Grained Policy Analysis of Android Firmware BIGMAC: Fine-Grained Policy Analysis of Android Firmware</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>August 12-14, 2020</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Grant</forename><surname>Hernandez</surname></persName>
							<email>grant.hernandez@ufl.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Swarnim</forename><surname>Yadav</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Byron</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><forename type="middle">R B</forename><surname>Butler</surname></persName>
							<email>butler@ufl.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Grant</forename><surname>Hernandez</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Florida Institute for Cyber Security (FICS) Research</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Florida</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Gainesville</settlement>
									<region>FL</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dave</forename></persName>
							<email>daveti@purdue.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jing</forename><surname>Tian</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution">Purdue University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>West Lafayette</settlement>
									<region>IN</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anurag</forename><forename type="middle">Swarnim</forename><surname>Yadav</surname></persName>
							<email>anuragswar.yadav@ufl.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Florida Institute for Cyber Security (FICS) Research</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Florida</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Gainesville</settlement>
									<region>FL</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Byron</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Florida Institute for Cyber Security (FICS) Research</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Florida</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Gainesville</settlement>
									<region>FL</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><forename type="middle">R B</forename><surname>Butler</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Florida Institute for Cyber Security (FICS) Research</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Florida</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Gainesville</settlement>
									<region>FL</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Dave (Jing) Tian</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Florida</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Purdue University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Anurag</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Florida</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Open access to the Proceedings of the 29th USENIX Security Symposium is sponsored by USENIX. BigMAC: Fine-Grained Policy Analysis of Android Firmware BIGMAC: Fine-Grained Policy Analysis of Android Firmware</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 29th USENIX Security Symposium</title>
						<meeting>the 29th USENIX Security Symposium						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published">August 12-14, 2020</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>This paper is included in the 978-1-939133-17-5</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The Android operating system is the world&apos;s dominant mobile computing platform. To defend against malicious applications and external attack, Android relies upon a complex combination of discretionary and mandatory access control mechanisms, including Linux capabilities, to maintain least privilege. To understand the impact and interaction between these layers, we created a framework called BIGMAC that combines and instantiates all layers of the policy together in a fine grained graph supporting millions of edges. Our model filters out paths and types not in use on actual systems that policy analysis alone would consider. Unlike previous work which requires a rooted device, using only static firmware and Android domain knowledge, we are able to extract and recreate the security state of a running system, achieving a process credential recovery at best 74.7% and a filesystem DAC and MAC accuracy of over 98%. Using BIGMAC, we develop attack queries to discover sets of objects that can be influenced by untrusted applications and external peripherals. Our evaluation against Samsung S8+ and LG G7 firmwares reveals multiple policy concerns, including untrusted apps on LG being able to communicate with a kernel monitoring service, Samsung S8+ allowing IPC from untrusted apps to some root processes, at least 24 processes with the CAP_SYS_ADMIN capability, and system_server with the capability to load kernel modules. We have reported our findings to the corresponding vendors and release BIGMAC for the community.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The Android operating system is the world's most dominant mobile computing platform. As smartphones increasingly become primary computing devices, Android commands an overwhelming market share, representing 88% of all end-user smartphone sales in the second quarter of 2018 <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref>. As such, assuring the security of Android devices is of paramount importance.</p><p>To this end, Android supports a complex combination of access control mechanisms. Substantial past work has examined the security model of the Android middleware layer, which mediates access decisions made by Android applications <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref>. However, underneath this middleware lies a Linux kernel and at this layer, the security model is similar to that of many other Linux-based systems. The access control framework includes not only a discretionary access control (DAC) mechanism common to UNIX operating systems, but supports mandatory access control (MAC) as well through Security-Enhanced Android (SEAndroid) <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[37]</ref>, a customized version of SELinux. Moreover, other mechanisms such as Linux capabilities are also used to assure least privilege and to minimize trusted processes. To maintain the integrity of an Android system against local and remote adversaries, all of these mechanisms must work in conjunction with each other; however, the complexity of creating and interacting with SEAndroid policies, MAC rule interactions, labeled filesystems, capabilities, and DAC policies creates a challenging environment for assuring security goals.</p><p>In this paper, we introduce a framework called BIGMAC for reasoning about the complex Android policy environment based on extracting policies and metadata from Android device firmware images. BIGMAC goes beyond the analysis of the SEAndroid MAC policy to consider how policy is instantiated on devices through processes, objects, and inter-process communication endpoints, SELinux type relationships between Android objects, filesystem extended attributes, and Linux capabilities. BIGMAC recovers system init scripts and simulates the behavior of commands that affect the filesystem in order to accurately model filesystem contexts and Android credentials. We demonstrate that compared to the ground truth provided by a running Android device, BIGMAC successfully labels over 98% of DAC and MAC filesystem metadata, and up to 74.7% of running process metadata can be identically reconstructed.</p><p>BIGMAC is valuable as a means of determining potential vectors of attack based on policy inconsistencies found, and we demonstrate that past exploits can be modeled with it. We are also, to our knowledge, the first to model the impact of external peripherals (e.g., USB interfaces) and their relation to a device's security policy. Supporting millions of access control edges, BIGMAC provides one of the finest-grained frameworks for policy examination currently available for reasoning about access control on Android devices. To benefit the community, we will open source BIGMAC and all of the collection scripts for reproducibility. <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">1</ref> Our contributions are as follows:</p><p>• We develop a new framework, BIGMAC, to extract, graph, and query Android security policies from static firmware images, without the need for a rooted device, and recover runtime security state by instantiating processes, files, and IPC objects with a 98% accuracy.</p><p>• We combine MAC, DAC, capabilities, and tagged external input sources to create an instantiated, fine-grained, whole-system attack-graph supporting millions of edges. Our Prolog engine then provides an interactive user interface to query the attack graph.</p><p>• We evaluate BIGMAC against Samsung S8+ and LG G7 firmware and discover apps on LG able to communicate with a kernel monitoring service, Samsung apps able to talk to multiple root processes via binder, at least 24 processes with the dangerous CAP_SYS_ADMIN capability, and system_server being able to load kernel modules. We reported our findings to the corresponding vendors.</p><p>Outline The rest of this paper is structured as follows: Section 2 develops the necessary background on Android security policies. Section 3 describes the design of BIGMAC and Section 4 the implementation. In Section 5 we evaluate BIGMAC against multiple Android firmware images and demonstrate how it can assist in discovering privilege escalation paths. We discuss our findings in Section 6, compare key related work in Section 7, and finally conclude in Section 8.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Background</head><p>Linux Access Control Historically, access control has been implemented using object ownership, group membership, and their respective permission bits for read, write, and execute. On modern UNIX inspired systems, such as Linux, this model persists with the creation and assignment of User IDs (UIDs) and Group IDs (GIDs), along with read, write, and execute permissions for each class of identifier. Privilege separation is primarily based on different UID and GID assignments to processes and file objects. This class of access control is formally known as Discretionary Access Control (DAC) because the permissions are assigned to new and owned objects at the discretion of the users (i.e., subjects or processes). This means that the system's access matrix is not fixed at runtime and may change dynamically, possibly leading to a loss of integrity. The all-powerful root user with the UID of zero has hard-coded 1 https://github.com/FICS/BigMAC superuser permissions in the kernel's code, allowing it to override all DAC permissions at will. For example, a root-owned process can accidentally create a world-readable and writable file that it trusts to be well-formed, but a lower privileged user could take advantage of this hole to affect the runtime state of the root owned process, possibly leading to confused deputy style attacks or even a privilege escalation.</p><p>To help limit the damage of a root process compromise, the Linux kernel divided up root's permissions using a Capabilitylike (CAP) system <ref type="bibr">[22]</ref>. Currently there are 38 capabilities with a wide-range of strengths. This works under the model that processes that usually need root-like permissions do not require all of its extensive set of capabilities. As such, system administrators are free to permanently drop any capabilities from processes that do not need them. For example, a process, such as Apache HTTPD, that needs to listen on privileged ports (those less than 1024) can only be granted the CAP_NET_BIND_SERVICE capability instead of all 38. This capability model works some applications, but its lack of granularity can still lead to over-permissioned processes, which can be dangerous in the face of untrusted processes and users.</p><p>To further lock down Linux-based systems, a Mandatory Access Control (MAC) scheme can also be deployed. MAC unlike DAC has the last word on actions taken on objects and is fixed at runtime (e.g., its access matrix is fixed). This has the major advantage in that the policy can be written and verified statically before being applied to a running system and set to immutable. There have been many MAC systems proposed in the literature, but today, the most popular implementation of MAC on Linux-based systems is SELinux <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[38]</ref>. SELinux has three core components: subjects, objects, and actions. The subject is an active process or device that is responsible for the flow of information between objects. Subjects are given access to objects via "allow" rules that permits the process to read or modify the object, leading to changes in the system state. Objects are resources such as files, sockets, and network interfaces which are accessed by subjects (i.e., active processes and devices) and classified according to the resource they provide. Every object has a set of permissions and a class identifier defining its purpose and services that the object handles. These allow rules form a security policy that ideally grants the minimal set of permissions required to complete a task (e.g., read only when writing permission is unnecessary). Both subjects and objects have a set of security attributes which the operating system can query to determine whether a requested action is allowed by the policy or not.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Android Security Model</head><p>Today, Android OS's kernel uses a modified version of Linux that benefits from the above access control implementations.</p><p>DAC on Android Android's use of DAC involves a fixed set of UID/GIDs for system purposes and ranges of UIDs for dynamically installed applications. On Android, a strong effort is made to limit the number of processes running as root, and as such the typical high privileged process is usually running as the system (UID 1000) user or a role-specific UID, such as radio, or graphics instead. This denies most running processes access to powerful root permissions, unless they have been explicitly granted or inherited the capabilities. At the app level, untrusted applications are each assigned a unique UID from a fixed range, preventing them from owning any files besides the ones included during their installation.</p><p>SEAndroid SELinux was introduced to the Android platform with a targeted policy in 2013 <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[37]</ref>. These policies are a set of rules which are based on file labels. These labels consist of a user, role, type, and level. On Android, the type is the primary identifier. Policies are rules which determine what types and actions a process has access to. From a security perspective, items are grouped together based on their accessibility.</p><p>SEAndroid extends SELinux to support new Android specific hooks, such as Binder IPC. Additional extensions include adding access classes for services, properties, etc. They also include modifying user-space configuration files and processes, as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>, to help apply security labels to Androidspecific objects. Besides these changes, the core functionality is largely unchanged, with the primary goal being mandatory, system-wide, type enforcement. The Binder implementation introduced new LSM hooks to the Binder driver which lets SEAndroid monitor and control interprocess communication between applications.</p><p>The SEAndroid user space introduced modifications to existing SELinux components including: init, Zygote, bionic (the Android C library), and the package manager. The Android init process is responsible for loading the security policy early during the boot process, interpreting init.rc commands without access to the shell, and enforcing aspects of the security policy (i.e., access to system properties). The Zygote process is responsible for spawning Android application processes. Zygote starts when the system boots and loads common framework code. Zygote can then set the security label of the socket interfaces and the security context for running applications. Bionic, Android's specific libc implementation, was modified to get and set extended file system attributes and to store file security labels. The package manager makes decisions on permissions requested by an application to determine if requested permissions can actually be granted. These user space components enforce SEAndroid security policy beyond the kernel layer <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[37]</ref>.</p><p>Middleware Application writers are abstracted away from the system access control models and instead focus on Android middleware permissions. These permissions are capabilitylike, but instead grant applications access to resources and services provided by the Android operating system, not the Linux kernel. For the purposes of this paper, we do not examine Android middleware permissions and instead focus on the combination of DAC, MAC, and capabilities and their impact on the security of the system.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Design</head><p>To examine and query the security policy of an Android firmware image, we design BIGMAC, as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>, to extract, recover, simulate and fully instantiate all objects, which include files, processes, and Interprocess Communication (IPC) end-points. This method is realized using a scalable approach that combines Android domain knowledge and files extracted from firmware images to recreate a running system's state. The recreation is possible without requiring complicated emulation techniques that may not work on all device-specific firmware images or on a diverse corpus of physical devices, of which no rooting method may be available. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2</ref> To begin, we describe how we extract MAC, DAC, and capability (CAP) information from firmware images, including saving key files, simulating Android's init daemon, and associating raw files with SELinux file types and domains. Next we explain our dataflow graph which processes an SEPolicy's access vectors into a simplified read/write model. Then we discuss how we recreate a running system's process hierarchy and process metadata from abstract SELinux domains. Following this discussion, we show how we flatten our dataflow graph into true objects and expand our process tree into actual processes by propagating credentials using a fork/exec model. Finally we overlay the dataflow graph onto the process list to create an attack graph that contains all of the possible read/write interactions between processes (e.g., IPC) and the filesystem (e.g., files). Once we have a completed attack graph, we convert this to facts for our query engine to explore the data paths between processes and the filesystem.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Security Policy Extraction</head><p>The Android ecosystem is made up of many Original Equipment Manufacturers (OEMs), each with their own proprietary extensions to the Android Open Source Project (AOSP). This fragmentation also extends to the Android image distribution formats, which vary wildly between OEMs. To canonicalize firmware images, we use an open source Android image extractor <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[39]</ref>. With the extracted images, we walk the filesystems to extract the DAC file permissions and extended attributes (xattrs), which include SELinux MAC labels and Linux capabilities. We save the filesystem metadata and extract all of the files shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> which include Android object SELinux associations (services, properties, and apps), the Android property list, the raw SEPolicy binary file, and finally the init system files which contain useful DAC/MAC/CAP metadata, plus a list of native daemons started at boot.</p><p>Init Boot Simulation Without simulating a device boot, we do not recover any policy information for the /data, /dev, and /sys directories -all of which are crucial to model. These directories and their files do not exist in the static firmware as they are created during the boot process. In order to capture these changes to the extracted security policy, we parse the saved init system files, following the Android init daemon's specification <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17]</ref>. Android's init system is custom to the platform and has two major components: the init daemon itself, which is responsible for starting and managing native daemon services, and the uevent daemon, which monitors the kernel for device state change notifications. Init is the first process executed on the system and it handles boot state changes, manages services, and executes Run Commands (RC). These RCs include triggers for handling boot and property change events, actions which are executed in a trigger, and service definitions. During different phases of the boot process, files are created and services are started. BIGMAC implements key RCs that affect the security state to capture these changes before proceeding further with the graph instantiation. These include the creation of directories, files, and the changing of file owner, group, and permission modes. Additionally, we save the service definitions for later spawning of processes and simulation of their runtime credentials.</p><p>Early in the boot process, init will spawn the uevent daemon. This sets customized DAC information for certain files in the /dev and /sys directories based off of a simplified configuration file. The format is a single entry per line, with optional glob match, containing a user, group, and permission. We heuristically apply these customizations to the filesystem in order to have properly labeled and credentialed objects for these directories.</p><p>Backing File Recovery In order to fully instantiate abstract, MAC-only, SELinux types into processes and objects, we need to associate them with concrete files containing DAC and capability information. To start, we decompile the binary SEPolicy back into a connected multi-edge directional graph representation, G s , via the Access Vector rules (AVRules), which link a source and target type via an action and a class. As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref>, G s , is the subject graph and the genesis of all derived graphs. This policy includes all of the types, T , and attributes, A, used during SELinux type enforcement. From this abstract policy, we divide all of the types into subjects (domains), S, and objects, O, and begin to instantiate them by correlating their policy types to real files, F, on the filesystem (backing files). For file objects this is straightforward as their types directly link to filesystem object types captured during extraction. To do this for subjects, we must invert Type Enforcement rules (TERules) related to process transitions via an object execution. A TERule connects two domains S i and S j via a transition using a 2-tuple containing object O j and class</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">C p : S i (O j ,C p ) − −−− → S j .</formula><p>For process transitions, this reads as domain S i uses the object O j , which is an instance of F j , to transition to the domain of S j via the class C p , which is a process. This is an explicit encoding of a process transition during the exec of a binary F j . By parsing these rules, we can back-propagate the binaries associated with subject types. We define the set of subjects with at least one backing file to be SB. Subjects may have more than one backing file, but if they have none, they cannot be fully instantiated. Example rules from an SEPolicy to allow init to execute mediaserver are:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">allow init mediaserver_exec : file { open ,</formula><p>read , execute }; allow init mediaserver : process { transition }; type_transition init mediaserver_exec : process mediaserver ;</p><p>Where S i = init, S j = mediaserver, O j = mediaserver_exec, and C p = process.</p><p>Not all Android domains have an explicit TERule due to a type of AVRule called dyntransition. A dynamic transition is encoded from a subject to another subject via the process class. It is the same as the TERule, minus the backing object, which means a subject does not need to exec to change its MAC label. The common Android platform domains that perform these transitions are init and Zygote. Zygote is started by init upon boot and is used as a warmed-up virtual-machine process source to fork app processes. As such, depending on the class of app (untrusted, system, privileged, etc.) the new forked process will be dynamically transitioned to a new domain. Applications are dynamically installed by the user and as such cannot have hardcoded TERules. This leads to all applications of a certain class sharing the same security label, unless customized by seapp_contexts. By recovering these dynamic transition edges, we are able to recreate the entire subject type hierarchy for later use in recovering the instantiated process tree.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Dataflow Graph</head><p>Now with a full set of subject nodes, S, and those that have concrete backing files, SB, we begin to create a dataflow graph, G d , from the subject graph, G s . <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref> shows this and the relationships between the other derived graphs of BIGMAC. In our model, we want to capture the dataflow between subjects as we are primarily interested in privilege escalation attacks, which involve other higher privileged subjects. To be clear, our dataflow model captures the potential transfer of bytes from one node to another following a directed edge. In the raw SEPolicy, each AVRule contains individual multiple access vectors, such as read, write, open, getattr, and so on. For our model, we are only interested in the vectors that imply a read or a write. As such we define a reduction mapping of AVRule actions to the simple dataflow properties of read (R) or write (W) as is listed in <ref type="table">Table 8</ref> in the Appendix.</p><p>As we are interested in an instantiated graph, we do not include any S not in SB. Without at least one associated executable, the subject is considered abstract. Therefore, for each SB, we examine all AVRules to other S or O nodes. We also ignore subject to subject edges and instead infer an implicit object to maintain a strict object-subject edge invariant. <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">3</ref> Our model divides objects into two sets: IPC objects O IPC and file objects O File . The key difference between objects is that IPCs have a single owning subject (the creator/manager), inheriting its credentials, while file objects contain one or more backing files, F i , each with separate MAC/DAC/CAP data. This split allows us to selectively and intelligently instantiate objects depending on their usage and context. For IPC objects we consolidate many individual AVRule classes into this object and tag it with the underlying AV class. For instance, all classes derived from socket commons class and Android's custom binder class are all considered IPC objects. Android defines specific AV classes for use in middleware, including property service and service_manager. For the property service, which in Android's case is the init process, we omit these flows as they allow for too many easy, and less likely to be exploitable paths to init from many processes. For the service manager, we examine the AVRules that have the AV of add, which allows us to find the owning domain. This is important for having correct service IPC credentials and edges. Once we have inferred an object from an AVRule edge, we insert it into G d with a read and/or write edge to the adjacent subject.</p><p>As all subjects and objects are iterated through, we also expand attributes A s . These attributes contain members that are common to all AVRules. Instead of leaving these attributes linked into the graph, we fully expand all of their edges into each member. This means we have a large increase in edge count, but no longer have to consider attribute membership during graph queries. This graph is bipartite and in the worst case has O(|S| * |O|) edges and O(|S|+|O|) nodes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Process Inflation</head><p>Using the subject hierarchy and backing files we recovered in Section 3.1, we can now begin to fully instantiate the subject nodes into individual process instances with virtual Process Identifiers (PIDs). Starting at the root kernel subject, we fork the init subject and assign the starting credentials of root (uid=0, gid=0, groups=[], sid=u:r:init:s0, cap=ALL). The kernel is assigned a PID of zero and init a PID of one. From here, we bring back the service definitions extracted in Section 3.1 in order to examine and filter all the children of init. For each child subject of init and for each backing file of that subject, we lookup a service definition that matches the backing file path in our virtual filesystem, is enabled, and not a oneshot process. With a potential match, we use the service security options, if any, to determine the process's user, group, supplemental groups, credentials, and security identifier. The defaults if these aren't included are to fork a service as root with all capabilities <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17]</ref>.</p><p>Once a process has been assigned credentials, it is inserted into a concrete process tree, G p , with proper Linux process semantics (parent, children, inherited credentials, etc.). With boot now simulated, we employ Android domain knowledge to fix the processes forked by Zygote. These include apps and the system_server. The credentials for the system server are hardcoded in the Zygote source code and we apply them manually.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Attack Graph Instantiation</head><p>To begin our final instantiation, we must first fully expand all object nodes within G d . Specifically, we split all file nodes into individual file instances. For example, the system_data_file object has many backing files. To make sure that each file's DAC information is considered, we split this node while duplicating edges to and from the original adjacent nodes. This greatly increases the edge count, but allows for a concrete yes or no answer for future DAC and MAC queries. We call this new graph G f . With the two primary input graphs, G f for flattened dataflow and G p for the process tree we, for each process P i of subject S j in G p , we copy all in and out edges from S j in G f to P i in the process tree. We effectively overlay the dataflow graph onto the process tree, giving the concrete processes concrete edges to all objects allowed to be read from or written to by the original MAC policy. This final graph, G a , is used to generate facts for all of our future attack queries using the logic engine.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.5">Logic-based Query Engine</head><p>To explore our BIGMAC attack graph, we design a Prologbased query engine as the backend, providing multiple query interfaces to end users, as shown below: query_mac(S,T,C,P). query_mac_dac(S,T,C,P). query_mac_dac_cap(S,T,C,B,P). query_mac_dac_cap_ext(S,T,C,B,E,P).</p><p>S represents the starting node; T stands for the target node; C is the cut-off parameter used to limit the length of a path; B specifies the target Linux capability; E determines the external attack surface type, such as USB and Bluetooth; and P contains the returned paths of the query. Both the starting node and the target node can be a process or a object (e.g., a file or IPC). They can also be wildcards, which is represented by underscore (_) in Prolog. Each query interface applies different policy layers and filtering mechanisms. For example, query_mac_dac_cap_ext(_,zygote,3,CAP_SYS_ADMIN,usb,P).</p><p>requests all (attack) paths which target the Zygote process, pass both MAC and DAC checking, have a maximum path length of 3, achieve CAP_SYS_ADMIN capability, and can be launched from USB connections. As the attack graph is built upon the MAC policy, each viable path within the graph is allowed by the MAC. To support different query interfaces, we apply different policy and filtering checks on a viable path. For instance, query_mac_dac_cap_ext predicate finds a viable path within the graph, such that: find_a_path(S,T,C,B,E,P) :-graph_travel(S,T,[S],P,C), dac_path(P), cap_path(P,B), ext_path(P,E).</p><p>The graph_travel predicate uses Depth First Search (DFS) to find a path, which is based on the MAC policy. The dac_path predicate then checks the corresponding DAC policy by looking into every adjacent pair of nodes within the path using the dac predicate. Each pair of nodes (A,B) is a combination of a process and a system object with any ordering. The dac predicate checks for root user, owner, group, and others based on the DAC information within each node. We perform the following query, ∀A,B ∈ S ∪T , perform: The cap_path predicate checks if a given path can achieve a certain Linux capability by examining the last node within the path. In case of the last node being a system object, we also need to look at the previous node which is the last process node within the path. Because each process node has its capability information encoded, the final check is to see if the requested capability is contained within the capability list of the node.</p><p>cap_path(P,C) :-cap_last(P,C); cap_prev(P,C).</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">cap_last(P,C) :- last(P,A), is_sub(A), cap_supp(A,C). cap_prev(P,C) :- prev(P,A), is_sub(A), cap_supp(A,C).</formula><p>Similarly, the ext_path predicate checks if a given path starts from an external attack surface, e.g., USB, by inspecting the starting node within the path. If the starting node is a system object and can be reached via external connections, the path is an attack path that can be triggered externally. Because each system object has its external connection information encoded, the final check is also a membership checking between the specific external attack and the surface list of the node.</p><p>ext_path(P,E) :-first(P,A), is_obj(A), ext_supp(A,E).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Implementation</head><p>Our implementation of BIGMAC is based upon Python 3.5 and SWI-Prolog, and it employs the NetworkX library for graphing and the SETools package <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref> 4 for decompiling SEPolicies into their original types and rules.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Firmware Extraction</head><p>BIGMAC uses an open source extraction library for the raw firmware, which supports 18 firmware vendors across many Android versions <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[39]</ref>. We extended this tool to support newer 8.0 Samsung images, which use the LZ4 compression on the raw disk images. For this paper, we only extracted Google, Samsung, and LG images, but we would be able to support many other vendors as the files we extract from disk images are standardized by the platform. The extraction tool starts by recursively unzipping firmware images, handling each layer based on the file type. We hook into the ext4 disk image extraction routine and disable the permission changes to maintain the original DAC and MAC information. Then in our separate frontend, we perform a filesystem walk of each disk image to extract out all metadata provided by the stat, getxattr, and readlink calls. We store this in a dictionary indexed by filename. Next we walk our in-memory Virtual Filesystem (VFS) using regular expressions to extract out every file shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>. Additionally we extract out the build.prop files to resolve properties containing key metadata like the Android version and the hardware configuration. We save all of these raw files in an image-specific database for later processing. There are some quirks between different Android major versions that our tool also takes into account. Most of these involve the major changes to the security policy file splitting by Project Treble <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[18]</ref>. Effectively, the platform (Google) and the vendor now have separate files for all of those shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>. Our tool handles this transparently, allowing us to analyze version 7.0 and above.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">System Boot Emulation</head><p>To recover an approximate state of a running system, we combine all known policy files at various stages. The most important set of files besides the raw SEPolicy are the Android init scripts. These are text based, shell-like commands that execute sequentially in blocks, but do not support constructs for control-flow or looping <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17]</ref>. This is a significant advantage for BIGMAC as we do not have to support arbitrary code and can instead selectively handle the most important commands. We implemented the mkdir, chown, chmod, trigger, enable, and mount commands. The first three change the state of the filesystem, including DAC information; trigger raises an event that causes other sections to be executed; enable starts a service; and mount mounts a filesystem to a hardpoint. The mount command is particularly important to handle as it affects the effective SEContext that files are assigned during our simulated restorecon process. During device ground-truth analysis, most of the wrong MAC/DAC data came from not handling these quirks. Each vendor and device model comes with its own set of quirks in the init system. For example, on a Pixel 8.1.0 image, we had to set the property vold.decrypt to trigger_post_fs_data in order for init simulator to execute the proper boot sections that create the /data directory. Another quirk we discovered was that some OEMs add their own custom group and user Android IDs (AID) that deviate from Android platform. This affects our equivalent getpwnam function which is unable to map these names to AIDs. To fix this, we plan on extracting out an exported table, android_id,</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Android Credential Simulation</head><p>After booting init and modifying the filesystem, we use recovered service definitions from the init files to properly assign runtime credentials to inflated processes. Service definitions contain their starting user, group, and capabilities. These are instrumental in getting accurate DAC and CAP information and improving the overall fidelity of our attack graphs. From the spawned children of init, we also perform a conservative reparenting of children processes that have no service definition, yet are able to be transitioned to by the init daemon. This helps fix the process tree in case a child of init also forks its own helper processes, which we noticed with the location service (loc_launcher). Overall, the credential simulation is a best-effort approximation given the available information and constraints recovered from the MAC policy.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Logic-based Query Engine</head><p>We implement our logic-based query engine using SWIProlog <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">5</ref> and provide all four query interfaces described in 3.5. To parse the output from Prolog (a list of paths), we created an interactive query frontend using the GNU readline library. This gives us support for interactive tab completion of all the possible processes and objects to use as source and target nodes. It also allows us to save, restore, and pretty print all queries. Within Prolog, we needed to add a cutoff parameter to prevent path explosion. The cut-off parameter (C ) drops the path if its length is beyond the value specified. We also implement an is_uniq predicate to filter paths which contain duplicated elements, making sure that paths within the length of the cut-off also do not contain loops. To collect all possible paths, we use Prolog's Depth First Search (DFS) with iterative deepening ( f indall). In total, we wrote 5,997 lines of Python across the extraction tool, graph creator, and query frontend. Our Prolog engine was 343 lines.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Evaluation</head><p>Our evaluation is broken up into two sections: a ground truth study and case studies of BIGMAC on Android firmware. The ground truth study's purpose is to evaluate BIGMAC's accuracy in recovering security policy from static firmware. This part is limited in the Android devices and vendors because we require real rooted devices to compare against. The case studies have no such limitations as BIGMAC works on firmware. As such, we evaluate images from Samsung, LG, and Google. For reproducibility of our results, all of the firmware used is described in <ref type="table">Table 9</ref> of the Appendix. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">5</ref> We initially used GNU Prolog but it crashed due to large edge counts.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Ground Truth Comparison</head><p>To evaluate the feasibility of recreating the Android runtime system state from firmware, we use custom scripts loaded via adb to collect MAC, DAC, and process information from a rooted Google Pixel 1 and Samsung Galaxy S7 edge. For the Pixel, we reflashed and rooted it with three different AOSP versions: Android 7.1.2, 8.1.0, and 9.0.0.</p><p>For the file and process recovery tables, we have marked metrics as True Positive (TP, found and accurate), False Positive (FP, recovered file not accurate or it was extra), and False Negative (FN, not found in recovery, but it exists on a real system).</p><p>File Permissions As shown in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>, we are able to fully replicate most major directories within the running system from static firmware, including /vendor and /system. To be precise, we can recover all of the MAC data within the system by parsing file_contexts and applying it to files from the firmware. This is equivalent to a running system performing a restorecon operation. For filesystems created during the runtime, such as /dev and /sys, we are able to infer potential files by parsing uevent.rc files, which would normally be loaded by ueventd during the phone's early boot. This file contains glob patterns to match device or sysfs nodes in order to apply a user, group, and file mode. We conservatively instantiate files we see referenced in this file, which leads us to be able to recover many character devices. Unfortunately, these files contain more device nodes than are actually found on running phones, as seen in the "Extra Files" (false positives) rows of <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. This is a difficult balance to strike. Without recovering /dev, many SELinux contexts have no backing files, which means we cannot fully instantiate the associated file objects, leading to false negatives.</p><p>Since we are limited by the content provided by firmware, some directories, namely /data and /odm, have a high falsenegative rate. These filesystems are only created after the first boot or are vendor-specific. For example, the missing 5,350 files on the Pixel 1 (8.1.0) in /data are mostly caches for applications. Our attack graph model is primarily focused on system-level directories and files, and we can safely ignore the verbose contents of these directories. Of the file DAC and MAC data that is possible to recover, our TP positive rate is greater than 98% for all images.</p><p>Process Tree In order to get actionable results from our attack queries, we need as close to an accurate of a picture of the running system as possible. Our process recovery involves a significant amount of information collection and firmware file parsing in order to make the best instantiation possible. Along the way, we employ device and version agnostic algorithms to do so, which is key to support a large range of firmware.</p><p>The results of our process recovery are in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 4</ref>. For the S7 edge in column 1a, we instantiate 49 processes, 25 of which Samsung S7 Edge (7.0.0) Pixel 1 (7.  <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: A comparison of BIGMAC's file recovery and their corresponding MAC and DAC metadata from firmware images versus running devices. Only the top three filesystem paths are shown. The "Good Files" (TP) category shows how many files had 100% identical metadata to the running filesystem. "Different MAC/DAC" (FP) is a listing of the top directories where MAC/DAC data was mismatched. "Extra Files" (FP) shows the directories where BIGMAC recovered files that did not exist at all on the real running system. Finally, "Missing Files" (FN) are the files that were not available from the raw firmware (/data contains installed app data, caches, and settings).    <ref type="figure">figure (a)</ref>, "Correct" (TP) shows how many recovered processes had 100% identical metadata (excluding process IDs) as compared to a running phone. "Different DAC/Cap." (TP/FP) is where a process was matched to a running device process, but parts of the DAC/capabilities were different. "Extra" (FP) shows the processes BIGMAC over-approximated and were not running on the real running system during the snapshot. In <ref type="figure">figure (b)</ref>, "Pair Found" (TP) shows how many recovered and real processes were able to be matched via executable and SELinux context. "Missing Native" (FN) are the native daemons that were not instantiated. "Missing App" (FN) are the Zygote-children (applications) that are not currently recovered by BIGMAC.</p><p>are completely accurate to a running device, 20 are partially accurate, and 4 are extraneous (not running on the real device). Of the missing processes in column 1b, 55.5% are app processes, which BIGMAC does not instantiate at this time as our focus is on native daemons. To do so would require APK extraction and manifest parsing in order to achieve accurate group membership. <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">6</ref> For the S7 edge, 20 of the processes are <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">6</ref> Android conflates some middleware permissions with UNIX groups, such as the INTERNET permission with the inet GID. native daemons, which were not instantiated for various reasons, such as already instantiated processes created children. <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">7</ref> For the Pixel 1 9.0.0 we fare the best with 74.7% of processes having a recovered pair and only 9 missing native processes. For the processes we did recover, in all cases, over 50% of the recovered processes completely matched paired real processes. This would not be possible without parsing Android init files to extract service definitions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Attack Graph Queries</head><p>To explore our graph instantiation, we emit the graph nodes, their attributes, and the edges between them to SWI-Prolog for further analysis. We develop an interactive query interface that allows us to ask attack queries about the graph. The result of a query is a list of all possible paths meeting the parameters of the query. The query parameters include: source node, target node, max path length (cutoff), target capabilities, and object type. To make our analysis concrete, we generate attack graphs from a Samsung S8+ 8.0 and LG G7 9.0 firmware.</p><p>Layered Path Reduction To demonstrate the path reduction through including DAC checks, we run query(untrusted_app,vold,4) with MAC-only filtering (query_mac) and with MAC+DAC filtering. As shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 2</ref>, we are able to bring down the number of query results by at least an order of magnitude by providing fine-grained query interfaces with multi-layer filtering. We chose the vold process because it is a powerful Android platform daemon responsible for mounting and managing disk volumes. It is also part of Android's formal definition of its TCB <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19]</ref>. On the S8+, vold is directly reachable by nearly 100K unique length-4 paths when just considering the MAC policy and only 14K paths after applying DAC. On LG's firmware, there are considerably fewer paths even on the MAC-only query. This is due to the number of unique files available to be written by processes along the path that can be read by vold. A diagram of some of the types of paths that were filtered out by the DAC checking, but passed MAC is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 5</ref>. Files and directories that would be considered writable by the MAC policy alone are discarded when the DAC policy is applied. In this case, the untrusted_app process is not a member of the media_rw. Therefore it cannot affect these directories. It is possible that at runtime the app process could gain access to this group or the DAC permissions on the directories could change. BIGMAC currently works off of snapshots of the security policy state. While applying DAC information increases the query running time, it provides realistic paths results that would be allowed by the MAC and DAC policy on a real system. MAC-only paths (effectively pure policy analysis) that are shown by previous work have many more false positives, leading to results not accurate enough to draw security conclusions from.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Analysis of a Privilege Escalation</head><p>To demonstrate how BIGMAC can discover unintended paths that could be used for privilege escalation, we analyze CVE-2018-9488 <ref type="bibr">[30]</ref>. As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 6</ref>, this flaw let the Zygote process compromise the crash_dump binary due to its control over the mount namespace. From here, crash_dump has the ability to read and    write the memory of vold using the ptrace syscall (which was allowed by the MAC policy). We use BIGMAC on the Google 8.1.0 image (before it was patched) to discover this escalation path by with query(process:zygote,process:vold,4). This query returns over 700 paths, all of which involve files, except for one, which involves a domain transition to crash_dump. Was Zygote the only daemon capable of compromising vold through the crash_dump binary? It was not, as query(_,transition:crash_dump,1,CAP_SYS_ADMIN) finds 24 other daemons that, if compromised, could achieve the same escalation. A notable daemon is installd, which handles installing untrusted APKs. installd is responsible for parsing the complicated APK file format and a exploitable vulnerability via this path could have quickly escalated into a full system compromise. We believe this highlights that the lack of granularity of CAP_SYS_ADMIN leads to an ineffective security policy. Any process with this capability can get arbitrary code execution in any other domain it can transition. We consider this to be a weakness in the capability security model, and more effort needs to be made to limit the number of processes with this. This analysis shows that BIGMAC could help policy writers determine the impact of a policy misconfiguration while taking into account Linux capabilities. This finding is not obvious when analyzing the MAC policy in isolation: Linux capabilities are a crucial part of the overall security model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Process Strength</head><p>As an attacker with control over a process and looking to privilege escalate, we would like to see all the possible avenues to write data to objects that can affect other processes. We can easily perform this query for any process by fixing the source node and having a wildcard for the target node. For example: query(untrusted_app,_,1) would find all of the objects that can be directly influenced by a process with the untrusted_app label. This query is useful as it takes into account the MAC+DAC policy to find actual writes. With this information, we can identify labels that are too strong and should be further compartmentalized. The top three strongest processes are shown in <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> for our three firmwares.</p><p>For the S8+ and G7 firmwares, init and system_server are ranked first and second. init's IPC edges consist of property service writes and transitions to new domains. The exception is that it has a socket open to logd and vold. The rest of its writes are to critical system files, making it file focused. system_server is heavily focused on IPC through binder and is also home to hundreds of services. This makes it a large target for attackers considering its key role in mediating application IPC. We argue that a single SELinux label with this much cross-domain write-strength is a risk to the whole system's integrity. For example, while system_server does not run as root, many services implicitly trust IPC from it. Using its binder connection to vold, it could request any mounting operation. Worse, it has the capability of CAP_SYS_MODULE allowing it to load arbitrary kernel modules. Based upon this finding, we believe system_server must be refactored into smaller services. As system_server is able to load kernel modules, we argue that it is actually in the system's TCB, yet it is too monolithic to be trustworthy. For the lpm process on the S8+ image, it is Samsung's charging daemon. All writable objects are focused on USB and SysFS power management. hal_usb_default on the LG G7 is a similar story. It only talks to system_server and hwservice_manager. All other writes are to USB files and SysFS. This analysis demonstrates that BIGMAC can be used to assist in identifying and triaging over-privileged processes, leading to improved and more modular polices at the MAC, DAC, and CAP layer.</p><p>Process Attack Surface Our query_mac_dac query interface implements a useful way to study the attack surface of a given process node. We define all possible paths for IPC as an attack surface of a given process. By ignoring the starting node (wildcard) and specifying the target node, we are able to find all the paths leading to the target node. In this case, we focus on system_server to further demonstrate how monolithic it is. By limiting the cut-off to be 1, we get all the objects (IPC &amp; files) that the target process can read from. Cut-off 2 finds all possible paths to the target, including the ones found by  <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Writable # IPC  S8+  init  2,066  296  system_server  1,398  458  lpm  634  8  G7  init  1,233  418  system_server  573  368  hal_usb_default 508  19   Table 3</ref>: A process strength query where we find all the writable adjacent objects to each process.</p><p>Query (S8+) # Paths # IPC Uniq. IPC query(_,system_server,1) 9,853 --query(_,system_server,2) 12,681 2,814 716 Query (G7) # Paths # IPC Uniq. IPC query(_,system_server,1) 11,844 --query(_,system_server,2) 13,759 1,875 564 <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>: A combination of BIGMAC queries to find all unique IPC paths and IPC objects in system_server.</p><p>cut-off 1. This finds all the writers of those objects (if any) and eliminates all read-only objects. As a result, the subtraction of these two query response provides us all possible IPC for a target, as shown in <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>. With these paths, we can look at the shared object between the writer and reader. This is our set of unique IPC objects. With the list of paths, we can perform an "IPC diff" to determine the OEM-specific IPC objects and paths. These are likely to be less audited than upstream AOSP IPC. With this IPC diff, we now know the OEM-specific IPC and can further filter out AOSP IPC paths. For this analysis, we are interested in which IPC paths are writable from an untrusted_app (UA). Using a Linux basic text processing and manual inspection, we identified some suspect paths.</p><p>LG has 11 UA-reachable IPCs. Of those, we discovered that a UA is allowed to connect to an LG-specific kernel monitoring service as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">Figure 7</ref>. The MAC nor DAC policy forbid this. This service allows applications to receive information, such as integrity checks, from the running kernel. Further investigation into the service's Binder proxy interface shows that an additional system-app only middleware check is performed at each proxied call. If any of the proxied calls were missing this middleware check, the service would be accessible from any application. Changing the MAC policy to only allow the system_app type instead of untrusted_app would increase the defense in-depth for this service, in case it exposes a vulnerability in the future. We disclosed this finding to LG, but it is unclear if they will implement the fix as they are deprecating the service going forward.</p><p>On the Samsung S8+ image, we discover 58 UA reachable, OEM-unique IPCs. This demonstrates the vast amount of vendor customizations that are made to an already large system_server. Capability Search Our query_mac_dac_cap query interface provides a way to find an attack path achieving a certain capability in the ending process node within the path. Some capabilities are more dangerous than others, such as CAP_DAC_OVERRIDE and CAP_SYS_ADMIN. Possessing one or more of these capabilities increases the strength of an attacker and improves their odds at finding additional escalation paths.</p><p>In our case, we look at the untrusted_app on the S8+ and LG G7 to see how they could achieve additional capabilities in one hop. We limit the cut-off to be 2, focusing on other processes which can directly communicate with the app (e.g., via binder). We run two queries on both images: query(untrusted_app,_,2,CAP_SYS_MODULE) and query(untrusted_app,_,2,CAP_DAC_OVERRIDE).</p><p>For the LG G7, an app can achieve DAC override via binder by compromising netd or zygote (both are running as root with all capabilities). For SYS_MODULE, it would have to target system_server via binder. Letting untrusted_app speak to root-level processes via IPC is concerning and indicates an SELinux over-permission. For the Samsung S8+, the paths found are the same, except for three OEM-specific paths to the hal_iop_default, hal_perf_default, healthd processes. All three are running as root with all capabilities. Additionally, in the default AOSP SELinux policy, none are allowed to talk to the untrusted_app domain via binder requests. As such, we believe that these direct paths should be eliminated and instead rely on a more trusted proxy for interaction.</p><p>External Attack Surface Our query_mac_dac_cap_ext interface enables studying external attack surfaces, such as USB, Bluetooth, and modem. By wildcarding the starting node and fixing the target node as a process, we use this query interface to understand the reachability to a certain process from external connections. Fixing the cut-off to be 1 and ignoring the capability option within a query, we find all direct connections between a process and external sources. In our case, we choose the AT distributor process in Samsung S8+ as the target.</p><p>As shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 5</ref>, the AT distributor process has direct connections with USB, Bluetooth, and Modem. There are 25, 7, and 31 unique device and sysfs files respectively that the process can access and Query # Paths query(_,at_distributor,1,_,usb) 29 query(_,at_distributor,1,_,bluetooth) 7 query(_,at_distributor,1,_,modem) 31 query(_,at_distributor,1,_,nfc) 0 Our query demonstrates that while no AT commands likely flow from NFC, USB, Bluetooth, and the modem are areas for further investigation. The large number of paths from the USB and modem demonstrate that native daemons, like the AT distributor, may be prime targets for external exploitation from peripherals.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Discussion</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">BigMAC for OEMs, Policy Writers, Auditors, and App Developers</head><p>BIGMAC, while primarily focused on firmware, will also work from rooted developer devices. An OEM could leverage this by integrating it into their build pipeline for debugging policy misconfigurations on actual devices. It would act as a last-mile check on the "actualized" security policy for the system. For example, imagine there is a rule stating that untrusted applications can never taint a root level process directly without a sanitization step (such as through a trusted process). A static BIGMAC query of the form query(untrusted_app,_,uid=0,2) could be used to find all short paths where an app can write to a file that can then be read by a root process. This file can be a regular file, a socket, or service. This list of paths could be compared against a whitelist or cause a failure outright if no paths are to be allowed. By having this query execute after a build, policy misconfigurations could be caught before release, even if their causes were not immediately obvious at the individual MAC/DAC/CAP policy layers. Effectively, BIGMAC could be come a part of Android's compatibility test suite (CTS) which performs many run-time checks already. Beyond the build pipeline, BIGMAC is extensible and able to give insight into the many policy layers. For example, consider an OEM that has heard about a zero day vulnerability (no public CVE yet) being used in the wild but only knows some of the details, such as "it's triggered from an app" and "it affects system_server". Using BIGMAC, they would be able to query all of the attack paths from an application to this daemon and use it to narrow down on the potential attack avenue: query(untrusted_app,system_server,2). They would do this by triaging individual paths found. The alternative without BIGMAC would mean manually auditing all of the security policies one by one without a joint perspective.</p><p>Policy writers would be able to use BIGMAC to debug permission violations at the MAC+DAC+CAP layers. Additionally, they would be able to use it to determine the attack surface of a process to further focus their fuzzing and hardening efforts. Also, when analyzing CVEs, BIGMAC would aid in finding more semantically similar violations given a query pattern. Security researchers would use BIGMAC to understand how processes interact via IPC and files to narrow down where to look for vulnerabilities.</p><p>Auditors could use BIGMAC's firmware extraction capabilities to easily comprehend the running system's security policy (or if they have a physical device with root, extract it dynamically). Previously, auditors would have to manually extract the firmware, decompile the SELinux policy, likely use grep or similar tools to find the relevant types for the process, then have to keep in mind the DAC and CAP policies simultaneously. This burdens the auditor, especially given the large semantic gaps between each policy, and can potentially lead to errors given the amount of manual analysis required. With BIGMAC, their analysis of system daemons will be greatly sped up. Instead of having to reason about what objects these daemons can affect, BIGMAC can print out a report for individual daemons or the links between them automatically. The fully-instantiated graph of BIGMAC boils down the policies to what a running kernel would see instead of a policy writer.</p><p>Although BIGMAC is mainly designed for auditors and OEMs, app developers could use BIGMAC to determine why they are getting permission denied errors, assess their application's data and its potential for accidental exposure to other apps via DAC (e.g., when writing files to the SDCard), to aid in porting libraries that rely on file system assumptions (such as permissions) which do not hold on Android.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Limitations</head><p>With only static information available, BIGMAC is limited by the security policy evident in the metadata and configuration files. In reality, a large portion of Android's security model, especially when it comes to IPC communication, relies on a significant amount of access control checks at API boundaries. These checks are a crucial part of middleware permissions and BIGMAC does not not recover a database of these. Previous work has extensively covered middleware permissions <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">6,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">14,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">20,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">27,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">28,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">36]</ref> and as such we instead focus on developing a fine-grained model of Linuxbased security policy. Loss of precision arises from the lack of insight into process behavior. As such, we infer potential IPC objects that exist at runtime, but it is possible that these endpoints are unused or managed by access control differently. Processes are able to create, remove, and change the security state of files at runtime, in addition to creating new instances of themselves at will. These dynamic changes are difficult to capture statically and we avoid making over-permissive assumptions. For example, we may know that a process spawns from init with certain credentials, but it is unclear if it will drop these privileges dynamically. This was the primary source of process DAC/CAP mismatches found during the ground truth evaluation. Processes will start as root temporarily, then setuid to a lower privileged Android ID. A potential solution to this issue is to perform binary static analysis using a tool with a powerful Intermediate Language (IL) such as Binary Ninja. 8 Using this IL, we could determine all the cross-references to privilege change functions like setuid and attempt to recover the arguments to them. This modification is still not free from the errors inherent with pure static analysis: the dead code problem.</p><p>BIGMAC operates on snapshots of a system's access control state. It is possible that a process could modify the DAC state of files under its ownership at runtime. Because BIGMAC relies on static analysis, there is a chance that runtime DAC changes could be missed. However, because of our ability to arbitrarily model DAC permissions, we can provide a conservative worstcase scenario in the case that the owning subjects for processes protected by DAC modify their permissions. Our focus in this paper is on existing permissions found through the static image and while our tool supports these capabilities, we defer further worst-case analysis of runtime behavior to future work.</p><p>The greedy approach taken by BIGMAC to creating files from uevent configuration files in Section 4.2 can lead to extra files that do not appear on our ground-truth equivalent. The alternative is missing a significant portion of the in-use file contexts. When supporting this feature, we increased the recovery of unique file contexts from 51% to 88% on the Pixel 8.1.0. Given the importance of these device nodes for overall system security, this is a particularly notable gain.</p><p>Another aspect of Android's system security model involves the use of allowxperm rules to perform IOCTL filtering. Our model does not consider the kernel as part of the attack surface, but with nearly 40% of the current Android exploits targeting the kernel <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[32]</ref>, future work should also take these escalation paths into consideration. On the kernel side, new versions of Android use eBPF SECCOMP to create sandbox profiles for untrusted applications. In our model, we only consider Supporting SECCOMP and allowxperm would require minor additional engineering work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Related Work</head><p>SELinux Policy Analysis Creating SELinux policies is nontrivial; as such, improving policy analysis has been a topic of significant research. One of the earliest tools in this space was Gokyo <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[25]</ref>, which originally considered SELinux policies and subsequently expanded to allow computing of multiple access control spaces <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[26]</ref>. Our work differs in that we consider DAC and Linux capabilities in addition to MAC policies. <ref type="bibr">Hicks et al. released PALMS [23]</ref>, a Prolog tool for specifying MLS policy in SELinux. We similarly use Prolog for reasoning over policy; while MLS is interesting and a topic of future support for BigMAC, in Android it is primarily enabled in Mobile Device Management (MDM) contexts, which we do not model. Chen et al. examined the overall protection quality of different SELinux-enabled operating systems by creating Vul-SAN <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. VulSAN used logic programming to create attackgraphs to help compare the difficulty of attack scenarios between operating systems. SCIATool integrates different methods of policy analysis together in a framework for querying policies <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[43]</ref> SEGrapher and V3SPA approach the problem of policy analysis visually and tackle many of the issues inherent in drawing and laying out large graphs with many edges <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[21,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">29]</ref>. Policy visualization gives insight into the relationships within and between policies. V3SPA also provides a visual diffing tool for two policies. Our work does not yet create interactive graphs, but we employ attribute clustering to avoid edgeexplosion from attribute expansion. Eatman et al. surveyed existing policy analysis frameworks and determined that a front-end, formally specified, policy language should be created for specifying SELinux rules <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref>. Existing tools have mostly employed variants of Prolog or other custom implementations to perform analysis. Effectively, researchers are already abstracting away from SELinux to perform useful analysis.</p><p>Mobile Security Policy Analysis The complexities of creating and maintaining SELinux policies has carried over to Android since its introduction of SEAndroid in 2013 <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[37]</ref>. Reshetova et al. performed one of the initial analyses of real SEAndroid policies from actual devices <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[34]</ref>. To achieve this, they developed a tool called SEAndroid Analytics Library (SEAL) to help collect SELinux contexts from running devices for further analysis. Using SEAL requires access to a rooted or developer device, which limits the ability to scale up the analysis to many vendors or devices. Chen et al. analyzed over ten SEAndroid policies for different classes of misconfiguration <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. They discovered that the combination of DAC and MAC policies could interact in unintended ways, leading to compositional over-privilege, amongst other errors. This work also required running devices running debug builds in order to extract security policies and maxed out at Android 6.0, which was widely available at that time. To help policy writers create new allow rules, EASEAndroid <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[41]</ref> developed a machine learning model to help classify Access Vector Cache (AVC) denials from collected SEAndroid logs as important or spurious.</p><p>Another approach has been to analyze the source code of SEAndroid policies for common misconfigurations through the tools SELint and SPOKE <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[33,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">40]</ref>. Our approach does not assume access to SEAndroid policy source code, as most policies are distributed in a compiled form and considered proprietary.</p><p>A historical analysis of the SEAndroid policy evolution focusing on policy complexity <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[24]</ref> is also proposed based on Git commit history. There has also been previous work on Android privilege escalations and how to mitigate them using a MAC approach <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>, but this was before SEAndroid was implemented and enforced on the platform. Similarly, prior to the development of SEAndroid, Muthukumaran et al. demonstrated a technique for enforcing CW-Lite, a lighter-weight approach to Clark-Wilson integrity <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[35]</ref>, on OpenMoko mobile devices running with an SELinux-enhanced kernel <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[31]</ref>.</p><p>Most mobile policy analysis has been focused on Android, but SandScout <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref> and iOracle <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref> focus on analyzing Apple iOS Sandbox profiles. SandScout decompiles these profiles from iOS firmware into a Prolog representation and create queries to discover new vulnerabilities used by previously released jailbreaks. iOracle expands upon this work by analyzing the whole iOS security model, including capabilities and UNIX permissions. Their work requires dynamic analysis for data collection, while BIGMAC relies solely on static analysis with domain knowledge. Additionally, BIGMAC incorporates Linux capabilities, DAC, and MAC together in a single graph for the whole-system, which previous iOS policy work does not replicate.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8">Conclusion</head><p>We present BIGMAC, a new security policy analysis framework for Android. BIGMAC can rebuild the running system state from firmware images without the need for physical devices. We build an attack-graph in BIGMAC and a logic-based query engine combining MAC, DAC, capabilities, and external attack surface analysis. We can thus find attack paths between processes and from external sources to audit Android security policies.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A Appendix</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A.1 Implementation Details</head><p>Graph Building Once we have a complete policy database saved, we may reload it and begin processing it how we like. In our case, we instantiate attack-graphs, therefore we employ NetworkX for constructing and traversing graphs. We load the saved SEPolicy image, covert it to nodes and labeled edges and also save this for future processing. We also employ Graphviz for visualizing our subject, process, and attack-graphs using the sfdp <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[42]</ref> program, which has no trouble laying out large graphs.</p><p>For our dataflow graph, we needed to handle a few quirks in our object model. One of these was splitting of character device files into separate read and write objects. Without doing this, processes P 1 and P 2 that can write and read from O 1 , P 1 ←→ O 1 ←→ P 2 , have an transitive dataflow to each other. This is not correct, therefore we split the object into a read-only and write-only versions: P 1 −→ O 1W ←− P 2 , P 1 ←− O 1R −→ P 2 . These new nodes are leaf nodes, preventing this unintended flow.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A.2 Tables</head><p>USB Attack Surface With our instantiated graph, we tag certain file objects, specifically device nodes relating to USB input and output. We then query our graph searching for all paths from these USB sources to a single or multiple processes. This allows us to get insight into the processes that can be directly affected by USB data. In our case, we chose the /dev/ttyUSB0 device file which connects with external USB devices. By fixing the cut-off to be 1, we are able to find all processes that are able to directly read from this device file.</p><p>As shown in <ref type="table">Table 6</ref>, a USB connection can directly reach 25 unique processes, such as DMM-daemon, adbd, remotedisplay, etc. Among these 25 processes, 22 have the CAP_DAC_OVERRIDE capability, and 22 have the CAP_SYS_ADMIN capability. The data demonstrates that USB as an external attack surface interacts with many privileged processes. While some of the daemons have clear reasons to talk with USB, e.g., adbd, others might not be obvious, e.g., sensors. To reduce the USB attack surface, the first question we need to ask is if it is reasonable to expose a native process to USB connections. We also need to constrain the capabilities within the processes exposed to external USB connections.</p><p>Type Reduction With our fully instantiated graph, we are able to distinguish between active and inactive subject domains and file contexts. System-wide security policies are required to describe every possible type transition and access vector by nature. In reality, many of these edges will never be taken on a real system due to its specific configuration. BIGMAC, by design is able to narrow in on the most important domains by finding mappings between them and the underlying filesystem (backing files). If an example of a file is not found, we can prune this type completely. For processes, if a backing executable is not found then, this process is abstract and is not able to be executed on a real system. This effectively prunes the set of types to be considered along with their corresponding access vector rules. In <ref type="table">Table 7</ref>, we see the effect that BIGMAC has in type reduction from a raw SEPolicy and show that we are able to reduce the set of subject types considered by at a minimum 12% and at a maximum 52%. The reduction varies by OEM and Android version. Some OEMs share a single SEPolicy for all devices and label only the necessary types during the image building, while others will have device-specific policies that are more tailored and compact. For file contexts, not all paths that can be assigned a context will exist all at once or at all, leading to a significant reduction in file types to instantiate. Pure policy analysis does not consider the true instantiation of a system, which may lead to discovering problems that do not affect real systems due to dead-types.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Query</head><p># Paths query(/dev/ttyUSB0,_,1) 25 query(/dev/ttyUSB0,_,1,CAP_DAC_OVERRIDE) 22 query(/dev/ttyUSB0,_,1,CAP_SYS_ADMIN) 22 <ref type="table">Table 6</ref>: Different queries on the starting node /dev/ttyUSB0, which can be reached via external USB connections. The cutoff 1 specifies the direction connection between processes and the device file. The number of paths also represents the unique number of processes.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: The relationship between key Android processes and their DAC and MAC configuration files.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: An overview of BIGMAC's layers of abstraction from device firmware all the way to kernel object recovery.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: The key graph derivations used by BIGMAC to create a fully-instantiated attack graph, G a .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: A comparison of BIGMAC's process recovery and versus running devices. In figure (a), "Correct" (TP) shows how many recovered processes had 100% identical metadata (excluding process IDs) as compared to a running phone. "Different DAC/Cap." (TP/FP) is where a process was matched to a running device process, but parts of the DAC/capabilities were different. "Extra" (FP) shows the processes BIGMAC over-approximated and were not running on the real running system during the snapshot. In figure (b), "Pair Found" (TP) shows how many recovered and real processes were able to be matched via executable and SELinux context. "Missing Native" (FN) are the native daemons that were not instantiated. "Missing App" (FN) are the Zygote-children (applications) that are not currently recovered by BIGMAC.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5: Three paths that were discarded due to DAC filtering on the S8+ image.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Figure 6: A diagram of the escalation path taken by CVE-2018-9488 to compromise vold.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Firmware Process #</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Figure 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Figure 7: A diagram of the suspicious IPC path discovered on the LG firmware.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>The results of the layered query filtering performed for 
the untrusted_app (abbreviated to ua) to vold attack surface 
with a cutoff of four. 

process:untrusted app 

/data/media &lt;drwxrwx---media rw media rw&gt; 
/data/knox/sdcard &lt;drwxrwx---media rw media rw&gt; 
/data/knox/secure fs/enc media &lt;drwxrwx--x system system&gt; 

process:vold 

media rw data file:write 

media rw data file:read 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Different queries on different external attack surface 
for the at_distributor process. 

connect to external devices, including /dev/mtp/usb, 
/dev/block/platform/soc/7464900.sdhci, /dev/mdm, 
etc. The AT distributor is mainly responsible for distributing 
AT commands to different native daemons and applications. 
</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> If a rooted device is available (such as on a developer phone), BIGMAC can work from runtime security policies too.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> The only subject-subject edges are self-edges (domain can interact with itself), file descriptor transfer (fd:use), and ptracing.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> SETools does not recover the policy source, but it recovers the effective policy after the source has had all of its macros expanded, comments removed, and neverallow rules checked.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="7"> We do not know when or if a process will fork or exec. Doing so would require binary analysis or an emulator.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="8"> https://binary.ninja</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This work was partially supported by the National Science Foundation CNS-1815883 and by the Semiconductor Research Corporation (SRC).</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Read Access Vectors</head></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">PScout: Analyzing the Android Permission Specification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">W Y</forename><surname>Au</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2012 ACM conference on Computer and communications security, CCS &apos;12</title>
		<meeting>the 2012 ACM conference on Computer and communications security, CCS &apos;12</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="217" to="228" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scippa: System-centric IPC Provenance on Android</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Backes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bugiel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gerling</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 30th Annual Computer Security Applications Conference, ACSAC &apos;14</title>
		<meeting>the 30th Annual Computer Security Applications Conference, ACSAC &apos;14<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="36" to="45" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Shastry. Towards Taming Privilege-Escalation Attacks on Android</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bugiel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Davi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Dmitrienko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Fischer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A.-R</forename><surname>Sadeghi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NDSS</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">19</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Analysis of SEAndroid Policies: Combining MAC and DAC in Android</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Enck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Aafer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 33rd Annual Computer Security Applications Conference, ACSAC 2017</title>
		<meeting>the 33rd Annual Computer Security Applications Conference, ACSAC 2017<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="553" to="565" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Analyzing and Comparing the Protection Quality of Security Enhanced Operating Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Mao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NDSS</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="11" to="16" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Analyzing Interapplication Communication in Android</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Chin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Felt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Greenwood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Wagner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 9th International Conference on Mobile Systems, Applications, and Services, MobiSys &apos;11</title>
		<meeting>the 9th International Conference on Mobile Systems, Applications, and Services, MobiSys &apos;11<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="239" to="252" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">SETools: SELinux Policy Analysis Tools v4</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Pebenito</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://github.com/SELinuxProject/setools" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018-03" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automated Evaluation of Access Control Policies in iOS</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Deshotels</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Deaconescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Carabas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Manda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Enck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Chiroiu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A.-R</forename><surname>Sadeghi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2018 on Asia Conference on Computer and Communications Security, ASIACCS &apos;18</title>
		<meeting>the 2018 on Asia Conference on Computer and Communications Security, ASIACCS &apos;18<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="117" to="131" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">SandScout: Automatic Detection of Flaws in iOS Sandbox Profiles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Deshotels</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Deaconescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Chiroiu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Davi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Enck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A.-R</forename><surname>Sadeghi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2016 ACM SIGSAC Conference on Computer and Communications Security, CCS &apos;16</title>
		<meeting>the 2016 ACM SIGSAC Conference on Computer and Communications Security, CCS &apos;16<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="704" to="716" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quire: Lightweight provenance for smart phone operating systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Dietz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Shekhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Pisetsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Wallach</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">USENIX Security Symposium</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">3</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Review of Existing Analysis Tools for SELinux Security Policies: Challenges and a Proposed Solution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Eaman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Sistany</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Felty</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">E-Technologies: Embracing the Internet of Things, Lecture Notes in Business Information Processing</title>
		<editor>E. Aïmeur, U. Ruhi, and M. Weiss</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="116" to="135" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Enck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Gilbert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Tendulkar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B.-G</forename><surname>Chun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Cox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Jung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Mcdaniel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Sheth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">TaintDroid: An Information-Flow Tracking System for Realtime Privacy Monitoring on Smartphones</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-06" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">29</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding android security</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Enck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ongtang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Mcdaniel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Secur. Privacy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="50" to="57" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Android Permissions Demystified</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Felt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Chin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Hanna</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Wagner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 18th ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security, CCS &apos;11</title>
		<meeting>the 18th ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security, CCS &apos;11<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="627" to="638" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Permission Re-Delegation: Attacks and Defenses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Felt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Moshchuk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Hanna</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Chin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">USENIX Security Symposium</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page">88</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Market Share Alert: Preliminary, Mobile Phones, Worldwide</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Gartner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.gartner.com/doc/3881811/market-share-alert-preliminary-mobile" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018-07" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Android Init Language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Google</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://android.googlesource.com/platform/system/core/+/master/init/README.md" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">SELinux for Android 8.0</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Google</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://source.android.com/security/selinux/images/SELinux_Treble.pdf" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Security Updates and Resources</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Google</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://source.android.com/security/overview/updates-resources" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019-08" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">ACMiner: Extraction and Analysis of Authorization Checks in Android&apos;s Middleware</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Gorski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Andow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Nadkarni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Manandhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Enck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Bodden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bartel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Ninth ACM Conference on Data and Application Security and Privacy, CODASPY &apos;19</title>
		<meeting>the Ninth ACM Conference on Data and Application Security and Privacy, CODASPY &apos;19<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA; Richardson, Texas, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="36" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">V3SPA: A visual analysis, exploration, and diffing tool for SELinux and SEAndroid security policies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Gove</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2016 IEEE Symposium on Visualization for Cyber Security (VizSec)</title>
		<editor>22] S. E. Hallyn and A. G. Morgan</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Linux capabilities: making them work</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A logical specification and analysis for SELinux MLS policy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Hicks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Rueda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>St</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Clair</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Jaeger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mcdaniel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Trans. Inf. Syst. Secur</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">31</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010-07" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An historical analysis of the seandroid policy evolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Im</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Wallach</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 34th Annual Computer Security Applications Conference</title>
		<meeting>the 34th Annual Computer Security Applications Conference</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="629" to="640" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Analyzing Integrity Protection in the SELinux Example Policy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Jaeger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Sailer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">USENIX Security Symposium</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Policy management using access control spaces</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Jaeger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Sailer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Trans. Info. Sys. Sec</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="327" to="364" />
			<date type="published" when="2003-08" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Run-Time Enforcement of InformationFlow Properties on Android</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Jia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Aljuraidan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Fragkaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Bauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Stroucken</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Fukushima</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Kiyomoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Miyake</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Computer Security -ESORICS 2013</title>
		<editor>J. Crampton, S. Jajodia, and K. Mayes</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Berlin Heidelberg</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="775" to="792" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">QuantDroid: Quantitative approach towards mitigating privilege escalation on Android</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Markmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Gessner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Westhoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2013 IEEE International Conference on Communications (ICC)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2144" to="2149" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">SEGrapher: Visualization-based SELinux policy analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Marouf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Shehab</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">4th Symposium on Configuration Analytics and Automation (SAFECONFIG)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011-10" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Protecting the integrity of trusted applications in mobile phone systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Muthukumaran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Schiffman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hassan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sawani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Rao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Jaeger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<publisher>Security and Communication Networks</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="633" to="650" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Honey, I Shrunk the Attack Surface -Adventures in Android Security Hardening. Black Hat</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nick</forename><surname>Kralevich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017-07" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Reshetova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Bonazzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Asokan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1608.02339</idno>
		<idno>arXiv: 1608.02339</idno>
		<title level="m">SELint: an SEAndroid policy analysis tool</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="47" to="58" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Reshetova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Bonazzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Nyman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Borgaonkar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Asokan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1510.05497</idno>
		<idno>arXiv: 1510.05497</idno>
		<title level="m">Characterizing SEAndroid Policies in the Wild</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015-10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automted Information-Flow Integrity Verification for Security-Critical Applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Shankar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Jaeger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Sailer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ISOC Network and Distributed Systems Security Symposium (NDSS)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Misuse of Android Unix Domain Sockets and Security Implications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Shao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Jia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Qian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Mao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2016 ACM SIGSAC Conference on Computer and Communications Security, CCS &apos;16</title>
		<meeting>the 2016 ACM SIGSAC Conference on Computer and Communications Security, CCS &apos;16<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="80" to="91" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Security Enhanced (SE) Android: Bringing Flexible MAC to Android</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Smalley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Craig</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NDSS</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20" to="38" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Implementing selinux as a linux security module</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Smalley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Vance</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Salamon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">NAI Labs Report</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">139</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">ATtention Spanned: Comprehensive Vulnerability Analysis of AT Commands Within the Android Ecosystem</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Tian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Hernandez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Frost</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Ruales</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Butler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Traynor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Vijayakumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Harrison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rahmati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Grace</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">27th USENIX Security Symposium (USENIX Security 18)</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Washington, D.C.</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>USENIX Association</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="351" to="366" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">SPOKE: Scalable Knowledge Collection and Attack Surface Analysis of Access Control Policy for Security Enhanced Android</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Azab</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Enck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Ning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Shen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2017 ACM on Asia Conference on Computer and Communications Security, ASIA CCS &apos;17</title>
		<meeting>the 2017 ACM on Asia Conference on Computer and Communications Security, ASIA CCS &apos;17<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="612" to="624" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Easeandroid: Automatic policy analysis and refinement for security enhanced android via large-scale semi-supervised learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Enck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Reeves</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Ning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Azab</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">24th USENIX Security Symposium (USENIX Security 15)</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Washington, D.C.</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>USENIX Association</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="351" to="366" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scalable force directed graph layout algorithms using fast multipole methods</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Yunis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Yokota</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ahmadia</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2012 11th International Symposium on Parallel and Distributed Computing</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="180" to="187" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">SCIATool: A Tool for Analyzing SELinux Policies Based on Access Control Spaces, Information Flows and CPNs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Zhai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">In</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Yung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Trusted Systems, Lecture Notes in Computer Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="294" to="309" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
