<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/atharsefid/Desktop/grobid-0.5.3/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.3" ident="GROBID" when="2020-09-29T04:25+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Standard Metrics and Scenarios for Usable Authentication</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Scott</forename><surname>Ruoti</surname></persName>
							<email>scott.ruoti@isrl.byu.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Brigham Young University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Brigham Young University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kent</forename><surname>Seamons</surname></persName>
							<email>seamons@cs.byu.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Brigham Young University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Brigham Young University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Standard Metrics and Scenarios for Usable Authentication</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">INTRODUCTION</head><p>There is a constant flow of new authentication schemes proposed in the literature. In the past, most proposed schemes were not evaluated empirically, though in recent years there has been an increase in the number of authentication systems that have undergone a user study. Still, most of these user studies employ ad-hoc metrics (e.g., task completion time) and a unique scenario. Bonneau et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref> included usability criteria in their heuristic evaluation of various types of web authentication mechanisms.</p><p>The use of ad hoc and disparate metrics and scenarios makes it difficult to compare the relative merit of these various proposals. This produces disjointed results that hinder our ability to make more rapid, scientific progress toward usable authentication systems. Based on our experience, we believe that the community would benefit significantly from the adoption of standard metrics and scenarios for use in the empirical evaluation of authentication schemes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">DIRECT COMPARISON</head><p>Adoption of standard metrics and scenarios in usability studies of authentication systems would allow the results to be directly compared. This would bring value to the community by allowing us to determine whether we are making systematic progress towards more usable and secure authentication, or whether we are all just "spinning our wheels."</p><p>Our opinions are based on our study comparing the usability of seven web authentication systems <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref>. The systems span three categories: federated single sign-on (Google OAuth 2.0, Facebook Connect, Mozilla Personas), email-based identification and authentication <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref> (SAW <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref>, Hatchet <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref>), and QR-code-based (WebTicket <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>, Snap2Pass <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>).</p><p>Our usability studies were organized in a tournament structure. In the preliminary round, we conducted within-subject tests for all the systems in a single category (e.g., federated). The winner from each category advanced to a championship round where we conducted a within-subjects usability test of three heterogeneous systems. To our knowledge, this was Copyright is held by the author/owner. Permission to make digital or hard copies of all or part of this work for personal or classroom use is granted without fee. Symposium on Usable Privacy and Security (SOUPS) 2016, June <ref type="bibr">22-24, 2016, Denver, Colorado.</ref> the first user study to compare a heterogeneous collection of web-authentication systems.</p><p>Evaluating each system using common metrics and scenarios provided a stronger basis for directly comparing their usability. Our results showed that users prefer federated, single sign-on and Snap2Pass. Our results also demonstrated that several authentication proposals (SAW, Hatchet, WebTicket) were rated as less usable than existing password-based authentication schemes. Interestingly, WebTicket had previously been evaluated with a user study, and our study found the same usability benefits and pitfalls. What our study added was an understanding of where WebTicket fit in the greater ecosystem of authentication schemes; precisely the benefit provided by comparing systems in a standardized manner.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Standard Metrics</head><p>Some metrics used in prior studies include task completion time, error rates, and recall rates. We promote the use of the System Usability Scale (SUS) as a standard metric for calculating the relative usability of authentication schemes. SUS <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">4]</ref> is a standard metric from the usability literature, and has been used in hundreds of usability studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. Our experience has also shown that a system's SUS score is consistent across different sets of users <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>. Moreover, Tullis and Stetson compare SUS to four other usability metrics (three standard metrics from the usability literature and their own proprietary measure) and determined that SUS gives the most reliable results <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref>.</p><p>The SUS metric is a single numeric score from 0, the least usable, to 100, the most usable, that provides a rough estimate of a system's overall usability. To calculate a system's SUS score, participants first interact with the system and then answer ten questions relating to their experience . Answers are given using a five-point Likert scale (strongly agree to strongly disagree). The questions alternate between positive and negative statements about the system being tested. Participants' answers are assigned a scalar value and then summed to produce the overall SUS score, and the system with the highest average SUS score is the most usable.</p><p>SUS produces a numeric score for a non-numeric measure (i.e., usability), making it difficult to intuitively understand how usable a system is based solely on its SUS score. As part of an empirical evaluation of SUS, Bangor et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref> reviewed SUS evaluations of 206 different systems and compared these scores against objective measurements of the various systems' success in order to derive adjective-based <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>: Adjective-based ratings to help interpret SUS scores ratings for SUS scores. We have summarized these ratings and their correlation to SUS scores in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>.</p><p>In our study, we found that SUS was a strong predictor of participants' preferred authentication schemes, and was consistent across multiple studies. As such, SUS is a promising standard metric for comparing authentication schemes. However, SUS was not designed for usable security. One potential direction is to extend SUS with questions targeted toward usable security. At the workshop, we are interested in comparing our experiences to others that have used standard metrics, and also discussing the pros and cons of the various standard metrics that are available.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Standard Scenarios</head><p>As part of our web authentication user studies, we built two websites: a forum website where users could get help with smartphones, 1 and a bank website. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2</ref> We chose these two types of websites because they represented diametrically different information assurance needs. We then tested each of the seven systems in the context of these websites. The reason for doing this was to limit the number of confounding factors. The only differences between the systems were due to authentication system details and not the application.</p><p>We have made the source code for these websites publicly available 3 so that others can re-use them to test other authentication systems. The sharing of implementations of compelling use case scenarios can reduce the start-up costs to run usability studies for new authentication system proposals. We are interested in identifying alternative scenarios for web-based authentication, as well as compelling scenarios for emerging forms of authentication.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">RECOMMENDATIONS</head><p>Based on our experience, we propose that usability studies incorporate standard metrics like SUS for vetting all new authentication proposals. In the case of SUS, we recommend that new authentication systems should exceed a baseline SUS score of 68 before receiving serious consideration. <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">4</ref> This will provide a basis to make cross-system comparisons and establish a minimum threshold for vetting new proposals. Any new system proposal that fails to achieve a sufficiently high average usability rating is very unlikely to see widespread adoption.</p><p>We should also design standard scenarios and make implementations available to researchers to reduce the effort to 1 https://forums.isrl.byu.edu 2 https://bank.isrl.byu.edu 3 https://bitbucket.org/isrlauth/battle-website 4 This is based on the SUS scores of the systems from our study. conduct usability studies; such studies will have a stronger basis for comparison across systems. Widespread adoption of these recommendations has the potential to significantly enhance our effort as a community to identify and focus on authentication systems that have the strongest potential to be usable.</p></div>		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Determining what individual SUS scores mean: Adding an adjective rating scale</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bangor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Kortum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Usability Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The quest to replace passwords: A framework for comparative evaluation of web authentication schemes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bonneau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Herley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Van Oorschot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Stajano</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Symposium on Security and Privacy</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">SUS -a quick and dirty usability scale</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Brooke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Usability Evaluation in Industry</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>CRC Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">SUS: A retrospective</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Brooke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Usability Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="29" to="40" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Secure, consumer-friendly web authentication and payments with a phone</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Dodson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Sengupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Boneh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Lam</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Conference on Mobile Computing, Applications, and Services</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Email-based identification and authentication: An alternative to pki?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Garfinkel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Security &amp; Privacy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20" to="26" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Webticket: Account management using printable tokens</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Hayashi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Pendleton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Ozenc</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
		<meeting>the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Confused Johnny: When automatic encryption leads to confusion and mistakes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ruoti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Burgon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Van Der</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Horst</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Seamons</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Ninth Symposium on Usable Privacy and Security (SOUPS)</title>
		<meeting>the Ninth Symposium on Usable Privacy and Security (SOUPS)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Authentication melee: A usability analysis of seven web authentication systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ruoti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Roberts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Seamons</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 24th International Conference on World Wide Web. International World Wide Web Conferences Steering Committee</title>
		<meeting>the 24th International Conference on World Wide Web. International World Wide Web Conferences Steering Committee</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A comparison of questionnaires for assessing website usability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Tullis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Stetson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Usability Professional Association Conference</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Simple authentication for the web</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Van Der</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Horst</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Seamons</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Third International Conference on Security and Privacy in Communication Networks (SecureComm)</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
