<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/atharsefid/Desktop/grobid-0.5.3/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.3" ident="GROBID" when="2020-09-29T04:25+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Strengthening Password-based Authentication</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Scott</forename><surname>Ruoti</surname></persName>
							<email>ruoti@isrl.byu.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Brigham Young University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Brigham Young University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Brigham Young University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeff</forename><surname>Andersen</surname></persName>
							<email>andersen@isrl.byu.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Brigham Young University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Brigham Young University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Brigham Young University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kent</forename><surname>Seamons</surname></persName>
							<email>seamons@cs.byu.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Brigham Young University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Brigham Young University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Brigham Young University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Strengthening Password-based Authentication</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">INTRODUCTION</head><p>Even with years of research into new authentication technologies, passwords still dominate the authentication landscape. This is due primarily to a combination of security, deployability, and usability that has been difficult to match <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[2]</ref>. While password alternatives exist, their lack of widespread adoption indicates that for the foreseeable future passwords are here to stay <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[11]</ref>.</p><p>Our research goal is to strengthen, not replace, passwordbased authentication. We focus on two serious problems with password-based authentication. First, poor security practices at the web servers leads to stolen password files that are easily compromised using an offline attack. Second, passwords are too easily stolen via phishing attacks.</p><p>Both of these problems arise because for the vast majority of authentication flows, servers require users to provide their plaintext passwords. In the case of a legitimate server receiving this password, the user must blindly trust that the server correctly salts and hashes the password. Experience, though, has shown that many websites do not follow proper password storage <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">9,</ref><ref type="bibr">1]</ref>. Moreover, there is a disconnect between perceived best practices for password storage and actual best practices <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[9]</ref>.</p><p>Even if websites were to safely store users' passwords, users would still be at risk to phishing attacks. Phishers impersonate legitimate websites in order to trick users into sending their authentication credentials to the phishing website. The problem of phishing is only compounded by password reuse, allowing a single stolen password to potentially compromise many of the user's sites.</p><p>In this paper, we describe two methods for strengthening existing password-based authentication: strong password protocols and safe password entry.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">STRONG PASSWORD PROTOCOLS</head><p>Strong password protocols are cryptographic zero-knowledge proofs that allow the user to demonstrate knowledge of their Copyright is held by the author/owner. Permission to make digital or hard copies of all or part of this work for personal or classroom use is granted without fee. Symposium on Usable Privacy and Security (SOUPS) 2016, June <ref type="bibr">22-24, 2016, Denver, Colorado.</ref> password without actually revealing that password. There are many benefits to strong password protocols. First, the user never sends the website their plaintext password, including at account registration. Instead, users only present a password verifier, which is stronger than a salted and hashed password. Second, in addition to authenticating the user to the website, strong password protocols authenticate the website to the user. Third, a phisher learns nothing about the user's password. Finally, strong passwords protocols do not require a secure connection and are safe from brute-force attacks by an active network attacker.</p><p>The adoption of strong password protocols has been stymied by patents. These patents are beginning to expire, and we believe the time may be ripe to reconsider them.</p><p>The most efficient strong password protocol is the Secure Remote Password protocol (SRP) <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[15]</ref>. In our research, we have proved the security of SRP in the random oracle model. Further, we have created a three-party, gateway-oriented <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[3]</ref> variant of SRP, that would allow it to be used in passwordbased OAuth. We believe SRP is an ideal strong password protocol, and our intention is to open source our implementation of SRP to benefit other researchers who are interested in exploring this area.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">SAFE PASSWORD ENTRY</head><p>Strong password protocols alone are insufficient to address phishing attacks because phishers will simply sidestep these protocols. To succeed, strong password protocols must be coupled with spoof-resilient password-entry interfaces where users can safely enter their passwords. Although prior research has explored this problem (PwdHash <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[12]</ref>, Password Multiplier <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[10]</ref>, Dynamic Security Skins <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[6]</ref>), there is still no optimal solution <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[4]</ref>. Our work seeks to build upon previous research and is based on the principle that users should never enter passwords into untrusted web pages, but should migrate to browser or operating system interfaces for password entry.</p><p>We intend to explore the usability and security trade-offs of the following options for deploying safe password entry interfaces.</p><p>• As a trusted web component. The browser could provide a trusted web component (e.g., &lt;srp /&gt;), that websites would be required to use in place of password fields. Still, special care would need to be taken to ensure that users could correctly identify legitimate interfaces (i.e., anti-phishing markers).</p><p>• In the browser's chrome. Interfaces in the browser's chrome are inaccessible to phishers. Still there is a risk that the phisher could try to create interfaces on their website that appear to be popdowns from the browser's chrome.</p><p>• As an operating system dialog. This approach would allow for a single safe password entry interface for all applications. Additionally, it could leverage OSspecific protections. Still, research has shown that OS dialogs can be susceptible to phishing.</p><p>In the workshop, we are interested in further discussing the benefits and risks of each approach.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">EVALUATION</head><p>Safe password entry solutions will need to be evaluated empirically to ensure that they help protect users from phishing. While there have been previous studies of anti-phishing tools, these studies have all had important limitations: <ref type="formula">(1)</ref> The studies explicitly draw users' attention to the fact that they are trying to detecting phishing, automatically elevating user awareness <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[8]</ref>. <ref type="formula">(2)</ref> The studies are lab-based, making it difficult to know how well solutions work in practice <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[14]</ref>. <ref type="formula">(3)</ref> The studies are short-term, making it difficult to know if habituation will decrease future performance <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[13]</ref>.</p><p>Our goal is to create a study that addresses each of these limitations. The three key features of our planned study are: (1) we will deceive users, having them install a system and assigning them tasks that are orthogonal to the study's true purposes, while simultaneously trying to phish their passwords; (2) we will require users to complete tasks from their own computers, according to their own schedules; and (3) we will test users' resilience to phishing over the course of several weeks.</p><p>As a first step, we intend to use our methodology to study Dynamic Security Skins (DSS) <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[7]</ref>. While it has been a decade since DSS was published, it has never been evaluated with a user study. We hope that by studying DSS we can better understand how safe password entry can be designed. Based on the results of this preliminary study, we intend to implement several prototypes for safe password entry. We will then refine these prototypes using an iterative design paradigm, where we conduct a usability study of the prototype and then address issues that arose during the study. We will continue this process until we have a prototype that successfully protects users from password phishing.</p><p>In the workshop, we are interested in discussing the study design, especially in crafting a scenario that supports phishing users' passwords in a natural fashion. A significant challenge is how to balance the goal of a real-world setting with the need to limit the harm to users if the study is to involve actual accounts and passwords.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">CONCLUSION</head><p>In this paper, we have described our vision for augmenting password-based authentication: strong password protocols coupled with safe password entry. Through the combination of these techniques, users' passwords will become resilient to negligent websites and phishers. In order to assure that we have a suitable methodology for evaluating safe password entry, we plan to run usability studies that attempt to phish users' credentials in a natural setting. We hope to discuss both safe password entry and its associated study methodology at the workshop. Additionally, we are interested in discussing how users might be protected during the transition to SRP and safe password entry; specifically, how to protect users from downgrade attacks when SRP and safe password entry are first beginning to be adopted.</p></div>		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The quest to replace passwords: A framework for comparative evaluation of web authentication schemes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bonneau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Herley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Van Oorschot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Stajano</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Symposium on Security and Privacy (SP)</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Security analysis and improvement of a gateway-oriented password-based authenticated key exchange protocol</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Byun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Lim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Communications Letters</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>IEEE</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A usability study and critique of two password managers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Chiasson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Van Oorschot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Biddle</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">15th USENIX Security Symposium</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Rockyou hack: From bad to worse</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Cubrilovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://techcrunch.com/2009/12/14/rockyou-hack-security-myspace-facebook-passwords/.Accessed2016/05/16" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The battle against phishing: Dynamic security skins</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Dhamija</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Tygar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACM International Conference Proceeding Series</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">93</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Dhamija</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Tygar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">The Battle Against Phishing : Dynamic Security Skins. Symposium on Usable Privacy and Security (SOUPS)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why phishing works</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Dhamija</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Tygar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hearst</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
		<meeting>the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An administrator&apos;s guide to internet password research</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Florêncio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Herley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Van Oorschot</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">28th Large Installation System Administration Conference (LISA14)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A convenient method for securely managing passwords</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Halderman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Waters</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Felten</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 14th international conference on World Wide Web</title>
		<meeting>the 14th international conference on World Wide Web</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A research agenda acknowledging the persistence of passwords</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Herley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Van Oorschot</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Security &amp; Privacy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stronger password authentication using browser extensions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Ross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Jackson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Miyake</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Boneh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Mitchell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 14th Usenix Security Symposium</title>
		<meeting>the 14th Usenix Security Symposium</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Learning Assigned Secrets for Unlocking Mobile Devices</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Schechter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bonneau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Do security toolbars actually prevent phishing attacks?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Garfinkel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CHI &apos;06: Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Secure Remote Password Protocol</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Symposium on Network and Distributed Systems Security NDSS 98</title>
		<meeting>the Symposium on Network and Distributed Systems Security NDSS 98</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
