<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/atharsefid/Desktop/grobid-0.5.3/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.3" ident="GROBID" when="2020-09-29T04:30+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Beliefs about Cybersecurity Rules and Passwords: A Comparison of Two Survey Samples of Cybersecurity Professionals Versus Regular Users</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ross</forename><surname>Koppel</surname></persName>
							<email>rkoppel@sas.upenn.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Sociology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Information Sciences Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Department of Computer Science Dartmouth College</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep4">Department of Computer Science Dartmouth College</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Southern</orgName>
								<address>
									<country>California</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jim</forename><surname>Blythe</surname></persName>
							<email>blythe@isi.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Sociology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Information Sciences Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Department of Computer Science Dartmouth College</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep4">Department of Computer Science Dartmouth College</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Southern</orgName>
								<address>
									<country>California</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vijay</forename><surname>Kothari</surname></persName>
							<email>vijayk@cs.dartmouth.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Sociology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Information Sciences Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Department of Computer Science Dartmouth College</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep4">Department of Computer Science Dartmouth College</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Southern</orgName>
								<address>
									<country>California</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sean</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Sociology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Information Sciences Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Department of Computer Science Dartmouth College</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep4">Department of Computer Science Dartmouth College</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Southern</orgName>
								<address>
									<country>California</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Beliefs about Cybersecurity Rules and Passwords: A Comparison of Two Survey Samples of Cybersecurity Professionals Versus Regular Users</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>1</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>In this paper we explore the differential perceptions of cybersecurity professionals and general users regarding access rules and passwords. We conducted a preliminary survey involving 28 participants: 15 cybersecurity professionals and 13 general users. We present our preliminary findings and explain how such survey data might be used to improve security in practice. We focus on user fatigue with access rules and passwords.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">INTRODUCTION</head><p>If designers and administrators of computer systems have different understandings of the purpose and value of access rules compared to the actual users of those systems, then the utility of those rules will be continually challenged. Circumvention of access policies is pandemic-often because the rules make little sense to users and because they create barriers to performing one's work and achieving the mission of the organization. To examine the differential perceptions and efficacy of cybersecurity policies, we created two parallel survey instruments to elicit the perceptions and beliefs about cybersecurity policies, rationales, and compliance.</p><p>One instrument was administered to cybersecurity professionals and one to regular users of IT systems-generally employees in firms or upper-level students who also held computer-related jobs. Most questions were identical except in a few instances where changes were required by the respondents' roles.</p><p>The findings and comparisons address the frequent circumvention of password and access rules-focusing on password creation and use. Our research is designed to inform questions about why security policy is often misdirected and why it sometimes generates unintended consequences such as security fatigueinduced circumventions-resulting in a greater attack surface instead of greater protection.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1">Background</head><p>User behavior is often at odds with security objectives, not because users are inherently bad, but because even good users subjected to fatigue-inducing security practices will be motivated to circumvent them (e.g., <ref type="bibr">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr">2]</ref>). Indeed, numerous studies are centered on understanding users' behaviors, users' motivations to engage in those behaviors, and security fatigue---including frustration and workflow impediments---that induces circumvention, many of which are concerned with passwords and access control (e.g., <ref type="bibr">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr">4,</ref><ref type="bibr">5,</ref><ref type="bibr">6,</ref><ref type="bibr">7,</ref><ref type="bibr">8,</ref><ref type="bibr">9,</ref><ref type="bibr">12]</ref>). If there's one thing to be learned from this research it is that security must be usable! The impetus for deploying usable security policies, mechanisms, and systems has led researchers to explore both general users' and cybersecurity professionals' mental models and to study the differences amongst these mental models and reality (e.g., <ref type="bibr">[10,</ref><ref type="bibr">11]</ref>). We build upon the existing literature by acquiring and analyzing new survey results on the differential perceptions of cybersecurity professionals and users regarding passwords and access rules. most often in the course of your work?" we received similar responses between the two groups, although cybersecurity professionals were three times as likely as general users to emphasize the role of "professional or industry rules." Most said senior security or IT staff set it on an enterprise-wide level. Other options, which generated few responses, were: "No idea," "Individual workplace units," or "regulators."</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Whose Logic?</head><p>When asked about the basis (logic or rationale) for setting your organization's policies on computer access rules, most general users assumed it was set by executive management or regulators (69%) and a few thought it was set by local leaders (23%). Only 15% said they didn't know. In contrast-and remarkable given their jobs-60% of the cybersecurity professionals said they didn't know who set the rules.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Users Asked?</head><p>We then asked whether users were asked for input on cybersecurity rules. Almost half, 46%, of the general users said or strongly suspected that input from users was used. In contrast, only 20% of the cybersecurity professionals said users' input was used in setting policy. That is, users were more likely to assume their input was considered in setting policy than those involved in setting those policies.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">FRUSTRATION ABOUT ACCESS POLICIES</head><p>The next question and comparison is about frustration. It has two slightly different introductory sentences, although the answer options are identical. The general user introductory sentence reads: "some of us are frustrated by access policies that appear restrictive and may interfere with our work." The cybersecurity professional introductory statement reads: "many of us are frustrated by access policies that seem to provide little if any security benefit, and are also non-responsive to the needs of users who are trying to do their jobs." Respondents rated their frustration on a Likert scale from 1 to 5 where 1 = "Not frustrated, policy seems reasonable" to 5 = "Very frustrated, policy seems arbitrary or not responsive to workflow needs."</p><p>Respondents in both groups were generally not that frustrated. However, general users were overall less delighted by security rules.</p><p>Subjects from both groups provided additional comments regarding their frustrations, including specific examples of frustrations. Cybersecurity professionals' comments were:</p><p>• "Having to login every time"</p><p>• "The requirement to change the password every 70 days."</p><p>• "Getting logged out because of timing when you're in a rush."</p><p>• "Waiting so long when turning on/off the computer as it decrypts/encrypts information."</p><p>• "Unplanned system downtime frequent mandatory password changes."</p><p>• "Having to retype my password all the time."</p><p>• "Sometimes the authentication is done with my real name; sometimes it's done with an arbitrary username I selected and sometimes it is done with [Enterprise name] ID. I often forget which is which."</p><p>• "Sometimes, there are no access to Internet and sometimes the speed is extreme slow."</p><p>• "Worrying about our servers or networks which are not protected (lab or dorm networks) being compromised."</p><p>• "Recalling multiple passwords each with different complexity rules."</p><p>• "Some workstations don't allow executable files to be run."</p><p>General users' comments were remarkably similar in tone and levels of frustration:</p><p>• "The work is delayed."</p><p>• "Sync'd credentials means that if I submit my credentials to an attempted phish, the bad guys could access more than just email, and it's bad enough when they just access email because our institution gets blacklisted and no one's email gets sent/received."</p><p>• "Passwords regularly forgotten (because they have to be changed). Delay in work (because password has changed). Confusion about usernames and passwords (multiple accounts and/or passwords) Confusion about internal and external accounts (for example Microsoft business and private accounts)." • "New employees can wait a week before full access to needed resources (training time lost) Parents frustrated because cannot pay tuition bill online until student grants parent access (FERPA) Alumni frustrated because they need an online account created by IT in order to request a transcript from Registrar. Off-site employees frustrated because their supervisor needs to request VPN and other access on their behalf."</p><p>• "I have seen people attempting to log in on public University computers and swearing that they are typing in their password correctly but are unable to access the system."</p><p>• "Frustration. Not able to do their job. Give up or don't care anymore."</p><p>• "Work delayed: 2 extra minutes like 10 times a day is true. Hate using the system. My boss says this about salesforce and deskflex."</p><p>• "I don't buy the assumption that there is an adverse effect [to cyber security]. Surely a compromised work station or exposure of sensitive data has a greater effect on productivity"?</p><p>• "Frustration, Yes, but they are constrained by some laws (FERPA, Wage laws) and constraints of supporting BYOD."</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">SENSIBILITY OF POLICY</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">How Well Thought Out is the Access Policy?</head><p>We asked both groups: "Even if you are frustrated by the access policy, do you see it as necessary to protect security, or do you see it as not well thought out, where the security benefit is less than the effort required to comply?" General users were less likely than cybersecurity professionals to view access policies as well-thought out; although no one insisted they were meaningless.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">How Sensible are the Several Rules?</head><p>When asked about management's rules regarding the many cybersecurity rules, the general users' reactions and cybersecurity professionals' reactions are often starkly different. General users' percentages are shown as the first number in each cell; the second number is the percent for cybersecurity professionals.</p><p>Cybersecurity professionals are far more likely than general users to see the value of: logon rules (87% of pros see them as sensible vs. 46% of general users), password complexity (40% v. 23%) and the logic of management granting access (31% v. 8%). Cybersecurity professionals also wrote additional comments that amplify (or contradict) the fixed-choice items. These cybersecurity professionals wrote:</p><p>• "I have to manually open doors for people from other departments, who need access to our department for meetings if someone forgets a password, it takes a long time to reset it (several hours), so time is lost"</p><p>• "Some regulations came from outside of the country and didn't quite take into consideration the local business sector. The directive of not sharing passwords / resources was also often ignored to get business done faster or remotely. People were however good about keeping client information secured, and using encryption for their devices and emails."</p><p>• "Users write down certain passwords, because they are impossible to remember (they are set by the system rather than [by] users)"</p><p>• "VPN server often denies overseas access and require user to  • "It's too hard to comply: Lots of users don't comprehend passwords requiring case switching or switching passwords every thirty days. They can't comply with log-ins for username and password"</p><p>• "In some systems, if you change the whole API to log in, it may cause many potential problems for old users."</p><p>For comparison, the general users wrote:</p><p>• "Our institution has a requirement to encrypt sensitive data stored locally and requires permission from a data owner. Alternatively, all sensitive data is permitted to be stored on institution servers. In general it's easy to comply by storing such data on a share and people general do, even when they 'have' to get permission to store it elsewhere."</p><p>• "Password and account sharing."</p><p>• "Saving sensitive data on personal hard drive."</p><p>• "Shared passwords because people don't want to ask how to delegate access to such things as calendars or cloud storage. Easy to do but requires asking or taking a few minutes to type the question into a search box."</p><p>• "Making passwords easy to guess by using alternate spellings to work around the dictionary rule. For example 'boyz' instead of 'boys' or 'bux' instead of 'bucks'"</p><p>• "1) system admins routinely ignore requirement to use separate admin accounts instead of their own account to manage systems. 2) sharing of account credentials to facilitate workflow 3) Don't change passwords and re-use passwords 4) Retain rights longer than necessary (say after a job change, they keep privileges no longer needed) "</p><p>• "Logging on to system applications to sign on to server, using time sheets, schedule rooms, kiosks, client web portals to assist with service questions."</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">CIRCUMVENTION JUSTIFICATIONS</head><p>We asked general users and cybersecurity professionals: "When do you think most personnel would find circumvention of the access rules is justified? (Check as many as applies.)" The answers are often similar-revealing the widespread awareness of circumvention and the rationales for it.</p><p>Cybersecurity professionals appear more aware than are general users of justifications for circumvention of access rules associated with the need for team-wide access and when users are taught the circumvention as part of their training. On the other hand, those pros seem less aware of many other justifications for circumvention, e.g., when rules make no logical sense to the users.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Why are the Access Rules (Perceived as) So Foolish?</head><p>We asked both general users and cybersecurity professionals questions about why so many users find access rules unreasonable. The question introduction reads: "If people have a theory or belief about why the access rules may appear nonresponsive to workflow needs, is it (can indicate multiple reasons)." As seen in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 5</ref>, both general users and cybersecurity professionals received three common questions; additionally, three questions were asked only of general users and one was asked only of cybersecurity professionals." Looking, at the first row, we see half of general users say security rules are generally reasonable, although a third report that such sanguine views are unwarranted ("unlikely"). Responses to the next question are even more disappointing. We asked general users if policy makers might not be fully aware of the workflow needs for all tasks? More than 9 out of ten (93%) report this is likely or very likely. Similarly, (row 3) almost three-fifths of general users report that those in charge of security are not concerned about general users.</p><p>Turning to the question asked only of cybersecurity professionals (row 4), we see that about two-fifths of them indicate they are likely viewed as "incompetent," by the users they are charged with protecting. On the plus side, most, two-thirds, say it's unlikely that the security chiefs are viewed as incompetent; and Critical task, e.g., saving a life, keeping the grid up 83% 79%</p><p>When the rules are so foolish that nothing else makes sense 42% 57%</p><p>Access associated with role(s) make no sense, e.g., members of the same team can't see all of the information because only some have official access 17% 36%</p><p>When allocation of access is foolish, e.g., people hired before November have access but others with similar functions and responsibilities don't 28% 9%</p><p>When everyone else is circumventing a specific rule 58% 43%</p><p>When people were officially taught to use a workaround 58% 71%</p><p>none said such negative perceptions were "very likely" to be the case.</p><p>The last three rows-where we can compare both groups' responses--offer some similarities and occasionally strong contrasts between the general users and the cybersecurity professionals. General users are slightly more likely than the pros to view security chiefs as "arrogant" (row 5). There is no clear pattern about the perceptions about externally imposed security rules. However, the last row (7) reveals that general users are considerably more likely than the pros to say cybersecurity staff use claims of "security" as an excuse to justify delays or refusals to fix problems or make changes.</p><p>The answers to these questions about the reasonableness or foolishness of cybersecurity policies offer opportunities for improvement, even if one finds general users' to be naive or misinformed. Only by understanding users' perceptions can one hope to better inform them and to better respond to their needs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">DISCUSSION</head><p>These findings illustrate widespread disappointment with current cybersecurity policies-a perception shared by both cybersecurity professionals and general users. Both groups expressed significant frustration and a sense of powerlessness over who created the rules and the ability to change them in positive ways. That said, there are clear differences in understandings and perceived solutions, often in unexpected directions. Cybersecurity professionals, for example, were more likely than general users to say they didn't know who set access rules, but they were more certain that the rules did not reflect user input. Both groups were often frustrated by access policies, and expressed long lists of examples. On the other hand, the security experts were far more likely than the general users to say that access policy was thoughtfully developed and sensible.</p><p>Both groups can easily envision conditions where they would circumvent security rules (e.g., saving a life or keeping the grid up).</p><p>Limitations: We reiterate that this is a preliminary study with a small sample size. Also, separation of the samples-as cybersecurity professionals vs. general users-is sometimes fuzzy. Also, for some items, respondents may be differentiating between their own views and their expectations of others' views. We aim to extend sample sizes and selection processes, and perform further analyses that can be used to inform cybersecurity professionals.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.">CONCLUSION</head><p>We explored the perceptions of general users and cybersecurity professionals regarding access rules and passwords. While both groups expressed dissatisfaction with access rules and passwords, their perceptions were in some ways very different; in ways that suggest misunderstandings and misdirected approaches to improved security. This preliminary study serves as a step toward informing both cybersecurity professionals and general users to ultimately improve user behavior and cybersecurity policy. A well-informed cybersecurity professional who understands the perceptions of general users will be in a better position to address users' concerns, to establish user trust, and to educate the user by dispelling user misperceptions and legitimizing existing (or new and better) security measures. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A. SURVEYS</head><p>Below, we provide both the survey we administered to general users and the one we administered to cybersecurity professionals.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A.1 Survey for General Users</head><p>The survey for general users begins on the next page.</p><p>The purpose of the study: To understand workers' frustrations and workarounds about access to computer systems. That is, we ask about barriers or inconveniences confronting personnel who seek to perform work they are supposed to accomplish. Personnel are sometimes denied access because of problems such as lost passwords, required password changes, forgetting a specific logon name, altered rules, system breakdowns, need to access the system via a different computer than usually used, etc. It is not a study of hackers or those with malicious intent. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Anonymous Survey about Computer Access Frustrations v4</head><p>ShucsSurvey 3</p><p>1. Which "industrial" sector best describes the principal business area of your organization? (Note that we do not ask for the name of your organization or any identifying information.) You may check more than one category. Other (please specify)</p><p>2. How would you define your role at your organization (may check more than one box, but indicate if that is your primary role):</p><p>Other (please specify)</p><p>3. Who sets policy about access to the computers and systems (e.g., desktops, network, laptops, servers) you use most often in the course of your work?</p><p>No idea</p><p>Individual workplace unit (e.g., my dept or my boss)</p><p>Senior security or IT staff -Set at organization-wide level</p><p>Regulatory rules (rules set by regulators)</p><p>Professional or industry rules (e.g., all engineers will password protect…)</p><p>Other (please specify)</p><p>4. To the best of your knowledge, are your organization's policies on computer access based on: (Check all that apply): 7. Some of us are frustrated by access policies that appear restrictive and may interfere with our work. On a scale from 1 to 5, where 1 = "Not frustrated, policy appears to be reasonable" to 5 = "Very frustrated, policy seems arbitrary or not responsive to workflow needs," please indicate your assessment:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Don't know</formula><formula xml:id="formula_1">1 (Thoughtfully developed) 2 3 4</formula><p>5 (More of a hindrance than anything else)</p><p>8. Even if you are frustrated by the access policy, do you see it as necessary to protect security, or do you see it as not well thought out, where the security benefit is less than the effort required to comply. 12. Do you think upper level managers understand how some computer security rules adversely affect productivity?</p><p>Yes, and they try to fix it Yes, they know but they can't fix it Yes, they know but don't care</p><p>Not sure, but suspect it's yes.</p><p>Not sure, but suspect it's no</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>No</head><p>Don't know a) Don't comply: rules are extremely difficult or impossible to complete or follow b) Not worth the effort: rules could be completed in theory but requires so much effort and/or so reduces productivity that they are routinely ignored or worked around. c) Can comply, but people routinely don't d) Can comply, and people routinely do.</p><p>13. We've all been given rules about access security. Some may be easy to follow, others may be hard or seemingly impossible to follow (e.g., instructions are incomprehensible, requires information we don't have).</p><p>Of the current access security rules with which you are familiar, please indicate the percent you estimate people (Should total to 100%):</p><p>14. If you wish, please give brief examples of the types of access rule compliance issues you were thinking about regarding the above question.</p><p>15. When do you think most personnel would find circumvention of the access rules is justified? (Check as many as applies.)</p><p>Critical task, e.g., saving a life, keeping the grid up When the rules are so foolish that nothing else makes sense</p><p>Access associated with role(s) make no sense, e.g., members of the same team can't see all of the information because only some have official access</p><p>When allocation of access is foolish, e.g., people hired before November have access but others with similar functions and responsibilities don't When everyone else is circumventing a specific rule When people were officially taught to use a workaround 16.</p><p>[Almost done, Thank you.] If you were able to change access rules to make work more efficient, but not endanger security, what recommendations might you suggest?</p><p>17. In general, thinking about computer use in your work, what is most frustrating about your job?</p><p>18. What useful computer-related practices or techniques would you teach a new colleague in the same role as yours to accomplish daily tasks?</p><p>19. Thank you very much. If you wish to add additional comments or suggestions, you may do so in the box below. Please remember not to indicate your name or the name of the organization where you may work.</p><p>9. If people have a theory or belief about why the access rules may appear non­responsive to workflow needs, is it (can indicate multiple reasons): should fix something but just say it must be as is because of "security"</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Your participation in this research study is voluntary. If you decide not to participate, you are free to stop at any time. Withdrawal will not interfere with your work or with your organization. If you have questions about your participation or rights in this research, you can discuss them with the study investigator or members of the study team. You may contact Prof. Ross Koppel, Ph.D. at the University of Pennsylvania at: rkoppel@sas.upenn.edu.</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Agriculture,</head><label></label><figDesc>Forestry, Fishing and Hunting Mining, Quarrying, and Oil and Gas Extraction Utilities (electricity, water, waste treatment, etc.) Construction Manufacturing Wholesale Trade Retail Trade Transportation and Warehousing Information Technology Finance and Insurance Real Estate and Rental and Leasing Professional, Scientific, and Technical Consulting Services Management of Companies and Enterprises Administrative &amp; Support &amp; Waste Management &amp; Remediation Services Educational Services Health Care and Social Assistance Arts, Entertainment, and Recreation Yes, Primary Yes, Secondary I use computers to get my job done -but I'm not an IT professional I work on the help desk in the IT Dept. of my organization I'm part of the IT team that addresses requests for modifications/fixes I'm a computer consultant working here I write or maintain software or hardware here I train staff on IT subjects I sell software or hardware (I work for a vendor) I work as a technician in the IT Dept of my organization I help set computer security policy for my organization I work in an administrative role in the IT Dept (e.g., office manager).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Perceived arrogance of those who are in charge of security ("I know what is best for you - don't question my authority…")Using security as an excuse for laziness, e.g., they</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Frustration about Access Policies 

1 
(Not Frustrated) 
2 
3 
4 
5 
(Very Frustrated) 

General users 
23% 
39% 
15% 
23% 
0 

Cybersecurity professionals 
33% 
27% 
33% 
7% 
0 </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="true"><head>Table 2 . How Well Thought Out is the Access Policy?</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>1 
(Thoughtfully 
Developed) 

2 
3 
4 
5 
(More of a hindrance 
than anything else) 

General users 
23% 
38% 
31% 
8% 
0% 

Cybersecurity professionals 
40% 
47% 
7% 
7% 
0% 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="true"><head>Table 3 . How Sensible are Several Rules?</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Generally Sensible 
Gen Pros 

Sometimes Sensible 
Gen Pros 

Not Sensible 
Gen Pros 

Don't Know 
Gen Pros 
Log on rules 
46% 87% 
46% 0% 
8% 13% 
0% 0% 

Password rules for different passwords for each app 
30 7 
20 53 
50 27 
0 13 

Password complexity 
23 40 
38 20 
38 40 
0 
0 

Password change frequency 
25 13 
58 40 
17 33 
0 13 

Management's rules on granting access 
8 31 
69 23 
15 8 
8 38 

Inactivity timeouts 
31 53 
54 33 
15 13 
0 
0 

Different rules for different systems 
17 21 
42 43 
33 14 
8 21 

Rules by how/why access is provided 
38 53 
46 20 
15 13 
0 13 </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 4 . Circumvention Justifications</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>General 
Users 

Cybersecurity 
Professionals 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 5 . Why are the Access Rules (Perceived as) So Foolish? Light Shaded Rows: Asked of only general users (rows 1-3); Dark Shaded Rows =only cyber security professionals (row 4)ACKNOWLEDGMENTS This material is based upon work supported by the Maryland Procurement Office under Contract No. H98230-14-C-0141. Any opinions, findings and conclusions or recommendations expressed in this material are those of the author(s) and do not necessarily reflect the views of the Maryland Procurement Office.</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Very Likely 
Gen Pros 

Likely 
Gen Pros 

Unlikely 
Gen Pros 

Don't know 
Gen Pros 

NA: Responsive 
Rules: Gen Pros 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>If "Yes" to above: To the best of your knowledge, was your input considered?</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Systematic analysis of use patterns, 

Local rules set by local leaders 

Rules set by executive management, political rules, regulators, etc 

Comment 

5. Do those who set security policy on access ask for input from users? 

Yes 

Not sure, but suspect it's yes. 

Not sure, but suspect it's no 

No 

Don't know 

Comment 

6. Yes 

Not sure, but suspect it's yes. 

Not sure, but suspect it's no 

No 

Don't know 

1 (Not Frustrated) 
2 
3 
4 
5 (Very Frustrated) 

Other (please specify) 

</table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A.2 Survey for Cybersecurity Professionals</head><p>The survey for cybersecurity professionals begins on the next page.</p><p>The purpose of the study: To understand how workers perceive computer access rules and their motivations to engage in workarounds to gain access to computer systems or parts of systems to which they are not supposed to access. We are not talking about hackers, rather we ask about barriers or inconveniences confronting personnel who seek to do their assigned work but are sometimes denied access because of problems such as lost passwords, required password changes, forgetting a specific log­on name, altered rules, system breakdowns, need to access the system via a different computer than usually used, etc. It is not a study of those with malicious intent. Your participation in this research study is voluntary. If you decide not to participate, you are free to stop at any time. Withdrawal will not interfere with your work or with your organization. If you have questions about your participation or rights in this research, you can discuss them with the study investigator or members of the study team. You may contact Prof. Ross Koppel, Ph.D. at the University of Pennsylvania at: rkoppel@sas.upenn.edu.</p><p>1. Which "industrial" sector best describes the principal business area of your organization? (Note that we do not ask for the name of your organization or any identifying information.) You may check more than one category.</p><p>Anonymous Survey about Computer Access, Worker's Understanding and Complian... n m l k j</p><p>We set policy based on our best judgement n m l k j</p><p>Yes, users are told by policy makers that we use data to formulate policy n m l k j</p><p>No, policy makers set rules based on other criteria</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl/>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
